<bill session="112" type="s" number="522" updated="2013-07-20T02:21:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Spectrum Relocation Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to clarify the rights and responsibilities of Federal entities in the spectrum relocation process, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="911"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="415"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="455"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2011--Introduced.
Spectrum Relocation Improvement Act of 2011 - Amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to require the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) to post on its website (while taking appropriate measures to safeguard classified or sensitive information) detailed transition plans from each federal entity that is eligible for payments from the Spectrum Relocation Fund for costs related to the reallocation of frequencies from federal to nonfederal use. Requires each federal entity's transition plan to provide certain public information about its spectrum relocation requirements including its: (1) current spectrum use; (2) geographic location of federal facilities or systems, including frequency bands used; (3) steps to be taken to relocate current spectrum uses from eligible frequencies; (4) necessary NTIA interactions; (5) authorized commercial licensee negotiator; (6) plans and timelines for equipment procurement, field-testing, and additional personnel; and (7) relocation process risk factors. Directs the FCC and the NTIA to jointly establish any necessary applicable conditions to define the term "shared access," including methods of sharing spectrum resources and coordination between federal and nonfederal entities (commercial licensees, and/or sharing network infrastructure or other resources). Requires the federal entities, to the fullest extent possible, to provide for sharing and coordination of eligible frequencies with commercial licensees. Requires federal entities to complete spectrum relocation within one year of receiving relocation payments. Sets forth a process for a federal entity to complete such relocation according to an approved alternative time period.</summary>
</bill>
