<bill session="109" type="h" number="4340" updated="2013-07-19T19:42:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-01-11">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-01-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States-Bahrain Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">United States-Bahrain Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">United States-Bahrain Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">United States-Bahrain Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">United States-Bahrain Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To implement the United States-Bahrain Free Trade Agreement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2005-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T14:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 109-318.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-12-06T14:41:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="171">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 171.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T19:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 583 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4340. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Sec. 2. During consideration of H.R. 4340 pursuant to this resolution, notwithstanding the operation of the previous question, the Chair may postponefurther consideration of the bill to a time designated by the Speaker in conconance with section 151 of the Trade Act of 1974. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-07T10:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 583 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-07T15:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 583.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11163-11179" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-07T15:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4340. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Sec. 2. During consideration of H.R. 4340 pursuant to this resolution, notwithstanding the operation of the previous question, the Chair may postpone further consideration of the bill to a time designated by the Speaker in conconance with section 151 of the Trade Act of 1974. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-07T15:11:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with two hours of debate on H.R. 4340.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-07T16:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11179" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-07T16:30:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on passage of the bill and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Bonilla demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed futher proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-07T17:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11181" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-12-07T17:18:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="616" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 327 - 95 (Roll no. 616).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11163-11168" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-07T17:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-12-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="322">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 322.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13507-13508" label="consideration"/>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-12-13" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-13">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-12-13">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2006-01-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-01-11">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2006-01-11" type="public" number="109-169">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-169.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="583"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="583"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="2027"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="2027"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2027"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2027"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bahrain"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Fibers"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="U.S. International Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/11/2006--Public Law.
United States-Bahrain Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act - Title I: Approval of, and General Provisions Relating to, the Agreement - (Sec. 101) Approves the United States-Bahrain Free Trade Agreement (Agreement) entered into on September 14, 2004, with the government of Bahrain, and the statement of administrative action proposed to implement the Agreement, both submitted to Congress on November 16, 2005. Authorizes the entry into force of the Agreement on or after January 1, 2006, if the President determines that the government of Bahrain has complied with certain provisions of the Agreement. (Sec. 102) Declares as void any provision of the Agreement which is inconsistent with U.S. law. Prohibits the invalidation of any state law, or the application thereof, on the ground of inconsistency with the Agreement, except as determined in a legal proceeding brought by the United States. (Sec. 103) Authorizes the President to proclaim actions and issue regulations to implement the Agreement on or after the date such Agreement enters into force. Requires the issuance of initial regulations for the statement of administrative action to implement the Agreement within one year after the Agreement enters into force. (Sec. 104) Grants the President proclamation authority under the Agreement subject to specified consultation requirements with the appropriate advisory committees established under the Trade Act of 1974 and the U.S. International Trade Commission (ITC). Requires the President to submit a report to the House Ways and Means Committee and the Senate Finance Committee on any action proposed to be proclaimed. Requires the expiration of a 60-day period before any action proposed to be proclaimed takes effect (layover). (Sec. 105) Authorizes the President to establish or designate within the Department of Commerce an office to provide administrative assistance to dispute settlement panels established under the Agreement. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Customs Provisions - (Sec. 201) Authorizes the President to: (1) proclaim tariff modifications necessary or appropriate to carry out the Agreement; (2) proclaim tariff modifications, subject to consultation and layover, necessary or appropriate to maintain concessions granted to Bahrain by the Agreement; and (3) substitute an ad valorem rate for goods under the Agreement for which the base rate is a specific or compound rate of duty, for purposes of carrying out tariff modifications. Requires the President to terminate the designation of Bahrain as a beneficiary developing country for purposes of the Generalized System of Preferences program under the Trade Act of 1974 on the date the Agreement enters into force. (Sec. 202) Prescribes rules of origin with respect to the reduction and elimination of duties imposed by the United States and Bahrain on goods imported directly from Bahrain or the United States into the other country's territory. Specifies content requirements allowing certain textile and apparel goods to be considered originating goods. Authorizes the President to proclaim, as part of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule (HTS) of the United States, certain provisions in the Agreement (including modifications) and any additional subordinate category that is necessary to carry out this title, consistent with the Agreement. (Sec. 203) Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to prohibit the charging of a fee for certain customs services for goods imported from, and originating in, Bahrain. Prohibits any service exempted from such fees from being funded with money from the Customs User Fee Account. (Sec. 204) Authorizes the President to direct the Secretary of the Treasury, pending the verification process under the Agreement to confirm the authenticity and claims of origin of Bahraini textiles and apparel goods, to take certain actions, including: (1) suspension of liquidation of the entry of any Bahraini textile or apparel good linked to unlawful activity; (2) publication of the name and address of any person subject to verification; (3) denial of preferential tariff treatment for such textiles or goods; and (4) denial of entry into the United States of such textiles or goods. (Sec. 205) Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe regulations to carry out provisions of this title relating to rules of origin, customs user fees, and presidential proclamation authority under the HTS. Title III: Relief From Imports - Subtitle A: Relief From Imports Benefiting From the Agreement - (Sec. 311) Authorizes an entity (including a trade association, firm, certified or recognized union, or group of workers) to petition the ITC for an adjustment to U.S. obligations (import relief) under the Agreement. Requires the ITC, upon the filing of a petition, to: (1) transmit a copy of the petition to the U.S. Trade Representative; (2) investigate whether an Bahraini article is being imported into the United States in such increased quantities that it constitutes a substantial cause of serious injury or threat to a domestic industry producing a similar article; (3) make a determination on a petition within 120 days after the start of an investigation; (4) report to the President on its determination with a recommendation on the amount of import relief necessary to remedy or prevent an injury to a domestic industry and to help the affected domestic industry to make a positive adjustment to import competition; and (5) make its report public and publish a summary in the Federal Register. (Sec. 313) Requires the President, not later than 30 days after receiving an ITC report affirming serious injury to a domestic industry, to provide import relief as recommended by the ITC. Exempts the President from providing import relief if the President determines that the cost of providing such relief outweighs its economic and social benefits. Sets forth the types of import relief which the President may grant, including suspension of any further reduction in the duty imposed on an imported article and an increase in the duty on such article. Limits the aggregate period during which import relief may be granted to three years. (Sec. 314) Prohibits any import relief under this title 10 years after the Agreement enters into force, unless the President determines that the government of Bahrain has consented to such relief. (Sec. 315) Authorizes the President to compensate Bahrain for reductions or eliminations of duties under the Agreement. (Sec. 316) Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to apply to ITC investigations conducted under this Act the procedural requirements of the Tariff Act of 1930 concerning release of confidential business information. Subtitle B: Textile and Apparel Safeguard Measures - (Sec. 321) Authorizes any interested party to petition the President to adjust U.S. obligations under the Agreement to reflect serious damage or actual threat to a domestic industry from the reduction or elimination of a duty on an Bahraini textile or apparel article (Bahraini article) which is in competition with articles produced by a domestic industry (safeguard relief). (Sec. 322) Authorizes the President, if an affirmative serious damage determination is made, to provide safeguard relief to remedy or prevent the damage and to facilitate adjustment by the domestic industry to import competition, including to increase the rate of duty imposed on the article. (Sec. 323) Limits the aggregate period during which safeguard relief may be granted to three years. (Sec. 324) Authorizes the President to exempt certain articles from safeguard relief. (Sec. 326) Terminates the authority to provide safeguard relief 10 years after the date on which certain duties are eliminated under the Agreement. (Sec. 327) Authorizes the President to compensate Bahrain if safeguard relief is ordered under this title. (Sec. 328) Restricts the authority of the President to release confidential business information provided in a safeguard review proceeding. Title IV: Procurement - (Sec. 401) Amends the Trade Agreements Act of 1979 to make products or services of any foreign country or instrumentality that is a party to the Agreement eligible for U.S. government procurement.</summary>
</bill>
