<bill session="111" type="h" number="3848" updated="2013-07-19T23:46:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Inspector General Authority Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Inspector General Act of 1978 to provide authority for Inspectors General to subpoena former agency employees, agency contractors, and employees of contractors for testimony, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2579"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5815"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/2009--Introduced.
Inspector General Authority Improvement Act of 2009 - Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to authorize each Inspector General of an establishment to issue a subpoena to require any former employee of the establishment, any former employee of a contractor (or subcontractor) of the establishment, or any former contractor (or subcontractor) of the establishment to provide testimony by deposition that relates to matters occurring in connection with that individual's employment or status. Requires an Inspector General, at least seven days before issuing a subpoena, to notify the Attorney General about the subpoena and the nature of the testimony sought. Prohibits the Inspector General from issuing the subpoena if the Attorney General objects within such seven days. Requires the Attorney General, if he or she objects, to find in writing within 30 days after receiving such notice that the testimony: (1) is likely to endanger U.S. national security, to interfere with a federal or state criminal investigation or prosecution, or to interfere with civil litigation to which the United States is, or is likely to be, a party; or (2) otherwise is not authorized by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
