<bill session="110" type="h" number="3358" updated="2013-07-19T21:33:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Renewing Our Commitment to Safe and Clean Power Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance the management and disposal of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste and to ensure the expansion of clean nuclear power in the United States to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and enhance our domestic energy security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400414"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400169" joined="2007-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2007-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2007-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2007-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2007--Introduced.
Renewing Our Commitment to Safe and Clean Power Act - Requires fees collected and deposited by the Secretary of Energy into the Nuclear Waste Fund to be credited to such Fund as discretionary offsetting collections each year in amounts not to exceed the amounts appropriated from the Nuclear Waste Fund for that year.Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 governing uses of such Fund to authorize costs incurred by the Secretary in connection with infrastructure activities to support construction or operation of a repository at the Yucca Mountain site or transportation to such site of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste. Instructs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), when it decides whether to permit construction or operation of a nuclear reactor, to deem without further consideration that sufficient capacity will be available in a timely manner to dispose of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste resulting from the operation of the reactor and related facilities.</summary>
</bill>
