<bill session="109" type="h" number="2475" updated="2013-07-19T19:26:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-21T16:46:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-06-21T16:46:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Authorization bill FY2006, Intelligence Agencies</title>
    <title type="popular">Intelligence Agencies FY2006 Authorization bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2006 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400182"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select)"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select)"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26T15:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hoekstra asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent) have until midnight on June 3 to file a report on H.R. 2475. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-02T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent). H. Rept. 109-101. Filed late, pursuant to previous special order.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-06-02T16:17:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="56">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 56.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-06-20T19:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 331 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2475 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Intelligence now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T14:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 331 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T14:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 331.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4840-4858" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4841-4842" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T14:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2475 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Intelligence now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T14:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 2475.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T15:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 331, the House proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Maloney amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Waxman moved to recommit with instructions to Intelligence (Permanent).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waxman motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment adding a new title which provides for establishment of an independent commission to investigate detainee abuses.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T16:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 197 - 228 (Roll no. 289).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4855-4858" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4855-4856" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-06-21T16:46:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="290" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 409 - 16 (Roll no. 290).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2475.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Select Committee on Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="331"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1803"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Confidential funding (Federal budgets)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Intelligence community staff"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Military intelligence"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Navy"/>
    <term name="Official secrets"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h335"/>
    <amendment number="h336"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/21/2005--Passed House amended.
Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006 - Title I: Intelligence Activities - (Sec. 101) Authorizes appropriations for FY2006 for the conduct of intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the: (1) Office of the Director of National Intelligence; (2) Central Intelligence Agency (CIA); (3) Department of Defense (DOD); (4) Defense Intelligence Agency; (5) National Security Agency (NSA); (6) Departments of the Army, Navy, and Air Force; (7) Departments of State, the Treasury, Energy, and Justice; (8) Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); (9) National Reconnaissance Office; (10) National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency; (11) Coast Guard; and (12) Department of Homeland Security. (Sec. 102) Specifies that the amounts authorized and the authorized personnel ceilings as of September 30, 2006, for such activities are those specified in the classified Schedule of Authorizations, which shall be made available to the Senate and House Appropriations Committees and the President. (Sec. 103) Allows the Director of National Intelligence (DNI), with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, to authorize employment of civilian personnel in excess of the number authorized for FY 2006 when necessary for the performance of important intelligence functions. Requires notification of the congressional intelligence committees on the use of such authority. (Sec. 104) Authorizes appropriations for the Intelligence Community Management Account for FY2006, for full-time personnel for elements within such Account, and for certain classified personnel. Title II: Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System - (Sec. 201) Authorizes appropriations for FY2006 for the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability Fund. Title III: General Provisions - (Sec. 301) Permits appropriations authorized by this Act for salary, pay, retirement, and other benefits for federal employees to be increased by such additional or supplemental amounts as may be necessary for increases in such compensation or benefits authorized by law. (Sec. 302) Specifies that the authorization of appropriations by this Act shall not be deemed to constitute authority for the conduct of any intelligence activity which is not otherwise authorized by the Constitution or laws of the United States. (Sec. 304) Requires the DNI's: (1) Science and Technology Committee to prioritize research and development related to intelligence; and (2) Director of Science and Technology to assist the DNI in establishing intelligence community (IC) technology goals. Directs the DNI to report to Congress a strategy for the development and use of technology in the IC through 2021. (Sec. 305) Requires the DNI to submit to the intelligence committees a classified comprehensive inventory of all special access programs under the National Intelligence Program. (Sec. 306) Expresses the sense of Congress that the DNI should expeditiously establish the necessary processes and procedures with the heads of executive departments and agencies to carry out the budgetary execution authorities within the National Security Intelligence Reform Act of 2004. (Sec. 307) Expresses the sense of Congress that the DNI should promptly establish and oversee implementation of a multi-level security clearance system across the IC to leverage the cultural and linguistic skills of subject matter experts and individuals proficient in foreign languages critical to national security. (Sec. 308) Requires the DNI to provide written notice to Congress explaining the failure of the executive branch to implement within the appropriate deadlines the National Counterterrorism Center, as required under the National Security Intelligence Reform Act of 2004, including the failure by the President to nominate an individual to serve as its Director. Requires monthly updates of such notice until the Center is fully implemented and operational.</summary>
</bill>
