<bill session="112" type="h" number="4408" updated="2013-07-20T01:48:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Sikes Act to promote the use of cooperative agreements under such Act for land management related to Department of Defense installations and to amend title 10, United States Code, to facilitate interagency cooperation in conservation programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2012-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/19/2012--Introduced.
Amends the Sikes Act (conservation programs on federal lands) to allow funds appropriated to the Department of Defense (DOD) to be obligated for funding an endowment for the costs of natural resource maintenance and improvement activities on military installations and state-owned National Guard installations. Allows the recipient of funds provided by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned under a natural resources cooperative agreement to use such funds to satisfy any matching funds or cost-sharing requirement of the Departments of Agriculture (USDA), Commerce, or the Interior.</summary>
</bill>
