<bill session="110" type="s" number="2881" updated="2013-07-19T22:46:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Cruise Ship Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish national standards for discharges from cruise vessels into the waters of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3147-3148"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3148-3154" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="6434"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Bacterial diseases"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Chlorine"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine engines"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sewage disposal"/>
    <term name="Sewage sludge"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2008--Introduced.
Clean Cruise Ship Act of 2008 - Prohibits cruise vessels calling on U.S. ports from discharging sewage, graywater, or bilge water into U.S. waters unless: (1) the treated effluent meets specified effluent limits and management standards; (2) the vessel is proceeding at not less than six knots; (3) the vessel is not less than 12 nautical miles from shore; and (4) the vessel is not in a no discharge zone. Prohibits the discharge of sewage sludge, incinerator ash, or hazardous waste into U.S. waters and requires it to be off-loaded at appropriate land-based facilities. Prescribes exceptions for: (1) discharges solely to secure the safety of a vessel or to save a life at sea; and (2) Alaskan vessels until 10 years after enactment.Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to promulgate such effluent limits that: (1) are consistent with the capability of the best available technology to treat effluent; (2) require compliance with state and federal water quality standards; (3) take into account the best available scientific information on environmental effects; and (4) require treated discharges to meet specified standards for minimum effluent quality, fecal coliform, and residual chlorine. Requires the EPA Administrator to implement a sampling and testing program, and requires the Commandant of the Coast Guard to implement an inspection program, sufficient to verify that such vessels are in compliance with this Act, the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, and other applicable federal laws and international agreements. Requires the Commandant to establish a program for the placement of trained independent observers on vessels to monitor and inspect vessel operations, equipment, and discharges. Requires the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to carry out a pilot program to develop and promote commercialization of technologies to provide federal agencies data regarding discharges from vessels and functioning of vessel components relating to fuel consumption and air and water pollution control.Calls for enactment of standards for: (1) ballast water; and (2) air quality regarding incineration and engine activities of vessels.Establishes the Cruise Vessel Pollution Control Fund. Requires the Commandant to collect fees from vessels for paying passengers to be deposited in such Fund for use in carrying out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
