<bill session="111" type="h" number="5815" updated="2013-07-20T00:05:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Inspector General Authority Improvement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Inspector General Authority Improvement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Inspector General Act of 1978 to provide authority for Inspectors General to subpoena the attendance and testimony of witnesses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400409"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2010-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23T12:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government. H. Rept. 111-623.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-23T12:41:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="363">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 363.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3848"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2010--Reported to House amended.
Inspector General Authority Improvement Act of 2010 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to authorize Inspectors General to subpoena the attendance and testimony of witnesses. Requires an Inspector General to use procedures other than subpoenas to obtain attendance and testimony from federal employees. Requires that such a subpoena provide reasonable notice to the individual whose testimony is sought and state that individual's name and the place of taking the testimony. Directs the Attorney General to represent an Office of Inspector General in the enforcement of such a subpoena. Prohibits an Inspector General from issuing a subpoena if: (1) the Inspector General believes there has been a violation of federal criminal law or the False Claims Act, unless the Inspector General provides 15 days' notice to the Attorney General; or (2) the Attorney General objects, within 14 days, to the issuance of the subpoena on the grounds that the taking of the testimony is likely to endanger national security or to interfere with any criminal investigation or prosecution, any pending investigation under the False Claims Act, or any civil litigation to which the United States is a party. (Sec. 3) Exempts Inspectors General from the Paperwork Reduction Act for any investigation, audit, inspection, evaluation, or other review conducted by any federal office of Inspector General, including any Inspector General defined under the Inspector General Act, any Special Inspector General established by statute, the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, and the Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board. (Sec. 4) Authorizes an Inspector General to compare, through a matching program, any federal records with other federal or non-federal records while conducting an audit, inspection, or investigation to identify weaknesses that make a program vulnerable to fraud, waste, or abuse and to detect improper payments and fraud. (Sec. 5) Requires: (1) the head of an establishment to take corrective action in response to any questioned costs, a recommendation that funds be put to better use, significant problems, abuses, or deficiencies identified by the establishment's Inspector General; and (2) such head's report to Congress accompanying each Inspector General's semiannual report to include a description of any such corrective action taken or proposed, a description of any potential cost savings generated by such action, and a certification of any determination that no such action is necessary or appropriate with respect to any such issue, with a detailed explanation of why that is the case. (Sec. 6) Codifies specified provisions concerning the classification and pay of Inspectors General of designated federal entities. Provides that an allegation of wrongdoing against a Special Counsel or Deputy Special Counsel may be received, reviewed, and referred for investigation by the Integrity Committee in the same manner as an allegation against an Inspector General, subject to Special Counsel recusal.</summary>
</bill>
