<bill session="112" type="s" number="98" updated="2013-07-20T02:17:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Creating American Jobs through Exports Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to renew trade promotion authority, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Panama"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2011--Introduced.
Creating American Jobs through Exports Act of 2011 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should: (1) continue the National Export Initiative to increase global export and investment opportunities for U.S. businesses that create jobs in the United States; and (2) submit the United States-Korea Free Trade Agreement, the United States-Colombia Trade Promotion Agreement, and the United States-Panama Trade Promotion Agreement to Congress, and Congress should approve them, to create U.S. jobs and stimulate the economy by eliminating trade barriers faced by U.S. exports that result in loss of jobs in the United States. Amends the Bipartisan Trade Promotion Authority Act of 2002 to authorize the President to enter into trade agreements with foreign countries regarding tariff and nontariff trade barriers: (1) on and after enactment of this Act and before July 1, 2016; or (2) on and after July 1, 2016, and before July 1, 2018, if certain congressional trade authorities procedures for implementing trade bills are extended for such period. Applies certain congressional and presidential trade authorities requirements to trade agreements that resulted from negotiations commenced before enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
