<bill session="111" type="h" number="3155" updated="2013-07-19T23:40:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-27T14:55:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-07-27T14:55:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Caregiver Assistance and Resource Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Caregiver Assistance and Resource Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Caregiver Assistance and Resource Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide certain caregivers of veterans with training, support, and medical care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400274"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2009-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2009-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412279" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2009-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412316" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-07-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 111-224.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-07-23T20:36:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="122">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 122.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Filner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8822-8825" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3155.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-07-27T14:55:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8822-8823" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2009--Passed House amended.
Caregiver Assistance and Resource Enhancement Act - (Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to develop and carry out a program of support services for family and non-family caregivers providing noninstitutional extended care to disabled veterans enrolled in the VA health care system. Requires such support services to include: (1) educational sessions, stipends, and access to support services; (2) counseling and related services; (3) respite care; (4) medical care for family caregivers; and (5) travel expenses in connection with the outpatient care of such veterans. Requires the Secretary to: (1) conduct outreach to inform disabled veterans and their families of services available for caregivers, as well as the ability of a caregiver to be trained and certified by a home health care agency in order to be paid for providing such services; (2) submit to the congressional veterans' committees a plan for implementation of such program; and (3) report annually thereafter for five years on plan implementation. (Sec. 3) Makes counseling and mental health services available to family and non-family caregivers of enrolled veterans. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to ensure that respite care meets the needs of the veteran receiving such care, including 24-hour home respite care, and is appropriate with respect to the veteran's age. (Sec. 5) Authorizes the provision of medical care through the VA for family caregivers of eligible veterans, if the caregiver is without health insurance and ineligible for other public health insurance. Defines a "family caregiver" as an individual who provides care to a veteran who was deployed in support of Operations Iraqi Freedom or Enduring Freedom and are determined by the Secretary to: (1) have a severe service-connected disability or illness; (2) be in need of caregiver services since, without such services, the veteran would require hospitalization, nursing home care, or other residential institutional care; and (3) be unable to carry out the activities of daily living. (Sec. 6) Authorizes a lodging and subsistence allowance for family caregivers of eligible veterans described above, to cover the time in which the veteran is traveling to and from a treatment facility as well as the duration of the treatment period. (Sec. 7) Requires the Secretary to: (1) at least once every three years, design and conduct a survey of family and non-family caregivers; (2) consider survey findings when carrying out programs related to caregivers; and (3) report to the veterans' committees on survey results and services made available to caregivers.</summary>
</bill>
