<bill session="111" type="s" number="1159" updated="2013-07-20T00:33:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vietnam Human Rights Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote freedom, human rights, and the rule of law in Vietnam.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2010-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1969"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6432"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Political representation"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Vietnam Human Rights Act of 2009 - Prohibits the federal government from providing the government of Vietnam with nonhumanitarian development, trade, economic, and security assistance during any fiscal year that exceeds the amount of such assistance provided during FY2009, unless such increases are matched or exceeded by additional funding for programs focusing on human rights and democracy promotion. Authorizes the President to waive such requirements if increased U.S. nonhumanitarian assistance would promote the purposes of this Act or it is otherwise in the U.S. national interest. Prohibits the President from providing certain duty-free treatment for Vietnam until the President certifies to Congress that the government of Vietnam protects freedom of association and does not engage in violations of workers' rights. Authorizes the President to provide U.S. assistance through appropriate nongovernmental organizations and the Human Rights Defenders Fund for the support of individuals and organizations to promote human rights in Vietnam. Expresses the sense of Congress regarding diplomacy with the government of Vietnam. Declares it is U.S. policy: (1) to take such measures as are necessary to overcome the jamming of Radio Free Asia by the government of Vietnam; and (2) that educational and cultural exchange programs with Vietnam should promote progress toward freedom and democracy. Declares it is U.S. policy to offer refugee resettlement to Vietnam nationals (including members of the Montagnard ethnic minority groups) who were eligible for the Humanitarian Resettlement program, the Orderly Departure program, the Resettlement Opportunities for Vietnamese Returnees program, the Amerasian Homecoming Act of 1988, or any other U.S. refugee program, but who were deemed ineligible for reasons of administrative error or certain circumstances beyond their control.</summary>
</bill>
