<bill session="109" type="h" number="6347" updated="2013-07-19T20:00:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the protection of health and safety during certain disasters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Child care workers"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Toxicology"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2006--Introduced.
Authorizes the President (acting through the Secretary of Health and Human Substances), upon determining that a substance of concern has been released in an area declared to be a disaster area and has disrupted the transportation system of the United States, to carry out a program for the coordination, protection, assessment, monitoring and study of the health and safety of responding or affected individuals with high exposure levels. Requires that such a program: (1) apply to workers or volunteers, clean up workers, residents of the area, and persons who are employed in or who attend school in the area; (2) ensure that such individuals are informed about and protected against potential health impacts of any such substance in a timely manner, are monitored and studied for any health impacts, and receive health care referrals; and (3) ensure that information from any such monitoring and studies is used to prevent or protect against similar health impacts. Requires the President to take appropriate measures to protect the privacy of any participant in a registry or study. Gives priority in any registry or study to the protection, monitoring, and study of the heath and safety of individuals with the highest level of exposure to a substance of concern. Allows the President to carry out such a program through a cooperative agreement with a medical institution. Requires the Secretary, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to jointly enter into a contract with the National Academy of Sciences to study disaster area health and environmental protection and monitoring.</summary>
</bill>
