<bill session="110" type="h" number="6213" updated="2013-07-19T21:58:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reinsurance International Solvency Standards Evaluation Board Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Reinsurance International Solvency Standards Evaluation Board.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400131"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2008--Introduced.
Reinsurance International Solvency Standards Evaluation Board Act of 2008 - Establishes the Reinsurance International Solvency Standards Evaluation Board to evaluate reinsurance supervisory systems of the states and jurisdictions outside the United States to determine, on a uniform basis, whether such systems provide adequate capital and risk management standards and an acceptable level of prudential supervision over their domiciled reinsurers. Requires the Board to: (1) establish evaluation standards and procedures for requesting an evaluation; and (2) develop uniform standards to improve reinsurance regulation, particularly where a domestic or international consensus standard or conflict of law has emerged. Prohibits the domiciliary state of a ceding insurer, for the purpose of determining credit for reinsurance for the ceding insurer, from treating a certified reinsurer domiciled and in good standing in any other domestic or foreign jurisdiction differently from reinsurers domiciled and in good standing in such domiciliary state.</summary>
</bill>
