<bill session="111" type="s" number="3642" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PACE Assessment Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that the underwriting standards of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac facilitate the use of property assessed clean energy programs to finance the installation of renewable energy and energy efficiency improvements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2010-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6206"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5766"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2010--Introduced.
PACE Assessment Protection Act of 2010 - Directs the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) to adopt underwriting standards that are consistent with the Guidelines for Pilot PACE Financing Programs issued on May 7, 2010, by the Department of Energy (DOE). Provides that liens or other property obligations that secure property taxes or assessments under a PACE program and that are consistent with such standards shall be considered to comply with the Uniform Instruments of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac and shall not constitute a default on an existing mortgage or trigger the exercise of lender's remedies for a property with such a lien. Defines a "PACE program" as a property assessed clean energy program under which a state or political subdivision levies taxes or assessments on real property to finance the installation of renewable energy and energy efficiency improvements. Prohibits Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac from requiring repayment of a PACE program tax or assessment in order for a property owner to finance, refinance, or transfer property that meets their underwriting criteria without consideration of the PACE program lien. Requires the underwriting standards to provide that, in the event that a tax or assessment under a PACE program is delinquent, only the unpaid delinquent amount along with applicable penalties, interest, and costs will be subject to foreclosure and not the entire amount. Prohibits the Federal Housing Finance Agency, Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, and all federal agencies and entities chartered under federal law from discriminating against communities implementing or participating in a PACE program.</summary>
</bill>
