<bill session="112" type="s" number="850" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Autism Services and Workforce Acceleration Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for enhanced treatment, support, services, and research for individuals with autism spectrum disorders and their families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2525"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2526-2529" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2011--Introduced.
Autism Services and Workforce Acceleration Act of 2011 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) to establish a demonstration project for the implementation of an Autism Care Program to provide grants and other assistance to improve the effectiveness and efficiency in providing comprehensive care to individuals diagnosed with autism spectrum disorders and their families. Sets forth eligibility requirements for the Program. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to carry out the Program and facilitate coordination with local communities to be better prepared and positioned to understand and meet the needs of the communities served by autism care programs. Requires each grantee to establish an autism care program advisory council to advise the autism care program regarding policies, priorities, and services. Directs the Secretary to establish a grant program to provide appropriate services to youth with autism spectrum disorders who are transitioning from secondary education to careers or postsecondary education (transitioning youth) and to adults with autism spectrum disorders, including individuals who are typically underserved, to enable such individuals to be as independent as possible. Requires the Secretary to award: (1) grants for multimedia campaigns to increase public education and awareness and reduce stigma concerning developmental milestones for infants and children and autism spectrum disorders, and (2) multiyear national training initiative supplemental grants to entities for training and technical assistance and to disseminate information to address the unmet needs of individuals with autism spectrum disorders and their families. Provides that nothing in this Act shall be construed to modify the legal rights of parents or legal guardians under federal, state, or local law regarding the care of their children.</summary>
</bill>
