<bill session="113" type="hr" number="122" updated="2013-11-02T06:16:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-19T14:53:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-03-19T14:53:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the concurrent resolution (H. Con. Res. 25) establishing the budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2014 and setting forth appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2015 through 2023; providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 115) providing for the expenses of certain committees of the House of Representatives in the One Hundred Thirteenth Congress; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412416"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-18T21:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-21, by Mr. Woodall.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-18T21:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Resolution provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 25 and for H. Res. 115. For H. Con. Res. 25, the resolution makes in order 4 hours of general debate, equally divided and controlled. Specified amendments are in order. For H. Res. 115, the resolution provides one hour of debate with one motion to recommit, without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-03-18T21:19:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="12">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 12.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19T12:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1581-1588" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19T12:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 122.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 122, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Slaughter demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1588-1590" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 223 - 189 (Roll no. 79).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1588-1589" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="80" datetime="2013-03-19T14:53:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 189 (Roll no. 80).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1581" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-03-19T14:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hc" number="25"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="hc" number="25"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="hr" number="115"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2013--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the concurrent resolution (H. Con. Res. 25) establishing the budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2014 and setting forth appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2015 through 2023; providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 115) providing for the expenses of certain committees of the House of Representatives in the One Hundred Thirteenth Congress.</summary>
</bill>
