<bill session="111" type="h" number="3078" updated="2013-07-19T23:39:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Investment in Rural After-School Programs Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To support after-school programs in rural areas of the United States by establishing a pilot program to assist communities establish, enhance, or expand rural after-school programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2009-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2009-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2009-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400254" joined="2009-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412229" joined="2009-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1281"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2009--Introduced.
Investment in Rural After-School Programs Act of 2009 - Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to award grants to local educational agencies, educational service agencies, community-based organizations, or other entities to improve, expand, or establish rural after-school programs that provide students with a broad array of activities when school is not in session that improve their academic performance and promote their positive development. Requires eligible programs to be implemented in active collaboration with the schools the students attend and take place in safe and easily accessible facilities. Gives priority to applicants that are partnerships between eligible entities or propose to serve students a majority of whom are eligible for free or reduced price meals under the school lunch and breakfast programs.</summary>
</bill>
