<bill session="109" type="h" number="6214" updated="2013-07-19T19:59:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prevention, Awareness, and Research of Autoimmune Disease Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase awareness of and research on autoimmune diseases, which are a major women's health problem, affect as many as 22 million Americans, and encompass more than 100 interrelated diseases, such as lupus, mulitple sclerosis, rheumatoid arthritis, Sjogren's syndrome, polymyositis, pemphigus, myasthenia gravis, Wegener's granulomatosis, psoriasis, celiac disease, autoimmune platelet disorders, scleroderma, alopecia areata, vitiligo, autoimmunethyroid disease, sarcoidosis, and fibromyalgia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Arthritis"/>
    <term name="Autoimmune diseases"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental depression"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Multiple sclerosis"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Quality of life"/>
    <term name="Rheumatism"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2006--Introduced.
Prevention, Awareness, and Research of Autoimmune Disease Act of 2006 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to award grants to eligible entities to conduct public and professional awareness activities regarding autoimmune diseases, such as lupus, multiple sclerosis, rheumatoid arthritis, and fibromyalgia. Defines an "eligible entity" as a nonprofit organization, a consumer group, an institution of higher education, a federal, state, or local government agency, or a media organization. Allows such an entity to use grant funds to: (1) promote increased awareness of early intervention and treatment to significantly improve the quality of life for people with autoimmune diseases; (2) target minority communities that may be underserved or disproportionately affected by such diseases; and (3) target women to help reduce the amount of time taken for correct diagnosis of such diseases. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to: (1) award grants to eligible entities for the education of health care providers on potential links between autoimmune diseases and cognitive and mood disorders, such as depression; and (2) establish an educational loan repayment program for physicians agreeing to conduct research on autoimmune diseases.</summary>
</bill>
