<bill session="111" type="h" number="1027" updated="2013-07-19T23:21:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Thrift Store Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To exempt second-hand sellers of certain products from the lead content and certification requirements of the Consumer Product Safety Improvement Act of 2008.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412267" joined="2009-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2009-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/2009--Introduced.
Thrift Store Protection Act - Allows, for two years after enactment of this Act, a secondhand reseller to sell, offer for sale, or distribute specified used products that are treated as a banned hazardous substances under the Federal Hazardous Substances Act: (1) because of the application of provisions of the Consumer Product Safety Improvement Act of 2008 relating to lead in children's products or paint; or (2) because the products lack a label required by specified provisions of the Consumer Product Safety Act. Defines "specified used product" as an article of clothing, a textile, shoes, or a book that, when sold or offered, has previously been purchased for use by a consumer. Defines "secondhand seller" as: (1) a consignment shop, thrift shop, or similar enterprise; (2) an individual who uses the Internet, a yard sale, or other casual means of selling; or (3) a person who sells at an auction for the benefit of a nonprofit organization.</summary>
</bill>
