<bill session="109" type="h" number="6243" updated="2013-07-19T19:59:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Contractors Accountability Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve Federal agency oversight of contracts and assistance and to strengthen accountability of the governmentwide debarment and suspension system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2006--Introduced.
Contractors Accountability Act of 2006 - Directs the Administrator of General Services to establish and maintain a database of information regarding integrity and performance of federal contracts and assistance recipients for use by federal procurement award officials and federal officials having authority to debar or suspend persons from federal contracts or assistance. Includes within required database information all judicial and administrative proceedings against such contractors or assistance recipients. Requires such information to be available to all federal agencies and the public. Requires federal agency suspension and debarment regulations to be amended to provide that an entity shall be presumed to be nonresponsible with respect to the award of a federal contract or assistance if a judgment or conviction for the same offense constituting a cause for federal debarment has been rendered against the entity twice within any three-year period. Requires an entity to disclose in any contract or assistance solicitation, bid, or offer all debarments or suspensions, judicial and administrative proceedings against the entity, and agreements that the entity is performing to avoid suspension or debarment within the last five years. Requires the Interagency Committee on Debarment and Suspension to take certain actions with respect to federal suspension or debarment proceedings, including resolving issues and coordinating actions among federal agencies. Allows: (1) federal agencies, commissions, or organizations not currently participating in the federal suspension and debarment system to do so; and (2) payments received under administrative agreements to avoid suspension or debarment to be used for costs associated with the database.</summary>
</bill>
