<bill session="109" type="hr" number="848" updated="2013-07-19T19:01:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the creation of refugee populations in the Middle East, North Africa, and the Persian Gulf region as a result of human rights violations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2006-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2006-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2006-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2006-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400132" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2006-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2006-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2006-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2006-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2006-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2006-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2006-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E973"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="sr" number="494"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab countries"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Christianity"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Islamic countries"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Jews"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2006--Introduced.
States that: (1) the United States deplores the past and continuing violations of human rights and religious freedoms of minority populations in Arab and Muslim countries throughout the Middle East, North Africa, and the Persian Gulf; and (2) any comprehensive Middle East peace agreement must resolve all outstanding issues relating to the legitimate rights of all refugees in the Middle East, including Jews, Christians, and other displaced populations. States that the President should instruct the U.S. Representative to the United Nations and all U.S. representatives in bilateral and multilateral fora to: (1) use U.S. influence to ensure that Middle East refugee resolutions which include a reference to the required resolution of the Palestinian refugee issue must also include a similarly explicit reference to the resolution of the issue of Jewish, Christian, and other refugees from Arab countries; and (2) make clear that the U.S. government supports the position that, as an integral part of any comprehensive Arab-Israeli peace, the issue of refugees from the Middle East, North Africa, and the Persian Gulf must include recognition of the legitimate rights of and losses incurred by all refugees displaced from Arab countries including Jews, Christians, and other minority groups.</summary>
</bill>
