<bill session="111" type="hr" number="464" updated="2013-07-19T23:00:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21T12:41:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-21T12:41:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 915) to amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize appropriations for the Federal Aviation Administration for fiscal years 2009 through 2012, to improve aviation safety and capacity, to provide stable funding for the national aviation system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412224"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T18:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-126, by Mr. Arcuri.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T18:37:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report, modified by the amendment printed in part B, shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment under the five-minute rule. The chair of the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure is authorized, on behalf of the committee, to file a supplemental report to accompany H.R. 915.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-05-20T18:37:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="59">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 59.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T10:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5901-5904" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T10:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 464.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T11:22:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 464 the question was put on ordering the previous question on H.Res. 464 and by voice vote the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lincoln Diaz-Balart demanded the Yeas and Nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question on H.Res. 464 until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5906-5907" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T12:33:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 246 - 175 (Roll no. 284).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5903, H5906-5907" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-05-21T12:41:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="285" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 178 (Roll no. 285).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5901" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T12:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="915"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 915) to amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize appropriations for the Federal Aviation Administration for fiscal years 2009 through 2012, to improve aviation safety and capacity, to provide stable funding for the national aviation system.</summary>
</bill>
