<bill session="112" type="h" number="359" updated="2013-07-20T01:13:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-26T14:13:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-01-26T14:13:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce Federal spending and the deficit by terminating taxpayer financing of presidential election campaigns and party conventions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2011-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2011-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2011-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412011" joined="2011-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2011-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2011-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2011-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412406" joined="2011-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2011-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2011-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2011-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="2011-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2011-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2011-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2011-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2011-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2011-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2011-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2011-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2011-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-20">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-25T14:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 54 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 359 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. All points of order against provisions of the bill are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T11:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 54 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T11:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 54.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H482-483, H483-499" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T11:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 359 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. All points of order against provisions of the bill are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T11:34:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 54 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T11:34:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steven C. LaTourette to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T11:35:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 359.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T11:42:00-05:00">
      <text>The Committee of the Whole rose informally to receive a message.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T11:44:00-05:00">
      <text>The Committee of the Whole resumed its sitting.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T12:44:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 54, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Peters amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T12:48:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Peters amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and announced by voice vote the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Peters requested a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T12:48:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 54, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Castor (FL) amendment number 2 under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T12:54:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 54, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Tsongas amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T12:58:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 54, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Moore amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T13:01:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 54, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Polis amendment in the nature of a substitute under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T13:11:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on the question of adoption of the Peters amendment which was debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T13:35:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 359.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T13:35:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H496" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T13:36:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H492" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T13:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Walz (MN) moved to recommit with instructions to Ways and Means.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H496-497" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H496-497" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T13:40:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the Committee on Ways and means to report the bill back to the House forthwith with an amendment which strikes all after the enacting clause and inserts in lieu thereof a complete new text.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T13:49:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H498-499" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T14:05:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 173 - 228 (Roll no. 24).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-01-26T14:13:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="25" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 160 (Roll no. 25).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26T14:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-14">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-02-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="11">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 11.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-02-28">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1021" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-28">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the bill presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1021" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1021" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-28">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure withdrawn in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1021" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-01">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the bill withdrawn by unanimous consent in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1075" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="54"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3463"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="194"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h5"/>
    <amendment number="h6"/>
    <amendment number="h7"/>
    <amendment number="h8"/>
    <amendment number="h9"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>1/26/2011--Passed House amended.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to terminate: (1) the taxpayer election to designate $3 of income tax liability for financing of presidential election campaigns; (2) the Presidential Election Campaign Fund; and (3) the Presidential Primary Matching Payment Account. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer all amounts in the Presidential Election Campaign Fund after its termination&#160;to the general fund of the Treasury, to be used only for deficit reduction.</summary>
</bill>
