<bill session="112" type="s" number="2104" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Water Resources Research Amendments Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Water Resources Research Amendments Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Water Resources Research Act of 1984 to reauthorize grants for and require applied water supply research regarding the water resources research and technology institutes established under that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2012-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2012-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S615-616"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S616" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-19">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 112-189.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-07-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="465">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 465.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2012--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Water Resources Research Amendments Act of 2012 - Amends the Water Resources Research Act of 1984 to: (1) declare that additional research is required into increasing the effectiveness and efficiency of new and existing treatment works through alternative approaches, including non-structural alternatives, decentralized approaches, water use efficiency, and actions to reduce energy consumption or extract energy from wastewater; (2) require each water resources research and technology institute to arrange for research that fosters the exploration of new ideas that expand understanding of water resources (currently, of water-related phenomena); (3) direct the Secretary of the Interior to report to specified congressional committees annually on each institute's compliance with matching fund requirements and provisions permitting the use of funds only to reimburse direct cost expenditures incurred for the conduct of the water resources research program; (4) require the Secretary to conduct his or her evaluation of each institute's research and effectiveness as an institution for planning, conducting, and arranging for research at least once every five (currently, three) years; and (5) authorize appropriations for such institutes through FY2017.</summary>
</bill>
