<bill session="112" type="s" number="3224" updated="2013-07-20T02:44:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeowners and Military Families Tax Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prevent an unfair tax burden for veterans and homeowners who have received assistance from the National Mortgage Settlement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4202"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4250"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4290"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4336"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2250"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2012--Introduced.
Homeowners and Military Families Tax Fairness Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) extend through 2015 the exclusion from gross income of income attributable to the discharge of indebtedness on a principal residence, (2) extend through 2012 the tax deduction for mortgage insurance premiums, and (3) exclude from gross income any National Mortgage Settlement amount. Defines "National Mortgage Settlement amount" as any amount received pursuant to the settlement in a legal action against Bank of America Corporation filed in U.S. District Court on March 12, 2012, which is: (1) a payment for transitional assistance; (2) a payment from the Borrower Payment Fund under the National Mortgage Settlement to a borrower whose home was finally sold or taken in foreclosure after December 31, 2007, and before January 1, 2012; or (3) a payment received as a result of a foreclosure that the Attorney General has determined was not in compliance with the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act.</summary>
</bill>
