<bill session="113" type="hr" number="223" updated="2013-11-02T06:17:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives concerning the ongoing conflict in Syria and the urgent need for the Syrian Opposition Coalition and local coordinating committees in Syria to assume the responsibilities of governance including the establishment of institutions of transitional justice, and to guarantee the rights of all Syria's people, regardless of ethnic or religious affiliation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400283"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E693"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and North Africa.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA13" subcommittee="Middle East and North Africa" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2013--Introduced.
Calls on: (1) the Syrian Opposition Coalition to publicly outline a detailed vision of inclusion for all of Syria's people, including a guarantee of full citizenship and equality under the law; and (2) the Obama Administration, in cooperation with international and regional partners, to continue to support the Coalition as it develops mechanisms of transitional justice guaranteeing the rights of all citizens under the law, and to support the Coalition as it forms an inclusive and democratic provisional government. Urges all parties in the conflict to respect international humanitarian law, protect minorities, preserve minority cultural and religious sites, and hold accountable those who violate such norms.</summary>
</bill>
