<bill session="112" type="h" number="6125" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act and the Federal Credit Union Act with respect to privilege of information provided to Federal and State agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412462"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412192" joined="2012-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2012-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4014"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2012--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act and the Federal Credit Union Act to declare that certain federal agencies ("covered agencies") shall not be deemed to have waived any confidentiality applicable to information by either transferring such information to, or permitting it to be used by, another covered agency or specified federal agencies. Includes among "covered agencies": (1) the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), (2) state bank and financial company supervisors, and (3) certain licensing and registry systems established under the Secure and Fair Enforcement for Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008. Defines "confidentiality" to include any work-product, attorney-client, or other privilege recognized under federal or state law. Shields also from the waiver of confidentiality any information submitted by a person to either a federal banking agency, the CFPB, a state bank supervisor, or foreign banking authority in the course of its supervisory or regulatory process.</summary>
</bill>
