<bill session="111" type="sr" number="622" updated="2013-07-20T00:21:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Secret Spending Resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution to stop secret spending.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2010-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7137-7138"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7137" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2010--Introduced.
Stop Secret Spending Resolution - Prohibits the passage by unanimous consent of legislation in the Senate that has been subject to a hotline notification unless the notification has been posted on the Senate's public website for at least three calendar days. Requires the Majority Leader to post in a prominent place on the Senate's webpage: (1) a notice that the legislation has been hotlined; (2) its number, title, a link to full text, and its sponsor; and (3) its estimated implementing cost and the number of new programs it would create. Requires the Secretary of the Senate to establish for both the Senate Calendar of Business and the Senate Executive Calendar a separate section entitled "Notice of Intent To Pass by Unanimous Consent." Makes this Act inapplicable: (1) if a quorum of the Senate is present at the time the unanimous consent is propounded to pass the bill; (2) to any legislation relating to an imminent or ongoing emergency, as jointly agreed to by the Majority and Minority Leaders; and (3) to legislation dealing solely with post office namings. Prohibits the Presiding Officer from entertaining requests to suspend this Act by unanimous consent.</summary>
</bill>
