<bill session="113" type="h" number="2891" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Waste Management Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate regulations on the management of medical waste.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2013--Introduced.
Medical Waste Management Act of 2013 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to: (1) revise the definition of "medical waste"; (2) require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to promulgate regulations listing types of medical waste; and (3) require the Administrator to conduct a medical waste management program to protect human health and the environment from medical waste and promulgate regulations on tracking, labeling, packaging, storing, handling, monitoring, and disposing of medical waste. Requires generators of medical waste (including tattoo and body art establishments) to: (1) provide waste transporters with written assurance that the generator has complied with labeling, packaging, and storage requirements and a manifest form for transporting such waste; (2) register with the Administrator; and (3) provide the Administrator with the names of all waste transporters. Requires transporters to: (1) not accept medical waste from a generator without receiving such assurance, (2) register with the Administrator, and (3) disclose to the Administrator the number and type of vehicles used to transport medical waste and the equipment and methods used to ensure segregation and handling of such waste. Requires owners or operators of storage and disposal facilities to: (1) provide notice of the disposal of medical waste to the generator, and (2) register with the Administrator. Sets forth provisions concerning inspections, public records, and enforcement under this Act. Requires the Administrator to: (1) establish a program to educate the public about, and increase access to, acceptable methods for disposal of used syringes; (2) study and report on medical waste generated and its management and disposal; and (3) consult with the International Joint Commission on tracking medical waste entering the United States from Canada.</summary>
</bill>
