<bill session="111" type="h" number="4831" updated="2013-07-19T23:56:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Earmark Reform Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to set a cap on allocated funds for earmarks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400151"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2010--Introduced.
Earmark Reform Act 2010 - Amends the Congressional Budget of 1974 to subdivide amounts allocated to the congressional appropriations committees into: (1) a specified total of new budget authority and outlays for earmarks in appropriations measures for the first fiscal year of the first concurrent budget resolution; and (2) an amount of total new budget authority and outlays for such earmarks for the first fiscal year of each ensuing budget resolution equal to 1% of total new budget authority and total outlays allocated to such committees. (Thus caps total earmarks at 1% of total new budget authority and total outlays allocated each fiscal year to such committees.) Makes it out of order in the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any bill, joint resolution, or amendment if its enactment would cause the applicable allocation of new budget authority or outlays for a fiscal year to be exceeded.</summary>
</bill>
