<bill session="112" type="hr" number="248" updated="2013-07-20T01:05:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Honoring the members of the military and intelligence community who carried out the mission that killed Osama bin Laden, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412383"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="240"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="241"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="sr" number="159"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2011--Introduced.
Declares that the death of Osama bin Laden represents a measure of justice and relief for the families and friends of the nearly 3,000 men and women who lost their lives on September 11, 2001, the men and women in the United States and around the world who have been killed by other al Qaeda-sponsored attacks, and the men and women of the U.S. Armed Forces and the intelligence community who have sacrificed their lives pursuing Osama bin Laden and al Qaeda. Commends the men and women of the U.S. Armed Forces and the U.S. intelligence community for: (1) their tremendous commitment, perseverance, professionalism, and sacrifice in bringing Osama bin Laden to justice; and (2) committing themselves to defeating, disrupting, and dismantling al Qaeda. Commends the President for ordering the successful operations to locate and eliminate Osama bin Laden. Reaffirms the U.S. commitment to disrupting, dismantling, and defeating al Qaeda and affiliated organizations around the world that threaten U.S. national security, eliminating a safe haven for terrorists in Afghanistan and Pakistan, and bringing terrorists to justice.</summary>
</bill>
