<bill session="113" type="s" number="1464" updated="2013-11-02T07:04:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving American Access to Information Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate and enhance the declassification of information that merits declassification, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2013-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
Preserving American Access to Information Act - Directs federal agency heads with authority to classify information to: (1) specify the types of information with short-lived sensitivity that could be automatically declassified without further review, and (2) consult with the Information Security Oversight Office of the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) in the declassification process. Exempts from such automatic declassification: (1) information on sources, methods, tactics, tradecraft, and procedures of members of the Armed Forces, the intelligence community, and other personnel performing similar security functions; and (2) any other information that could endanger military, intelligence, diplomatic, or law enforcement personnel, operations, or capabilities. Directs the President to take appropriate actions to enhance the authority and capacity of the National Declassification Center under Executive Order 13526 to promote a government-wide strategy for the declassification of information. Requires the Director of the National Declassification Center to provide for consultation between the Center's Advisory panel and the public on a regular basis. Extends authority for the Public Interest Declassification Board until December 31, 2018. Requires federal agencies to identify and designate historically valuable records as soon as possible after their creation to ensure the preservation and future accessibility of such records. Requires federal agency heads that classify information to report to Congress on: (1) options for pilot programs to assess the feasibility and advisability of mechanisms to improve the current declassification capabilities of federal agencies; and (2) the feasibility and advisability of replacing the current agency classification systems and of declassifying records with Formerly Restricted Date (FRD) that have no national security value.</summary>
</bill>
