<bill session="109" type="h" number="493" updated="2013-07-19T19:08:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ruben Estrella-Soto Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 37, United States Code, to establish an allowance to cover the cost of premiums for Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance coverage for members of the Armed Forces serving in combat zones, for junior enlisted members, and for certain other members.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400337"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2005-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2005--Introduced.
Ruben Estrella-Soto Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned to provide an allowance to a member of the Armed Forces who has obtained insurance coverage under the Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance program for each month during which such member: (1) served in an area for which special combat zone pay is authorized; (2) underwent training for immediate deployment to a combat zone; (3) underwent outprocessing immediately following return from a combat zone; (4) was in transit to or from a combat zone; (5) was hospitalized as a result of an injury, illness, or condition incurred or aggravated in a combat zone; or (6) was serving in pay grades E-1 through E-4. Makes the amount of such allowance the same amount as the pay deduction for such insurance coverage. Requires the Secretary concerned to notify eligible individuals of the availability of such allowance.</summary>
</bill>
