<bill session="113" type="h" number="1178" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Access to Residency Education Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize grants for graduate medical education partnerships in States with a low physician-resident-to-general-population ratio.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2013-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2013--Introduced.
Creating Access to Residency Education Act of 2013 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) to make grants to or contracts with eligible partnerships between state or local governments and private entities to support the creation of new medical residency training programs or slots within existing programs in underserved states in which there is a low physician-resident-to-general-population ratio. Requires any partnership to consist of: (1) a state with fewer than 25 medical residents per 100,000 population or a local government within such a state, and (2) a public or nonprofit teaching hospital or an accredited graduate medical education (GME) training program. Directs the Administrator in any grant or contract to require matching funds consisting of: (1) a public or private entity contribution of one-third of the cost of the medical residency program or new slots in an existing program, (2) a state or local government contribution of one-third, and (3) a CMS contribution of one-third. Requires the Administrator in awarding grants and contracts to give preference to eligible partnerships: (1) in which the participating state has 20 or fewer medical residents per 100,000 population or the participating local government is within such a state, (2) in which the state involved has a population over 15 million and less than 10% percent of the nation's residency slots, or (3) which fund new GME programs or slots within existing programs in the field of family medicine, internal medicine and its subspecialties, geriatrics, or pediatrics.</summary>
</bill>
