<bill session="109" type="s" number="1835" updated="2013-07-19T20:29:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Energy to purchase certain essential mineral rights and resolve natural resource damage liability claims.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300003"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2005-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="3978"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Liability for nuclear damages"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Sand and gravel industry"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2005--Introduced.
States that specified funds authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Energy for the Rocky Flats Environmental Technology Site (Colorado) shall be available to the Secretary for the purchase of essential mineral rights at Rocky Flats. Prescribes related conditions under which any natural resource damage liability claim shall be deemed to be satisfied. Exempts mineral rights purchased under this Act from the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Amends the Rocky Flats National Wildlife Refuge Act of 2001 to repeal the mandate for a Memorandum of Understanding in connection with the transfer to the Secretary of the Interior of management responsibilities and jurisdiction over Rocky Flats. Repeals, also, the prohibiton against any reduction in funds available to the Secretary of Energy for cleanup and closure of Rocky Flats as a result of such transfer. Revises the composition of the Rocky Flats National Wildlife Refuge and excludes specified lands subject to certain essential mineral rights.</summary>
</bill>
