<bill session="112" type="s" number="2180" updated="2013-07-20T02:35:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tax Credit for Early Educators Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a tax credit for professional school personnel in early childhood education, to expand the deduction for certain expenses of teachers to teachers in early childhood education, and to modify the credit for dependent care services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1542-1543"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3148"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2012--Introduced.
Tax Credit for Early Educators Act of 2012 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow an individual taxpayer who is employed in a position involving regular contact with students in an early childhood school or education program and whose position involves the formulation or implementation of educational programs for such school or program a $3,000 tax credit, adjusted for inflation after 2012; (2) extend until 2017 the tax deduction for certain expenses of eligible educators (currently, elementary and secondary school teachers) and expand the definition of "eligible educators" to include teachers, instructors, counselors, or aides in a preschool or early childhood program; and (3) eliminate the income-based reduction in the tax credit for employer-provided dependent care services (thus allowing a full 35% credit for employment-related expenses incurred for the care of a dependent).</summary>
</bill>
