<bill session="111" type="h" number="3599" updated="2013-07-19T23:44:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Deposit Restricted Qualified Tuition Programs Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to provide for deposit restricted qualified tuition programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2009-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2305"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4178"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2009--Introduced.
Deposit Restricted Qualified Tuition Programs Act of 2009 - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to prescribe requirements for deposit restricted qualified tuition programs which are exempt from federal income tax. Defines such a program as one in which: (1) the cash provided to it by a contributor may be invested only in deposits insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC); (2) the contributor may become a participant in the program by depositing funds into an account at a depository institution participating in the program; and (3) the program may include multiple depository institutions. Deems a deposit restricted qualified tuition program to be an identified banking product for purposes of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934. Denies treatment as a security under the Securities Act of 1933, the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, or the Investment Company Act of 1940 of: (1) the investment of cash in deposits at an insured depository institution through a deposit restricted qualified tuition program; (2) any certificate of deposit or other instrument evidencing any such deposit; or (3) any participation by a contributor to a deposit restricted qualified tuition program. Declares that in no event shall a deposit restricted qualified tuition program be deemed to be an issuer of a security or an investment company.</summary>
</bill>
