<bill session="113" type="h" number="2627" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Caring for Coal Miners Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to protect the health care benefits of our Nation's miners.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400431"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2013-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2013--Introduced.
Caring for Coal Miners Act - Amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to revise the formula for determining transfers from the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund to the Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan. Requires the formula to be calculated by taking into account only: (1) those beneficiaries actually enrolled in the Plan as of the enactment of this Act (currently, enrolled as of December 31, 2006), who are eligible to receive health benefits on the first day of the calendar year for which the transfer is made; and in addition to these beneficiaries (2) those who would be denied health benefits payable directly by an employer in the bituminous coal industry under a coal wage agreement as a result of a bankruptcy proceeding commenced in 2012. Considers the latter beneficiaries to be eligible to receive such health benefits under the Plan. Requires reduction of the amount made available to a beneficiary as a result of this Act, however, by the amount of any benefits actually paid by a Voluntary Employees' Beneficiary Association (VEBA) to or on behalf of a covered beneficiary, so that no covered beneficiary receives a greater benefit than would have been payable before the VEBA was established. Defines "Voluntary Employees' Beneficiary Association" as one established pursuant to the order entered May 29, 2013, by the Court in the case In re: Patriot Coal Corporation (Case No. 12-51502, Bankruptcy Court for the Eastern District of Missouri).</summary>
</bill>
