<bill session="111" type="h" number="4997" updated="2013-07-19T23:57:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2011 through 2015 for the National Science Foundation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400630"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Science Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Research and Science Education" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5116"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2010--Introduced.
National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2010 - Authorizes appropriations for FY2011-FY2015 to the National Science Foundation (NSF) for: (1) research and related activities; (2) education and human resources; (3) major research equipment and facilities construction; (4) agency operations and award management; (5) the Office of the National Science Board; and (6) the Office of Inspector General. Limits National Science Board reports to the President and Congress related to science and engineering and education in science and engineering to matters within NSF authority (or otherwise as requested by the Congress or the President). Repeals the requirement that the Inspector General of NSF conduct an audit every three years on the Board's compliance with open meetings subject to the Government in the Sunshine Act. Directs NSF to implement a policy for a specified broader impacts review criterion, including goals to achieve increased U.S. economic competitiveness, development of a globally competitive STEM workforce, and increased national security. Requires NSF to: (1) use at least 5% of its research budget to fund basic, high-risk, high-reward (transformative) research proposals; (2) make awards of not exceeding $5 million over a period of up to five years to interdisciplinary research collaborations likely to assist in addressing critical challenges to national security, competitiveness, and societal well-being; and (3) carry out a program to support research leading to advances in manufacturing, including nanomanufacturing. Directs the National Science Board to evaluate mid-scale research instrumentation needs at NSF. Sets forth provisions concerning funding for related education and workforce training, including STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics) education.</summary>
</bill>
