<bill session="112" type="hr" number="470" updated="2013-07-20T01:07:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-18T14:03:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-11-18T14:03:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3094) to amend the National Labor Relations Act with respect to representation hearings and the timing of elections of labor organizations under that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400643"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17T16:57:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-291, by Ms. Foxx.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17T16:57:00-05:00">
      <text>The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. The resolution provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and Workforce now printed in the bill shall be considered as orginial text for the purpose of amendment and shall be considered as read. The resolution waives all points of order against the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute. The resolution makes in order only those amendments printed in the report, to be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considred as read, debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole. The resolution waives all points of order agains the amendments printed in the report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-11-17T16:57:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="93">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 93.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18T09:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7835-7840" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18T09:17:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 470.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18T10:02:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7840" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18T10:03:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 470, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the resolution until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18T13:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7874-7875" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-11-18T14:03:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="859" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 167 (Roll no. 859).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7835" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18T14:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="3094"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2011--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3094) to amend the National Labor Relations Act with respect to representation hearings and the timing of elections of labor organizations under that Act.</summary>
</bill>
