<bill session="111" type="h" number="5927" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Share the Financial Burden Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit the amount which may be provided for allowances and expenses of any office of the House of Representatives or Senate to 95% of the amount provided for the office for fiscal year 2010, and to limit the pay of Members of Congress to 95% of the amount provided for fiscal year 2010.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412386"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4761"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4762"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6134"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2010--Introduced.
Share the Financial Burden Act - Prohibits the aggregate amount which may be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for allowances and expenses (including salaries) of any congressional office from exceeding 95% of the aggregate amount for FY2010. Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to reduce to 95% of the FY2010 rate the annual salary of a Member of Congress, Delegate or Resident Commissioner, the President pro tempore of the Senate, the Majority Leaders and Minority Leaders of both chambers, and the Speaker of the House, until otherwise provided by enactment of other law.</summary>
</bill>
