<bill session="110" type="s" number="2257" updated="2013-07-19T22:40:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Burma Democracy Promotion Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to impose sanctions on officials of the State Peace and Development Council in Burma, to amend the Burmese Freedom and Democracy Act of 2003 to prohibit the importation of gemstones and hardwoods from Burma, to promote a coordinated international effort to restore civilian democratic rule to Burma, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2007-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2007-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2007-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13521-13522"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13522-13524" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3890"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2172"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Alien property"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Ethnic groups"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/29/2007--Introduced.
Burma Democracy Promotion Act of 2007 - States that it is U.S. policy to: (1) condemn the repression carried out by the State Peace and Development Council (SPDC); (2) support a peaceful transition to constitutional democracy in Burma; and (3) hold accountable individuals responsible for the repression of peaceful political activity in Burma. Directs the President to submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of: (1) SPDC officials who play or have played a substantial role in political repression in Burma or in the commission of human rights abuses; and (2) other Burmese SPDC supporters. Subjects persons so identified to U.S. entry prohibition and financial sanctions (blocked property, financial transaction prohibitions, and banking sanctions). Exempts medical and humanitarian assistance from such restrictions. Authorizes additional waivers for diplomatic and travel purposes. Terminates such prohibitions upon a presidential certification to the committees that the SPDC has: (1) released all political prisoners, including Aung San Suu Kyi and other members of the National League for Democracy; (2) entered into a dialogue with democratic forces led by the National League for Democracy and the ethnic minorities of Burma on transitioning to democratic government; and (3) allowed humanitarian access to populations affected by armed conflict in all regions of Burma. Amends the the Burmese Freedom and Democracy Act of 2003 to prohibit the importation into the United States of Burmese gems, teak, or other hardwood timber. Directs the President to appoint a Special Representative and Policy Coordinator for Burma. Authorizes: (1) the Secretary of the Treasury to issue multi-year licenses for humanitarian or religious activities in Burma; and (2) the President to assist nonviolent democracy activists in their efforts to promote freedom, democracy, and human rights in Burma. Directs the Secretary of State to report to the appropriate committees respecting countries that provide military aid to Burma. Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should lead U.N. Security Council efforts to impose an international arms embargo on Burma.</summary>
</bill>
