<bill session="112" type="s" number="3449" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">China Fair Trade Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit purchases by the Federal Government of Chinese goods and services until the People's Republic of China becomes a party to the Agreement on Government Procurement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2012-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2012--Introduced.
China Fair Trade Act of 2012 - Amends the Trade Agreements Act of 1979 to provide that certain exceptions and waivers to the prohibition on the procurement of the products of a country that is not a party to the Agreement on Government Procurement shall not apply with respect to the procurements of products or services of the People's Republic of China. Amends the Buy American Act to declare that certain exceptions to the Act requiring only U.S. materials be used for public use shall not apply to the procurement of Chinese-made products until China becomes a party to the Agreement. Declares that certain exceptions to Buy American requirements shall not apply to the procurement of Chinese products by the Department of Defense (DOD) until China becomes a party to such Agreement. Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to declare that certain exceptions to Buy American requirements under such Act shall not apply to the procurement of Chinese steel and products until China becomes a party to the Agreement. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to report to Congress on the productive capacity of the major industrial sectors in China. Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to report to Congress on: (1) Chinese policies and the subsidies China provides in the development and exportation of renewable energy products and technologies, and (2) the impact such policies and subsidies have on U.S. manufacturers of such products and technologies.</summary>
</bill>
