<bill session="110" type="h" number="5614" updated="2013-07-19T21:53:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-15T12:13:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-05-15T12:13:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Saint-Gaudens Double Eagle Ultra-High Relief Bullion Coin Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Original Saint-Gaudens Double Eagle Ultra-High Relief Palladium Bullion Coin Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the production of Saint-Gaudens Double Eagle ultra-high relief bullion coins in palladium to provide affordable opportunities for investments in precious metals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To authorize the production in palladium of Saint-Gaudens Double Eagle coins as ultra-high relief numismatic coins and bullion investment coins in order to provide affordable opportunities for investments in precious metals, and for other purposes</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2008-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2008-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-13T16:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gutierrez moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-13T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3719-3722" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-13T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5614.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-13T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Simpson objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-15T12:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3903-3904" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-05-15T12:13:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="325" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 415 - 0 (Roll no. 325).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/13/2008 H3720-3721" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-05-15T12:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-15T12:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="2924"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Artists"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sculpture"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2008--Passed House amended.
Original Saint-Gaudens Double Eagle Ultra-High Relief Palladium Bullion Coin Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to mint and issue a $20 coin that bears, on the obverse and reverse, the designs of the famous 27-millimeter version of the 1907 Augustus Saint-Gaudens Double Eagle ultra-high relief gold piece. Authorizes the Secretary to commence minting and issuing such coins for sale, beginning January 1, 2009, in: (1) an appropriate number of $20 bullion investment coins meeting specified requirements; and (2) up to 15,000 ultra-high relief numismatic $20 coins meeting certain other requirements. Requires all coins to be minted at West Point, New York. Prohibits numismatic coins from being made available as so-called "fractional" coins. Requires the Secretary to take specified protective and anti-counterfeiting measures. Instructs the Treasury Inspector General to report to certain congressional committees on the extent of counterfeiting of rare, collectible, or numismatic coins for sale in the United States, regardless of the country where the original of such coin was produced or of the country in which the counterfeiting takes place, or sales overseas if such counterfeit coins are unauthorized copies of coins originally produced by the U.S. Mint.</summary>
</bill>
