<bill session="109" type="s" number="2115" updated="2013-07-19T20:31:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Morris K. Udall Parkinson's Disease Research Act Amendments of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve provisions relating to Parkinson's disease research.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2006-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2006-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2006-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2006-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2006-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2006-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2005-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S16780, S16781"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13680-13681" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3550"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmentally induced diseases"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Parkinson's disease"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2005--Introduced.
Morris K. Udall Parkinson's Disease Research Act Amendments of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise provisions regarding a research planning conference required to be convened by the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to require such conference to: (1) investigate Parkinson's research funded by NIH; and (2) identify shortcomings and opportunities for more effective treatments and a cure for Parkinson's disease. Requires the result of each conference to be included in a research investment plan that also: (1) provides for measurable results with the goals of better treatments and a cure for Parkinson's disease determining the allocation of research dollars; (2) includes an outline of how to fully utilize the Udall Center program; and (3) includes a budget and implementation strategy. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to ensure adequate funding to carry out activities described in the investment plan. Requires the Director to ensure funding for an additional Morris K. Udall research center to coordinate activities conducted by, and manage the interdisciplinary efforts of, the other centers. Requires each research center to ensure that there is a significant clinical component and ongoing basic research. Requires the Director to establish an application review process for grants to fund such research centers. Directs (currently, allows) the Director to award grants to support qualified investigators with potential for significant future Parkinson's disease breakthroughs. Requires the Director to investigate and report to Congress on the incidence of Parkinson's disease.</summary>
</bill>
