<bill session="111" type="s" number="3348" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the treatment of documents that express disagreement with decisions of the Board of Veterans' Appeals and that are misfiled with the Board within 120 days of such decisions as motions for reconsideration of such decisions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3646"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3646" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2010--Introduced.
Provides that if a person adversely affected by a final decision of the Board of Veterans' Appeals who has not filed a notice of appeal with the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims within the required 120-day period files a document with the Board or the agency of original jurisdiction within 120 days after the Board's decision expressing disagreement with the decision, such document shall be treated as a motion for reconsideration by the Board. Provides that such a document shall not be considered a motion for reconsideration if the Board or agency of original jurisdiction receives the document, determines that it expresses an intent to appeal the decision to the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, and forwards the document to such Court within the 120-day period.</summary>
</bill>
