<bill session="111" type="h" number="3146" updated="2013-07-19T23:40:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-15T15:00:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-09-15T15:00:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">21 Century FHA Housing Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">21st Century FHA Housing Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make improvements to the FHA mortgage insurance programs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412264"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412291" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412192" joined="2009-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-15T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Adler (NJ) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-15T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9520-9522" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-15T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3146.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-09-15T15:00:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9520-9521" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-09-15T15:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Cooperative and condominium housing"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2009--Passed House amended.
21st Century FHA Housing Act of 2009 - (Sec. 2) Amends the National Housing Act to declare that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Affairs (HUD) is not subject to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 when insuring any mortgage for a one-family unit in a multifamily project that holds an undivided interest in the common areas and facilities which serve the project (condominium). (Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) appoint and fix the compensation of HUD personnel; and (2) use certain funds to maintain an appropriate level of investment in information technology in order to upgrade HUD technology systems used in carrying out personnel-related functions. Sets a cap upon the use of premium-generated income for such upgrades, subject to approval in advance in an appropriation Act. (Sec. 5) Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a comprehensive training and education program to improve certain HUD services to users of Federal Housing Administration (FHA) mortgage insurance programs; and (2) conduct an ongoing review of delinquencies among recent single family housing mortgage originations; and (3) make available to certain congressional committees any information and conclusions pursuant to such review of delinquencies. Amends the Helping Families Save Their Homes Act of 2009 to direct the Secretary to implement procedures that analyze mortgage performance during the mandatory random review of mortgagees on one- to four-family residences who potentially present a high risk to the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund. (Sec. 6) Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of HUD, and the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) should use their statutory and regulatory authorities to provide financial assistance to facilitate increased warehouse credit capacity by qualified warehouse lenders. Urges that such assistance: (1) be used only to expand the amount of credit or lending capacity made available to qualified mortgage lenders by qualified warehouse lenders in order to fund residential mortgage loans; and (2) be provided in a manner which might include direct loans, guarantees, credit enhancement, and other incentives. (Sec. 7) Amends the National Housing Act to authorize the Secretary to implement alternative insured mortgage foreclosure avoidance demonstration programs, including methods involving short sales and deeds in lieu of foreclosure, and partial or full payment of insurance benefits to the mortgagee.</summary>
</bill>
