<bill session="111" type="h" number="5830" updated="2013-07-20T00:05:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">One Church, One Child Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for competitive grants for the establishment and expansion of programs that use networks of public, private, and faith-based organizations to recruit and train foster and adoptive parents and provide support services to foster children and their families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400081"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2010--Introduced.
One Church, One Child Act of 2010 - Amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make competitive grants to support establishment and expansion of programs that use networks of public, private, and faith-based organizations to: (1) recruit and train foster and adoptive parents; and (2) provide support services to foster and adoptive children and their families. Makes eligible for such grants state or local governments, local public agencies, community-based or nonprofit organizations, or private entities, including charitable or faith-based organizations. Directs the Secretary to provide for a National Clearinghouse for Adoption Promotion and Foster Parent Recruitment Programs through a contract with a nationally recognized, nonprofit adoption promotion and foster parent recruitment organization.</summary>
</bill>
