<bill session="112" type="h" number="3614" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Achievement Through Technology and Innovation Reauthorization Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the Enhancing Education Through Technology Act of 2001.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400347"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2011-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2012-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2218"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1178"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3578"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2011--Introduced.
Achievement Through Technology and Innovation Reauthorization Act of 2011 - Amends title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to rename part D (Achievement through Technology and Innovation) and reauthorize it through FY2017. Requires states to use a portion of their allotted funds under subpart 1 (State and Local Grants) of part D to develop challenging academic content and achievement standards to ensure that students are technologically literate before the end of grade eight. Specifies that such standards are only for tracking technological literacy and not for assessing adequate yearly progress (AYP) under title I. Permits technological literacy testing to be embedded in other state tests or performance-based assessments portfolios, or made through other valid and reliable means. Requires states to use the bulk of their allotment for two new subgrant programs for local educational agencies (LEAs), devoting: (1) 60% for formula subgrants to improve teaching and learning through technology, and (2) 40% for competitive subgrants for systemic school redesign through technology integration. Requires LEAs to: (1) include a new or updated local long-range strategic educational technology plan in their applications, (2) use a specified percentage of each subgrant for teacher training, and (3) use each subgrant to acquire and apply technology to identify individual student learning needs and support personalized learning. Allows LEAs that receive funds for both programs to use all the funds for systemic school redesign through technology integration program activities. Creates a new subpart 2 (State Competitive Grants) program to which all funding is to be directed if part D appropriations fall below a specified amount, otherwise all funding is to be made available for subpart 1 programs. Directs the Secretary to award competitive grants under subpart 2 to states and consortia of states to support LEAs' enhanced use of technology, including online and blended learning for systemic education transformation, curricula redesign, and new instructional strategies to personalize learning.</summary>
</bill>
