<bill session="112" type="h" number="2297" updated="2013-07-20T01:30:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-09">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote the development of the Southwest waterfront in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1165"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health Care, District of Columbia, Census and the National Archives     .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Subcommittee on Health Care, District of Columbia, Census and the National Archives Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-12-06T13:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gowdy moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-06T13:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8160-8161" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-06T13:48:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2297.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-12-06T13:53:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8160" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-12-06T13:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-12-14">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman without amendment. With written report No. 112-154.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-03-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="352">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 352.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2275" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2012-03-29" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2275" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-26T16:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Farenthold moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4001-4003" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-26T16:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 2297.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2012-06-26T16:16:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4001-4002" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-06-26T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2012-06-29">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2012-07-09">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2012-07-09" type="public" number="112-143">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-143.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSGO27" subcommittee="Health Care, District of Columbia, Census and the National Archives" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1998"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/9/2012--Public Law.
Amends the District of Columbia Official Code to revise certain specifications for the authorized transfer by the District Council, on behalf of the United States, to the District Redevelopment Land Agency of all federal right, title, and interest in the Southwest Waterfront Project Site. Authorizes such transfer by one or more quitclaim deeds. Authorizes the Agency to lease or sell the Site to a redevelopment company or other lessee or purchaser. Repeals the U.S. reversionary interest in such property. Amends the Code with respect to the municipal fish wharf and market in Southwest D.C. to remove its exclusive character as a fish wharf and market and make it simply a market. Repeals its designation as the sole wharf for the landing of fish and oysters for sale in the District of Columbia. Declares that nothing in this Act or any amendment made by it authorizes the removal, destruction, or obstruction of the Maine Lobsterman Memorial located near Maine Avenue in the District as of the enactment of this Act. Authorizes removal of the Memorial, however, from this location to another one on the Southwest waterfront of Maine Avenue if at the second location there would be a clear, unimpeded pedestrian pathway, and line of sight from the Memorial to the water. Deauthorizes a specified portion of the project for navigation of the Corps of Engineers at Potomac River, Washington Channel, District of Columbia.</summary>
</bill>
