<bill session="109" type="hr" number="686" updated="2013-07-19T19:00:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House to restore transparency, accountability, and oversight, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400254" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2006-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Standards of Official Conduct</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee membership"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Debt limit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House Rules"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2006--Introduced.
Amends rule XXII (House and Senate Relations) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require a rule or order for the consideration of a conference report to contain an itemized list of any provisions in violation of the scope rule. Makes it out of order to consider a rule or order: (1) waiving the three-day layover availability requirement before consideration of a conference report; or (2) containing a serious violation of the scope rule, or additions or deletions made after final agreement. Requires that minority party managers of the House be allowed to fully participate in a conference. Permits consideration of a conference report only if a roll call vote, in open meeting, was held on its final version and the result included in the accompanying joint explanatory statement of managers. Amends rule XIII (Privileged Reports by the Committee on Rules) to prohibit call up of a report by the Committee on Rules within 24 hours of presentation to the House (currently, on the same day). Amends rule XX (Voting and Quorum Calls) to require the Speaker of the House to publish in the Congressional Record a log of all voting activity occurring after the first 30 minutes of any recorded vote whose maximum time for voting exceeds 30 minutes. Amends rule XXIII (Code of Official Conduct) to prohibit a Member from negotiating for future employment with any person who has a direct interest in legislation referred to any committee during this or the preceding Congress while that Member serves on that committee. Amends rule XV (Business in Order on Special Days) to prohibit consideration under suspension of any bill or joint resolution authorizing or appropriating more than $100 million. Requires the Speaker of the House to endeavor to allow an equal number of bills and resolutions sponsored by majority and minority party members under suspension during any session of Congress. Repeals rule XXVII (Statutory Limit on Public Debt). Amends Rule XIII to prohibit the Committee on Rules from reporting a rule or order unless at least one minority party member of the committee is allowed to offer an amendment to it. Provides that, following adoption of an order of business, the Speaker of the House may not entertain a unanimous consent request to modify such order unless its text has been available to Members for at least 24 hours.</summary>
</bill>
