<bill session="111" type="s" number="3332" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Border Security Enforcement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to implement a comprehensive border security plan to combat illegal immigration, drug and alien smuggling, and violent activity along the southwest border of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2010-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2010--Introduced.
Border Security Enforcement Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Governor of Arizona to: (1) order 3,000 members of the Arizona National Guard and other National Guard units to perform Active Guard and Reserve duty by immediately deploying along the Tucson Sector border and the Yuma Sector border; and (2) construct and maintain related surveillance platforms. Directs such deployment's continuation until the Governor of Arizona certifies that the federal government has achieved operational control of the Tucson Sector and the Yuma Sector borders. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to increase, by January 1, 2015, the number of Border Patrol agents stationed along the Tucson Sector and the Yuma Sector borders by 3,000. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) DHS to implement Operation Streamline along the Tucson Sector and the Yuma Sector borders and reimburse state, local, and tribal law enforcement for related detention costs; and (2) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to enhance law enforcement readiness along the U.S. borders through Operation Stonegarden. Directs the Secretary to: (1) make specified enhancements to the Tucson Sector border; (2) analyze the feasibility of creating an additional Border Patrol sector in eastern Arizona and western New Mexico to interrupt drug trafficking operations; (3) construct a permanent checkpoint near Tubac, Arizona, and operate roving checkpoints along the Tucson Sector and the Yuma Sector borders; and (4) establish a two-year grant program, to be administered by Arizona, to improve emergency communications along the Tucson Sector and the Yuma Sector borders. Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to direct the Secretary to: (1) complete the required 700 mile southwest border fencing by December 31, 2011; and (2) construct double- and triple-layer fencing at appropriate locations along the Tucson Sector and the Yuma Sector borders. Provides for additional mobile surveillance systems and unmanned aerial vehicles along the Tucson Sector and the Yuma Sector borders. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) purchases and upgrades of law enforcement communications equipment; (2) the state criminal alien assistance program; and (3) reimbursement of state, county, tribal, and municipal costs associated with the prosecution and pre-trial detention of federally initiated criminal cases declined by local U.S. Attorneys' offices.</summary>
</bill>
