<bill session="111" type="h" number="5586" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Equity in Excellence Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To support high-achieving, educationally disadvantaged elementary school students in high-need local educational agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400312"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2010-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2010-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3086"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2010--Introduced.
Equity in Excellence Act of 2010 - Amends title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish an Equity in Excellence Grant program authorizing the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to eligible entities for efforts to ensure that the academic achievement rates of high-achieving students in grades one through four, who are from impoverished families and served by high-need local educational agencies (LEAs), do not fall behind the achievement rates of their more advantaged, high-achieving peers. Lists as eligible grantees: (1) high-need LEAs; (2) consortia of LEAs that include high-need LEAs; and (3) partnerships composed of high-need LEAs and institutions of higher education or nonprofits that have expertise in educating gifted students. Requires the use of grant funds to: (1) ensure that assessments provide diagnostic information that informs the instruction of high-achieving students; (2) implement evidence-based, innovative educational strategies, such as enrichment programs and academic acceleration strategies; (3) procure or use high-quality instructional materials; (4) train school personnel involved in teaching high-achieving students from impoverished families; and (5) conduct education and training for such students' parents that supports their children's excellence. Allows the Secretary to extend such grants based on recipient performance. Directs the Secretary to: (1) collect data annually comparing the longitudinal achievement levels of the students served by this Act's grants with their more advantaged peers; and (2) release such data for analysis to independent research institutions.</summary>
</bill>
