<bill session="112" type="h" number="3010" updated="2013-07-20T01:36:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-02T12:21:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-12-02T12:21:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regulatory Accountability Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Regulatory Accountability Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Regulatory Accountability Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform the process by which Federal agencies analyze and formulate new regulations and guidance documents.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412414" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412265" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2011-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400633" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412473" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2011-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412398" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412417" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="409888" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2011-11-02" withdrawn="2011-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-25">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-27">
      <text>Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 16 - 6.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-11-22T10:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 112-294.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-11-22T10:42:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="195">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 195.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-11-29T19:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 477 Reported to House. Measure provides for consideration of H.R. 3463 with one hour of general debate, equally divided and controlled; bill is closed to amendments. Provides for consideration of H.R. 527 with one hour of general debate, equally divided and controlled; specified amendments are in order. Provides for consideration of H.R. 3010 with one hour of general debate, equally divided and controlled; specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-30T18:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 477 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T09:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 477.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8081-8105" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T09:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Measure provides for consideration of H.R. 3463 with one hour of general debate, equally divided and controlled; bill is closed to amendments. Provides for consideration of H.R. 527 with one hour of general debate, equally divided and controlled; specified amendments are in order. Provides for consideration of H.R. 3010 with one hour of general debate, equally divided and controlled; specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T09:14:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 477 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T09:14:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steve Womack to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T09:15:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3010.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T10:14:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the the provisions of H.Res. 477, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moore amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T10:20:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Moore amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Moore demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T10:21:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the the provisions of H.Res. 477, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Olson amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T10:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the the provisions of H.Res. 477, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T10:34:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T10:35:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the the provisions of H.Res. 477, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly (VA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T10:42:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Connolly amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T10:42:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the the provisions of H.Res. 477, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nadler amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T10:50:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nadler amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the the provisions of H.Res. 477, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T10:57:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment No. 7, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson Lee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T11:41:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3010.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T11:42:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8088-8092" label="text of committee amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T11:42:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8103" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T11:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Boswell moved to recommit with instructions to Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8103-8105" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8103" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T11:43:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boswell motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment that stipulates the provisions in this Act shall not apply to new regulations or the revision of existing regulations that reduce costs or increase coverage for pharmaceuticals and other health services for seniors, or efforts by the Secretaries of Health and Human Services, Veterans Administration, and Defense to negotiate lower prescription drug prices.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T11:55:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8104" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T12:11:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 186 - 233 (Roll no. 887).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8105" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-12-02T12:21:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="888" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 253 - 167 (Roll no. 888).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02T12:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="477"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="477"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1606"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h888"/>
    <amendment number="h889"/>
    <amendment number="h890"/>
    <amendment number="h891"/>
    <amendment number="h892"/>
    <amendment number="h893"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/2/2011--Passed House amended.
Regulatory Accountability Act of 2011 - (Sec. 2) Defines "major rule" and "major guidance" for purposes of this Act as a rule or guidance that is likely to impose: (1)&#160;an annual cost on the economy of $100 million or more, adjusted annually for inflation; (2)&#160;a major increase in costs or prices; (3)&#160;significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or the ability of U.S. enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises; or (4) significant impacts on multiple sectors of the economy.&#160; Defines "high-impact rule" as a rule that is likely to have an annual cost on the economy of $1 billion or more, adjusted annually for inflation. (Sec. 3) Revises procedures for rulemaking under the Administrative Procedure Act (APA) to require a federal agency, in the rulemaking process, to make all preliminary and final factual determinations based on evidence and to consider: (1) the legal authority under which a rule may be proposed, (2) the specific nature and significance of the problem the agency may address with a rule, (3) whether existing rules have created or contributed to the problem the agency may address with a rule and whether such rules may be amended or rescinded, (4) any reasonable alternatives for a new rule, and (5) the potential costs and benefits associated with potential alternative rules. Revises rulemaking notice requirements to require an agency to: (1) publish in the Federal Register&#160;advance notice of proposed rulemaking involving a major or high-impact rule&#160;that involves a novel legal or policy issue arising out of statutory mandates; (2) consult with the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) before issuing a proposed rule and after the issuance of an advance notice of proposed rulemaking; (3) provide interested persons an opportunity to participate in the rulemaking process; (4) hold a hearing before the adoption of any high-impact rule; (5) expand requirements for the adoption of a final rule, including requiring that the agency adopt a rule only on the basis of the best evidence and at the least cost; and (6) grant any interested person the right to petition for the issuance, amendment, or repeal of a rule.&#160; Specifies the minimum amount of information that must be included in an advance notice. Requires the Administrator to issue guidelines to promote coordination, simplification, and harmonization of agency rules during the rulemaking process Exempts from such revised procedures rulemakings that concern monetary policy proposed or implemented by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Open Market Committee. (Sec. 4) Imposes new requirements for issuing any major guidance or guidance that involves a novel legal or policy issue arising out of statutory mandates. Authorizes the Administrator to issue guidelines for agencies in issuing major guidance or other guidance. (Sec. 5) Provides for electronic access to transcripts of testimony and exhibits and other papers filed in a rulemaking proceeding. Requires the record of decision in a rulemaking proceeding to include information from a hearing under the Information Quality Act or on a high-impact rule. Requires an agency to grant a petition for a hearing in the case of a major rule, unless the agency reasonably determines that a hearing would not advance consideration of the rule or would unreasonably delay completion of the rulemaking. Exempts from this requirement rulemakings that concern monetary policy proposed or implemented by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Open Market Committee. (Sec. 6) Provides that an agency's denial of an Information Quality Act petition, or a failure&#160;to grant or deny&#160;such petition within 90 days, is reviewable by a court as a final action.&#160; Allows immediate judicial review of interim rules, other than in cases involving national security interests, issued without compliance with the notice requirements of this Act. (Sec. 7) Revises standards for the scope of judicial review of agency rulemaking to prohibit a court from deferring to an agency's: (1) interpretation of a rule if the agency did not comply with APA requirements, (2) determination of the costs and benefits or other economic or risk assessment if the agency failed to conform to guidelines on such determinations and assessments established by the Administrator, (3) determinations made in the adoption of an interim rule, or (4) guidance. (Sec. 8) Defines "substantial evidence" for purposes of evaluating agency adjudications and for rulemaking under APA as such relevant evidence as a reasonable mind might accept as adequate to support a conclusion in light of the record considered as a whole, taking into account whatever in the record fairly detracts from the weight of the evidence relied upon by the agency to support its decision. (Sec. 9) Provides that the amendments made by this Act to specified provisions of federal law shall not apply to any rule makings pending or completed on the enactment date of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
