<bill session="113" type="h" number="2606" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stabilization and Reconstruction Integration Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the United States Office for Contingency Operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410396"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2013-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2013--Introduced.
Stabilization and Reconstruction Integration Act of 2013 - Establishes as an independent entity the United States Office for Contingency Operations (Office), which shall report to the Department of Defense (DOD) and the State Department. Requires the Director of such Office, among other duties, to: (1) monitor political and economic instability worldwide in order to anticipate the need for mobilizing U.S. and international assistance for the stabilization and reconstruction of a foreign country or region that is at risk of, in, or in transition from, conflict or civil strife; (2) develop contingency plans and procedures to mobilize and deploy civilian and military personnel to conduct appropriate foreign stabilization and reconstruction operations (operations); (3) aid the President in preparing rules and regulations relating to the planning, coordination, and execution of such operations; and (4) evaluate, and report to Congress on, the impact of such operations. Authorizes the President: (1) upon finding that circumstances and U.S. security interests so require, to declare that a stabilization and reconstruction emergency exists and to determine the geographic extent and the date of commencement of such emergency; and (2) to terminate such declaration upon determining that such emergency no longer exists. Gives the Director sole control over such operations conducted during a stabilization and reconstruction emergency. Requires the Director to: (1) coordinate with the Secretary of Defense and commanders of unified and specified combatant commands regarding Office plans or activities for operations, and (2) prescribe a Stabilization Federal Acquisition Regulation. Establishes the Stabilization and Reconstruction Fund. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Director and Office staff should partner with the country in which an operation is taking place, other foreign government partners, international organizations, and local nongovernmental organizations throughout the planning, implementation, and the transition stages of such operations in order to facilitate long term capacity building and sustainability of initiatives. Sets forth the duties of the Inspector General of the Office, including special audit and investigative authority and reporting requirements. Provides information coordination responsibilities of other federal agencies with respect to Office monitoring and evaluation requirements.</summary>
</bill>
