<bill session="111" type="h" number="1712" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Savings for Seniors Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to establish a Social Security Surplus Protection Account in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund to hold the Social Security surplus, to provide for suspension of investment of amounts held in the Account until enactment of legislation providing for investment of the Trust Fund in investment vehicles other than obligations of the United States, and to establish a Social Security Investment Commission to make recommendations for alternative forms of investment of the Social Security surplus in the Trust Fund.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412230" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2009-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2009--Introduced.
Savings for Seniors Act of 2009 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to establish in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund a Social Security Surplus Protection Account to hold the Social Security surplus. Denies the availability of the balance in the Account for investment by the Managing Trustee. Establishes in the executive branch of Government a Social Security Investment Commission to study and report to the President and Congress on the most effective vehicles for investment of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, other than investment in the form of U.S. obligations resulting in the transfer of Trust Fund assets to the general fund of the Treasury.</summary>
</bill>
