<bill session="111" type="h" number="6459" updated="2013-07-20T00:10:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 1848 of the Social Security Act to provide for a 4-year transition in reductions in relative value units for certain newly bundled services to allow physician practice time to adjust to new payment rates.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400152"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2010-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2010-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2010-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412332" joined="2010-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2010-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2010-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/30/2010--Introduced.
Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise requirements for determining the relative value of physicians' services for fee payment purposes. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to provide for a 4-year transition applicable in the case of codes (for services) for which: (1) a single code is used for payment for services for which multiple codes were previously used; and (2) a change in relative value units results in a reduction in such units of 10% or more. Applies this 4-year transition to the number of percentage points of the reduction in excess of 10%.</summary>
</bill>
