<bill session="109" type="s" number="786" updated="2013-07-19T20:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Weather Service Duties Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to clarify the duties and responsibilities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the National Weather Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300085"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3658"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-21">
      <text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation agreements"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Meteorology"/>
    <term name="Oceanography"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2005--Introduced.
National Weather Services Duties Act of 2005 - Requires the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the National Weather Service (NWS), in order to protect life and property, to be responsible for: (1) the preparation and issuance of severe weather forecasts and warnings; (2) the preparation and issuance of hydrometeorological guidance and core forecast information; (3) the collection and exchange of meteorological, hydrological, climatic, and oceanographic data information; and (4) reports, forecasts, warnings, and other advice necessary for aircraft safety and efficiency. Prohibits the Secretary from providing or assisting other entities in providing a product or service (other than a product or service for the preparation and issuance of severe weather forecasts and warnings as described above) that is or could be provided by the private sector unless: (1) the private sector is unwilling or unable to provide such product or service; or (2) the U.S. Government is obligated to provide such product or service under international aviation agreements. Sets forth requirements for the issuance of all data, information, guidance, forecasts, and warnings from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) or the NWS. Prohibits, as specified, disclosures by Federal employees of any weather data, information, guidance, forecast, or warning that might influence or affect the market value of a product, service, commodity, tradable, or business.</summary>
</bill>
