<bill session="109" type="h" number="3375" updated="2013-07-19T19:34:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financial Data Security Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to provide for secure financial data, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400327"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2005-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contractors"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2005--Introduced.
Financial Data Security Act of 2005 - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to declare that each consumer reporting agency, reporting broker, or reporting collector (consumer reporter) has an obligation to maintain reasonable policies and procedures to protect the security and confidentiality of a consumer's sensitive financial account and identity information against any unauthorized use that is reasonably likely to result in substantial inconvenience or substantial harm to such consumer. Prescribes data security safeguards that include: (1) investigations to protect against identity theft and fraudulent transactions; (2) notification alerts to law enforcement agencies, functional regulatory agencies, and affected consumers; (3) investigation and notice requirements for third party agreements; and (4) financial fraud mitigation procedures that offer free file monitoring service for affected consumers. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury (Secretary), the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Board), and the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) jointly to prescribe regulations that shield a consumer reporter from liability under state common law for loss or harm to the consumer subsequent to such reporter's offer of the free file monitoring service. Cites conditions under which persons in compliance with the Gramm-Leach Bliley Act governing disclosure of nonpublic personal financial information shall be deemed to be in compliance with this Act. Prescribes guidelines for joint promulgation of uniform security regulations by the Secretary, the Board, and the FTC. Preempts state law with respect to the data security safeguards and financial fraud mitigation prescribed by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
