<bill session="111" type="h" number="5342" updated="2013-07-20T00:00:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the use of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to document, predict, or mitigate the climate effects of specific Federal actions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2010-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2010-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2010-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2010-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2010-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3230"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2010--Introduced.
Provides that compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) does not require consideration of: (1) the climate change effects or greenhouse gas emissions of a proposed action and alternative actions; or (2) the relationship of climate change effects or greenhouse gas emissions to a proposed action or alternatives, including the relationship to proposal design, environmental impacts, mitigation, and adaptation measures. Prohibits the provisions of a draft, proposed, or final results of any analysis, study, mitigation measure, adaptation measure, environmental impact statement or similar analysis, design proposal, action, or alternative developed pursuant to NEPA (including regulations) relating to climate change effects or greenhouse gas emissions from being the basis for any enforceable measure or action under any other provision of law. Declares that this Act does not preempt or interfere with: (1) any authority to consider the climate change effects or greenhouse gas emissions effects of proposed legislation or regulations specifically addressing greenhouse gas emissions; or (2) requirements to consider the potential climate change effects or greenhouse gas emission effects of proposals for agency action during planning or design processes under provisions of law other than NEPA.</summary>
</bill>
