<bill session="112" type="hc" number="112" updated="2013-07-20T02:09:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-29T15:25:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-03-29T15:25:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Establishing the budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2013 and setting forth appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2014 through 2022.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400351"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-23T20:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on The Budget reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-421, by Mr. Ryan (WI).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-03-23T20:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="290">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 290.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T18:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 597 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 112 with 4 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The first reading of the concurrent resolution shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the concurrent resolution are waived. No amendment shall be in order except those printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Each amendment may be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, and shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent. All points of order against such amendments are waived except that the adoption of an amendment in the nature of a substitute shall constitute the</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T14:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 597 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 597.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1665-1731" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1699-1705" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 112 with 4 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The first reading of the concurrent resolution shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the concurrent resolution are waived. No amendment shall be in order except those printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Each amendment may be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, and shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent. All points of order against such amendments are waived except that the adoption of an amendment in the nature of a substitute shall constitute the conclusion of consideration of the concurrent resolution for amendment. It shall be in order at any time on the   ...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 597 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John Kline to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with four hours of general debate on H. Con. Res. 112.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T19:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 597, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Mulvaney amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T20:04:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mulvaney (SC) substitute amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Mulvaney (SC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T20:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 597, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Cleaver (MO) amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T20:38:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cleaver (MO) substitute amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cleaver (MO) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T20:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 597, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Cooper (TN) amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T21:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cooper (TN) substitute amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cooper (TN) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T21:07:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T21:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ryan (WI) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T21:45:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T21:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H. Con. Res. 112 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T21:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1731-1738" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T21:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T21:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 597, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Honda amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T22:27:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Honda (CA) substitute amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Honda (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T22:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McClintock moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T22:28:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28T22:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H. Con. Res. 112 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1762-1775" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T11:55:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of the Honda amendment in the nature of a substitute, which had been debated on earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T12:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 597, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Garrett amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T13:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ryan (WI) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T13:26:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T13:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H. Con. Res. 112 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1776-1795" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T13:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 597, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Van Hollen amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 597, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with an additional 20 minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 112.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H. Con. Res. 112.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T15:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1794" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29T15:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-03-29T15:25:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="151" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 191 (Roll no. 151).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-04-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-16">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Budget discharged pursuant to Section 300 of the Congressional Budget Act.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-04-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="354">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 354.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3183-3222" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 41 - 58. Record Vote Number: 98.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hc" number="34"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="597"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="37"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="40"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="41"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="42"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h999"/>
    <amendment number="h1000"/>
    <amendment number="h1001"/>
    <amendment number="h1002"/>
    <amendment number="h1003"/>
    <amendment number="h1004"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/29/2012--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the congressional budget for the federal government for FY2013, including the appropriate budgetary levels for FY2014-FY2022. Title I: Recommended Levels and Amounts - (Sec. 101) Lists recommended budgetary levels and amounts for FY2013-FY2022 with respect to: (1) federal revenues, (2) new budget authority, (3) budget outlays, (4) deficits (on-budget), (5) debt subject to limit, and (6) debt held by the public. (Sec. 102) Lists the appropriate levels of new budget authority and outlays for specified major functional categories for FY2013-FY2022. Title II: Reconciliation and Directive to the Committee on the Budget - (Sec. 201) Sets forth reconciliation instructions for the House Committees on: (1) Agriculture, (2) Energy and Commerce, (3) Financial Services, (4) the Judiciary, (5) Oversight and Government Reform, and (6) Ways and Means. (Sec. 202) Requires the House Committee on the Budget to report a bill that: (1) amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) to replace the sequester for enforcement of the $1.2 trillion budget goal established by the Budget Control Act of 2011, and (2) includes language making its application contingent upon the enactment of the required reconciliation bill. Title III: Recommended Levels and Amounts for FY2030, FY2040, and FY2050 - (Sec. 301) Lists recommended budgetary levels and amounts for FY2030, FY2040, and FY2050 as a percent of the federal gross domestic product (GDP) with respect to: (1) federal revenues, (2) budget outlays, (3) deficits, and (4) debt held by the public. Title IV: Reserve Funds - (Sec. 401) Authorizes the chair of the House Committee on the Budget to revise the allocations, aggregates, and other appropriate levels in this resolution (create a reserve fund) for the budgetary effects of any legislation repealing the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act or the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010. (Sec. 402) Authorizes a similar creation of certain deficit-neutral reserve funds for legislation concerning: (1) sustainable growth rate of the Medicare program, (2) revenue measures, (3) rural counties and schools, and (4) transportation. Title V: Budget Enforcement - (Sec. 501) Prohibits House legislation that would require advance appropriations, except certain FY2014 programs, projects, activities, or accounts. (Sec. 503) Authorizes the chair of the House Committee on the Budget to create reserve funds for the budgetary effects of measures: (1) extending the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001; (2) extending the Jobs and Growth Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2003; (3) adjusting the Alternative Minimum Tax (AMT) exemption amounts to prevent a larger number of taxpayers than those in tax year 2008 from being subject to the ATM or of allowing the use of nonrefundable personal credits; (4) extending the estate, gift, and generation-skipping transfer tax requirements of title III of the Tax Relief, Unemployment Insurance Reauthorization, and Job Creation Act of 2010; (5) granting a 20% deduction in income to small businesses; (6) implementing trade agreements; (7) repealing or reforming the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and the Health Care and Education Affordability Reconciliation Act of 2010; and (8) reforming the tax code and lowering tax rates. Disqualifies measures from such adjustments that increase: (1) the federal deficit between FY2013-FY2022; or (2) revenues over such period, other than by amending the Internal Revenue Code to repeal or modify the individual health care insurance mandate or modify the subsidies to purchase health insurance. Declares that, if a committee other than the Committee on Appropriations reports legislation that decreases direct spending (budget authority and outlays) for any fiscal year and also authorizes appropriations for the same purpose, upon the enactment of that measure, the chair of the Committee on the Budget may decrease the allocation to such committee and increase the allocation of discretionary spending to the Committee on Appropriations for FY2013 by the amount of the new budget authority and outlays provided for in legislation making appropriations for the same purpose. (Sec. 504) Makes it out of order in the House to consider legislation reported out of committee (other than the Committee on Appropriations) if it has the net effect of increasing direct spending in excess of $5 billion for any of the first four consecutive 10-fiscal-year periods beginning with FY2023. (Sec. 505) Requires the joint explanatory statement accompanying the conference report on any budget resolution to include in its allocation to the House Committee on Appropriations amounts for the discretionary administrative expenses of the Social Security Administration (SSA) and of the Postal Service. Authorizes the chair to adjust allocations and aggregates for legislation reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform that reforms the federal retirement system, but does not cause a net increase in the deficit for FY2013-FY2022. (Sec. 507) Requires the Congressional Budget Office (CBO), upon the request of the chair or ranking member of the Committee on the Budget, to make a supplemental estimate of the current actual or estimated market values representing the "fair value" of assets and liabilities affected by a measure as part of any estimate prepared for the measure under credit reform requirements of the Federal Credit Reform Act. Authorizes the chair to use such estimate to determine compliance of the measure in question with the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 and other budgetary enforcement controls. Requires CBO to estimate the change in net income to the National Flood Insurance Program by this Act, if such income is included in a reconciliation bill, as if that income were deposited in the general fund of the Treasury. (Sec. 508) Requires legislation that transfers funds from the general fund of the Treasury to the Highway Trust Fund to be counted as new budget authority and outlays equal to the amount of the transfer in the fiscal year the transfer occurs. (Sec. 509) Requires a separate allocation in the House to the Committee on Appropriations for overseas contingency operations and the global war on terrorism (GWOT). Title VI: Policy - (Sec. 601) Declares the policy of this resolution on: (1) Medicare reform, (2) Social Security, (3) deficit reduction through the cancellation of unobligated balances, and (4) deficit reduction through the reduction of unnecessary and wasteful spending. Title VII: Sense of the House Provisions - (Sec. 701) Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives on the importance of child support enforcement.</summary>
</bill>
