<bill session="109" type="s" number="989" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reservists Pay Security Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that a Federal employee who takes leave without pay in order to perform service as a member of the uniformed services or member of the National Guard shall continue to receive pay in an amount which, when taken together with the pay and allowances such individual is receiving for such service, will be no less than the basic pay such individual would then be receiving if no interruption in employment had occurred.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2005-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-05-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="99">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 99.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="981"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2005--Introduced.
Reservists Pay Security Act of 2005 - Entitles Federal employees who are absent from their positions while on active duty in the uniformed services or the National Guard to receive the amount of their basic pay which, when taken together with their military pay and allowances, is no less than the amount of pay that they would have earned if there had been no interruption in their civilian employment. Expands the reemployment rights of Federal employees on active duty in the uniformed services.</summary>
</bill>
