<bill session="112" type="h" number="4976" updated="2013-07-20T01:53:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Lands Tracts Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the conveyance of small parcels of National Forest System land and small parcels of public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management to landowners whose lands share a boundary with the National Forest System land or public lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412500"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412446" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2012-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2012--Introduced.
Small Lands Tracts Conveyance Act - Requires the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) for a state (respecting certain public lands) or the Regional Forester (respecting certain National Forest System lands) to select an eligible federal lands parcel for conveyance: (1) in response to a request by an owner of non-federal land that shares one or more boundaries with such parcel, or (2) upon the recommendation of the BLM District Office or System unit that exercises administration over such parcel. Bars a conveyed eligible parcel from exceeding 160 acres unless the Director or Regional Forester concerned approves a request for additional acreage. Permits acquisition by a person of only one eligible parcel a year, subject to an exception. Instructs the Director or Regional Forester concerned, as consideration for the sale of an eligible parcel, to require a cash payment in an amount equal to not less than the fair market value of such parcel, including the mineral estate, being conveyed. Requires the Director or the Regional Forester concerned to: (1) pay 50% of the consideration received for the sale of an eligible parcel to the county government in which such parcel is located, and (2) deposit the remaining amount in the general Treasury fund. Requires the purchaser of an eligible federal lands parcel under this Act to cover the costs to be incurred, or to reimburse the Director or Regional Forester concerned for the costs incurred, in carrying out the conveyance.</summary>
</bill>
