<bill session="110" type="h" number="3880" updated="2013-07-19T21:37:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 40, United States Code, to authorize the National Capital Planning Commission to designate and modify the boundaries of the National Mall area in the District of Columbia reserved for the location of commemorative works of preeminent historical and lasting significance to the United States and other activities, to require the Secretary of the Interior and the Administrator of General Services to make recommendations for the termination of the authority of a person to establish a commemorative work in the District of Columbia and its environs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2169"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="National Capital Planning Commission"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/17/2007--Introduced.
Mall Designation and Revitalization Act - Authorizes the National Capital Planning Commission (the Commission) to modify the boundaries of Areas I and II of the National Mall in the District of Columbia reserved for the location of commemorative works of preeminent historical and lasting significance to the United States. Prohibits such a decision from being subject to review. Requires the Commission to notify the Secretary of the Interior and the Administrator of General Services, the National Capital Memorial Advisory Commission, and certain congressional committees of any boundary modification made under such authority. Allows the Secretary or the Administrator to submit a recommendation to Congress that the legislative authority for a commemorative work be terminated before the expiration date of the legislative authority applicable to the work, if the person authorized to establish the work does not possess the capacity and resources to successfully complete the project for the establishment of the work before that expiration date. Directs: (1) the Commission to prepare recommendations for improving upon the process required for the selection, design, and subject matter of commemorative works in the District of Columbia and its environs; and (2) the Secretary to submit a plan to enhance visitor enjoyment, amenities, cultural experiences in, and the vitality of the National Mall.</summary>
</bill>
