<bill session="110" type="h" number="4129" updated="2013-07-19T21:40:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeless Access to Recovery through Treatment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to strengthen and expand substance abuse and mental health services to persons experiencing homelessness in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2007-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2007-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug addiction"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Runaway children"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/2007--Introduced.
Homeless Access to Recovery through Treatment Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to: (1) require hospitals and other inpatient facilities receiving federal funding under such Act or under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to ensure that patients are referred to appropriate medical care upon discharge and are placed in stable and appropriate housing; (2) establish a state substance abuse planning council to evaluate state substance abuse plans; (3) establish comprehensive community-based substance abuse prevention treatment for the homeless that is linguistically and culturally competent; (4) designate the homeless as a priority population and expand substance abuse and mental health services for the homeless; (5) expand substance abuse services for runaway, homeless, and street youth; (6) expand mental health and substance abuse services under the Projects for Assistance in Transition from Homelessness (PATH); (7) require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to report to Congress on federal, state, and local policies and practices regarding homelessness and addiction and mental illness prevention and treatment; and (8) require the Director of the Center for Substance Abuse Treatment to collaborate with the Assistant Secretary of Health and Human Resources for Children and Families to develop programs to provide substance abuse, alcohol abuse, and mental health services to children and families experiencing homelessness.</summary>
</bill>
