<bill session="112" type="h" number="3730" updated="2013-07-20T01:42:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Data Breach Timely Notification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide notice to individuals whose sensitive personal information is involved in a data breach, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2011-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR08" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2011--Introduced.
Veterans Data Breach Timely Notification Act - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in the event of a data breach with respect to sensitive personal information that is processed or maintained by the Secretary, to notify Congress and each individual whose sensitive personal information is involved in the data breach. Directs the Secretary to make such notifications within: (1) 5 business days, or (2) 10 business days if the Secretary determines that providing earlier notification is not feasible due to circumstances necessary to accurately identify the individuals whose sensitive personal information is involved in the data breach or to prevent further breach or unauthorized disclosure and reasonably restore the integrity of the data system. Requires such notification, in writing or by email or other electronic means, to include: (1) a description of the sensitive personal information involved in the breach, (2) a telephone number that the individual may use to contact the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), (3) notice that the individual is entitled to receive certain credit protection services at no cost to such individual, (4) the toll-free contact telephone numbers and addresses for the major credit reporting agencies, and (5) a toll-free telephone number and website address where the individual may obtain identity theft information. Directs the VA's Office of Public Affairs to notify the general public concerning any data breach involving sensitive personal information within five working days or as soon as possible pursuant to specified exceptions.</summary>
</bill>
