<bill session="111" type="s" number="2752" updated="2013-07-20T00:50:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gulf Oyster Industry Jobs Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure the sale and consumption of raw oysters and to direct the Food and Drug Administration to conduct an education campaign regarding the risks associated with consuming raw oysters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2009-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2009-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2009-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2009-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2009-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412380" joined="2009-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2009-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Immunology"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/2009--Introduced.
Gulf Oyster Industry Jobs Protection Act - Prohibits the use of funds made available to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to require that oysters be treated with post-harvest processing or other treatment or cooking requirements that result in a prohibition on selling or consuming raw oysters. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (FDA) and in cooperation with the oyster industry and the Interstate Shellfish Sanitation Conference, to conduct an education campaign to increase awareness of the risks associated with consuming raw oysters. Prohibits any proposed regulation or guidance issued by the Secretary that affects the harvesting, processing, or transportation of seafood harvested in the United States from becoming final or taking effect until the Secretary submits to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains: (1) a cost-benefit analysis, economic impact study, and health impact analysis of such proposed regulation or guidance; and (2) an analysis that compares such proposed regulation or guidance to any similar regulations or guidance with respect to other regulated foods and that compares the risks associated with seafood and the instances of those risks in such other regulated foods.</summary>
</bill>
