<bill session="109" type="sr" number="459" updated="2013-07-19T20:10:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding United States participation and agreement in the Doha Development Round of the World Trade Organization.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300006"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3900-3901" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="577"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="sc" number="55"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/2006--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that the United States should not be a signatory to any agreement or protocol with respect to the Doha Development Round of the World Trade Organization (WTO) negotiations, unless: (1) a nonagricultural market access (NAMA) agreement would lead to a significant reduction or elimination of the substantial inequities in the average level of industrial tariff rates of all WTO members; (2) substantial increases in market access and U.S. exports are achieved through reductions in average tariff rates applied to manufactured goods; (3) sectoral tariff agreements are included that would result in a significant number of countries eliminating tariffs on products and in sectors that would increase U.S. exports; and (4) real new market access is achieved through the dismantling of nontariff barriers, particularly in sectors of primary importance to American manufacturers.</summary>
</bill>
