<bill session="112" type="hr" number="576" updated="2013-07-20T01:07:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Government of the People's Republic of China has violated internationally recognized human rights by implementing severe restrictions on the rights of Uyghurs to freely associate and engage in religious and political speech, subjecting detained Uyghurs to torture and forced confessions, carrying out extrajudicial killings against Uyghur dissidents, and pressuring other governments to unlawfully return Uyghurs to China, where they face mistreatment and persecution.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400263"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2012-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/2012--Introduced.
Condemns violence against innocent individuals in China. Recognizes that China's policies of suppression against the Uyghurs in Xinjiang and other ethnic groups have created ethnic tension in those areas. Calls on China to: (1) desist from further executions, ensure that trials are conducted in accordance with international obligations, and allow international observers and the media to attend the trials; (2) provide a list of individuals detained in the aftermath of the July 2009 events in Xinjiang to the International Committee of the Red Cross, and grant access to those individuals for family members and legal counsel; and (3) cease government-sponsored crackdowns in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region and refrain from pressuring other governments to return Uyghurs to China. Calls on the President to: (1) state U.S. opposition to the flawed trials, executions, and harsh prison sentences against peaceful Uyghur protestors; and (2) restate the U.S. interest to open consulates in Lhasa, Tibet, and in Urumqi, Xinjiang.</summary>
</bill>
