<bill session="112" type="h" number="1080" updated="2013-07-20T01:19:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pediatric Research Consortia Establishment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title IV of the Public Health Service Act to provide for the establishment of pediatric research consortia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400101"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2011-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2011--Introduced.
Pediatric Research Consortia Establishment Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), acting through the Director of the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, to award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to public or nonprofit private entities to pay all or part of the cost of planning, establishing, and providing basic operating support for up to 20 national pediatric research consortia. Requires the Director of NIH to take unmet research needs into account when making awards under this Act. Declares that research conducted under this Act shall supplement, but not replace, research that is otherwise conducted or supported as part of the comprehensive pediatric research portfolio. Requires consortia to conduct basic, clinical, behavioral, social, or translational research, as well as training in, and demonstration of, advanced diagnostic and treatment methods relating to pediatrics. Requires the Director of NIH to: (1) provide for the coordination of information and ensure regular communication between consortia, and (2) require periodic reports on the activities of the consortia. Requires each consortium under this Act to be formed from a collaboration of cooperating institutions with a lead institution, meeting requirements that may be prescribed by the Director of NIH. Declares that payments made under this Act may be provided for a period of five years and extended for additional five-year periods with enhanced funding opportunities based on an appropriate scientific review of the operations.</summary>
</bill>
