<bill session="112" type="h" number="6540" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common Sense USA Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common Sense Utilization of Spaceport Assets Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 51, United States Code, to authorize the Director of the Kennedy Space Center to convey excess property at the Kennedy Space Center to a State or political subdivision, municipality, or instrumentality of a State for the development and operation of a spaceport.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412309"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
Common Sense Utilization of Spaceport Assets Act or the Common Sense USA Act - Authorizes the Director of the Kennedy Space Center in Florida to convey excess real property to a state, or a subdivision of a state, for the development and operation of a spaceport. Prohibits the involvement of the Administrator of General Services Administration (GSA) in any such conveyance. Permits such conveyance to be made only after specific conveyance requirements have been met, including that the Director has received and approved a development plan that assures that the conveyed land will be developed and operated as a spaceport. Requires the deed of conveyance to provide that all of the property will be used and maintained in perpetuity for the purpose for which it was conveyed.</summary>
</bill>
