<bill session="109" type="s" number="2390" updated="2013-07-19T20:34:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Innovation Act--Commerce Provisions</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide a national innovation initiative.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300004" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2006-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2006-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2006-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2006-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2006-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4654"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="High technology"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial engineering"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Nanotechnology"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2006--Introduced.
National Innovation Act--Commerce Provisions - Directs the President to establish the: (1) President's Council on Innovation; and (2) Innovation Acceleration Grants Program to support and promote innovation in the United States. Requires the National Science Foundation (NSF) to: (1) submit a multiyear plan that describes how the funds authorized by this Act for doubling research funding shall be used; (2) study how the federal government should support the new discipline of service science; (3) expand the Graduate Research Fellowship Program and the Integrative Graduate Education and Research Traineeship Program; (4) establish a clearinghouse for sharing program elements used in successful professional science master's degree programs; (5) award grants for pilot programs to four-year institutions of higher education to facilitate the creation or improvement of such programs; and (6) award grants to local educational agencies to enable implementation of innovation-based experiential learning. Requires the Office of Science and Technology Policy to submit recommendations for an increase in funding for research and development in physical sciences and engineering. Requires the Department of Commerce to: (1) review federal programs that support local economic development and implement a strategy to fund initiatives that improve the ability of communities to participate successfully in the modern economy through innovation; (2) promote economic development opportunities for serving local communities as specified; and (3) coordinate activities focused on promoting innovation through development of regional innovation hot spots. Requires the National Institute of Standards and Technology to support research and development for advanced manufacturing systems designed to increase productivity and efficiency and to create competitive advantages for U.S. businesses. Requires the Director of the NSF to conduct a study regarding how the federal government should support, through research, education, and training, the new discipline of service science.</summary>
</bill>
