<bill session="113" type="h" number="2829" updated="2013-11-02T06:42:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Important Voter Eligibility Requirements to States Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require an applicant for voter registration for elections for Federal office to affirmatively state that the applicant meets the eligibility requirements for voting in such elections as a condition of completing the application, to require States to verify that an applicant for registering to vote in such elections meets the eligibility requirements for voting in such elections prior to registering the applicant to vote, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400089"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2013-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2013--Introduced.
Restoring Important Voter Eligibility Requirements to States Act of 2013 - Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require an applicant for voter registration for federal elections to state affirmatively in the application form provided along with an application for a motor vehicle driver's license (as well as in other voter registration forms) that the applicant meets the eligibility requirements for voting in such elections as a condition of the application's acceptance. Requires all such forms to include a statement specifying the penalty for perjury in an application for voter registration. Prohibits states from registering an individual to vote in federal elections unless they verify that the information provided in the individual's application is correct. Requires the head of an office of the federal government, upon request, to enter into an agreement with the chief state election official to enable the official to verify the eligibility of such an applicant.</summary>
</bill>
