<bill session="110" type="s" number="1873" updated="2013-07-19T22:36:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving Emergency Medical Care and Response Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish demonstration programs on regionalized systems for emergency care, to support emergency medicine research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10143"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3173"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2007--Introduced.
Improving Emergency Medical Care and Response Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting though the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, to award contracts or competitive grants to support demonstration programs that design, implement, and evaluate innovative models of regionalized, comprehensive, and accountable emergency care systems. Requires the Secretary to give priority to entities that serve a population in a medically underserved area. Directs the Secretary to: (1) support federal programs involved in improving the emergency care system to expand and accelerate research in emergency medical care systems and emergency medicine; and (2) support research to determine the estimated economic impact of, and savings that result from, the implementation of coordinated emergency care systems.</summary>
</bill>
