<bill session="109" type="s" number="2759" updated="2013-07-19T20:37:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Part D Outreach and Enrollment Enhancement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for additional outreach and education related to the Medicare program and to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide a special enrollment period for individuals who qualify for an income-related subsidy under the Medicare prescription drug program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2006-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2006-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4157-4158"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the aged"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2006--Introduced.
Medicare Part D Outreach and Enrollment Enhancement Act of 2006 - Authorizes and makes appropriations to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services for additional grants to state health insurance counseling and assistance (HICA) programs to conduct outreach and education related to enrollment in the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (SSA). Makes appropriations to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to provide funding to Area Agencies on Aging and Native American aging programs to conduct outreach and education related to the Medicare prescription drug program under part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of SSA title XVIII. Amends SSA title XVIII part D to provide a special enrollment period for individuals who qualify for a low- income-related subsidy under the Medicare prescription drug program.</summary>
</bill>
