<bill session="111" type="s" number="3024" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Job Impact Analysis Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that the creation of jobs by small businesses is considered during the Federal legislative and rulemaking process, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2010-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S704-706"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S706-707" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3103"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/23/2010--Introduced.
Job Impact Analysis Act of 2010 - Amends the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to require the Director of the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to include in the statement submitted to an authorizing congressional committee for a public bill or joint resolution reported by that committee for which estimated direct costs of all federal intergovernmental mandates, or all federal private sector mandates, will equal or exceed $5 billion (adjusted annually for inflation) estimates of the potential job creation or job loss in state, local, and tribal governments, or in the private sector, as a result of such mandates. Amends the Regulatory Flexibility Act to require: (1) each initial regulatory flexibility analysis to contain a detailed statement estimating the additional cumulative economic impact of the proposed rule on small businesses; (2) an agency to notify the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration (SBA) of any draft rules that may have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small businesses; (3) each final regulatory flexibility analysis to include the agency's response to any comments filed by the Chief Counsel in response to the proposed rule; and (4) the agency to publish the final regulatory flexibility analysis on its website. Requires each agency: (1) to place on its website its plan for the periodic review of rules, providing for the review of all agency rules at specified intervals; and (2) in reviewing the rules, to consider specified factors, including the continued need for the rule, the nature of complaints received, and the rule's complexity and current impact. Requires: (1) the Office of Advocacy of the SBA to carry out responsibilities concerning the analysis of regulatory functions; (2) each federal budget to include a separate statement of the amount requested for the Office, designated in a separate account in the General Fund of the Treasury; and (3) the SBA Administrator to provide the Office with appropriate office space and necessary equipment, operating budget, communications, and maintenance services.</summary>
</bill>
