<bill session="111" type="s" number="2336" updated="2013-07-20T00:44:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">USA PATRIOT Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to safeguard intelligence collection and enact a fair and responsible reauthorization of the 3 expiring provisions of the USA PATRIOT Improvements and Reauthorization Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2009-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10928-10929, S10933-10934"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10934" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3845"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1692"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/29/2009--Introduced.
USA PATRIOT Reauthorization Act of 2009 - Amends the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 to extend until December 31, 2013, provisions: (1) granting roving electronic surveillance authority; and (2) authorizing the production of tangible things (including books, records, papers, and documents) for foreign intelligence and international terrorism investigations. Amends the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to extend until December 31, 2013, provisions revising the definition of an "agent of a foreign power" to include any non-U.S. person who engages in international terrorism or preparatory activities ("lone wolf" provision). Amends the federal criminal code to revise procedures for obtaining judicial review of national security letter nondisclosure orders. Allows the recipient of a nondisclosure order to request judicial review of the order and requires the government to respond by setting forth specific facts in a certification that justify the need for nondisclosure based upon national security and other concerns. Requires courts, in considering whether to grant a nondisclosure order, to give substantial weight to the facts alleged by the government in its certification. Repeals provisions granting government certifications a conclusive presumption of veracity.</summary>
</bill>
