<bill session="110" type="h" number="2400" updated="2013-07-19T21:24:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-23T12:40:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-07-23T12:40:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to establish an integrated Federal ocean and coastal mapping plan for the Great Lakes and coastal state waters, the territorial sea, the exclusive economic zone, and the Continental Shelf of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1108"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-23T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-253, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-23T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Science and Technology discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-07-23T12:02:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="162">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 162.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-07-23T12:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-23T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8199-8201" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-23T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2400.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-07-23T12:40:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8199-8200" label="text as passed in House"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-07-23T12:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science and Technology"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="39"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Ocean currents"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oceanography"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Submarine cables"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2007--Passed House amended.
Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act - (Sec. 2) Directs the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to establish an integrated ocean and coastal mapping program for the Great Lakes and coastal state waters, the territorial sea, the exclusive economic zone, and the U.S. continental shelf that enhances ecosystem approaches in decision-making for conservation and management of marine resources and habitats, establishes research priorities, supports the siting of research and other platforms, advances safety of navigation, and advances ocean and coastal science. (Sec. 3) Directs the Administrator to convene or use an existing interagency committee on ocean and coastal mapping to implement such program and to coordinate federal ocean and coastal mapping and surveying activities with other federal efforts (including the Digital Coast, Geospatial One-Stop, and the Federal Geographic Data Committee), international mapping activities, coastal states, user groups, and nongovernmental entities. Authorizes the Administrator to convene an ocean and coastal mapping advisory panel consisting of representatives from nongovernmental entities to provide input regarding activities of the committee. (Sec. 4) Directs the Administrator to develop a plan for an integrated ocean and coastal mapping initiative within NOAA that: (1) identifies all ocean and coastal mapping programs within NOAA, establishing priorities; (2) encourages the development of innovative ocean and coastal mapping technologies and applications through research and development (R&amp;D) cooperative agreements at joint or cooperative research institutes or centers and with other nongovernmental entities; and (3) documents available and developing technologies, best practices in data processing and distribution, and leveraging opportunities with other federal agencies, coastal states, and nongovernmental entities. Authorizes the Administrator to establish joint ocean and coastal mapping centers (including a joint hydrographic center) of excellence in institutions of higher education to conduct specified activities, including: (1) research and development of innovative ocean and coastal mapping technologies, equipment, and data products; and (2) mapping of the U.S. outer continental shelf. Requires the Administrator to continue developing a strategy for expanding contracting with nongovernmental entities. (Sec. 5) Requires a biannual report from the Committee to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives on progress made in implementing this Act. (Sec. 6) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
