<bill session="113" type="s" number="927" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Outreach Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a demonstration project to assess the feasibility and advisability of using State and local government agencies and nonprofit organizations to increase awareness of benefits and services for veterans and to improve coordination of outreach activities relating to such benefits and services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3528"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2013--Introduced.
Veterans' Outreach Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out a two-year demonstration project to assess the feasibility and advisability of using state and local government agencies and nonprofit organizations to increase veteran awareness of available benefits and services, and to improve the coordination of outreach activities between the Secretary and federal, state, and local government and nonprofit providers of health care and benefit services for veterans. Allows the Secretary to extend such program for an additional two years. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with various state departments and agencies concerning the provision of veterans' activities. Requires the Secretary to include, in annual VA budget justification materials, a separate statement of amounts requested for outreach activities of the VA in aggregate as well as for each of the Office of the Secretary, the Veterans Health Administration, the Veterans Benefits Administration, and the National Cemetery Administration. Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) an advisory committee on VA outreach activities; and (2) for each VA medical center, an advisory board relating to outreach activities at such center. Changes from biennial to annual a required report to Congress on VA outreach activities. Requires the inclusion in each report of recommendations: (1) to maximize resources for VA outreach activities, and (2) to focus such efforts on activities proven to be more effective.</summary>
</bill>
