<bill session="109" type="s" number="3878" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide compensation for United States citizens taken hostage by terrorists or State sponsors of terrorism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300004"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="6305"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alien property"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hostages"/>
    <term name="International claims"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iran Hostage Crisis"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2006--Introduced.
Authorizes the President to compensate a U.S. national, or his or her estate, who: (1) has a claim pending in U.S. court against a foreign state seeking compensation for injuries caused by an act of hostage-taking, or has obtained a judgment on such a claim that has not been fully satisfied; (2) on or after August 2, 1990, and while not serving on active duty in the U.S. Armed Forces, was taken hostage by a terrorist party; or (3) was a representative plaintiff or class member in Case Number 1:00CV03110(EGS) in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia. Bars a person who has accepted compensation under this Act from commencing or maintaining a U.S. civil action seeking compensation for such injuries or damages associated with such hostage taking against a foreign state or its agencies or instrumentalities. Funds compensation under this Act from the Hostage Victims Fund, into which the President shall direct deposits from: (1) blocked assets of terrorist parties; (2) amounts received against any person in connection with the U.N. Oil for Food Program; or (3) amounts received as a result of any fine or forfeiture in connection with a violation of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, the Trading With the Enemy Act, the USA PATRIOT Act of 2001, the Bank Secrecy Act, or the Export Administration Act. Provides additional compensation for victims of the 1979 Iranian hostage taking in Tehran, including spouses and children of persons taken captive.</summary>
</bill>
