<bill session="112" type="s" number="690" updated="2013-07-20T02:22:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeowner Advocate Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Office of the Homeowner Advocate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2011--Introduced.
Office of the Homeowner Advocate Act of 2011 - Establishes in the Department of the Treasury the Office of the Homeowner Advocate to assist homeowners, housing counselors, and housing lawyers in resolving problems with the Home Affordable Modification Program (HAMP) of the Making Home Affordable initiative of the Secretary of the Treasury, authorized under the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008. Prohibits any modification of a mortgage under the Making Home Affordable Program, or with any funds from the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP), unless the servicer of the mortgage loan has determined, in accordance with standards and requirements established by the Secretary, that the mortgagor cannot afford to make payments under the terms of the existing mortgage loan. (Thus prohibits participation in such Program for borrowers who strategically default.) Requires the Secretary to revise the guidelines for HAMP to establish that the data collected by the Secretary from each mortgage servicer and lender participating in the Program is made public at the individual record level in a specified manner.</summary>
</bill>
