<bill session="112" type="h" number="3597" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Shawn Johnson Fitness for Life Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Education to make grants to 10 institutions of higher education for the expansion of master's degree in physical education programs that emphasize technology and innovative teaching practices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2011-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/7/2011--Introduced.
Shawn Johnson Fitness for Life Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make competitive, renewable four-year grants to ten institutions of higher education (IHEs) for the expansion of their master's degree in physical education programs. Requires IHEs to use the grant funds to: (1) teach students to incorporate technology and innovative teaching practices into physical education instruction and encourage children to be more physically active outside the classroom, (2) develop program curricula that link practice and theory, (3) partner with local educational agencies (LEAs) that serve schools where their students are to serve as full-time student teachers and most of their instruction is to occur, (4) extend their programs into the communities served by their partner LEAs, (5) actively promote their programs to prospective students, and (6) engage in such other activities the Secretary requires. Directs the Secretary, in developing the grant program, to consult with an IHE that for the past five years has: (1) offered a master's degree in physical education program that emphasizes the incorporation of technology into physical education instruction, and (2) partnered with an LEA that serves schools in which its master's degree candidates serve as student teachers.</summary>
</bill>
