<bill session="110" type="h" number="1832" updated="2013-07-19T21:19:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Hurricane Research Initiative Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the National Hurricane Research Initiative to improve hurricane preparedness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2007-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="2007-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412196" joined="2007-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2007-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400212" joined="2007-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2007-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Science Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Research and Science Education" name="House Science and Technology"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2407"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="931"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Meteorological research"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban planning"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2007--Introduced.
National Hurricane Research Initiative Act of 2007 - Requires the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere of the Department of Commerce and the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to establish a National Hurricane Research Initiative and to cooperate with other specified federal agencies to carry it out. Requires such Initiative to set research objectives (based on a National Science Board report on the need for such Initiative) to: (1) make recommendations to the Board; (2) assemble the expertise of U.S. science and engineering capabilities through a multi-agency effort focused on infrastructure, the natural environment, and improving understanding of hurricane prediction, intensity, and mitigation on coastal populations; and (3) make grants for hurricane research, including regarding hurricane dynamics, modification, and observation, air-sea interaction, relationships between hurricanes and climate, predicting flooding and storm surge, coastal infrastructure, building construction, emergency communication networks, information utilization by public officials, and sharing computational capability.Directs the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy, through the National Science and Technology Council, to coordinate U.S. activities related to the Initiative as a formal program with a well-defined organizational structure and execution plan. Directs the Under Secretary and the Director to: (1) establish a National Infrastructure Database to catalog infrastructure, provide information to improve information public policy related to hurricanes, and provide data to improve researchers' abilities to measure hurricane impacts in order to improve building codes and urban planning; and (2) develop a National Hurricane Research Model to conduct integrative research and facilitate the transfer of research knowledge to operational applications.</summary>
</bill>
