<bill session="112" type="s" number="325" updated="2013-07-20T02:19:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Embedded Mental Health Providers for Reserves Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to require the provision of behavioral health services to members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces necessary to meet pre-deployment and post-deployment readiness and fitness standards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2011-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="948"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2011--Introduced.
Embedded Mental Health Providers for Reserves Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned to provide to each reserve member performing inactive-duty training during scheduled unit training assemblies access to mental health assessments with a licensed mental health professional, who shall be available for referrals during duty hours at the principal duty location of the member's unit. Requires all mental health services provided to be subject to and comply with applicable federal privacy and security rules. Requires each reserve member participating in annual training or individual duty training to have access, during such participation, to specified behavioral health support programs, including: (1) suicide prevention and post-suicide response, and (2) psychological health programs.</summary>
</bill>
