<bill session="110" type="s" number="304" updated="2013-07-19T22:22:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAFE Commission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securing America's Future Economy Commission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a commission to develop legislation designed to reform tax policy and entitlement benefit programs and to ensure a sound fiscal future for the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S599-600"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="473"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Balance of payments"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget resolutions"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Entitlements"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal budget process"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fiscal policy"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Gross national product"/>
    <term name="House Budget"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Senate Budget"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/2007--Introduced.
Securing America's Future Economy Commission Act, or SAFE Commission Act - Establishes the Securing America's Future Economy (SAFE) Commission to develop legislation designed to address: (1) the unsustainable imbalance between long-term federal spending commitments and projected revenues; (2) increases in net national savings to provide for domestic investment and economic growth; (3) the implications of foreign ownership of federally issued debt instruments; and (4) revision of the budget process to place greater emphasis on long-term fiscal issues. Requires the Commission to: (1) develop one or two methods for estimating the cost of legislation as an alternative to the current Congressional Budget Office (CBO) method; and (2) hold at least one town-hall style public hearing within each federal reserve district. Requires the Commission to submit a legislative proposal to Congress and the President. Authorizes the President to submit to Congress an alternative proposal. Authorizes the Committee on the Budget of either chamber to publish its own alternative proposal in the Congressional Record. Sets forth procedures for consideration of such legislation. Requires CBO to prepare a long-term cost estimate and have it published in the Congressional Record as expeditiously as possible whenever requested to do so by the Commission, the President, or the chairman or ranking minority member of the Committee on the Budget of either chamber.</summary>
</bill>
