<bill session="113" type="h" number="2538" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Access and Inclusion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to clarify Federal law with respect to reporting positive consumer credit information to consumer reporting agencies by public utility or telecommunications companies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400646"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412488" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412462" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2013-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Credit Access and Inclusion Act - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act, with respect to the responsibilities of furnishers of information to consumer reporting agencies, to declare that nothing in the Act or related regulations shall be construed as to prohibit a person from furnishing to a consumer reporting agency certain consumer identifying information, including: (1) a consumer's full name, telephone number, mother's maiden name, address, zip code, date of birth, any generational designation, or Social Security number; (2) information solely as to transactions or experiences between the consumer and the person furnishing the information; (3) public record information; and (4) information about the performance of a consumer making payments under a real property lease or pursuant to a utility or telecommunications service contract. Defines "utility or telecommunication service" as an entity that provides utility services to the public through pipe, wire, landline, wireless, cable, or other connected facilities, or radio, electronic, or similar transmission, including the extension of such facilities.</summary>
</bill>
