<bill session="109" type="s" number="2285" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Whistleblower Empowerment, Security, and Taxpayer Protection Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the protection of witnesses, victims, and informants.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-28">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce,  and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional witnesses"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Removal of officials"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="Special prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2006--Introduced.
Whistleblower Empowerment, Security, and Taxpayer Protection Act of 2006 - Modifies federal criminal law provisions relating to tampering with or retaliating against a witness, victim, or an informant. Allows a victim of a prohibited personnel practice to bring a civil action against a covered entity and to recover damages. Makes any prospective waiver of the right of any individual to file a civil action under this Act void and unenforceable. Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to allow an Inspector General (IG) to be removed from office prior to the expiration of that IG's term only on one of the following grounds: (1) permanent incapacity; (2) inefficiency; (3) neglect of duty; (4) malfeasance; or (5) conviction of a felony or conduct involving moral turpitude. Establishes the term of office of an IG as seven years and permits reappointment. Authorizes an IG to annually transmit an appropriation estimate and request to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and to the appropriate congressional committees, in addition to the head of the establishment concerned. Requires the President to include in each annual budget specified IG appropriation information. Prohibits any funds appropriated for activities under the supervision of an IG from being reprogrammed, transferred, or otherwise spent for any other purpose without such IG's written consent. Directs each IG to: (1) create and maintain a hotline for employees confidentially reporting alleged violations; and (2) compile a statistical summary of all allegations for annual reporting to Congress. Sets forth a special rule regarding revocation of security clearances. Permits the creation of whistleblower affairs directorates within offices of IGs. Includes coverage of certain planned disclosures of information under prohibited personnel practices provisions. Permits petitions for the appointment of special prosecutor to handle cases alleging prohibited personnel practices. Directs the Comptroller General to study the costs of retaliation against or suppression of whistleblowers.</summary>
</bill>
