<bill session="110" type="sr" number="99" updated="2013-07-19T22:13:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that United States military assistance to Pakistan should be guided by demonstrable progress by the Government of Pakistan in achieving certain objectives related to counterterrorism and democratic reforms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2824" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/2007--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that it is U.S. policy to: (1) maintain and deepen its long-term strategic partnership with Pakistan; (2) work with the government of Pakistan to combat international terrorism and to end the use of Pakistani territory as a safe haven for Al Qaeda, the Taliban, and associated terrorist organizations; (3) work with the government of Pakistan to dismantle existing proliferation networks and prevent nuclear proliferation; (4) facilitate the peaceful resolution of all bilateral disputes between Pakistan and its neighboring countries; (5) encourage Pakistan's transition to a fully democratic system of governance; and (6) implement an aid strategy that supports programs in Pakistan related to education, governance, rule of law, women's rights, medical access, and infrastructure development. Expresses the sense of the Senate that the determination of appropriate levels of U. S. military assistance to Pakistan should be guided by progress by the government of Pakistan in: (1) preventing Al Qaeda and associated terrorist organizations from operating in Pakistan; (2) preventing the Taliban from using Pakistan as a sanctuary to launch attacks within Afghanistan; and (3) implementing democratic reforms.</summary>
</bill>
