<bill session="112" type="hr" number="549" updated="2013-07-20T01:07:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Calling for democratic change in Syria.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-11-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2012-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2012-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and South Asia .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA13" subcommittee="Middle East and South Asia" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="sr" number="370"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2012--Introduced.
Condemns the ongoing and systematic human rights violations conducted by Syrian authorities. Maintains that Bashar al-Assad has lost all claims to legitimacy and calls upon him to step down from power. Condemns the governments of the Russian Federation and the Islamic Republic of Iran for providing military and security equipment to the government of Syria which has been used to repress peaceful demonstrations. Commends the League of Arab States' efforts to bring about a peaceful resolution in Syria and regrets that the League's observer mission was unable to monitor the full implementation of the League's Action Plan. Commends President Obama for authorizing targeted sanctions on human rights abusers in Syria. Urges President Obama to: (1) support a transition to democracy in Syria; (2) develop a plan to identify weapons stockpiles and prevent their proliferation in Syria; and (3) engage with Turkey, League members, and the European Union (EU) to protect the Syrian people. Urges the Department of State to: (1) establish a Friends of the Syrian People Contact Group of countries committed to democratic change in Syria, and (2) develop a strategy to encourage defections from the Syrian military. Urges the international community to support a post-Assad democratic and inclusive government of Syria that holds accountable those responsible for crimes against humanity and violations of human rights.</summary>
</bill>
