<bill session="111" type="h" number="5160" updated="2013-07-19T23:58:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-24">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Haiti Economic Lift Program Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Haiti Economic Lift Program Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Haiti Economic Lift Program Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Haiti Economic Lift Program Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act, to provide customs support services to Haiti, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400021" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400092" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400633" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2010-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T10:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Levin moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T10:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3132-3140" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T10:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5160.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-05-05T11:08:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3132-3136" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T11:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-05-06" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3384" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2010-05-06">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2010-05-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-05-13">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-05-24" type="public" number="111-171">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-171.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3275"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Dominican Republic"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2010--Public Law.
Haiti Economic Lift Program Act of 2010 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act (CBERA) (as amended by the United States-Caribbean Basin Trade Partnership Act, the Haitian Hemispheric Opportunity through Partnership Encouragement Act of 2006 [HOPE Act], and the Haitian Hemispheric Opportunity through Partnership Encouragement Act of 2008 [HOPE II]) to extend, in each succeeding one-year period through FY2020 (transition period), the duty-free treatment of certain imported knit apparel articles made in one or more Caribbean Basin Trade Partnership Act (CBTPA) beneficiary countries from yarns wholly formed in the United States. Extends, in each applicable one-year period through FY2020, the duty-free treatment of imported apparel articles made in Haiti or the Dominican Republic. (Sec. 4) Prescribes duty-free treatment also, without regard to the source of the fabric, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns from which the article is made, for specified apparel articles or made-up textile articles: (1) wholly assembled, or knit-to-shape, in Haiti from any combination of fabrics, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns; and (2) imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic. (Sec. 5) Sets forth a special rule for certain woven articles and certain knit articles entered during FY2010 and succeeding one-year periods. Requires the Commissioner responsible for U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to verify that such apparel articles imported into the United States are not being unlawfully transshipped into the United States. (Sec. 6) Revises requirements for one particular credit under the earned import allowance certificate program to reduce from three to two the number of square meter equivalents of qualifying woven fabric or qualifying knit fabric that the producer or entity controlling production can demonstrate that it purchased for the manufacture in Haiti of articles like or similar to any article eligible for preferential treatment. (Sec. 7) Extends the value-added rule for apparel articles and the special rule for certain wire harness automotive components. (Sec. 9) Directs the Commissioner to seek to send a rapid response team, as well as a support team, to Haiti to: (1) assess the short-term and long-term technical, capacity-building, and training needs of the authorities of the government of Haiti responsible for customs services; and (2) provide immediate assistance, particularly with respect to reestablishing full capacity for commercial port operations at the seaport at Port-au-Prince, facilitating trade between the United States and Haiti under CBERA, preventing unlawful transshipment of goods through Haiti to the United States, and otherwise strengthening cooperation between U.S., Haitian, and Dominican customs authorities. Requires the Commissioner to report to Congress on the results of such assessment. Authorizes appropriations to the CBP: (1) to help meet the immediate infrastructure needs of the authorities of the government of Haiti responsible for customs services to facilitate trade between the United States and Haiti; and (2) for FY2011-FY2020 to maintain the support team. (Sec. 10) Declares the sense of Congress regarding regional cooperation and transshipment. (Sec. 11) Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to extend the authority for certain customs fees for the processing of merchandise entered into the United States: (1) from May 14, 2018, through November 10, 2018; and (2) from June 7, 2018, through August 17, 2018. (Sec. 12) Amends the Corporate Estimated Tax Shift Act of 2009 to increase required estimated tax payments of corporations with at least $1 billion in assets in the third quarter of 2014 by 0.75% to 101.00% of such amount. Amends the Hiring Incentives to Restore Employment Act to increase required estimated tax payments of corporations with at least $1 billion in assets in the third quarter of 2015 by 0.75% to 121.80% of such amount. (Sec. 13) Declares that the budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled "Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation" for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted before the vote on passage.</summary>
</bill>
