<bill session="109" type="s" number="809" updated="2013-07-19T20:20:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Access to Legal Pharmaceuticals Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish certain duties for pharmacies when pharmacists employed by the pharmacies refuse to fill valid prescriptions for drugs or devices on the basis of personal beliefs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2006-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2005-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2006-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3685"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3685-3686" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1539"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1652"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2005--Introduced.
Access to Legal Pharmaceuticals Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require any pharmacy receiving prescription drugs or prescription devices in interstate commerce to: (1) ensure that any in stock prescription that one pharmacist refuses to fill on the basis of a personal belief is filled by another pharmacist employed by the pharmacy without delay; (2) ensure that any individual who presents a prescription for an item that is not in stock which one pharmacist refuses to order on the basis of a personal belief is immediately informed that the product can be ordered by the pharmacy and to order such product without delay; and (3) not employ any pharmacist who engages in any conduct with the intent to prevent or deter an individual from filling a valid prescription, including refusing to return a prescription form, refusing to transfer a prescription, or subjecting the individual to humiliation or harassment. Provides that this Act does not require the pharmacy to keep any particular product in stock nor does it apply with respect to a product for a health condition if the pharmacy does not keep in stock any product for such condition. Sets forth civil penalties. Allows a private cause of action for a violation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
