<bill session="111" type="s" number="809" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Assistance for Workforce Recovery Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a program to provide tuition assistance to individuals who have lost their jobs as a result of the economic downturn.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2009-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2009-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
Assistance for Workforce Recovery Program Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1988 to require the Secretary of Labor to establish the Unemployment Tuition Assistance Program making tuition assistance available to individuals who became or become unemployed on or after December 1, 2007, due to the recession for their pursuit of education and job training at participating community colleges. Directs the Secretary to provide tuition assistance payments directly to participating community colleges. Permits the Secretary to provide additional assistance to community colleges in high need and underserved areas. Requires state unemployment compensation program applicants to be informed of their possible eligibility for participation in the Unemployment Tuition Assistance Program. Directs the Secretary to maintain a public Internet website containing Program information, including a list of participating community colleges. Terminates the Program at the close of 2011.</summary>
</bill>
