<bill session="110" type="h" number="6571" updated="2013-07-19T22:01:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Air for Federal Workers Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit smoking near executive, legislative, and judicial branch buildings and entryways.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2008-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on House Administration, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Capitol (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional office buildings"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2008--Introduced.
Healthy Air for Federal Workers Act - Prohibits the smoking of tobacco products in any area outside of any federal executive, legislative, or judicial building which is within 25 feet of any of the building's entrances, exits, windows that open, or ventilation intakes that serve an enclosed area of the building where smoking is prohibited. Excludes the smoking of tobacco products which occurs solely for purposes of research on smoking conducted by an agency. Requires the Administrator of General Services, in conjunction with agency heads, regarding executive branch buildings, and the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, regarding judicial branch buildings, to inform all employees and visitors to such buildings about the smoke-free policy, educate employees about the dangers of exposure to secondhand smoke, and undertake necessary related activities.</summary>
</bill>
