<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1209" updated="2013-07-19T23:06:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing disapproval of the House of Representatives with respect to the Department of Energy's motion with the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to withdraw the license application for a high-level nuclear waste repository at Yucca Mountain with prejudice.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400016" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2010-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2010-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2010-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/2010--Introduced.
Declares that the House of Representatives strongly believes that the decision to abandon the 23-year bipartisan project establishing Yucca Mountain as the nation's primary permanent nuclear waste storage site: (1) breaks a commitment made to certain states nearly three decades ago; and (2) goes against the will and intent of Congress by extending the length of time states will be forced to store nuclear waste at significant additional cost to the taxpayers. Calls upon the Administration to comply with the bipartisan commitment passed by Congress, and to cease and desist: (1) withdrawing the Yucca Mountain license application from the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) with or without prejudice; and (2) any action to move forward with terminating activities required to complete the Yucca Mountain license application, including the termination of employees supporting the project and termination of any leases housing employees. Calls upon the Administration to: (1) halt reprogramming of FY2010 funds appropriated by Congress for the Yucca Mountain license application; and (2) preserve all scientific and site-specific files and data related to Yucca Mountain in accordance with NRC document controls and quality assurance procedures.</summary>
</bill>
