<bill session="111" type="h" number="6481" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disability Integration and Coordination Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish the Office of Disability Integration and Coordination within the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2010-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-02">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-02">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM12" subcommittee="Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/2/2010--Introduced.
Disability Integration and Coordination Improvement Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to: (1) establish an Office of Disability Integration and Coordination; (2) use such Office to implement strategies and activities in support of the responsibilities of the Disability Coordinator, who shall serve as the Director of the Office. and (3) establish specific, measurable, achievable, and relevant performance measures for the Office, including to ensure the integration of people with disabilities into emergency, preparedness, protection, mitigation, evacuation, sheltering, transition, resiliency, and recovery plans. Directs the Administrator to contract with the National Academy of Public Administration to: (1) conduct an assessment of the efficacy of state, local, and tribal governments' and nonprofits' registries of people with disabilities to guide planning and preparedness during local, state, and national disasters or emergencies resulting from a natural disaster, an act of terrorism, or other man-made disaster; and (2) provide recommendations for establishing a federal disabilities registry.</summary>
</bill>
