<bill session="109" type="h" number="325" updated="2013-07-19T19:07:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hybrid HOV Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 23, United States Code, to establish requirements for the operation of high occupancy vehicle facilities on highways.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2005-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="444"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Bicycles"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Car pools"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limited access highways"/>
    <term name="Liquefied petroleum gas"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Methanol"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Motorcycles"/>
    <term name="Natural gas vehicles"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Toll roads"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2005--Introduced.
Hybrid HOV Access Act of 2005 - Amends the Federal Aid Highways program to require a State agency with jurisdiction over the operation of a HOV facility to establish the occupancy requirements of vehicles operating on it. Requires such agency to permit motorcycles and bicycles to use the HOV facility. Permits a State agency to restrict use of the HOV facility by motorcycles or bicycles (or both) if it certifies to the Secretary of Transportation that such use would create a safety hazard. Prescribes guidelines under which a State agency may permit use of an HOV facility by: (1) public transportation vehicles and high occupancy toll vehicles; (2) inherently low-emission vehicles and low emission and energy-efficient vehicles; and (3) advanced lean burn technology vehicles. Permits tolls on a HOV facility on the Interstate System. Requires a State agency that allows low emission and energy-efficient vehicles to use a HOV facility to certify to the Secretary that it will establish: (1) a continuous monitoring, assessment, and reporting program regarding the impacts such vehicles may have on the operation of the facility and adjacent highways; and (2) an enforcement program that ensures the facility is operated in accordance with this Act. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection to issue: (1) a final rule establishing certification requirements for low emission and energy-efficient vehicles and advanced lean burn technology vehicles; and (2) guidance on methods for determining whether a vehicle meets the fuel efficiency standards required to qualify as a hybrid vehicle.</summary>
</bill>
