<bill session="112" type="s" number="2056" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Scofield Land Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain interests in Federal land acquired for the Scofield Project in Carbon County, Utah.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2012-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-642.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2012--Introduced.
Scofield Land Transfer Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) complete a full physical and title survey of specified federal land concerning the Scofield Dam and Reservoir in Carbon County, Utah, and any other related land in and around Scofield Reservoir Basin; and (2) attempt to notify each person or entity claiming title to, or an interest in, such land (claimant) of the claimant's trespass or encroachment on federal land, including the existence of any trespassing or encroaching structures. Authorizes the Secretary, in order to resolve trespass and encroachment issues and upon a claimant's request, to convey either a fee interest or a life estate to a claimant. Subjects any conveyance to: (1) a claimant paying fair market value for the claimed land, (2) the United States retaining a flood easement over the entire portion of the federal land conveyed, and (3) specified deed restrictions. Establishes the Scofield Reservoir Fund to provide enhanced recreation opportunities at the Scofield Reservoir. Deposits into the Fund any amounts paid by claimants pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
