<bill session="110" type="h" number="2693" updated="2013-07-19T21:27:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-26T14:48:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-09-26T14:48:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Popcorn Workers Lung Disease Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Occupational Safety and Health Administration to issue a standard regulating worker exposure to diacetyl.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400436"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2007-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400384" joined="2007-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2007-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1279"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-06-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-07-18T19:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and Labor. H. Rept. 110-239.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-07-18T19:06:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="149">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 149.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-09-25T18:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 678 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2693 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26T11:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 678 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 678.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10920-10932" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2693 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 678 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Dennis A. Cardoza to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2693.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 678, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the George Miller (CA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 678, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wilson (SC) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2693.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10931" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26T14:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10928" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-09-26T14:48:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="913" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 260 - 154, 2 Present (Roll no. 913).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-09-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="400">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 400.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="678"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lung diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h812"/>
    <amendment number="h813"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/26/2007--Passed House amended.
Popcorn Workers Lung Disease Prevention Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor to promulgate: (1) within 90 days, an interim final standard regulating worker exposure to diacetyl that applies to all locations in the flavoring manufacturing industry that manufacture, use, handle, or process diacetyl and all microwave popcorn production and packaging establishments that use diacetyl-containing flavors; and (2) within two years, if diacetyl is still being processed or utilized in facilities, a final standard that contains a short term exposure limit and a permissible exposure limit not exceeding the lowest feasible level and that applies to all facilities where diacetyl is processed or used. Gives the interim standard the legal effect of an occupational safety and health standard until the final standard becomes effective.Requires such standards to provide no less protection than the recommendations contained in the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH) Alert "Preventing Lung Disease in Workers Who Use or Make Flavorings" and to include specified requirements for: (1) engineering, work practice controls, and respiratory protection to minimize exposure to diacetyl; (2) a written exposure control plan that will indicate specific measures the employer will take to minimize employee exposure; (3) airborne exposure assessments; (4) medical surveillance for workers and referral for prompt medical evaluations; (5) protective equipment and clothing for workers; and (6) the provision of written safety and health information and training to employees. Requires NIOSH to study and report to the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) on food flavorings that may be used as substitutes for diacetyl.</summary>
</bill>
