<bill session="111" type="h" number="5348" updated="2013-07-20T00:00:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Workforce Reduction Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to reduce the number of civil service positions within the executive branch, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412294"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412011" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412230" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2010-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3747"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2010--Introduced.
Federal Workforce Reduction Act of 2010 - Prohibits the head of an executive agency from appointing any individual to a position in the agency in any fiscal year for which the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) projects a federal budget deficit. Makes an exception if: (1) there is a position available in the federal workforce hiring pool (to be established by the President); and (2) the President approves an agency head's request for the allocation of a position in the pool to the agency. Sets the number of positions in the hiring pool at zero as of the first day of FY2011, after which the number shall: (1) increase by .50 for each full time-equivalent position in any agency which subsequently becomes vacant; and (2) decrease by 1.0 for each request for a full time-equivalent position that is approved by the President. Authorizes the President to waive this limitation upon determining that such waiver is required by the existence of a state of war, other national security concern, or an extraordinary emergency threatening life, health, safety, or property. Exempts the Department of Defense (DOD), the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA).</summary>
</bill>
