<bill session="110" type="h" number="7214" updated="2013-07-19T22:06:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Combat Stress Healthcare Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to use the Health Professionals Educational Assistance Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs to increase the number of licensed mental health professionals in the Department of Veterans Affairs available to assist veterans suffering from the effects of combat stress, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2008--Introduced.
Veterans Combat Stress Healthcare Improvement Act - Revises the veterans' health professionals educational assistance program to provide a selection priority under various program components for those seeking to obtain the specialized training necessary to treat combat stress. Provides a similar priority for individuals who have completed the degree requirements necessary for qualification as a licensed mental health professional, are employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) in positions related to the treatment of combat stress, and owe any principal or interest on loans used to pay costs related to earning the degree. Reauthorizes the program's scholarship program for FY2009-FY2011.</summary>
</bill>
