<bill session="109" type="h" number="3513" updated="2013-07-19T19:35:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Solutions to Limit the Abuse of Methamphetamine (SLAM) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for enhanced Federal penalties for production, distribution, trafficking, and possession of methamphetamine, listed chemicals, and other controlled substances, and for other offenses related to such production, distribution, trafficking, and possession; and to provide for enhanced residential substance abuse treatment programs for State and Federal prisoners.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400214"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="2005-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community-based corrections"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Urinalysis"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2005--Introduced.
Solutions to Limit the Abuse of Methamphetamine (SLAM) Act - Amends the Controlled Substances Act (CSA) to lower the threshold for amounts of methamphetamine the manufacture, distribution, dispensation, possession, importation, or exportation of which is subject to specified penalties. Increases: (1) the prison sentence of persons convicted under CSA or the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act for offenses involving methamphetamine or listed chemicals while in a facilitated entry program; and (2) penalties for various offenses involving listed chemicals and the manufacturing of controlled substances, including maintaining drug-involved premises. Prohibits sexual abuse, sexual exploitation, and coercive prostitution while illegally manufacturing, distributing, dispensing, possessing, or transporting a controlled substance. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to require a state, to be eligible for justice system improvement grant funds for residential substance abuse treatment for state prisoners, to implement both periodic and random substance abuse testing and to require, as a condition of participation, that such testing indicate that the individual has not used a controlled substance for at least three months prior to testing. Amends the federal criminal code to direct that substance abuse treatment include urinalysis or other proven reliable forms of testing, including both periodic and random testing before entering, and while the prisoner participates in, the program. Directs the Attorney General: (1) acting through the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration, to provide information to retailers regarding the purchase of precursor products by individuals who may intend to use them in illicit methamphetamine production; and (2) to designate such program as the MethWatch program.</summary>
</bill>
