<bill session="111" type="s" number="1028" updated="2013-07-20T00:32:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening America's Public Health System Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve the Nation's surveillance and reporting for diseases and conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5437"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5437-5439" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="805"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2009--Introduced.
Strengthening America's Public Health System Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) establish the Epidemiology and Laboratory Capacity Grant Program to assist public health agencies in improving surveillance for, and response to, infectious diseases and other conditions of public health importance; and (2) issue guidelines for public health entities relating to information systems to receive, monitor, and report infectious diseases and other such conditions. Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Director, to: (1) address documented workforce shortages in state and local health departments in applied public health epidemiology and public health laboratory science and informatics; and (2) provide for the expansion of applied epidemiology training programs.Requires the Director, upon request, to assist the Council of State and Territorial Epidemiologists in developing or improving a process for states to conduct surveillance and submit reports to the Director on nationally notifiable diseases and conditions.Requires the Secretary to adopt and use guidelines to develop improved standards and protocols for binational epidemiology, surveillance, laboratory analyses, and control of infectious diseases between the United States and Mexico.Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to establish a committee to: (1) evaluate best practices in public health surveillance; and (2) assess systems needed for improving coordination among public health surveillance and monitoring systems.</summary>
</bill>
