<bill session="113" type="h" number="752" updated="2013-11-02T06:25:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Methamphetamine Education, Treatment, and Hope Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the establishment of a drug-free workplace information clearinghouse, to support residential methamphetamine treatment programs for pregnant and parenting women, to improve the prevention and treatment of methamphetamine addiction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412519" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412515" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2013-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2013--Introduced.
Methamphetamine Education, Treatment, and Hope Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the Center for Substance Abuse Treatment to collaborate with professionals in the addiction field and primary health care providers to raise awareness about how to: (1) recognize the signs of a substance abuse disorder; and (2) apply evidence-based practices for screening and treating individuals with, or at-risk for developing, an addiction. Revises requirements governing a grant program for substance abuse residential treatment for pregnant and parenting women (currently, for postpartum women), to include treatment for addiction to methamphetamine, outpatient treatment services, and referrals for dental services. Requires the Director to give grant priority to a program serving an area that: (1) is a rural area, an area with a shortage of mental health professionals, or an area with a shortage of family-based substance abuse treatment options; and (2) has high rates of addiction to methamphetamine or other drugs. Revises requirements for biennial reports to Congress to require such reports to include: (1) data on the number of pregnant and parenting women in need of, but not receiving, treatment for substance abuse; and (2) data on recovery and relapse rates of women receiving treatment for substance abuse under the grant program. Requires the Director to expand, intensify, and coordinate efforts to provide pregnant and parenting women treatment for addiction to methamphetamine or other drugs. Requires the Director of the Office for Substance Abuse Prevention to: (1) maintain a clearinghouse that provides information and educational materials to employers and employees about comprehensive drug-free workplace programs and substance abuse prevention and treatment resources; and (2) support the involvement of youth in the development and implementation of prevention strategies focused on youth.</summary>
</bill>
