<bill session="111" type="h" number="4881" updated="2013-07-19T23:56:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Toxic Drywall Homeowner Relief Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow individuals a deduction for costs incurred to remediate the presence of drywall containing elevated levels of sulphur or strontium in the principal residence of the taxpayer, a deduction for alternative living costs incurred by reason of the need to vacate such residence because of such drywall, and a credit against income tax for the costs of moving to and from the temporary living quarters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412196" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412301" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2010-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2010--Introduced.
Toxic Drywall Homeowner Relief Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a deduction from gross income for the cost of removing and remediating drywall installed in a principal residence between 2004 and 2009 which is reasonably believed to have been manufactured in China and which contains elevated levels of sulphur or strontium. Allows an additional deduction for the taxpayer's alternative living costs, and a tax credit of up to $1,000 for the cost of moving from a principal residence to temporary lodging, while drywall in such residence is being evaluated, removed, and replaced. Terminates the tax deductions and credit allowed by this Act after 2011.</summary>
</bill>
