<bill session="112" type="h" number="5988" updated="2013-07-20T02:01:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">San Antonio Missions National Historical Park Boundary Expansion Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a cooperative agreement for a park headquarters at San Antonio Missions National Historical Park, to expand the boundary of the Park, to conduct a study of potential land acquisitions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400657"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2012-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="114"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2012--Introduced.
San Antonio Missions National Historical Park Boundary Expansion Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to study land within Bexar and Wilson Counties in Texas, to identify land that would be suitable for inclusion in the San Antonio Missions National Historical Park. Requires the study to examine the natural, cultural, recreational, and scenic values and characteristics of the land within such counties. Permits the assignment of Park employees to provide interpretive services, including visitor information and education, at facilities outside the Park boundary. Modifies the boundary of the Park to include approximately 151 acres of additional identified land. Permits the Secretary to acquire such land or any interest in such land by purchase from willing sellers, donation, or exchange.</summary>
</bill>
