<bill session="112" type="h" number="2087" updated="2013-07-20T01:28:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-20T17:24:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-03-20T17:24:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To remove restrictions from a parcel of land situated in the Atlantic District, Accomack County, Virginia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412483"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2011-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 32 - 11.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-01-18T17:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-369.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-01-18T17:10:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="250">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 250.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-03-19T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 587 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2087 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. The resolution makes in order the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill as original text for the purpose of amendment. The resolution makes in order only those amendments that are submitted for printing in the Congressional Record dated March 19, 2012, or pro forma amendments for the purpose of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 587 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 587.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1411-1420" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2087 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. The resolution makes in order the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill as original text for the purpose of amendment. The resolution makes in order only those amendments that are submitted for printing in the Congressional Record dated March 19, 2012, or pro forma amendments for the purpose of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 587 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Cory Gardner to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2087.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T16:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 587, the Committee of the Whole proceeded debate on the Grijalva amendment No. 1 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T16:10:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grijalva amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Grijalva demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 587, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hastings (FL) No. 2 amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished question was on the adoption of amendments which had previously been debated and on which further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2087.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1417" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1415" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T16:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Sanchez, Loretta moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1418" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1418" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sanchez, Loretta motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to prohibit the sale or use of land for adult entertainment or by foreign governments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1418" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T17:15:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 180 - 226 (Roll no. 116).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1418-1419" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-03-20T17:24:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="117" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 240 - 164 (Roll no. 117).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="587"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2214"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h985"/>
    <amendment number="h986"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/20/2012--Passed House amended.
Instructs the Secretary of the Interior, within 90 days of enactment of this Act, to remove all deed restrictions, including easements and covenants, described in a specified quitclaim deed from the United States to Accomack County, Virginia, relating to a parcel of land consisting of approximately 31.6 acres situated in the Atlantic District of the county.</summary>
</bill>
