<bill session="111" type="h" number="3117" updated="2013-07-19T23:40:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Georgetowne Houses Preservation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide enhanced voucher rental assistance for residents of certain federally assisted low-income housing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400249"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/2009--Introduced.
Georgetowne Houses Preservation Act of 2009 - Applies this Act to the housing developments known as Georgetowne Houses I and II (covered properties), located in Boston, Massachusetts. Requires, upon the expiration of certain use restrictions for the covered properties, the offer of enhanced voucher assistance under the United States Housing Act of 1937 to each eligible low-income or moderate income family who, as of such expiration, is residing in a dwelling unit in the covered properties which is not covered by project-based rental assistance. Grants each such family who chooses to remain in the covered properties three years from the issuance of such enhanced voucher to commence its use. Deems such use restrictions to expire on March 1, 2010, but only if the covered property owner agrees with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to maintain the project-based rental assistance for the properties at least another 20 years. Requires determination of the contract rents for dwelling units in such covered properties, until such expiration date, to be based upon the rents for comparable unassisted and unrestricted units in the area in which the covered properties are located. But restricts the rental assistance payments for such project-based units in Georgetowne Houses II, before May 1, 2012, to the rent levels provided under the Emergency Low Income Housing Preservation Act of 1987.</summary>
</bill>
