<bill session="110" type="s" number="1228" updated="2013-07-19T22:30:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campus Law Enforcement Emergency Response Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend section 485(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 regarding law enforcement emergencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5200"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5199-5200" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Bombs"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2007--Introduced.
Campus Law Enforcement Emergency Response Act of 2007 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require each institution of higher education (IHE) participating in any program under title IV (Student Assistance) to include information concerning its law enforcement emergency response program and the occurrence of campus law enforcement emergencies in the annual campus security report it must provide to current and prospective students and employees. Requires such an IHE to: (1) test annually its law enforcement emergency response program; and (2) inform those on campus of any school law enforcement emergency within 30 minutes of discovering it. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make competitive grants to IHEs or consortia of IHEs, or enter into competitive contracts with IHEs, consortia, and other organizations, to develop, implement, operate, improve, test, or disseminate campus law enforcement emergency response programs. Defines "campus" for purposes of this Act to include property controlled by recognized student organizations, off-campus school-related property, and certain public property used by and adjacent to the school.</summary>
</bill>
