<bill session="111" type="h" number="4231" updated="2013-07-19T23:50:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Cities Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to reduce the rate of occurrence of homicides and violent crimes in violent and drug crime zones.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412268"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2009--Introduced.
Safe Cities Act of 2009 - Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to: (1) authorize the Attorney General to designate a Violent and Drug Crime Zone (i.e., a metropolitan area with a higher than average rate of homicides, violent felonies, sex offenses, and drug and gang-related crimes) in each state; (2) establish a drug and violent crime intervention team and a Safe Cities Task Force in each Zone, consisting of state and local law enforcement officials, to coordinate the investigation, apprehension, and prosecution of criminal activity; (3) require the use of grant funds under such Act to increase the number of prosecutors available to work with drug and violent crime intervention teams; and (4) require the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice (DOJ) to award grants to states to establish and maintain a state-wide database to track criminals, arrests, prosecutions, and convictions.</summary>
</bill>
