<bill session="112" type="s" number="1475" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nellis Dunes National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to convey certain land to Clark County, Nevada, to designate the Nellis Dunes National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412218"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2011--Introduced.
Nellis Dunes National Off-Hughway Vehicle Recreation Area Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey specified federal land to Clark County, Nevada, for use for: (1) a centralized off-road vehicle recreation park, and (2) a designated area and facilities to discourage unauthorized use of off-highway vehicles in environmentally sensitive areas. Allows the use of federal land conveyed to Clark County for the incidental purpose of generating renewable energy and solar energy for the Clark County Off Highway Vehicle Recreation Park, a certain shooting park, and the County. Designates: (1) the Economic Support Area (ESA), and (2) the Nellis Dunes as the Nellis Dunes National Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area. Requires proceeds from the ESA to be used to develop and operate the Recreation Area and the park. Requires the Clark County Board of Commissioners, the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), and Nellis Air Force Base to enter into an interlocal agreement for the federal land and the Recreation Area to: (1) enhance safe off-highway recreation use, and (2) ensure that development of the federal land is consistent with the long-term mission requirements of Nellis Air Force Base.</summary>
</bill>
