<bill session="109" type="s" number="3758" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish certain requirements relating to the continuation of the Survey of Income and Program Participation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2006-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8380-8381"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8381" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="5941"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2006--Introduced.
Prohibits the Secretary of Commerce from: (1) discontinuing the Survey of Income and Program Participation; (2) making any change in the design or content of such Survey; or (3) allowing any of the foregoing unless the discontinuation or change involved has first been approved in accordance with this Act. Provides that whenever, in the judgment of the Secretary, it becomes necessary to discontinue the Survey of Income and Program Participation (SIPP), or to make any change in its design or content, the Secretary shall prepare a written proposal. Establishes the Commission on the Survey of Income and Program Participation (SIPP Commission) to consider and act on any proposal relating to the SIPP in accordance with this Act. Requires the SIPP Commission to consider promptly any proposal received under this Act and, after appropriate deliberation, transmit its decision of approval or disapproval to the Secretary in a timely fashion.</summary>
</bill>
