<bill session="113" type="h" number="3212" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure compliance with the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction by countries with which the United States enjoys reciprocal obligations, to establish procedures for the prompt return of children abducted to other countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2013-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2013-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412553" joined="2013-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412543" joined="2013-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2013-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2013-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2013-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2013-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2013-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412525" joined="2013-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2013--Introduced.
Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of State to submit to Congress an Annual Report on International Child Abduction. Directs the Secretary to ensure that U.S. diplomatic and consular missions: (1) maintain a consistent reporting standard with respect to abduction or access cases, (2) designate at least one official in each mission to assist U.S. parents who are visiting to resolve such cases, and (3) monitor cases involving abducted children in their country of location. Directs the Secretary to seek to enter into a memorandum of understanding (an agreement between the United States and a country that is not a Convention country to resolve abduction and rights of access cases) with every country that is not a Convention country. Defines "Convention country" as a country other than the United States that has ratified, acceded, or succeeded to the Hague Abduction Convention and with respect to which the United States has entered into a reciprocal agreement pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention. Provides that whenever the President determines that the government of a foreign country has failed to resolve an unresolved abduction or access case, or has engaged in a pattern of noncooperation, the President shall take one or more specified actions to promote resolution or cooperation. Terminates any action taken under this Act with respect to a foreign country on the earlier of the following two dates: (1) not later than two years after the effective date of such action unless expressly reauthorized by law, or (2) the date on which the President certifies to Congress that such country has resolved any unresolved abduction case or has taken substantial and verifiable steps to correct the pattern of noncooperation at issue.</summary>
</bill>
