<bill session="110" type="s" number="1441" updated="2013-07-19T22:32:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State Veterans Home Modernization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to modify authorities for the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to accept new applications for grants for State home construction projects to authorize the Secretary to award grants for construction of facilities used in non-institutional care programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6404-6405"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Soldiers' homes"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2007--Introduced.
State Veterans Home Modernization Act of 2007 - Prohibits the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from approving any application for financial assistance for a construction project at a state veterans' home that is submitted 730 days after the enactment of this Act if the Secretary determines that the construction would result in an increase in the total number of beds in such state for which the Secretary makes per diem payments for the care of veterans residing in such homes. Expands the state home grant program of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to authorize grants for noninstitutional care programs. Requires, for fiscal years after 2007, that not less than 10% of sums appropriated for VA home construction grants be used for grants to states which have submitted applications for noninstitutional care projects.</summary>
</bill>
