<bill session="112" type="s" number="2038" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-04">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STOCK Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">STOCK Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">STOCK Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">STOCK Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Public Corruption Prosecution Improvements Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">STOCK Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">An original bill to prohibit Members of Congress and employees of Congress from using nonpublic information derived from their official positions for personal benefit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-01-26">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Lieberman. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-01-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="301">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 301.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-01-26">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S120" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S120" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-26">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S120" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-30">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S142-149" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-30">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to proceed to the measure invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 93 - 2. Record Vote Number: 3.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S148-149" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S148-149" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S181" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S181" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S187-193, S194-200, S201-202" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-01">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S238-250, S250-254" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S290-315" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2012-02-02" how="roll" result="pass" roll="14" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 96 - 3. Record Vote Number: 14.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S310-315" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-02-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-06T14:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-06T16:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09T09:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09T09:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H645-657" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09T09:13:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2038.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE" datetime="2012-02-09T10:34:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="47" type="vote2" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 417 - 2 (Roll no. 47).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H645-648" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09T10:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1839-1840" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20">
      <text>Motion by Senator Reid to concur in the House amendment to the bill (S. 2038) made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1839" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to concur in the House amendment to the bill (S. 2038) presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1839" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1839" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20">
      <text>Motion by Senator Reid to concur in the House amendment to the bill (S. 2038) with an amendment (SA 1940) made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1839" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20">
      <text>Motion by Senator Reid to refer to Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs the House message on S. 2038 with instructions to report back forthwith with amendment (SA 1942) made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1839" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-22">
      <text>Considered by Senate (Message from the House considered).</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1977-1981" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-22">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to concur in the House amendment to the bill (S. 2038) invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 96 - 3. Record Vote Number: 56.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1980-1981" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1980" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-22">
      <text>Motion by Senator Reid to refer to Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs the House message on S. 2038 with instructions to report back forthwith with amendment (SA 1942) fell when cloture invoked on the motion to concur in the House amendment to the bill (S. 2038) in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1981" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-22">
      <text>Motion by Senator Reid to concur in the House amendment to the bill (S. 2038) with an amendment (SA 1940) withdrawn in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1981" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2012-03-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to House amendment to the bill (S. 2038) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2012-03-28">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2012-04-04">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2012-04-04" type="public" number="112-105">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-105.</text>
    </enacted>
    <action datetime="2012-12-03">
      <text>By Senator Lieberman from Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs filed written report. Report No. 112-244.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1148"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4054"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Office of Government Ethics"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1470"/>
    <amendment number="s1471"/>
    <amendment number="s1472"/>
    <amendment number="s1473"/>
    <amendment number="s1474"/>
    <amendment number="s1475"/>
    <amendment number="s1476"/>
    <amendment number="s1477"/>
    <amendment number="s1478"/>
    <amendment number="s1479"/>
    <amendment number="s1480"/>
    <amendment number="s1481"/>
    <amendment number="s1482"/>
    <amendment number="s1483"/>
    <amendment number="s1484"/>
    <amendment number="s1485"/>
    <amendment number="s1486"/>
    <amendment number="s1487"/>
    <amendment number="s1488"/>
    <amendment number="s1489"/>
    <amendment number="s1490"/>
    <amendment number="s1491"/>
    <amendment number="s1492"/>
    <amendment number="s1493"/>
    <amendment number="s1494"/>
    <amendment number="s1496"/>
    <amendment number="s1497"/>
    <amendment number="s1498"/>
    <amendment number="s1499"/>
    <amendment number="s1500"/>
    <amendment number="s1501"/>
    <amendment number="s1502"/>
    <amendment number="s1503"/>
    <amendment number="s1504"/>
    <amendment number="s1505"/>
    <amendment number="s1506"/>
    <amendment number="s1507"/>
    <amendment number="s1508"/>
    <amendment number="s1509"/>
    <amendment number="s1510"/>
    <amendment number="s1511"/>
    <amendment number="s1940"/>
    <amendment number="s1941"/>
    <amendment number="s1942"/>
    <amendment number="s1943"/>
    <amendment number="s1944"/>
    <amendment number="s1945"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/4/2012--Public Law.
Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act of 2012 or STOCK Act - (Sec. 3) Requires the congressional ethics committees to issue interpretive guidance of the rules of each chamber, including rules on conflicts of interest and gifts, with respect to the prohibition against the use by Members of Congress and congressional employees (including legislative branch officers and employees), as a means for making a private profit, of any nonpublic information derived from their positions as Members or congressional employees, or gained from performance of the individual's official responsibilities. (Sec. 4) Declares that such Members and employees are not exempt from the insider trading prohibitions arising under the securities laws, including the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and Rule 10b-5. Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to declare that such Members and employees owe a duty arising from a relationship of trust and confidence to Congress, the U.S. government, and U.S. citizens with respect to material, nonpublic information derived from their positions as Members or congressional employees or gained from performance of the individual's official responsibilities. (Sec. 5) Amends the Commodity Exchange Act to apply to Members and congressional employees, or to judicial officers or employees its prohibitions against certain transactions, involving the purchase or sale of any commodity in interstate commerce, or for future delivery, or any swap. (Sec. 6) Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (EGA) to require specified individuals to file reports within 30 to 45 days after receiving notice of a purchase, sale, or exchange which exceeds $1,000 in stocks, bonds, commodities futures, and other forms of securities and subject to any waivers and exclusions. Lists such individuals as: (1) the President; (2) the Vice President; (3) executive officers or employees, including certain special government employees and members of a uniformed service; (4) appointed administrative law judges; (5) executive branch employees in positions excepted from the competitive service because of their confidential or policymaking character (except those excluded from such exception by the Director of the Office of Government Ethics [OGE]); (6) the Postmaster General, the Deputy Postmaster General, each Governor of the Board of Governors of the U.S. Postal Service, and certain U.S. Postal Service officers or employees; (7) the OGE Director and each designated agency ethics official; (8) civilian employees of the Executive Office of the President (other than a special government employee) appointed by the President; (9) Members of Congress; and (10) congressional officers and employees. (Sec.7) Directs the Comptroller General to report to specified congressional committees on the role of political intelligence in the financial markets. (Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate, and the Clerk of the House of Representatives, by August 31, 2012, or 90 days after the enactment of this Act, to ensure that financial disclosure forms filed by Members, candidates for Congress, and congressional officers and employees, in calendar year 2012 and in subsequent years be made available to the public on the respective official Senate and House websites within 30 days after filing. Terminates such requirement upon implementation of the following public disclosure systems. Directs the Secretary, the Sergeant at Arms, and the Clerk to develop systems to enable the electronic filing of such reports as well as their on-line public availability. Amends EGA to revise the retention period for mandatory public availability of financial disclosure reports. Requires retention and public availability of the financial disclosure reports of a Member of Congress until six years after the date the individual ceases to be a Member (currently, six years after receipt of the report). (Sec. 9) Requires the OGE to issue interpretive guidance of the relevant federal ethics statutes and regulations, including the Standards of Ethical Conduct for executive branch employees, to specify that no such individual may use non-public information derived from his or her position or gained from the performance of official responsibilities as a means for making a private profit. Requires the U.S. Judicial Conference to issue interpretive guidance of similar ethics rules, including the Code of Conduct for U.S. Judges, applicable to: (1) federal judges, and (2) judicial employees. Declares that executive branch employees, judicial officers, and judicial employees are not exempt from the insider trading prohibitions arising under the securities laws, including the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and Rule 10b-5. Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to declare that such individuals owe a duty arising from a relationship of trust and confidence to the federal government and U.S. citizens with respect to material, nonpublic information derived from their positions as executive branch employees, judicial officers, or judicial employees gained from performance of the individual's official responsibilities. (Sec. 11) Directs the President to ensure that financial disclosure forms filed in calendar year 2012 and in subsequent years by executive branch employees are publicly available on appropriate official websites of executive branch agencies within 30 days after such forms are filed. Requires the OGE Director to develop systems to enable electronic filing and public access to these financial disclosure forms. (Sec. 12) Amends the Securities and Exchange Act of 1934 to prohibit individuals required to file financial disclosure reports under EGA from purchasing securities that are the subject of an initial public offering in any manner other than is available to members of the public generally. (Sec. 13) Amends EGA to require the financial disclosure report of the following individuals to include any secured mortgage which is their personal residence or that of his or her spouse: (1) the President, the Vice President, Members of Congress; and (2) certain individuals nominated for appointments as executive branch officers or employees (except those nominated to positions as Foreign Service Officers or a grade or rank in the uniformed services with a pay grade of 0-6 or below). (Sec. 14) Declares that the transaction reporting requirements established by this Act shall not be construed to apply to a widely held investment fund (whether a mutual fund, regulated investment company, pension or deferred compensation plan, or other investment fund): (1) if the fund is publicly traded or its assets are widely diversified, and (2) the reporting individual neither exercises control over nor has the ability to exercise control over the financial interests held by the fund. (Sec. 15) Denies Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) or Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS) retirement benefits (other than a lump-sum reimbursement of personal contributions) to the President, the Vice President, or an elected official of a state or local government, if convicted of certain felonies. (Sec. 16) Prohibits senior executives at the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) (government-sponsored enterprises [GSEs]) from receiving bonuses during any period of conservatorship on or after the enactment of this Act. (Sec. 17) Prohibits an individual required to file a financial disclosure report under EGA from directly negotiating or having any agreement of future employment or compensation without filing a signed disclosure statement, within three business days after commencement of the negotiation or agreement, with the individual's supervising ethics office. Requires such an individual to recuse himself or herself whenever there is or there appears to be a conflict of interest with respect to the subject matter of the statement. Requires the individual, upon such a recusal, to notify the supervising ethics office and submit the relevant disclosure statement. (Sec. 18) Amends the federal criminal code to subject to a fine or imprisonment of up to 15 years, or both, as well as possible disqualification from holding federal office, certain covered government persons, in addition to Member of Congress and congressional employees, who with the intent to influence, on the basis of partisan political affiliation, an employment decision or employment practice of any private entity: (1) takes or withholds, or offers or threatens to take or withhold, an official act; or (2) influences, or offers or threatens to influence, the official act of another. Extends the meaning of "covered government person" (currently restricted to Members of Congress and congressional employees) to include the President, Vice President, an employee of the U.S. Postal Service or the Postal Regulatory Commission, or any other executive branch employee. (Sec. 19) Makes conforming amendments to EGA and the Honest Leadership and Open Government Act of 2007. Requires retention and public availability of the financial disclosure reports of Members of the House until six years after the date an individual ceases to be a Member of Congress (currently, six years after receipt of the report).</summary>
</bill>
