<bill session="110" type="s" number="2750" updated="2013-07-19T22:45:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Abandoned Mine Reclamation Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to modify the requirements applicable to locatable minerals on public domain lands, consistent with the principles of self-initiation of mining claims, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2001-2002"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2002-2006" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2262"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mine wastes"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Tunnels"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2008--Introduced.
Abandoned Mine Reclamation Act of 2008 - Applies this Act to any mining claim, millsite claim, or tunnel site claim: (1) located under the general mining laws; or (2) used for beneficiation or mineral processing activities, regardless of whether legal and beneficial title to the mineral is held by the United States. Subjects production of locatable minerals from any mining claim, including mineral concentrates or products derived from such minerals, to a royalty of 8% of the gross income from mining. Imposes a 4% royalty upon federal lands subject to an existing operations permit and producing valuable locatable minerals in commercial quantities. Establishes a civil penalty for failure to comply with royalty requirements, including underreporting. Requires a hardrock mining claim maintenance fee and a location fee for each unpatented mining claim, mill, or tunnel site on federally owned lands, whether located before, on, or after enactment of this Act. Establishes a fee for transfer of ownership of an unpatented mining claim, mill, or tunnel site. Requires each operator of a hardrock minerals mining operation to pay a reclamation fee of 0.3 % of the gross income of the hardrock minerals mining operation for each calendar year. Establishes the Abandoned Mine Cleanup Fund for reclamation and restoration of land and water resources adversely affected by past mineral activities on certain federal lands. Requires deposit in the Fund of all royalties, fees, and civil penalties.</summary>
</bill>
