<bill session="112" type="s" number="1691" updated="2013-07-20T02:31:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Firearms Interstate Commerce Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to update certain procedures applicable to commerce in firearms and remove certain Federal restrictions on interstate firearms transactions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2011-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-11-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="58"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/2011--Introduced.
Firearms Interstate Commerce Reform Act - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) allow licensed firearms importers, manufacturers, dealers, or collectors (licensees) to sell or deliver any firearm (currently, rifles or shotguns) to a resident of a state other than the state in which the licensee is located or temporarily located if the licensee meets with the purchaser to complete the sale or delivery and the transaction complies with the laws of the state in which the transfer is conducted and the purchaser's state of residence; and (2) eliminate the requirement that a licensee must conduct business at a gun show only in the state that is specified on the licensee's license. Provides that nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit the sale or other disposition of a firearm or ammunition: (1) between licensed firearms dealers at any location in any state; or (2) by a licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer to an unlicensed person at a temporary location in any state. Amends definitions for federal firearms provisions to: (1) revise the definition of a "member of the Armed Forces on active duty" to include a resident of the state in which the member maintains legal residence or in which the member maintains a place of abode from which he or she commutes each day to the permanent duty station, and (2) provide that an officer or employee of the United States (other than a member of the Armed Forces) stationed outside the United States for a period exceeding one year is a resident of the state in which the member maintains legal residence.</summary>
</bill>
