<bill session="111" type="s" number="3005" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Institute of Finance Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to create an independent research institute, to be known as the "National Institute of Finance", that will oversee the collection and standardization of data on financial entities and activities, and conduct monitoring and other research and analytical activities to support the work of the Federal financial regulatory agencies and the Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-02-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S496"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S497-500" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2010--Introduced.
National Institute of Finance Act of 2010 - Establishes an independent National Institute of Finance (NIF) to support the federal financial regulatory agencies, including any systemic risk council or agency established by Congress, by: (1) collecting and providing data; (2) standardizing the types and formats of data reported and collected; (3) performing applied research and essential long-term research; (4) developing tools for risk measurement and monitoring; and (5) making the results of its activities available to financial regulatory agencies. Requires the NIF Director to be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and the NIF to be funded through assessments on the financial entities required to report data to it. States that the Institute shall implement its programmatic responsibilities through: (1) the Federal Financial Data Center; and (2) the Federal Financial Research and Analysis Center.</summary>
</bill>
