<bill session="112" type="h" number="2940" updated="2013-07-20T01:35:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-03T18:54:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-11-03T18:54:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Access to Capital for Job Creators Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Access to Capital for Job Creators Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Access to Capital for Job Creators Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Securities and Exchange Commission to eliminate the prohibition against general solicitation as a requirement for a certain exemption under Regulation D.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412420" joined="2011-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412452" joined="2011-10-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-21">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises Prior to Referral.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-10-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-31T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 112-263.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-10-31T13:18:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="176">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 176.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-11-02T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 453 Reported to House. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The resolution provides that the amendments in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in each of the bills are considered adopted. The bills, as amended, are considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 453 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 453.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7289-7295" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The resolution provides that the amendments in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in each of the bills are considered adopted. The bills, as amended, are considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 2940.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T15:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 453, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Miller (NC) Part B amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Miller (NC) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Miller (NC) demanded a recored vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment under clause 8(a)(1)(A) of rule XX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7311-7314" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T18:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. DeFazio moved to recommit with instructions to Financial Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7312" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7312" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeFazio motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to prohibit those who have been convicted of fraud in connection with a financial transaction.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T18:32:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7313" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T18:47:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 190 - 236 (Roll no. 827).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7313" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-11-03T18:54:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="828" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 413 - 11 (Roll no. 828).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7289" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2940.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2930.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-11-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="225">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 225.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="453"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1831"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h848"/>
    <amendment number="h849"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/3/2011--Passed House amended.
Access to Capital for Job Creators Act - Amends the Securities Act of 1933 to exempt from specified prohibitions relating to interstate commerce and the mails any transactions by an issuer that do not involve a public offering (as under current law), whether or not such transactions involve general solicitation or general advertising. Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to revise rules governing an exemption from public offering requirements for limited offers and sales without regard to the dollar amount of the offering (Regulation D), so as to provide that a specified prohibition against general solicitation or general advertising does not apply to offers and sales of securities made pursuant to Regulation D if all purchasers of the securities are accredited investors. Requires such rules to require the issuer to take reasonable steps to verify that purchasers of the securities are accredited investors, using methods determined by the SEC.</summary>
</bill>
