<bill session="113" type="h" number="1925" updated="2013-11-02T06:35:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Care Criminal Background Check Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to require criminal background checks, inspections, and training of child care providers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412258"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412546" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2013--Introduced.
Child Care Criminal Background Check Act of 2013 - Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to require a state child care services plan to certify that the state will require child care providers that are licensed by the state or that receive funds under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Program to obtain a comprehensive criminal background check of each individual who provides child care services, each applicant selected for employment before providing such services, and each family child care provider who provides or applies to provide such services and to refuse to employ, or continue to employ, an individual to provide such services: (1) if such individual was convicted of a crime of violence or a crime against children; (2) to an eligible child without the supervision of an employee whose criminal background check satisfies requirements, pending receipt of such individual's background check; and (3) to an eligible child for a period exceeding 90 days with the supervision of an employee whose criminal background check satisfies requirements, pending receipt of such individual's background check. Requires a state child care services plan to also certify that the state will carry out a comprehensive criminal background check of an employee or applicant of such a child care provider as soon as practicable after the provider's request and make the results available to such provider, employee, and applicant. Requires the state to certify that: (1) each eligible child care provider (with an exception related to child care provided by a relative) that is licensed by the state will be inspected at least at 3-month intervals; and (2) each such provider that receives funds under the Program will receive not less than 40 hours of training provided by an entity recognized by the state and 24 hours of training annually that includes CPR, first aid, recognizing child abuse, basic safety and health, and child behavior and development. Reduces by 10% allotments to states that fail to comply with the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
