<bill session="109" type="s" number="963" updated="2013-07-19T20:21:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Health Care and Equitable Access Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for a guaranteed adequate level of funding for veterans' health care, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct a pilot program to improve access to health care for rural veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2005-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2005-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2005-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6400-6401"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2005--Introduced.
Veterans' Health Care and Equitable Access Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to make specified funds available to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) for Veterans Health Administration FY 2007 programs. Prohibits fund use for: (1) construction, acquisition, or alteration of veterans' medical facilities (other than for certain repairs); or (2) grants for the construction of State home facilities for veterans' domiciliary, nursing home, and hospital care. Directs the Secretary to conduct a pilot program to improve health care access for rural veterans. Provides: (1) for travel reimbursement for veterans receiving treatment in VA facilities at the same as for Federal employees on official business; (2) that the disability rating for a veteran who loses a limb as a result of a service-connected injury shall be at least 50 percent; and (3) that if a member of the Armed Forces, National Guard, or Reserve dies while on active service or active status such individual's child enrolled in any Federal child care program shall continue receiving such services for 24 months after such death. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to direct the Secretary and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a Medicare subvention project under which HHS shall reimburse the VA for Medicare health care services furnished to Medicare-eligible veterans in VA facilities.</summary>
</bill>
