<bill session="110" type="sr" number="344" updated="2013-07-19T22:16:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-04">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution commending the Government of Germany for preventing a large-scale terrorist attack in September 2007, and supporting future cooperation to prevent terrorism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300007"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2007-10-04" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12826" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S12826" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S12786" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hr" number="639"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/2007--Passed Senate without amendment.
Commends the efforts of law enforcement and intelligence authorities in Germany in preventing a large-scale terrorist attack on numerous targets in Germany, including sites frequented by U.S. citizens. Recognizes the role of U.S. intelligence agencies in providing critical information to German authorities in their investigation and apprehension of the suspected terrorists and notes the continuing importance of such U.S. intelligence cooperation with Germany. Condemns those individuals who would use acts of violence against innocent civilians to spread a message of hate and intolerance. Urges the allies of the United States to remain steadfast in their efforts to defeat international terrorism. Expresses readiness to assist the government of Germany in its counterterrorism effort to bring to justice the individuals involved in such terrorist plot.</summary>
</bill>
