<bill session="110" type="hr" number="195" updated="2013-07-19T20:52:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-28T11:08:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-02-28T11:08:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 556) to ensure national security while promoting foreign investment and the creation and maintenance of jobs, to reform the process by which such investments are examined for any effect they may have on national security, to establish the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412224"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-27T19:36:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-25, by Mr. Arcuri.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-27T19:36:00-05:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill. Notwithstanding clause 11 of rule XVIII, no amendment to the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII and except pro forma amendments for the purpose of debate. Each amendment so printed may be offered only by the Member who caused it to be printed or his designee and shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-02-27T19:37:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="17">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 17.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-02-28T10:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1982-1986" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-28T10:31:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 195.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-28T11:08:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1986" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2007-02-28T11:08:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1982" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-02-28T11:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="110" type="h" number="556"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2007--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 556 (National Security Foreign Investment Reform and Strengthened Transparency Act of 2007).</summary>
</bill>
