<bill session="111" type="h" number="1157" updated="2013-07-19T23:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Reassignment Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish certain protections for preference eligibles selected for involuntary geographic reassignment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400443"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2010-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2009-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2009-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/24/2009--Introduced.
Veterans Reassignment Protection Act - Prohibits a preference eligible federal employee (including a preference eligible serving in or under the U.S. Postal Service) from being involuntarily separated for failing to accept a directed reassignment to a position outside his or her commuting area or to accompany a position outside of such area pursuant to a transfer of function unless such preference eligible: (1) receives written notice of the reassignment at least 30 days before the effective date of the reassignment; and (2) is allowed to elect to have the selection of employees for release conducted in the same manner as would be required in the case of a reduction in force. Entitles a preference eligible involuntarily separated in the circumstances described above to appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board any failure to comply with the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
