<bill session="113" type="s" number="380" updated="2013-11-02T06:55:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Recovery from Trauma Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize and update the National Child Traumatic Stress Initiative for grants to address the problems of individuals who experience trauma and violence related stress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2013-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/2013--Introduced.
Children's Recovery from Trauma Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize and revise the National Child Traumatic Stress Initiative (NCTSI). Requires the NCTSI coordinating center to: (1) collect, analyze, and report NCTSI child outcome and process data for the purpose of establishing the effectiveness, implementation, and clinical utility of early identification and delivery of treatment and services delivered to children and families served by the NCTSI grantees; (2) oversee interprofessional training initiatives in treatments, interventions, and practices offered to NCTSI grantees and providers in all child-serving systems; and (3) collaborate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) in the dissemination of interventions, treatments, products, and other resources to all child-serving systems and policymakers. Directs the Secretary to establish consensus-driven, in-person or teleconference review of NCTSI applications by child trauma experts and review criteria related to expertise and experience related to child trauma and evidence-based practices. Requires the Secretary, in awarding grants under NCTSI, to prioritize expertise and experience in the field of trauma-related disorders over geographic distribution of grantees. Extends the duration of a grant from five years to six years. Gives expertise and experience in the field of trauma-related disorders priority for new and continuing awards.</summary>
</bill>
