<bill session="110" type="h" number="4917" updated="2013-07-19T21:46:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">NEO Preparedness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To formulate situation and decision analyses, and to select procedures and systems, for deflecting and mitigating potentially hazardous near-Earth objects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Asteroids"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2007--Introduced.
NEO Preparedness Act - Directs the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to establish an Office of Potentially Hazardous Near-Earth Object Preparedness, to prepare the United States for readiness to avoid and to mitigate collisions with potentially hazardous near-Earth objects in collaboration with other agencies through the identification of situation-and-decision-analysis factors and the selection of procedures and systems.Requires submission of interim and concluding reports that summarize the results of the activities of the Office carried out under this Act to identify situation- and decision-analysis factors and to select procedures and systems for such purposes.Requires the Administrator of NASA to convene a NASA Advisory Council to provide the Administrator with advice for the concluding report and for subsequent identification and selection activities.</summary>
</bill>
