<bill session="110" type="h" number="872" updated="2013-07-19T21:11:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Endowment for Workforce Education in Renewables and Agriculture Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">NEW ERA Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to make competitive grants to community colleges and advanced technology education centers partnering with community colleges to support the education and training of technicians in the fields of bioenergy and other agriculture-based, renewable energy resources, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2007-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2007-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community colleges"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy crops"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="High technology"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2007--Introduced.
National Endowment for Workforce Education in Renewables and Agriculture Act of 2007, or NEW ERA Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to make competitive grants to community colleges and advanced technology education centers located in Iowa or other midwestern states to support the education and training of technicians in the fields of bioenergy and other agricultural, renewable energy resources. Requires grant applicants to demonstrate the ability to leverage existing partnerships and develop educational and occupation outreach and training programs with secondary schools, four-year institutions of higher education, and the agricultural extension system. Gives funding priority to specified occupational education and training initiatives, which include: (1) improving the capacity of bioenergy service industry technicians to meet the needs of agricultural bioenergy businesses; (2) teacher training in agricultural bioenergy research, efficiency, and conservation; (3) the identification of agricultural bioenergy employment opportunities; and (4) the development of partnerships with nonprofit organizations dedicated to bioenergy education and training. Requires grant applications to include a comprehensive education and training evaluation component.</summary>
</bill>
