<bill session="111" type="h" number="4945" updated="2013-07-19T23:57:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Census Oversight Efficiency and Management Reform Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 13 of the United States Code to provide for a 5-year term of office for the Director of the Census and to provide for the authority and duties of the Director and Deputy Director of the Census, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2010-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E493"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3167"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2010--Introduced.
Census Oversight Efficiency and Management Reform Act of 2010 - Requires the individual appointed as Director of the Census to have a demonstrated ability in management and experience in the collection, analysis, and use of statistical data. Provides that: (1) the Director shall report directly to the Secretary of Commerce; and (2) no U.S. officer or agency shall have authority to require the Director to submit legislative recommendations, testimony, or comments for review prior to the submission to Congress if such submission includes a statement indicating that the views expressed are those of the Bureau of the Census and do not necessarily represent the views of the President. Requires the term of office of the Director to be five years and to begin on January 1, 2012, and every fifth year thereafter. Prohibits an individual from serving more than two full terms as Director. Sets forth provisions governing: (1) vacancies in and removal from office; and (2) the authorities and duties of the Director. Establishes the position of Deputy Director of the Census. Requires the Director to: (1) provide a plan to Congress on how the Bureau will test, develop, and implement an Internet response option for the 2020 Census and the American Community Survey; and (2) submit to the appropriate congressional committees, by the date of submission of the President's budget request for a fiscal year, a comprehensive status report on the next decennial census.</summary>
</bill>
