<bill session="109" type="h" number="3864" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Assistance for Individuals with Disabilities Affected by Hurricanes Katrina and Rita Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Assistance for Individuals with Disabilities Affected by Hurricanes Katrina or Rita Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Assistance for Individuals with Disabilities Affected by Hurricanes Katrina or Rita Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Assistance for Individuals with Disabilities Affected by Hurricanes Katrina or Rita Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide vocational rehabilitation services to individuals with disabilities affected by Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">A bill to assist individuals with disabilities affected by Hurricane Katrina or Rita through vocational rehabilitation services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400636"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2005-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400634" joined="2005-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2005-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2005-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T12:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Boustany moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T12:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8406-8408" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T12:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3864.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-09-28T12:57:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8406-8407" label="text as passed House"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-09-28" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10622" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-09-28">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2005-09-29">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-09-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-09-30" type="public" number="109-82">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-82.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/2005--Public Law.
(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on September 28, 2005. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Assistance for Individuals with Disabilities Affected by Hurricane Katrina or Rita Act of 2005 - Provides vocational rehabilitation services to individuals with disabilities affected by Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita. Directs the Commissioner of the Rehabilitation Services Administration, in realloting amounts to states under certain provisions of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (RA), to give preference to affected states that contain an area, or that received a significant number of individuals who resided in an area, in which the President has declared that a major disaster exists. Authorizes waiver of nonfederal share requirements in specified circumstances. Allows an affected state to use such reallotted funds for FY2005 to: (1) pay for vocational rehabilitation services for such individuals that contribute to economic growth and development of communities; (2) enable such individuals to participate in reconstruction or other major disaster assistance activities in the areas in which the individuals resided on certain dates; (3) pay for vocational rehabilitation services for such individuals who do not meet the affected state's order of selection criteria under RA; or (4) carry out other activities in accordance with title I of RA.</summary>
</bill>
