<bill session="111" type="h" number="4499" updated="2013-07-19T23:53:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Advisory Voter Initiative Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that the voters of the United States be given the right, through advisory voter initiative, to propose the enactment and repeal of Federal laws in a national election.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400182"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/2010--Introduced.
National Advisory Voter Initiative Act of 2010 - Grants the people, subject to specified voting qualifications, the right to: (1) propose any law which the Congress has authority to pass; and (2) propose the repeal of any provision of law passed by Congress which has become law. Outlines the procedure for the people to exercise such right through petition and state vote. Provides that, if a law or repeal proposed under this Act receives a majority of the votes cast in 3/5 of the several states, the proposed law or repeal shall be introduced in the House of Representatives by the Speaker of the House and in the Senate by the President pro tempore on the first day of the first session of Congress following the vote.</summary>
</bill>
