<bill session="111" type="s" number="1383" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dextromethorphan Abuse Reduction Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to prevent the abuse of dextromethorphan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2009-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7097-7098"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7098-7099" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2009--Introduced.
Dextromethorphan Abuse Reduction Act of 2009 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to prohibit sales of products containing dextromethorphan (including cough medicines) to individuals under age 18, including sales using the Internet, and to impose civil penalties for such sales. Directs the Director of National Drug Control Policy to provide grants to certain nonprofit drug prevention entities, including the National Community Antidrug Coalition Institute, for antidrug educational campaigns aimed at individuals under age 18 and for assistance to community antidrug coalitions to prevent abuse of prescription and nonprescription drugs (including dextromethorphan). Directs the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to implement comprehensive community-wide strategies for preventing abuse of prescription and nonprescription drugs (including dextromethorphan).</summary>
</bill>
