<bill session="111" type="s" number="3907" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Debbie Blanchard Access to Health Care for Individuals With Disabilities Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to increase access to health care for individuals with disabilities and increase awareness of the need for health care facilities and examination rooms to be accessible for individuals with disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7810"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Debbie Blanchard Access to Health Care for Individuals With Disabilities Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to states to develop, maintain, and improve Internet directories of health care providers that are known to have entrances, examination rooms, and examination tables that are accessible to individuals with disabilities. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Office on Disability of HHS, to: (1) establish a pilot program to increase the awareness of health care providers of the need to offer accessible environments, examination rooms, and examination tables for individuals with disabilities and to increase voluntary compliance with federal accessibility requirements; and (2) develop and disseminate resources to support individuals with disabilities in finding providers that are accessible to such individuals, which shall include a concise list of questions for individuals with disabilities to ask when calling a health care provider for the first time to schedule an appointment and suggestions for explaining the special needs of such individuals to the provider and for seeking accommodation from the provider. Requires the Secretary to establish a National Advisory Committee on Access to Health Care for Individuals With Disabilities to support implementation of this Act and to ensure interagency coordination of efforts to improve access to care for individuals with disabilities.</summary>
</bill>
