<bill session="111" type="h" number="5688" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Law Enforcement Torture Prevention Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide a criminal penalty for torture committed by law enforcement officers and others acting under color of law.</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="official">An act to amend title 38, United States Code, to increase the rates of disability compensation for disabled veterans and of dependency and indemnity compensation for surviving spouses and children of veterans, to increase the rates of subsistence and educational assistance allowances for veterans pursuing vocational rehabilitation programs under chapter 31 of such title and for veterans and eligible persons pursuing programs of education or training under chapter 34, 35, or 36 of such title, to increase the opportunities for vocational rehabilitation of certain veterans receiving disability compensation, and to provide vocational training opportunities for certain veterans receiving pension; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2010-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/2010--Introduced.
Law Enforcement Torture Prevention Act of 2010 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose a prison term of up to 10 years on any person who, acting under color of federal, state, or local law, commits, or attempts or conspires to commit, torture. Increases such prison term to any term of years or life if death results from such torture. Defines "torture" to mean intentionally inflicting severe pain or suffering, whether physical or mental, on a person for such purposes as obtaining from that person or another person information or a confession, punishing that person, or intimidating or coercing that person or another person, or for any reason based on discrimination of any kind, but does not include pain or suffering arising only from, inherent in, or incidental to lawful sanctions.</summary>
</bill>
