<bill session="109" type="s" number="1237" updated="2013-07-19T20:24:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAVE LIVES Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Spectrum Availability for Emergency-Response and Law-Enforcement to Improve Vital Emergency Services Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to expedite the transition to digital television while helping consumers to continue to use their analog televisions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2005-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6486"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1268"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronics"/>
    <term name="Electronics industry"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Grocery trade"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Postal facilities"/>
    <term name="Recycling industry"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television and children"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="Television relay systems"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Video display terminals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/2005--Introduced.
Spectrum Availability for Emergency-Response and Law-Enforcement to Improve Vital Emergency Services Act or SAVE LIVES Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to extend through December 31, 2008 (currently, 2006) the termination date for television broadcast licenses that authorize analog television service. Repeals provisions authorizing analog service extensions in limited circumstances. Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to take specified actions within specified deadlines for the final television channel assignment of full-power broadcast television stations authorized for digital service. Provides deadlines for the auction of recovered analog spectrum to be used for providing public emergency services. Directs the FCC to distribute to eligible persons analog-to-digital signal converter devices. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a grant program to provide enhanced interoperability of communications equipment for first responders. Provides certain consumer education requirements regarding the transition to digital television service. Authorizes, with a sunset, temporary digital-to-analog signal conversion for certain cable television subscribers. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow tax credits for qualified electronic waste (television display screens) collected from consumers and recycled. Directs the: (1) Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to study establishing a nationwide recycling program for electronic waste; and (2) FCC to complete certain pending proceedings relating to conversion to digital television and related matters.</summary>
</bill>
