<bill session="111" type="h" number="5762" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia National Disaster Insurance Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the creation of disaster protection funds in the District of Columbia by property and casualty insurance companies for the payment of policyholders' claims arising from natural catastrophic events.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1339"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2010--Introduced.
District of Columbia National Disaster Insurance Protection Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for a tax-exempt natural disaster protection fund held by an insurance company that: (1) is incorporated and domiciled in the District of Columbia; (2) is subject to supervision by the District of Columbia Commissioner of Insurance, Securities, and Banking; (3) maintains an office in the District of Columbia that employs no fewer than 10 full-time employees, at least 5 of whom are District of Columbia residents; (4) is subject to taxes imposed by the District of Columbia on premiums for natural catastrophic risk coverage; and (5) is not subject to premium taxes imposed by any state or other taxing jurisdiction for natural catastrophic risk coverage written through the fund. Allows distributions from such fund to cover losses attributable to wind (including hurricanes and tornadoes), earthquakes, floods, tsunami or tidal wave, volcanic eruption, fire, hail, snow, ice freezing, or other winter catastrophes, or a pandemic or other public health catastrophe. Sets forth tax rules for contributions to and distributions from such fund.</summary>
</bill>
