<bill session="113" type="h" number="2199" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flood Insurance Implementation Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To delay the implementation of certain provisions of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412530" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2013-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2013-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2013-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2013-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Flood Insurance Implementation Reform Act of 2013 - Delays until three years after enactment of this Act the requirement of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (Biggert-Waters) that any property located in an area participating in the national flood insurance program have the risk premium rate charged for flood insurance on the property adjusted to accurately reflect its current risk of flood. Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to delay until five years after enactment of Biggert-Waters the prohibition against provision to prospective insureds of flood insurance by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) at (subsidy) rates less than full actuarial estimates for property purchased after enactment of Biggert-Waters. Prohibits FEMA, when determining whether a community has made adequate progress on flood protection improvement systems, from counting federal funding or participation in such efforts. Makes flood insurance available at certain special flood hazard area rates to riverine and coastal levees located in a community which FEMA has determined to be in the process of restoring a flood protection system previously accredited on a Flood Insurance Rate Map as providing 100-year frequency flood protection but which no longer does so. Requires such rates to apply without regard to the level of federal funding or participation. Amends Biggert-Waters to authorize FEMA to to use other funds in addition to those specified in that Act to carry out a specified affordability study. Requires FEMA, upon notice to certain congressional committees that it cannot submit the report on that study by the current deadline, to specify in such notice an alternative method of gathering the requisite information and subsequently to submit the information so gathered. Directs FEMA to: (1) identify, review, update, maintain and publish National Flood Insurance rate maps pertaining to areas protected by non-structural flood mitigation features; and (2) work with states, local communities, and property owners to identify such areas and features.</summary>
</bill>
