<bill session="111" type="s" number="3798" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Prison Conditions Improvement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Foreign Prison Conditions Improvement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize appropriations of United States assistance to help eliminate conditions in foreign prisons and other detention facilities that do not meet minimum human standards of health, sanitation, and safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2010-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7176-7177"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-12-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-12-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="724">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 724.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="6153"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Foreign Prison Conditions Improvement Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of State to annually report to Congress describing prison and detention facility conditions in countries receiving U.S. assistance, including a list of countries whose governments do not meet minimum prison and detention facility standards but are, and those who are not, making significant compliance efforts. Urges the Secretary and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to provide assistance to countries whose governments do not meet such minimum standards but are making significant compliance efforts. Prohibits such funds from being used to construct new prisons. Directs the Secretary to enter into negotiations to achieve the purposes of this Act with a government listed in the report as not making significant compliance efforts. Authorizes in order to achieve such purposes: (1) the Secretary and the Administrator to restructure or reduce U.S. assistance to such government; and (2) the Secretary to issue or deny visas for U.S. travel by officials of such government. Directs the Secretary to establish within the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor a full-time equivalent Deputy Assistant Secretary level position to advance the purposes of this Act. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
