<bill session="111" type="h" number="4560" updated="2013-07-19T23:53:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Earmark Performance and Accountability Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 31, United States Code, to increase transparency and accountability for earmarks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412289"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400631" joined="2010-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2010--Introduced.
Earmark Performance and Accountability Act of 2010 - Requires a state, a local government, a nonprofit organization, or a private entity (non-federal entity) to: (1) conduct an audit using an independent external auditor of any program, project, or activity it administers that is funded through an earmark; and (2) report to Congress about such audit, including whether the earmarked funds are being spent efficiently and effectively and whether the program, project, or activity is meeting any applicable stated purpose. States that such program, project, or activity is funded through an earmark if it is included on: (1) a list of congressional earmarks generated under the Rules of the House of Representatives; (2) a list of congressionally directed spending generated under the Standing Rules of the Senate; or (3) both such lists. Requires a federal agency that conducts an audit of any program, project, or activity it administers that is funded through an earmark to report to Congress on its results, including whether the earmarked funds are being spent efficiently and effectively and whether the program, project, or activity is meeting any applicable stated purpose. Requires each such report to be transmitted to the Government Accountability Office (GAO) and GAO to make them publicly available on its website.</summary>
</bill>
