<bill session="110" type="s" number="3624" updated="2013-07-19T22:53:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean, Low-Emission, Affordable, New Transportation Efficiency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to require States and metropolitan planning organizations to develop transportation greenhouse gas reduction plans to reduce greenhouse gas emissions from the transportation sector, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300019"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Bicycles"/>
    <term name="Car pools"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emissions trading"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad equipment"/>
    <term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2008--Introduced.
Clean, Low-Emission, Affordable, New Transportation Efficiency Act - Establishes the Low Greenhouse Gas Transportation Fund. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), for each of calendar 2012-2050, to auction 10% of emission allowances established under any EPA program providing for the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions and the auctioning of emission allowances. Requires deposit of auction proceeds into the Fund to implement state and metropolitan planning organization (MPO) greenhouse gas emission reduction plans, and provide funding to transit projects that help reduce such emissions. Requires states and MPOs to: (1) establish goals for reducing greenhouse gas emissions from the transportation sector for the next 10 years; and (2) develop transportation greenhouse gas emission reduction plans, updated quadrennially, including supporting lists of prioritized transit projects, that are integrated into state and MPO long-range transportation and transportation improvement plans. Directs the Secretary of Transportation and the EPA Administrator to arrange with the Transportation Research Board of the National Academy of Sciences to study and report recommendations for improving research tools and federal data sources necessary to assess the effect of transportation and land use plans on motor vehicle use rates and transportation sector greenhouse gas emissions.</summary>
</bill>
