<bill session="111" type="s" number="1770" updated="2013-07-20T00:39:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Recreational Fishing and Hunting Heritage and Opportunities Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to recognize the heritage of recreational fishing, hunting, and shooting on Federal public lands and ensure continued opportunities for these activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2009-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2009-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="3749"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2009--Introduced.
Recreational Fishing and Hunting Heritage and Opportunities Act - Requires federal public land management officials to exercise their authority under existing law, including regarding land use planning, to provide for the use of, and access to, federal public lands and waters for fishing, sport hunting, and recreational shooting, except as described in this Act. Requires the heads of federal public land management agencies to exercise their discretion in a manner that supports, promotes, and enhances recreational fishing, hunting, and shooting opportunities, to the extent authorized under applicable law. States that Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and Forest Service lands, excluding lands on the Outer Continental Shelf, shall be open to recreational fishing, hunting, and shooting unless the managing agency acts to close lands to such activity. Permits closures or restrictions on such lands for purposes including resource conservation, public safety, energy or mineral production, energy generation or transmission infrastructure, water supply facilities, national security, or compliance with other law. Requires publication of a public notice preceding any such closures or restrictions, unless mandated by other law. Requires annual reports on closures of federal public lands to recreational fishing, sport hunting, or shooting. Sets forth requirements for specified closures or significant restrictions involving 640 or more acres of federal public lands or waters to fishing or hunting. Establishes the Sport Fishing and Boating Partnership Council and the Sporting Conservation Council.</summary>
</bill>
