<bill session="112" type="h" number="4179" updated="2013-07-20T01:46:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Iran Financial Sanctions Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen the multilateral sanctions regime with respect to Iran, to expand sanctions relating to the energy sector of Iran, the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction by Iran, and human rights abuses in Iran, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400371"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2012-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, the Judiciary, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Monetary Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA20" subcommittee="International Monetary Policy and Trade" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration Policy and Enforcement" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2012--Introduced.
Iran Financial Sanctions Improvement Act of 2012 - Directs the Comptroller General to submit to Congress a list of all known entities that provide services to, or facilitate service access for, the Central Bank of Iran or any Iranian financial institution. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to report to Congress on efforts to ensure that the Society for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunication (SWIFT), Clearstream, and other similar entities have terminated the provision of services to, and the facilitation of service access for, the Central Bank of Iran and other Iranian financial institutions. Authorizes the President to impose specified sanctions on an entity that has not terminated any such relationship. Amends the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 to require each foreign financial institution that maintains a U.S. correspondent account or a payable-through account to report to the Secretary of the Treasury regarding any financial dealings with an Iranian financial institution during the preceding 180 days. Directs the Secretary to make such reports public. Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 to include as a sanctionable activity the maintenance of funds or accounts for, or on behalf of, the Central Bank of Iran or another Iranian financial institution. Applies specified sanctions with respect to a foreign financial institution owned or controlled by the government of a foreign country (including a central bank of a foreign country) to the same extent and in the same manner as such sanctions apply to other foreign financial institutions. Directs the President to impose specified sanctions against a person that knowingly provided underwriting services or reinsurance: (1) for any activity regarding Iran for which sanctions have been imposed, or (2) to or for any person on which sanctions have been imposed for engaging in an activity with respect to Iran or any person designated for the imposition of sanctions in connection with Iran's proliferation of weapons of mass destruction or support for international terrorism. Includes among such sanctions export and procurement sanctions, and visa, property, banking, loan, and foreign exchange prohibitions.</summary>
</bill>
