<bill session="109" type="s" number="3947" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Soldiers to Citizens Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to permit the Secretary of Homeland Security to grant citizenship to an alien who serves on active duty in the Armed Forces, to assist such an alien in applying for citizenship, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300045"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10289-10290"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10290-10291" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4533"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2097"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2165"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Quality control"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2006--Introduced.
Soldiers to Citizens Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to state that, except for provisions relating to revocation of citizenship for separation from service under other than honorable conditions, noncitizens: (1) shall not be denied the opportunity to apply for Armed Forces membership; and (2) who become active duty Armed Forces members shall, consistent with active duty naturalization provisions and with the approval of their chain of command, be granted U.S. citizenship after performing at least two years of honorable active duty service. Requires citizenship to be granted within 90 days of application. Waives certain naturalization requirements, but requires that the applicant participate in the oath ceremony and demonstrate to his or her military chain of command English proficiency, good moral character, and knowledge of U.S. government and history. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to use the fingerprints provided by an individual at the time of military enlistment to satisfy any naturalization fingerprint requirements if the individual: (1) may be naturalized; (2) was fingerprinted at the time of enlistment; and (3) submits a naturalization application within 12 months of enlistment. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a toll-free naturalization assistance telephone service for Armed Forces members and their families; (2) ensure that such service is operated by Department of Homeland Security (DHS) employees with specialized training on the naturalization process for Armed Forces members, and who are located in the same unit as the military processing unit that adjudicates naturalization applications; and (3) monitor the accuracy and quality of information provided by such employees.</summary>
</bill>
