<bill session="113" type="h" number="2089" updated="2013-11-02T06:36:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defending State Authority Over Education Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to prohibit Federal mandates, direction, or control, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412394"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412547" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412477" joined="2013-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412479" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412528" joined="2013-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2013-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2013--Introduced.
Defending State Authority Over Education Act of 2013 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to prohibit the Secretary of Education from attempting to influence, incentivize, or coerce a state to participate in a voluntary partnership with another state to develop and implement academic content and achievement standards and assessments. Prohibits the Secretary from conditioning the approval of a state's, local educational agency's (LEA's), or Indian tribe's request for a waiver of ESEA statutory or regulatory requirements on such an entity: (1) including in, or deleting from, such request, specific academic standards; (2) using specific academic assessment instruments or items; or (3) including in, or deleting from, such waiver request any criteria used to establish, implement, or improve state academic standards, academic assessments, state accountability systems, or teacher and school leader evaluation systems. Prohibits any federal officer or employee from directly or indirectly mandating, directing, or controlling a state's, LEA's, or school's specific instructional content, academic standards and assessments, curricula, or program of instruction, including through the placement of conditions on financial support.</summary>
</bill>
