<bill session="111" type="s" number="2918" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Helping Small Business Succeed Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make improvements to certain loan programs under the Small Business Act and the Small Business Investment Act of 1958, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13699"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1615"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2009--Introduced.
Helping Small Business Succeed Act of 2009 - Amends the Small Business Act to increase maximum amounts of loans under the section 7(a) guaranteed loan program and the Microloan Program. Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to increase maximum amounts of loans to state and local development companies for plant acquisition, construction, conversion, and expansion. Increases the maximum loan guarantee percentage under the 7(a) program, effective until October 3, 2011. Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to extend through such date the authority to extend increased loan guarantees to small business lenders and to eliminate certain loan fees. Authorizes the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), through such date, to make loans to small businesses located in an economic disaster area. Amends the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer to the Administrator necessary amounts to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
