<bill session="110" type="h" number="5496" updated="2013-07-19T21:52:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Health Preparedness Workforce Development Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish various programs for the recruitment and retention of public health workers and to eliminate critical public health workforce shortages in Federal, State, local, and tribal public health agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2008-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2008-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2008-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400384" joined="2008-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E247-248"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1882"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Job vacancies"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/2008--Introduced.
Public Health Preparedness Workforce Development Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish the Public Health Workforce Scholarship Program to assure an adequate supply of public health professionals to eliminate critical public health preparedness workforce shortages in federal, state, local, and tribal public health agencies by offering four-year scholarships in return for employment at such agencies. Requires the Secretary to establish the Public Health Workforce Loan Repayment Program to provide for the repayment of loans incurred by individuals in the pursuit of the relevant public health preparedness workforce educational degree or certificate in exchange for working at such agencies for at least three years. Requires the Secretary to award grants to public health agencies that receive public health preparedness cooperative agreements from the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to operate state, local, and tribal public health workforce loan repayment programs. Authorizes the Secretary to provide for scholarships to enable mid-career professionals in the public health workforce to receive additional training in the field of public health preparedness or biodefense. Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to ensure that included in the OPM website there is an online catalogue of public health workforce employment opportunities in the federal government. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to award grants to establish Academic Health Departments to provide for collaboration between the academic and practice aspects of public health.</summary>
</bill>
