<bill session="111" type="h" number="2576" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chinook Nation Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restore Federal recognition to the Chinook Nation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3084"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Chinook Nation Restoration Act - Extends federal recognition to the Chinook Indian Nation. Makes the Chinook Tribe and its members eligible for all services and benefits provided by the government to federally recognized tribes regardless of the existence of a reservation or the location of residence of any member on or near any Indian reservation. Designates specified counties in Washington and Oregon as the Tribe's service area for delivery of federal services to enrolled members. Requires the Tribe to: (1) submit to the Secretary of the Interior a membership roll; and (2) conduct, by secret ballot, an election to adopt a constitution and bylaws. Directs the Secretary: (1) if the Tribe transfers all rights to land to the Secretary, to take such land in trust for the Tribe's benefit, subject to restrictions; (2) to negotiate with the tribal governing body regarding establishing a reservation; and (3) to develop a plan for doing so. Requires the Secretary to: (1) notify and consult with all appropriate state officials and owners of land adjacent to those considered for the proposed reservation; and (2) provide complete information on the proposed plan to such officials. Requires submission of the plan to Congress upon approval by the tribal governing body. Requires any real property transferred by the Tribe or any member to the Secretary to be held in the name of the United States for the Tribe's benefit. Prohibits the exercise of eminent domain for purposes of acquiring lands for the Tribe's benefit. Allows and regulates ceremonial hunting and fishing in specified Washington counties.</summary>
</bill>
