<bill session="109" type="h" number="4250" updated="2013-07-19T19:41:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Export Promotion Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To eliminate fees for assistance provided by the Department of Commerce and agencies thereof under export promotion programs, to authorize appropriations for such purpose, to direct the Secretary of Commerce to take certain steps to expand export promotion activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2005-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/2005--Introduced.
United States Export Promotion Act of 2005 - Prohibits the Secretary of Commerce, the International Trade Administration, and the U.S. and Foreign Commercial Service (USFCS) from charging fees to U.S. exporters, businesses, or persons for assistance provided to them under export promotion programs. Revises the capital security cost-sharing program under the Secure Embassy Construction and Counterterrorism Act of 1999 to exclude from determination of an agency's total overseas presence any positions or activities attributable to export promotion programs. Requires the Secretary to develop and submit to Congress plans to: (1) locate and relocate USFCS offices, officers, and employees in other countries at places other than the U.S. embassy or the U.S. chief diplomatic mission; and (2) place a USFCS office where the United States has diplomatic relations or, where viable in countries with smaller markets, one or more foreign nationals working under a regional USFCS officer's supervision to carry out export promotion functions. Directs the Secretary to develop and submit to Congress a plan for conducting at least 100 U.S. trade missions abroad in FY2006-FY2007. Requires the Secretary to: (1) increase the participation in global markets of small and medium-sized U.S. businesses; (2) review, reorganize, and expand the Department of Commerce Web site to increase its usability and scope; and (3) create a database of U.S. exporters.</summary>
</bill>
