<bill session="112" type="s" number="1696" updated="2013-07-20T02:31:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Safety Officers' Benefits Improvements Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the Public Safety Officers' Benefits Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2011-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2012-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2011-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2012-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6466-6467"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6467-6469" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1668"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4018"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="385"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/2011--Introduced.
Public Safety Officers' Benefits Improvements Act of 2011 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to revise provisions concerning public safety officer death or disability benefits, including by: (1) modifying the list of recipients of death benefits payable when a public safety officer has died as the direct and proximate result of a personal injury sustained in the line of duty to include as an eligible individual, if there is no other individual meeting existing eligibility requirements, the surviving individual (or individuals, in equal shares) who would qualify as an eligible "child" but for age; (2) providing that disability benefits shall be payable when an officer has become permanently and totally disabled as the direct and proximate result of a personal injury (currently, as the direct result of a catastrophic injury) sustained in the line of duty; (3) eliminating the $5,000,000 limit on total annual disability benefits paid; (4) providing that such death or disability benefits shall not be in addition to payments under the September 11th Victim Compensation Fund of 2001; (5) revising the criteria for death resulting from a heart attack, stroke, or vascular rupture suffered by a public safety officer while on duty; (6) including as eligible for benefits a candidate-officer (an individual officially enrolled or admitted in an officially recognized, formal program of instruction or training as a law enforcement officer, firefighter, or member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew) who is injured while engaging in an activity or exercise that is part of that program; (7) including within the definitions of "member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew" and "public safety officer" an officially recognized or designated employee or volunteer member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew that is a public agency or a nonprofit entity serving the public that is officially authorized or licensed to engage in rescue activity or to provide emergency medical services and that is officially designated as a prehospital emergency medical response agency; and (8) making those who have sustained a catastrophic injury in the line of duty eligible for peer support and counseling programs. Makes funds available for appeals from final determinations (currently, decisions) of the Bureau of Justice Assistance, and for expenses of representation of hearing examiners, with respect to public safety officer's death benefits under specified circumstances. Provides that no appeal shall bring a final determination of the Bureau before any court for review unless notice of appeal is filed within 90 days after the date on which the Bureau serves notice of the final determination. Defines a "hearing examiner" under such Act to include any medical or claims examiner.</summary>
</bill>
