<bill session="111" type="s" number="3177" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Home Star Energy Retrofit Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the establishment of a Home Star Retrofit Rebate Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2010-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2121"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2121-2127" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5019"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3434"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2010--Introduced.
Home Star Energy Retrofit Act of 2010 - Requires the Secretary of Energy to establish: (1) the Home Star Retrofit Rebate Program to provide rebates to contractors to be passed through as discounts to homeowners who retrofit their homes to achieve energy savings; (2) a Federal Rebate Processing System to enable rebate aggregators to submit claims for reimbursement; and (3) a national retrofit website and public information campaign that provide information on the Program. Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop a network of rebate aggregators that can facilitate the delivery of rebates to reimburse participating contractors; and (2) develop guidelines for states to allow utilities participating as rebate aggregators to count the energy savings from their participation toward state-level energy saving targets. Sets forth eligibility criteria for rebate aggregators. Establishes: (1) a Silver Star Home Energy Retrofit Program to award rebates during the first year after this Act's enactment for the energy retrofit of a home for the installation of specified energy saving measures, including air-sealing and insulation measures, duct seal or replacement, window or door replacement, heating or cooling system replacement, and water heater replacement; and (2) a Gold Star Home Energy Retrofit Program to award rebates for retrofits that achieve whole home energy savings. Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) the amount of the rebates (up to $3,000 per home for Silver Star rebates or $8,000 per home for Gold Star rebates); and (2) the treatment of rebates for tax purposes (excluded from taxable income). Requires a state that receives funding under this Act to submit to the Secretary a plan to implement a quality assurance program that covers all federally assisted residential efficiency retrofit work administered, supervised, or sponsored by the state. Requires the Secretary to establish a Home Star Energy Efficiency Loan Program to make funds available to states to support financial assistance provided by qualified financing entities for making, to existing homes, energy efficiency improvements that qualify under the Silver Star or Gold Star programs.</summary>
</bill>
