<bill session="112" type="s" number="2097" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Cancer Care Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of comprehensive cancer care planning under the Medicare Program and to improve the care furnished to individuals diagnosed with cancer by establishing grants programs for provider education, and related research.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3705"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2012--Introduced.
Comprehensive Cancer Care Improvement Act of 2012 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of comprehensive cancer care planning services. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to eligible entities to improve the quality of: (1) graduate and postgraduate training of physicians, nurses, and other health care providers in developing cancer care plans for, and communicating such plans to, patients; and (2) continuing professional education regarding the development and communication of written cancer care plans that outline a system of care that coordinates active treatment and palliative care. Requires the Secretary to provide investment, through existing programs, for research on topics related to cancer care planning and coordination, symptom management, palliative care, and comprehensive survivorship care.</summary>
</bill>
