<bill session="112" type="h" number="2406" updated="2013-07-20T01:31:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Administrator of General Services to convey a parcel of real property in Tracy, California, to the City of Tracy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412403" joined="2012-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-06">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-06">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="1302"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1302"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/6/2011--Introduced.
Authorizes the Administrator of General Services (GSA) to offer to enter into a binding agreement with the city of Tracy, California, under which the Administrator may convey to the city any reversionary interest retained by the United States in a specified parcel of land conveyed to the city for educational or recreational purposes and all other terms, conditions, reservations, and restrictions imposed in connection with the conveyance of such parcel. Requires the city to pay to the Administrator not less than the appraised fair market value of the parcel, as determined by the Administrator pursuant to an appraisal, based on the highest and best use of the parcel. Makes such determination regarding the value of such parcel final. Makes the city responsible for reimbursing the Administrator for costs associated with the implementation of this Act, including the costs of each applicable appraisal and survey. Requires the net proceeds from such conveyance to be deposited into the Federal Buildings Fund and made available for expenditure for any lawful purpose consistent with the Administrator's authority.</summary>
</bill>
