<bill session="109" type="s" number="1635" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bottom Trawl and Deep Sea Coral Habitat Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish ocean bottom trawl areas in which trawling is permitted, to protect deep sea corals and sponges, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2005-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9835"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9835-9838" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="3778"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Coral reefs"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Ecological surveys"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Geographic information systems"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Ocean floor"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/2005--Introduced.
Bottom Trawl and Deep Sea Coral Habitat Act - Requires the Secretary of Commerce to direct the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere to explore, identify, research, and map the locations of deep sea corals and deep sea sponges. Directs the Secretary to develop a cooperative research program to identify: (1) the ideal areas for the use of bottom trawls; and (2) the locations of deep sea corals and deep sea sponges. Requires each Regional Fishery Management Council to submit to the Secretary a list of areas that were fished using bottom trawls during the seven-year period ending on December 31, 2004, including recommendations of which areas should be designated as Bottom Trawl Zones. Requires the Secretary to designate each area that does not contain a deep sea coral and sponge ecosystem as a Bottom Trawl Zone. Prohibits the use of bottom trawls in an area not designated as a Bottom Trawl Zone. Directs the Secretary to designate as a Coral Habitat Conservation Zone each area that a Council has designated as an area in which the use of bottom trawls is prohibited for the protection of seafloor habitat, or for which a map and best available data has detected the presence of deep sea corals or deep sea sponges. Sets forth both civil and criminal penalties for persons who violate the requirements under this Act. Authorizes the President to permit the Secretary to work with appropriate international organizations and foreign nations to develop data to identify areas in international waters that contain deep sea corals or deep sea sponges and to protect such deep sea corals or deep sea sponges.</summary>
</bill>
