<bill session="112" type="h" number="4043" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Readiness and Southern Sea Otter Conservation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Military Readiness and Southern Sea Otter Conservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Defense to establish Southern Sea Otter Military Readiness Areas for national defense purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 13.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-17T18:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-606, Part I.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2012--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Military Readiness and Southern Sea Otter Conservation Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to establish Southern Sea Otter Military Readiness Areas for national defense purposes (thereby conserving the southern sea otter [otter] in such Areas while allowing reasonable military readiness activities). Allows certain incidental otter takings in such Areas in the course of a military readiness activity, while authorizing the Secretary of the Interior to revise or terminate such authorized takings upon determining that the military activities are substantially impeding otter conservation or the return of such otters to optimum sustainable levels. Directs: (1) the Secretary of the Navy to monitor the Areas, at least annually, to evaluate otter status; and (2) the Secretaries of the Navy and the Interior to report jointly every three years to Congress and the public on such monitoring. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, upon ending a specified otter relocation and management plan and in planning and implementing recovery and conservation measures to allow for the expansion of otter range, to coordinate and cooperate with: (1) the Secretary of the Navy, (2) the Secretary of Commerce regarding recovery efforts for endangered species, and (3) the state of California in continuing viable commercial harvest of state fisheries.</summary>
</bill>
