<bill session="110" type="h" number="2254" updated="2013-07-19T21:23:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ending Nuclear Trafficking Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to establish the transfer of any nuclear weapon, device, material, or technology to terrorists as a crime against humanity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2007-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2007--Introduced.
Ending Nuclear Trafficking Act - Declares it to be the policy of the United States that the transfer of a nuclear weapon or device or of nuclear material or technology for terrorist purposes is a crime against humanity and should be punished under customary international criminal law. Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit the transfer of a nuclear weapon or device, or of nuclear material or sensitive nuclear technology, to any foreign terrorist organization or any other person engaged in terrorist activities. Grants extraterritorial jurisdiction to prosecute violations of this Act. Imposes a fine and minimum prison term of 25 years for violations (life imprisonment for violations resulting in death).Requires the Secretary of State to direct the Permanent Representative of the United States to the United Nations and representatives to bilateral and multilateral fora to seek international recognition that the transfer of nuclear weapons, devices, material, or technology for terrorist purposes is a crime against humanity.</summary>
</bill>
