<bill session="111" type="h" number="4504" updated="2013-07-19T23:53:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SINC Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Standards for Internet Non-Censorship Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Federal Communications Commission to issue regulations against the censorship of Internet search results, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2010-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-26">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications, Technology, and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications, Technology, and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2010--Introduced.
Standards for Internet Non-Censorship Act of 2010 or the SINC Act of 2010 - Declares it to be the sense of Congress that: (1) the President should establish interim minimum standards of non-censorship for Internet search providers and create programs to restrict access to domestic online information by providers determined to be censoring nonviolent political speech; (2) any long-term solution to the problem of the censorship of nonviolent political speech on the Internet must include minimum standards of non-censorship set by a coalition of free countries; and (3) the President should negotiate with free countries to adopt minimum standards for non-censorship of nonviolent political speech as a condition for access to the Internet. Authorizes the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to begin a proceeding to adopt regulations to restrict repressive Internet search providers from accessing domestic online information. Requires the FCC, if it adopts such regulations, to develop, operate, and maintain a public website that lists repressive providers and the reasons for finding that the providers were repressive. Authorizes the FCC to enforce the regulations using any existing enforcement authority to prevent collusion to evade the regulations. Directs the Secretary of State to seek to enter into agreements with free countries to adopt minimum standards. Authorizes the FCC to begin a proceeding to adopt regulations to restrict or prevent entities that operate outside of any such agreements from accessing domestic online information.</summary>
</bill>
