<bill session="109" type="h" number="5956" updated="2013-07-19T19:57:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Fund Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make all civil penalties collected by the Securities and Exchange Commission in securities law enforcement actions available for the benefit of victims of securities law violations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400012"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2006-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Victims"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2006--Introduced.
Fair Fund Improvement Act - Amends the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 to revise the requirement that, if the Securities Exchange Commission (SEC) obtains an order requiring disgorgement for a violation, and also obtains a civil penalty, such penalty shall, at SEC motion or discretion, be added to the disgorgement fund for the benefit of victims. Repeals the initial requirement for a disgorgement order. Declares that, if the SEC obtains a civil penalty for violation of securities laws, the penalty shall, upon SEC motion, be added to and become part of a disgorgement or other fund established for the benefit of the victims of such violation. Authorizes the SEC to enter into contracts to retain private legal counsel to collect delinquent judgments and orders.</summary>
</bill>
