<bill session="111" type="h" number="6291" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freight FOCUS Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freight is the Future Of Commerce in the United States Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for merit-based investment in the freight transportation system of the United States to ensure economic growth, increase vitality and competitiveness in national and global markets, address goods mobility and accessibility issues, reduce air pollution and other environmental impacts of freight transportation, better public health conditions, enhance energy security, and improve the condition and connectivity of the freight transportation system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Freight is the Future Of Commerce in the United States Act of 2010 or Freight FOCUS Act of 2010 - Establishes within the Office of the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) an Office of Freight Planning and Development, which shall be headed by an Assistant Secretary for Freight Planning and Development. Directs the Assistant Secretary to submit to Congress and publish on DOT's website a national freight plan for supporting freight movement for the next 20 years. Directs the Secretary to establish a Freight Advisory Committee. Directs the Assistant Secretary to: (1) establish a freight corridors of national significance program, and (2) designate such corridors. Authorizes the Assistant Secretary to designate one entity to serve as a freight corridor coalition. Requires the freight corridor coalition to submit annually to the Assistant Secretary a freight corridor plan that includes, among other things, a prioritized list of projects that will improve the freight movement performance of the freight corridors of national significance. Authorizes the Assistant Secretary to make grants to states for such projects. Requires a grant recipient to submit to the Assistant Secretary: (1) a project management plan and an annual financial plan for a project with a total cost of at least $500 million; and (2) an annual financial plan for a project with a total cost of less than $500 million. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish in the Treasury the Goods Movement Trust Fund. Increases by 12 cents the tax on the sale of diesel fuel used for the transportation of goods by highway. Transfers amounts equivalent to the increase in tax to the Fund. Requires the Secretary to pay an amount based on a certain formula to purchasers of diesel fuel that is not used for the transportation of goods by highway in which such tax was paid. Allows an income tax credit in lieu of payment to certain tax exempt entities.</summary>
</bill>
