<bill session="109" type="s" number="294" updated="2013-07-19T20:15:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to strengthen the restrictions of the importation from BSE minimal-risk regions of meat, meat byproducts, and meat food products from bovines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300015"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2005-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2005-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2005-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2005-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2005-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300097" joined="2005-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2005-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Bovine spongiform encephalopathy"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Cattle"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/2005--Introduced.
Applies the Code of Federal Regulations as amended by the final rule issued by the Secretary of Agriculture on January 4, 2005 (and any successor regulations) restricting importation from bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE) minimal-risk regions of meat and edible products from ruminants only to meat, meat byproducts, and meat food products derived from a bovine that is slaughtered at less than 30 months of age. Provides that if the Secretary, in consultation with appropriate officials in such a minimal risk region, determines that the region is in full compliance with a ruminant feed ban and other BSE safeguards, the Secretary: (1) shall report to specified congressional committees on the determination; and (2) may promulgate regulations to allow such rules to apply to meat, meat byproducts, and meat food products derived from a class of bovines in the region that is determined by the Secretary by the regulations.</summary>
</bill>
