<bill session="111" type="s" number="3060" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Thorium Energy Security Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to provide for thorium fuel cycle nuclear power generation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2010-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1019"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2010--Introduced.
Thorium Energy Security Act of 2010 - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to direct the Secretary of Energy to establish, and provide funds to, an office for the regulation of thorium fuel cycle nuclear power generation within the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) and an office of thorium-based fuel cycle research within the Department of Energy. Directs the NRC Chairman to: (1) establish standards for the manufacture, testing, use, and management of spent thorium-based nuclear fuel; and (2) promulgate regulations for facilities and materials used in thorium-based fuel cycle nuclear power generation. Directs the Secretary to implement demonstration projects for thorium-based nuclear power generation. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress recommendations for: (1) strengthening international partnerships to advance nuclear nonproliferation through the design and deployment of thorium fuel cycle nuclear power generation; and (2) providing incentives to nuclear reactor operators to use proliferation-resistant, low-waste thorium fuels in lieu of other fuels.</summary>
</bill>
