<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1583" updated="2013-07-19T23:09:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-15T13:53:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-09-15T13:53:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Observing the fifth anniversary of the date on which Hurricane Rita devastated the coasts of Louisiana and Texas, remembering those lost in the storm and in the process of evacuation, recovery, and rebuilding; saluting the dedication of the volunteers who offered assistance in support of those affected by the storm, recognizing the progress of efforts to rebuild the affected Gulf Coast region, commending the persistence of the people of the States of Louisiana and Texas following the second major hurricane to hit Louisiana that season, and reaffirming Congress' commitment to restore and renew the Gulf Coast region.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">Observing the fifth anniversary of the date on which Hurricane Rita devastated the coasts of Louisiana and Texas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400636"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412268" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400635" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Johnson, E. B. moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6719-6721" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1583.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-09-15T13:53:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6719" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15T13:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15T13:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="1577"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="sr" number="641"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2010--Passed House amended.
Observes the fifth anniversary of the date on which Hurricane Rita devastated the coasts of Louisiana and Texas. Expresses support to the survivors and condolences to the victims' families. Commends the efforts of those who assisted in the response to the storm and the recovery process. Reaffirms a commitment to rebuild, renew, and restore the Gulf Coast region.</summary>
</bill>
