<bill session="111" type="h" number="6439" updated="2013-07-20T00:10:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Targeted Tax Lien Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require certain determinations before the filing of all notices of Federal tax liens and supervisory approval before the filing of certain notices of Federal tax liens, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1969-1970"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2010--Introduced.
Targeted Tax Lien Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require the Secretary of the Treasury to determine, prior to filing a notice of tax lien for unpaid taxes, that: (1) the lien attaches to distrainable property; (2) the benefit to the government of filing such lien outweighs the harm to the taxpayer; and (3) the filing of such lien will not jeopardize the taxpayer's prospective ability to comply with tax laws or an otherwise viable business taxpayer's prospective ability to secure funding to maintain business operations. Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to limit the period in which certain released or erroneously filed federal tax liens may be reported on a consumer 's credit report.</summary>
</bill>
