<bill session="110" type="s" number="2114" updated="2013-07-19T22:39:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Home Ownership Preservation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Truth in Lending Act, to provide for enhanced disclosures to consumers and enhanced regulation of mortgage brokers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Moderate income housing"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2007--Introduced.
American Home Ownership Preservation Act of 2007 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to require certain mortgage originators or lenders with primary responsibility for underwriting an assessment on a home mortgage loan to include a borrower's ability to repay certain associated costs. Requires a mortgage broker to clearly disclose its relationship to the borrower. Directs the federal banking agencies to establish a nationwide registry and database system in which all mortgage brokers in the United States must register. Eliminates prepayment penalties for home mortgages. Instructs the Secretary of the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to make grants to state governments and tribal organizations to assist: (1) programs established for foreclosure mitigation; and (2) housing trust funds supporting low- and moderate-income housing. Amends the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 to direct the HUD Secretary to establish an annual goal for each government-sponsored enterprise to identify and assist homeowners at risk of default or foreclosure on their mortgage, but who would be able to stabilize the situation with fixed rate 30- or 40-year mortgages. Authorizes appropriations for mortgage fraud enforcement and prosecution.</summary>
</bill>
