<bill session="113" type="s" number="980" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chris Stevens, Sean Smith, Tyrone Woods, and Glen Doherty Embassy Security and Personnel Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for enhanced embassy security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3579-3580"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1386"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/2013--Introduced.
Chris Stevens, Sean Smith, Tyrone Woods, and Glen Doherty Embassy Security and Personnel Protection Act of 2013 - Authorizes FY2014 appropriations to restore the capital security cost sharing program to its full capacity. Expresses the sense of Congress concerning priorities of the program and funding through interagency agreements. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) foreign language training, especially in critical need languages including Arabic, for Department of State employees, including the Bureau of Diplomatic Security; and (2) a Foreign Affairs Security Training Center (FASTC). Expresses the sense of Congress concerning the value of a FASTC and its use of existing training synergies. Authorizes the Secretary of State to transfer to, and merge with, any appropriation for embassy security, construction, and maintenance such amounts appropriated for any other purpose related to the administration of foreign affairs on or after October 1, 2013. Revises provisions regarding: (1) local guard contracts abroad, and (2) computation of the death gratuity payable to surviving dependents of Foreign Service employees who die from injuries sustained in the performance of duty abroad. Authorizes the Department to use a noncompetitive procurement procedure to meet emergency security requirements. Provides that unsatisfactory leadership by a senior official regarding a security incident involving loss of life, serious injury, or significant destruction of property at or related to a U.S. government mission abroad may be grounds for disciplinary action. Authorizes the Secretary to provide physical security enhancements at overseas educational facilities established for the children of U.S. government employees. Makes permanent the Secretary's authority to waive the annuity termination of a temporarily reemployed annuitant in a position for which there is exceptional difficulty in recruiting or retaining a qualified employee. Provides special immigrant status for the surviving spouse or child of a U.S. government employee killed abroad in the line of duty, provided that the employee had performed faithful service for at least 15 years and the appropriate recommendations have been made. Directs the Secretary to: (1) implement a plan to incorporate the additional Marine Corps Security Guard personnel at U.S. diplomatic facilities, and (2) conduct an annual review of the Marine Corps Security Guard Program. Directs the Secretary to: (1) report to Congress regarding the facts and circumstances surrounding the September 11-12, 2012, killings of four U.S. government personnel in Benghazi, Libya; and (2) report to Congress annually regarding overseas posts determined to be "high risk, high threat."</summary>
</bill>
