<bill session="112" type="h" number="1285" updated="2013-07-20T01:21:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Health Care Affordability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to prohibit certain increases in fees for military health care before fiscal year 2014.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2011-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412485" joined="2012-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2011-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412483" joined="2012-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412413" joined="2011-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/2011--Introduced.
Military Health Care Affordability Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) so long as the United States sends men and women into battle, the United States will be faithful to care for them upon their return; (2) as the veteran answered the call of duty, so too, is the United States duty-bound to answer the call of the veteran; and (3) the Department of Defense (DOD) and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) have the tools and ingenuity to provide continued excellent health care without increasing TRICARE payments from the veteran before fiscal year 2014. Extends through FY2013 (under current law, through FY2011) the prohibition on increases in certain health care costs and restrictions on health benefit adjustments for members of the Armed Forces, retirees, and their dependents, including charges and premiums under TRICARE (a DOD managed care program) and cost-sharing requirements under the DOD pharmacy benefits program.</summary>
</bill>
