<bill session="113" type="sj" number="5" updated="2013-11-02T06:49:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States relative to authorizing regulation of contributions to candidates for State public office and Federal office by corporations, entities organized and operated for profit, and labor organization, and expenditures by such entities and labor organizations in support of, or opposition to such candidates.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/28/2013--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Gives Congress the power to regulate the contribution of funds by corporations, for-profit entities, and labor organizations to a candidate for election to, or nomination for election to, a federal office, and the power to regulate the expenditure of funds by corporations, for-profit entities, and labor organizations made in support of, or in opposition to, such candidates. Gives a state the power to regulate the contribution of funds by corporations, for-profit entities, and labor organizations to a candidate for election to, or for nomination for election to, public office in the state, and the power to regulate the expenditure of funds by corporations, for-profit entities, and labor organizations made in support of, or in opposition to, such candidates.</summary>
</bill>
