<bill session="111" type="h" number="2384" updated="2013-07-19T23:33:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Park Service and Northwestern State University Collections Conservation Center Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with Northwestern State University in Natchitoches, Louisiana, to construct a curatorial center for the use of Cane River Creole National Historical Park, the National Center for Preservation Technology and Training, and the University, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412275"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1018"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2009--Introduced.
National Park Service and Northwestern State University Collections Conservation Center Act - Amends the Cane River Creole National Historical Park and National Heritage Area Act (the Act) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with Northwestern State University in Natchitoches, Louisiana, to construct a facility on land owned by the University to be used for: (1) housing the museum collection of the Historical Park; (2) providing additional space for use by the National Center for Preservation Technology and Training; and (3) providing space to the University for educational purposes related to the Williamson Museum collection if the University pays an appropriate rental fee to the National Park Service (NPS), as determined in such agreement. Requires the proceeds from the rental fees collected pursuant to this Act to be made available for the Historical Park.</summary>
</bill>
