<bill session="113" type="s" number="943" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Growth to Excellence Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an alternative accountability model.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2013-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1977"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2013--Introduced.
Growth to Excellence Act of 2013 - Amends part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to allow states to measure student progress toward academic achievement standards using adaptive assessments that are computerized, aligned with grade-level academic content standards, and measure student growth above and below grade level. Allows states, upon the Secretary of Education's approval, to adopt an alternative accountability model requiring their local educational agencies and public elementary and secondary schools to achieve adequate student growth toward college and career readiness standards. Requires such states to: (1) adopt college and career ready academic content standards; (2) adopt college and career ready assessments that measure annual student growth in mathematics and reading or the language arts; (3) measure secondary school graduation rates; (4) assess at least two additional indicators of students' college or career readiness; and (5) provide a comprehensive system of accountability for schools that do not meet annual progress targets, which shall categorize schools based on student performance, include supports and consequences based on such categorization, and provide incentives for schools that consistently exceed such targets. Requires an alternative accountability model to establish annual progress targets for each school that: (1) aim to reduce by half, in less than six years, the difference between the percentage of students (overall and in specified student subgroups) at the top performing schools who meet the college and career readiness standards or make adequate student growth, and the percentage of such students at each school that is not a top performing school; or (2) are calculated in another manner, but result in ambitious and achievable targets for students overall and in specified student subgroups. Requires annual progress targets for secondary schools that aim to reduce by half, in less than six years, the difference between the percentage of students who graduate and 90%. Describes what shall be considered adequate student growth toward college and career readiness standards.</summary>
</bill>
