<bill session="111" type="h" number="3158" updated="2013-07-19T23:40:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Place Based Health Care Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform health care delivery by providing incentives for place-based health care, which seeks to bring health services to the patient by locating community health centers, federally qualified health centers, and community integrated health centers in or near settings that already serve a particular target population, such as schools, workplaces, and senior services facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412212"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7921"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2009--Introduced.
Place Based Health Care Act of 2009 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to Eligible Community Integrated Health Centers, which are organizations: (1) seeking to fully integrate their health care services into the community by locating in or near settings that serve particular target populations, such as schools, workplaces, or senior service facilities; and (2) organized for the purpose of providing health care, improving the quality of health care, and reducing the costs associated with the provision of health care provided to Center patients. Requires states to implement procedures to pay for primary health services furnished in a school-based health clinic under Medicaid and the State Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP). Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a business credit for employer-provided health and wellness benefits. Amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 to require the Assistant Secretary for Aging to establish an evidence-based disease prevention and health promotion program. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to authorize a Medicare Advantage organization to offer a Medicare Advantage plan exclusively within a geographic area that is limited to a senior housing facility if certain requirements are met. Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary to award grants for the planning and delivery of services to a special medically underserved population comprised of: (1) school-aged children in a school-based health center; or (2) residents of Naturally Occurring Retirement Communities, patrons of multipurpose senior centers, and individuals living in areas and facilities immediately accessible to such Communities and centers.</summary>
</bill>
