<bill session="109" type="s" number="2589" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Fuel Management and Disposal Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance the management and disposal of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste, to ensure protection of public health and safety, to ensure the territorial integrity and security of the repository at Yucca Mountain, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300036"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2006-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3237"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3237-3239" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-736.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5360"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2610"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Trapping"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2006--Introduced.
Nuclear Fuel Management and Disposal Act - Withdraws specified land (as generally depicted on the Yucca Mountain Project Map) in Nye County, Nevada, from all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws. Transfers to the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) the land covered by such withdrawal that is under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned (the Secretary of the Air Force, or the Secretary of the Interior, depending upon the specific lands). Reserves the land covered by the withdrawal for use by the Secretary for specified activities associated with the disposal of high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel. Revokes Public Land Order 6802 of September 25, 1990, and a certain right-of-way reservation. Subjects the use of the land covered by the withdrawal to conditions the Secretary deems necessary to conduct activities related to the Yucca Mountain Project. Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 governing Yucca Mountain site application procedures to provide that an application for construction authorization shall not be required to contain information relating to any surface facility other than those necessary for initial operation of the repository. Revises requirements governing Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) actions on construction applications and infrastructure activities. Includes infrastructure activities within the scope of expedited authorizations. Prohibits surface or subsurface mining or oil or gas production, including slant drilling from outside the boundaries of the land covered by the withdrawal. Declares specified federal, state, or local regulatory requirements inapplicable to: (1) material owned by the Secretary that is transported or stored in an NRC-certified container for transportation or storage; or (2) material located at the Yucca Mountain site for disposal, if its management and disposal is subject to an NRC license. Prohibits a state or local governmental entity from issuing, administering, or enforcing a new or existing air quality permit or requirement affecting a federal facility or activity subject to the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982. Authorizes the Secretary to determine the extent to which certain transportation regulated under the Hazardous Materials Transportation Authorization Act of 1994 shall instead be regulated exclusively under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954. Deems the use of water from any source to implement this Act to be: (1) beneficial to interstate commerce; and (2) non-detrimental to the public interest. Requires the NRC, in deciding whether to permit the construction or operation of a nuclear reactor or any related facilities, to deem that sufficient capacity will be available in a timely manner to dispose of the spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste resulting from the operation of the reactor and related facilities.</summary>
</bill>
