<bill session="112" type="h" number="2110" updated="2013-07-20T01:28:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Long Island Sound Improvement Act Amendments of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to reauthorize and improve activities for the protection of the Long Island Sound watershed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2011-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3717"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3717"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Long Island Sound"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2011--Introduced.
Long Island Sound Improvement Act Amendments of 2011 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to create additional duties for the Long Island Sound Office of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), including studying the impacts of climate change on the Sound watershed. Requires a municipality that owns or operates a municipal separate storm sewer system to obtain, without regard to the size of the population served by the system, a permit for discharges composed entirely of stormwater for any portion of the municipality that is located within both the Long Island Sound watershed and an urbanized area. Authorizes such permits to be issued on a regional basis. Requires the EPA Administrator to ensure that: (1) permits held by industrial stormwater dischargers and permits held by construction activity dischargers conform to regional permits' conditions, and (2) monitoring requirements are included in a regional permit. Authorizes the Administrator to provide technical assistance to municipalities with respect to establishing regional permits. Establishes: (1) reporting requirements for the Office; and (2) requirements directing agencies to ensure that their property, actions, and activities within the watershed are consistent with the Long Island Sound Comprehensive Conservation and Management Plan (Plan) and to develop plans to maximize forest cover and riparian habitat and minimize stormwater discharge on agency property. Requires the Administrator to establish a voluntary interstate nitrogen trading program with respect to the Sound that includes the generation, trading, and use of nitrogen credits to facilitate the attainment and maintenance of the Sound Total Maximum Daily Load (TMDL). Authorizes: (1) grants for a prioritized list of projects and studies that will assist in meeting the Plan's goals and objectives; and (2) the Administrator to make grants for the construction of a publicly owned treatment work within Connecticut, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New York, Rhode Island, and Vermont solely to a municipal or state agency if the state has established allocations for discharges within the state in a Long Island Sound TMDL. Requires the Administrator to implement a pilot project to demonstrate the efficacy of nutrient bioextraction for the removal of nitrogen and phosphorous from the waters of the Sound watershed.</summary>
</bill>
