<bill session="112" type="s" number="1129" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Grazing Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to improve the management of grazing leases and permits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2012-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2012-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-642.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4234"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
Grazing Improvement Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (the Act) to double from 10 to 20 years the period of a term for grazing permits and leases for domestic livestock grazing on public lands or lands within national forests in 16 contiguous western states. Permits the issuance of permits and leases for a period shorter than 20 years (under current law, shorter than 10 years). Directs that grazing permits or leases issued by the Secretary of the Interior respecting lands under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Interior and grazing permits issued by the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) respecting National Forest System lands that expire, are transferred, or are waived after this Act's enactment be renewed or reissued, as appropriate, under the Act, Granger-Thye Act, Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act, or California Desert Protection Act of 1994. Excludes the renewal, reissuance, or transfer of a grazing permit or lease by the Secretary concerned from the requirement under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) to prepare an environmental analysis if such decision continues current grazing management of the allotment. Makes provisions of the Administrative Procedure Act applicable to appeals made by grazing permittees regarding grazing permits or leases under the Act and the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974.</summary>
</bill>
