<bill session="112" type="h" number="2030" updated="2013-07-20T01:27:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Green Infrastructure for Clean Water Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish centers of excellence for green infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412263"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2011-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2011-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2011-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2011-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2012-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2011-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2012-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2012-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2011-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2012-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2012-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2011-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2012-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2011-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2011-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
Green Infrastructure for Clean Water Act of 2011 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to make competitive grants to eligible higher education institutions and research institutions to establish and maintain between three and five centers of excellence for green infrastructure. Defines "green infrastructure" as a stormwater management technique that preserves, restores, enhances, or mimics natural hydrology. Establishes the duties of each center, including: (1) researching green infrastructure; (2) developing manuals and setting industry standards on best management practices relating to state, local, and commercial green infrastructure; (3) providing information about its research and manuals to the national electronic clearinghouse center; (4) providing technical assistance and training on green infrastructure; and (5) evaluating regulatory and policy issues about green infrastructure. Requires one of the centers to be designated as the national electronic clearinghouse center, which shall, in addition to its other duties, operate a website and a public database on green infrastructure. Requires the Administrator to make competitive grants to eligible entities that manage stormwater, water resources, or waste water resources to: (1) plan and design and install green infrastructure projects; (2) develop standards and revisions to local zoning, building, or other local codes necessary to accommodate such projects; (3) develop fee structures to provide financial support for green infrastructure; (4) develop training and educational materials about green infrastructure; (5) develop and implement a green infrastructure portfolio standard program; (6) monitor and evaluate the environmental, economic, or social benefits of green infrastructure; and (7) implement a best practices standard for a green infrastructure program. Requires the Administrator to give priority to applications from: (1) a community that has combined storm and sanitary sewers in its collection system or is low-income or disadvantaged; or (2) an eligible entity that will use 10% of the grant for a low-income or disadvantaged community. Requires the Administrator to: (1) ensure that&#160;EPA's Office of Water, the Office of Enforcement and Compliance, the Office of Research and Development, and the Office of Policy promote the use of green infrastructure and coordinate the integration of green infrastructure into permitting programs, planning efforts, research, technical assistance, and funding guidance; (2) direct each EPA regional office to promote and integrate the use of green infrastructure within the region;&#160;(3) create a green infrastructure compliance assistance center; and&#160;(4) establish measurable goals, to be known as the green infrastructure portfolio standard, to increase the percentage of annual water managed by eligible entities that uses green infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
