<bill session="111" type="s" number="796" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hardrock Mining and Reclamation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to modify the requirements applicable to locatable minerals on public domain land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4331-4333"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 111-116.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
Hardrock Mining and Reclamation Act of 2009 - Prohibits the issuance of a federal patent for any mining claim, millsite, or tunnel site (claim or site) unless the Secretary of the Interior determines that: (1) a patent application was filed by September 30, 1994; and (2) all application requirements were fully complied with by such date. Prescribes a mandatory claim maintenance fee and location fee for each claim or site. States that failure to perform assessment work, pay a mandatory maintenance or location fee, or file timely notice of location shall: (1) conclusively constitute forfeiture; and (2) make the claim or site null and void. Subjects production of locatable minerals from any mining claim to a royalty of between 2 % and 5% of the value of the production, not including reasonable transportation, beneficiation, and processing costs. Authorizes the Secretary to grant royalty relief. Directs the Secretary to establish a comprehensive inspection, collection, fiscal, and production accounting and auditing system to: (1) determine accurately any royalties, interest, fines, penalties, fees, deposits, and other payments owed; and (2) collect and account for such payments in a timely manner. Requires a permit to engage in the following activities on federal land: (1) mineral activities that would disturb surface resources, including land, air, water, and fish and wildlife; and (2) exploration and mineral activities that involve more than casual use of the land. Prescribes requirements for mining permits. Requires an operator to give the Secretary specified financial assurances before beginning any mineral activities requiring an exploration or mining permit in order to ensure reclamation and restoration of any land or water adversely affected by the activities. Establishes the Hardrock Minerals Reclamation Fund for the reclamation and restoration of land and water resources adversely affected by past hardrock minerals and mining and related activities in abandoned hardrock mine states, and on Indian land located within the exterior boundaries of abandoned hardrock mine states. Subjects each operator of a hardrock minerals mining operation to an abandoned mine land reclamation fee.</summary>
</bill>
