<bill session="112" type="h" number="3620" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Quality Care for Moms and Babies Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title IX of the Social Security Act to improve the quality, health outcomes, and value of maternity care under the Medicaid and CHIP programs by developing a maternity care quality measurement program, evaluating maternity care home models, and supporting maternity care quality collaboratives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2011-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="1969"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2011--Introduced.
Quality Care for Moms and Babies Act - Amends title XI of the Social Security Act (SSA) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop a maternity care quality measurement program with respect to childbearing women and newborns for voluntary use by: (1) a state in administering a state plan under SSA title XIX (Medicaid) or a state child health plan under SSA title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance) (CHIP), (2) health insurance issuers and managed care entities contracting with states to administer such plans, and (3) item and service providers (including accountable care organizations). Directs the Secretary to make grants to eligible entities to support: (1) the development of new state and regional maternity care quality collaboratives, (2) expanded activities of existing maternity care quality collaboratives, and (3) maternity care initiatives within established state and regional quality collaboratives that are not focused exclusively on maternity care. Requires the Secretary to establish a maternity care home demonstration program.</summary>
</bill>
