<bill session="109" type="hr" number="819" updated="2013-07-19T19:01:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Requesting the President and directing the Attorney General to submit to the House of Representatives all documents in the possession of the President and the Attorney General relating to requests made by the National Security Agency and other Federal agencies to telephone service providers requesting access to telephone communications records of persons in the United States and communications originating and terminating within the United States without a warrant.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400430"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-06-23T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 109-527.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-06-23T16:29:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="203">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 203.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Presidential records"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Resolutions of inquiry"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2006--Reported to House without amendment.
Requests the President, and directs the Attorney General, to submit to the House of Representatives, within 14 days of the adoption of this resolution, all documents in the possession of the President and the Attorney General, including all legal opinions, relating to requests made without a warrant by the National Security Agency (NSA) or other federal departments and agencies to telephone service providers, including wireless telephone service providers, for access to telephone communications records of persons in the United States (other than as authorized under titile I (Electronic Surveillance) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) or specified federal criminal law), subject to necessary redactions or requirements for handling classified documents.</summary>
</bill>
