<bill session="112" type="h" number="3205" updated="2013-07-20T01:37:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FDA Renewing Efficiency From Outside Reviewer Management Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to persons who, with respect to devices, are accredited to perform certain reviews or inspections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2011-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412441" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2011-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2011-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2012-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2011-10-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/14/2011--Introduced.
FDA Renewing Efficiency From Outside Reviewer Management Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to revise and extend through October 1, 2017, provisions authorizing accredited persons to provide classification reports for a medical device and to inspect class II device or class III device facilities. Deems a recommendation of an accredited person as to the classification of a medical device to be accepted by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) if the Secretary fails to make a determination with respect to the recommendation within 30 days. Requires the Secretary to regularly publish: (1) detailed decision summaries for each clearance of a device, classification of a device, approval of an application of a device, or grant of exemption for a device occurring after the enactment of this Act; and (2) total product life cycles information for devices. Expands the devices for which an accredited person may perform a review to include: (1) a class II device for which clinical data is required in the report, and (2) a class II device which is intended to be permanently implantable or life sustaining or supporting only if notification is provided to the Secretary before such a review. Deems the review permissible if the Secretary does not object within 60 days. Requires the Secretary to provide for the initial training and periodic updating of training of accredited persons. Makes accreditation valid for three years. Sets forth provisions regarding reaccreditation. Prohibits an accredited person from being a sole practitioner. Provides that the prohibitions against an accredited person being owned or controlled by a manufacturer, supplier, or vendor of devices or engaging in the design, manufacture, promotion, or sale of devices shall apply only if the devices are of the same type for which the person is accredited.</summary>
</bill>
