<bill session="111" type="s" number="4047" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FAST Deployment Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Acceleration of State Technologies Deployment Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Federal Acceleration of State Technologies Deployment Program and for related purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300007"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/17/2010--Introduced.
Federal Acceleration of State Technologies Deployment Act of 2009 or the FAST Deployment Act of 2010 - Directs the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development to establish a Federal Acceleration of State Technologies (FAST) Deployment Program to distribute matching federal funds to qualifying states. Requires each qualified state to use FAST grant funds exclusively for making assistance grants to small manufacturing enterprises for approved technology development projects. Establishes a national manufacturing technology database to disseminate to U.S. manufacturers information related to new U.S. manufacturing technologies. Requires an annual assessment of small manufacturing technology needs and information from such assessment to be incorporated into the database.</summary>
</bill>
