<bill session="113" type="s" number="800" updated="2013-11-02T06:58:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Treto Garza Far South Texas Veterans Inpatient Care Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that the South Texas Department of Veterans Affairs Health Care Center at Harlingen, located in Harlingen, Texas, includes a full-service inpatient health care facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to redesignate such center, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2963" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="552"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2013--Introduced.
Treto Garza Far South Texas Veterans Inpatient Care Act of 2013 - Redesignates the Department of Veterans Affairs Health Care Center in Harlingen, Texas, as the "Treto Garza South Texas Department of Veterans Affairs Health Care Center." Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) ensure that such Center includes a full-service inpatient health care facility, (2) modify the existing facility to meet such requirement, and (3) include in the annual VA strategic capital investment plan a project to expand the Center's capabilities to provide increased inpatient capacity, an urgent care center, and a full range of services for women veterans.</summary>
</bill>
