<bill session="113" type="s" number="598" updated="2013-11-02T06:57:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deepwater Drilling Royalty Relief Prohibition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit royalty incentives for deepwater drilling, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2013-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1907-1908"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1908" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2013--Introduced.
Deepwater Drilling Royalty Relief Prohibition Act - Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior from issuing any oil or gas lease sale under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act with royalty-based incentives in any tract located in water depths of 400 meters or more on the outer Continental Shelf. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to repeal royalty relief (suspension of royalties) for deepwater oil and gas production in the Western and Central Planning Area of the Gulf of Mexico (including the portion of the Eastern Planning Area encompassing whole lease blocks lying west of 87 degrees, 30 minutes West longitude). Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to prohibit the Secretary from reducing or eliminating any royalty or net profit share for any lease or unit located in water depths of 400 meters or more on the outer Continental Shelf.</summary>
</bill>
