<bill session="110" type="h" number="2257" updated="2013-07-19T21:23:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to increase the number of benefits claims representatives employed by the Department of Veterans Affairs, and to ensure that there are not fewer than two such claims representatives located at each center for the provision of readjustment counseling and related mental health services established under section 1712A of title 38, United States Code (commonly referred to as a "vet center"), to help reduce the backlog of claims pending with the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412239"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-10-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2007--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to increase the number of benefits claims representatives employed by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) so that there are no fewer than two representatives for each center for the provision of veterans' readjustment counseling and related mental health services (known as vet centers). Requires the Secretary to: (1) ensure that representatives have a specified level of knowledge of the benefits claims process; and (2) direct additional VA resources to more hours of social worker and mental health time, more staff to keep vet centers open longer, and the provision of links to veteran job centers and training.</summary>
</bill>
