<bill session="111" type="h" number="4156" updated="2013-07-19T23:49:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Increasing Housing Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for certain improvements in the laws relating to housing for veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412186"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2009-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2009--Introduced.
Increasing Housing Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to provide assistance to for-profit developers to expand the supply of supportive housing for veteran families, such assistance coming in the form of zero interest loans and project rental assistance. Requires: (1) not less than 75% of the units in such housing to be made available for occupancy only by veteran families; (2) rent contribution limits for low-income veterans; and (3) owners of assisted housing to ensure that veterans and their families are provided a range of supportive services tailored to their needs. Provides housing development cost limitations. Directs the HUD Secretary to provide information concerning the availability of such housing to the Secretaries of Veterans Affairs and Labor. Requires the repayment of housing assistance and the prevention of undue benefits with respect to housing that fails or ceases to be used for veterans' purposes. Provides funding for such assistance from the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) under the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008. Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to include veterans service agencies as entities authorized to submit state and local housing strategies for housing assistance provided under such Act. Requires a study by the Comptroller General on the availability of credit for veterans of Operations Iraqi Freedom and Enduring Freedom. Directs the HUD Secretary to carry out a program to provide mortgage assistance through the provision of grants and loans for direct mortgage payments on behalf of eligible households (households containing a member of the Armed Forces serving on active duty for more than 30 days). Outlines assistance requirements and limitations. Requires assistance repayment when the annual income of the household exceeds 200% of the poverty level applicable to that family size. Provides TARP funding for such assistance.</summary>
</bill>
