<bill session="110" type="s" number="3231" updated="2013-07-19T22:49:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Shark Conservation Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act and the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to improve the conservation of sharks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5741"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishery agreements"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Protection of animals"/>
    <term name="Sharks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2008--Introduced.
Shark Conservation Act of 2008 - Amends the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act to direct the Secretary of Commerce to list a nation in the biennial report on international compliance if the nation's fishing vessels are or have been engaged in fishing activities that target or incidentally catch sharks and the nation has not adopted a shark conservation program that is comparable, taking into account different conditions, to that of the United States, including measures to prohibit removal any of the fins of a shark (including the tail) and discarding the carcass of the shark at sea. Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to make it a prohibited act to: (1) remove any shark fin (including the tail) at sea; (2) have a fin aboard a fishing vessel unless the fin is naturally attached to the carcass; (3) transfer a fin from one vessel to another or receive a fin unless it is naturally attached; or (4) land a fin that is not naturally attached or a carcass without fins naturally attached. Eliminates a rebuttable presumption that any shark fins landed from or found on a fishing vessel were taken, held, or landed in violation if the total weight of shark fins landed or found exceeds 5% of the total weight of shark carcasses landed or found on board.</summary>
</bill>
