<bill session="109" type="h" number="2741" updated="2013-07-19T19:28:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Subcontractor Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to provide a penalty for the failure by a Federal contractor to subcontract with small businesses as described in its subcontracting plan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400438"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2005-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2005--Introduced.
Subcontractor Protection Act - Amends the Small Business Act to require a Federal agency to include in contracts awarded pursuant to a subcontracting plan calling for the maximum practicable opportunity for participation by small businesses owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals (qualified small businesses) a clause providing for the withholding of a specified amount or percentage of the total contract if the contractor does not achieve the percentage goal for the utilization of the qualified small businesses. Directs the awarding agency to require the contractor to provide written justification for not entering into a subcontract as required under the plan. Directs the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish a telephone line or other electronic means of communication through which a qualified small business may inform the SBA of any concerns regarding major deviations by prime contractors from the use of such qualified small businesses.Requires the consideration of the use of such qualified small businesses as subcontractors when determining a contractor's past compliance with other subcontracting plans.</summary>
</bill>
