<bill session="109" type="s" number="2999" updated="2013-07-19T20:39:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe and Timely Interstate Placement of Foster Children Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve protections for children and to hold States accountable for the safe and timely placement of children across State lines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2006-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="2006-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2006-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5120"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="5403"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2006--Introduced.
Safe and Timely Interstate Placement of Foster Children Act of 2006 - Amends the Social Security Act to require each state plan for foster care and adoption assistance to provide that the state shall: (1) have in effect procedures for orderly and timely interstate placement of children; (2) complete home studies requested by another state within a specified period; (3) accept such studies received from another state; and (4) not impose any restrictions on contracting with a private agency to conduct such a study. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants for timely interstate home study incentive payments to states that have approved plans and that have completed, and provided the Secretary a report on, such studies. Expresses the sense of Congress that state agencies should cooperate with courts which have authority with respect to the placement of a child in foster care or for adoption for the purpose of locating a parent of the child. Amends the definition of "case review system" to: (1) increase the required frequency of state caseworker visits to a child who is placed in foster care outside the state in which the child's parents reside; (2) require a child's health and education record to be supplied to the child at no cost when he/she leaves foster care by reason of having attained the age of majority under state law; and (3) provide for a foster parent's right (currently, opportunity) to be heard in any proceeding (currently, review or hearing) respecting their foster child. Requires state courts to ensure that foster parents, pre-adoptive parents, and relative caregivers of a child in foster care are notified of any such proceedings. Includes among the purposes of grants to the highest state courts the assessment of the court's role in carrying out state laws requiring proceedings that determine the best strategy to use to expedite the interstate placement of children. Provides for consideration of out-of-state placements in permanency hearings, case plans, and case reviews. Requires each plan for child welfare services to include the assurance that the state will eliminate legal barriers to facilitate timely adoptive or permanent placements for children.</summary>
</bill>
