<bill session="110" type="s" number="1080" updated="2013-07-19T22:29:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Crow Tribe Land Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to develop a program to acquire interests in land from eligible individuals within the Crow Reservation in the State of Montana, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 110-469.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-06-19">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2007--Introduced.
Crow Tribe Land Restoration Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a loan program to assist the Crow Tribe of the State of Montana in purchasing from eligible individuals land and interests in land within the Crow Reservation in the state. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into one or more loan obligation(s) with the Tribe as the Secretary determines necessary to fund such program. Allows the Secretary to accept from any eligible individual a donation of land or an interest in land within the Reservation to hold in trust for the benefit of the Tribe. Requires the Tribe to manage such land and interests in accordance with a land management program to be developed and implemented by the Tribe to achieve repayment of each applicable loan obligation issued pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
