<bill session="112" type="s" number="2241" updated="2013-07-20T02:35:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">GI Bill Consumer Awareness Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that veterans have the information and protections they require to make informed decisions regarding use of Post-9/11 Educational Assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2087-2088"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2088-2092" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-567.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-09-12">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/2012--Introduced.
GI Bill Consumer Awareness Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary), on an ongoing basis, to make available to veterans, members of the Armed Forces (members), and spouses and dependents eligible to receive, or who are receiving, educational assistance through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) or the Department of Defense (DOD) specified information about educational institutions and the programs of education available to such veterans and members. Directs the Secretary of Defense, on an ongoing basis, to make available to individuals eligible to receive, or who are receiving, assistance under the DOD Military Spouse Career Advancement Account program specified information about the types of accreditation available to educational institutions and programs of education, a general overview of federal student aid programs and the implications of incurring student loan debt, and educational program results. Provides additional requirements for institutions providing programs of education under VA and DOD educational assistance programs, including employee training about benefits and assistance available to veterans and members, and special advising and support services for such veterans and members. Prohibits the approval of a course of education if the institution: (1) requires a student enrolled to waive the right to legal recourse or submit to arbitration, or (2) imposes onerous legal notice provisions in the case of a dispute with the institution. Directs the Secretary to enter into a memorandum of understanding with each institution to carry out requirements protecting individuals receiving VA or DOD educational assistance. Requires the VA and DOD Secretaries to jointly develop policies to curb the aggressive recruiting (for enrollment) of veterans and members by educational institutions. Directs the Secretaries to establish a working group to: (1) coordinate consumer protection efforts of VA and DOD with respect to educational assistance provided, and (2) develop policies related to postsecondary education marketing and recruitment of veterans and members. Directs the Secretaries to assess, and report to Congress on, the quality and delivery of career information and counseling provided to veterans and members enrolled in programs of VA or DOD educational assistance. Makes eligible for VA educational and vocational counseling an individual serving on active duty in any state who has served in the Armed Forces on active duty for at least 180 days. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish procedures for the submission of complaints by students pursuing programs of VA or DOD educational assistance, (2) collect and disseminate information about best practices for the provision of educational assistance to veterans and members, and (3) report to Congress on the receipt of VA educational assistance. Directs the Secretary of Defense to establish and report on metrics for tracking the successful completion of DOD education and workforce training programs.</summary>
</bill>
