<bill session="112" type="h" number="56" updated="2013-07-20T01:10:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gulf Coast Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for restoration of the coastal areas of the Gulf of Mexico affected by the Deepwater Horizon oil spill, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2011-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2011-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2011-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2011-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412433" joined="2011-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412432" joined="2011-01-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1870"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1140"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
Gulf Coast Restoration Act - Establishes the Gulf Coast Ecosystem Restoration Task Force, which shall: (1) consult with, and provide recommendations to, the Chair of the Task Force regarding approval of State Coastal Ecosystem Restoration Plans submitted by the governors of Alabama, Florida, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Texas providing for restoration activities the Gulf Coast ecosystem adversely impacted by the blowout and explosion of the mobile offshore drilling unit Deepwater Horizon on April 20, 2010; (2) coordinate scientific and other research associated with restoration of such ecosystem; and (3) submit an annual report to Congress that summarizes the Plans approved by the Chair. Establishes in the Treasury the Gulf Coast Ecosystem Restoration Fund. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to deposit into the Fund sums equal to not less than 80% of any amounts collected by the United States as penalties, settlements, or fines under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) in relation to the Deepwater Horizon explosion and resulting hydrocarbon releases into the environment. Makes the Fund available for the conservation, protection, and restoration of the Gulf Coast ecosystem in accordance with approved Plans.Requires the governors of such states to: (1) submit a Plan to the Chair by October 1, 2011; and (2) solicit local input and provide for public participation in the development of the Plan. Requires the Chair to disburse amounts from such Fund to such a state for which the Chair has approved a Plan only for: (1) projects and activities for the conservation, protection, or restoration of coastal areas, including wetlands; (2) mitigation of damage to fish, wildlife, or natural resources; (3) planning assistance and the administrative costs of complying with this Act; and/or (4) implementation of a federally approved marine, coastal, or comprehensive conservation management plan.</summary>
</bill>
