<bill session="110" type="h" number="6658" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disaster Response, Recovery, and Mitigation Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to enhance the Nation's disaster preparedness, response, recovery, and mitigation capabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412234" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2008-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2008--Introduced.
Disaster Response, Recovery and Mitigation Enhancement Act of 2008 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to: (1) require the President to award financial assistance under the pre-disaster hazard mitigation program on a competitive basis; and (2) authorize continuing appropriations for such program through FY2011.Requires: (1) the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), to modernize and implement the integrated U.S. public alert and warning system; and (2) the Administrator to establish an Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee.Makes temporary FEMA employees hired in the aftermath of a disaster eligible to enroll in the Federal Employees Health Benefits Plan.Authorizes the President to transfer excess materials, supplies, or equipment acquired for response or recovery efforts in connection with a major disaster or emergency to a state, local government, or relief organization to assist victims of other major disasters, emergencies, or incidents. Directs the Administrator to: (1) continue to administer the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System; (2) provide for a national network of standardized search and rescue resources; (3) designate task forces to participate in the System and determine participation criteria; and (4) enter into annual preparedness cooperative agreements with sponsoring agencies.Provides for the establishment of a Disaster Relief Fund.Authorizes the President to: (1) increase disaster mitigation assistance to states that are actively enforcing approved building codes; and (2) provide temporary assistance in the form of mortgage or rental payments for individuals and families who, because of financial hardship caused by a major disaster, are at imminent risk of dispossession or eviction from a residence.Authorizes FEMA to rescue and shelter animals during disasters and emergencies.Authorizes the Administrator to: (1) continue to administer the Citizen Corps and the Community Emergency Response Team Program; and (2) make grants for implementation of the Emergency Management Assistance Compact.</summary>
</bill>
