<bill session="113" type="h" number="2793" updated="2013-11-02T06:42:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Financial Efficiency Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to permit the Government of the District of Columbia to determine the fiscal year for the Government of the District of Columbia, to amend such Act to make local funds of the District of Columbia available for use by the District at the beginning of the District's fiscal year at the rate of operations provided under the local budget act for the fiscal year if neither the regular District of Columbia appropriation bill nor a District of Columbia continuing resolution for the year does not become law prior to the beginning of such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1196"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3100"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2013--Introduced.
District of Columbia Financial Efficiency Act of 2013 - Amends the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to authorize a change of the District of Columbia fiscal year by an Act of the D.C. Council. Appropriates, out of any moneys of the District of Columbia government not otherwise appropriated, and out of applicable corporate or other revenues, receipts, and funds, the amount provided for any project or activity for which funds are provided in the local budget act for such fiscal year, if as of the first day of the District government fiscal year neither the regular District of Columbia appropriation bill for the fiscal year nor a District of Columbia continuing resolution for such fiscal year is in effect. Declares that an appropriation and funds made available or authority granted for a project or activity for a fiscal year under this Act shall be at the rate of operations provided for it under the local budget act for the fiscal year. Terminates such an appropriation and the availability of those funds: (1) during any period of the fiscal year in which a District of Columbia continuing resolution for the fiscal year is in effect, or (2) upon enactment of the regular District of Columbia appropriation bill for such fiscal year. Specifies restrictions on programs or activities subject to other appropriations Acts. States that nothing in this Act shall be construed to effect obligations of the District government mandated by other law. Increases the salary of the District's Chief Financial Officer to a rate that does not exceed the total annual compensation payable to the Vice President (currently, that does not exceed the rate at level I of the Executive Schedule).</summary>
</bill>
