<bill session="112" type="h" number="970" updated="2013-07-20T01:18:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Aviation Research and Development Reauthorization Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Federal Aviation Research and Development Reauthorization Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the civil aviation research and development projects and activities of the Federal Aviation Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400165"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2011-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 17 - 13.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-04-04T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 112-52.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-04-04T17:20:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="26">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 26.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="658"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/2011--Reported to House amended.
Title X: Federal Aviation Research and Development Reauthorization Act of 2011 - Federal Aviation Research and Development Reauthorization Act of 2011 - (Sec. 1003) Authorizes appropriations for FY2011-FY2014 for civil aviation research and development, including specified research, engineering, and development projects. (Sec. 1004) Requires the FAA Administrator to conduct or supervise specified research to develop technologies and methods to assess the risk of and prevent defects, failures, and malfunctions in all classes of drones. (Sec. 1005) Directs the FAA Administrator to conduct research on: (1) improved runway surfaces as well as engineered material restraining systems for such runways at both general aviation and commercial airports, and (2) methods and procedures to improve certification of new technologies for introduction into the national airspace system. (Sec. 1007) Converts the airport cooperative research program from a four-year pilot into a permanent program. (Sec. 1008) Authorizes the FAA Administrator to increase the federal share of costs of operating regional centers of air transportation excellence and related research activities from a maximum of 50% to a maximum of 75% for any fiscal year if a center is unable to carry out authorized activities without additional funding. (Sec. 1009) Authorizes the FAA Administrator to establish a center of excellence for aviation human resource research on: (1) human performance in the air transportation environment, including air traffic controllers, pilots, and technicians; and (2) any other aviation human resource issues pertinent to developing and maintaining a safe and efficient air transportation system. (Sec. 1010) Authorizes the FAA Administrator, in coordination with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), to: (1) maintain a research program to assess the potential effect of aviation on the environment and, if warranted, to evaluate approaches to address such effect; and (2) continue research and development into the qualification of and safe transition to the use of unleaded aviation fuel by the fleet of piston engine aircraft. (Sec. 1012) Directs the Secretary to establish a research grant program to develop technologies that produce jet fuel from alternative sources (such as coal, natural gas, biomass, ethanol, butanol, and hydrogen). (Sec. 1013) Directs the FAA Administrator to review FAA energy-, environment-, and aviation safety-related research programs.</summary>
</bill>
