<bill session="111" type="h" number="6270" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">MADE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Monuments Assembled and Domestically Engineered Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 89 of title 40, United States Code, to require commemorative works in the District of Columbia and its environs to be constructed of materials that are grown, produced, or manufactured in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412313" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Monuments Assembled and Domestically Engineered Act or the MADE Act - Requires a commemorative work in the District of Columbia and its environs to be constructed using: (1) unmanufactured material mined or produced in the United States; and (2) material manufactured in the United States substantially all from articles, materials, or supplies mined, produced, or manufactured in the United States. Requires the Secretary of the Interior or the Administrator of General Services (GSA), before issuing a permit for the construction of such a work, to determine that the contract documents demonstrate that the material to be used in its construction complies with such requirement.</summary>
</bill>
