<bill session="113" type="s" number="577" updated="2013-11-02T06:57:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Resident Physician Shortage Reduction Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for the distribution of additional residency positions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412586" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2013-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1180"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1201"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2013--Introduced.
Resident Physician Shortage Reduction Act of 2013 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with respect to distribution of additional resident positions as they affect calculation of payments for direct graduate medical education (DGME) costs. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), for each of FY2015-FY2019 (and each succeeding fiscal year if additional residency positions are available to distribute), to increase the otherwise applicable resident limit for each qualifying hospital. Requires the aggregate number of increases in the otherwise applicable resident limit to be 3,000 in each of FY2015-FY2019, of which 1,500 in each such fiscal year shall be used for full-time equivalent residents training in a shortage specialty residency program. Specifies the process for distributing positions. Declares that, for discharges occurring on or after July 1, 2015, the indirect teaching adjustment factor, with respect to additional payments for subsection (d) hospitals with indirect costs of medical education (IME), insofar as those additional payments are attributable to resident positions distributed to a hospital according to such process, shall be computed in a specified manner with respect to those resident positions. (Generally, a subsection [d] hospital is an acute hospital, particularly one that receives payments under Medicare's inpatient prospective payment system [IPPS] when providing covered inpatient services to eligible beneficiaries.) Directs the National Health Care Workforce Commission to study the physician workforce. Directs the Comptroller General to study strategies for increasing the diversity of the health profession workforce.</summary>
</bill>
