<bill session="109" type="h" number="1812" updated="2013-07-19T19:20:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-29">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patient Navigator Outreach and Chronic Disease Prevention Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Patient Navigator Outreach and Chronic Disease Prevention Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Patient Navigator Outreach and Chronic Disease Prevention Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Patient Navigator Outreach and Chronic Disease Prevention Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Patient Navigator Outreach and Chronic Disease Prevention Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize a demonstration grant program to provide patient navigator services to reduce barriers and improve health care outcomes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="2005-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-27">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-05-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-06-07T19:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 109-104.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-06-07T19:22:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="58">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 58.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-06-13T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gillmor moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-13T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4358-4361" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-13T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1812.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-06-13T14:12:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4358-4359" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-06-13T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-22">
      <text>Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7200" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-06-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2005-06-22">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2005-06-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-06-27">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-06-29">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-06-29" type="public" number="109-18">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-18.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="898"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="898"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2005--Public Law.
Patient Navigator Outreach and Chronic Disease Prevention Act of 2005 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to make grants to eligible entities for the development and operation of demonstration programs to provide patient navigator services to improve health care outcomes. Requires the Secretary to coordinate with, and ensure the participation of, the Indian Health Service, the National Cancer Institute, and the Office of Rural Health Policy. Requires that each grantee agree to recruit, assign, train, and employ patient navigators who have direct knowledge of the communities they serve to facilitate the care of individuals, including by: (1) acting as contacts for individuals seeking prevention or early detection services for cancer or other chronic diseases; (2) facilitating the involvement of community organizations to provide better access to high-quality health care services to individuals at risk for, or who have, cancer or other chronic diseases; (3) coordinating with the relevant health insurance ombudsman programs to provide information to such individuals about health coverage; (4) notifying individuals of clinical trials; (5) helping patients overcome barriers within the health care system to ensure prompt diagnostic and treatment resolution of an abnormal finding of cancer or other chronic disease; and (6) conducting ongoing outreach to health disparity populations. Requires the Secretary to: (1) require each grant recipient to prohibit patient navigators from accepting anything of value in return for referring an individual to a particular health care provider; and (2) prohibit the use of any grant funds to pay any fees or costs resulting from any proceeding to resolve a legal dispute. Allows the Secretary to grant awards for a period of no more than three years with a one year extension. Requires the Secretary to: (1) direct that each application for a grant outline how the eligible entity will establish baseline measures and benchmarks that meet the Secretary's requirements to evaluate program outcomes; (2) establish uniform baseline measures in order to properly evaluate the impact of the demonstration projects; (3) give preference to those entities that demonstrate plans to utilize patient navigator services to overcome significant barriers to improve health care outcomes within their respective communities; and (4) ensure coordination of the grant programs under this Act with existing authorized programs to facilitate access to high-quality health care services. Requires the Secretary to study the program and report to Congress on the results to include an evaluation of program outcomes and recommendations as to whether such programs could be used to improve patient outcomes in other public health areas. Sets forth reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
