<bill session="111" type="s" number="2741" updated="2013-07-20T00:50:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Telemedicine Enhancing Community Health (TECH) Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish telehealth pilot projects, expand access to stroke telehealth services under the Medicare program, improve access to "store-and-forward" telehealth services in facilities of the Indian Health Service and Federally qualified health centers, reimburse facilities of the Indian Health Service as originating sites, establish regulations to consider credentialing and privileging standards for originating sites with respect to receiving telehealth services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11216-11217"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/5/2009--Introduced.
Rural Telemedicine Enhancing Community Health (TECH) Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish telehealth pilot projects for the purpose of analyzing the clinical outcomes and cost effectiveness associated with telehealth services in a variety of geographic areas. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) provide for expansion of originating telehealth sites for stroke telehealth services; (2) provide access to store-and-forward telehealth services in facilities of the Indian Health Service and federally qualified health centers; and (3) direct the Secretary to establish reasonable regulations to consider the remote credentialing and privileging standards for originating sites with respect to telehealth services.</summary>
</bill>
