<bill session="111" type="h" number="5507" updated="2013-07-20T00:02:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Defense Alternative Energy Mapping Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Defense to identify areas on military installations and certain other properties as acceptable, unacceptable, or unassessed regarding their suitability for placement of geothermal, wind, solar photovoltaic, or solar thermal trough systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412218"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2010--Introduced.
Department of Defense Alternative Energy Mapping Act - Requires the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to: (1) prepare maps of military installations and eligible adjacent property that classify locations on the installations and property as acceptable, unacceptable, or unassessed regarding their suitability for placement of geothermal, wind, solar photovoltaic, or solar thermal trough systems; (2) enter into agreements with entities involved in the production or installation of alternative energy systems to utilize their expertise and to share the costs of preparing such maps; and (3) disseminate such maps to Congress, the states in which the installations are located, local governments having jurisdiction over adjacent land, and the owners of adjacent private property.</summary>
</bill>
