<bill session="110" type="s" number="1682" updated="2013-07-19T22:35:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Servicemembers' Healthcare Benefits and Rehabilitation Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to improve the management of medical care for members of the Armed Forces, to improve the speed and efficiency of the physical disability evaluation system of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8303-8304"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8303-8304" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="1670"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Brain"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Head injuries"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2007--Introduced.
Servicemembers' Healthcare Benefits and Rehabilitation Enhancement Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Defense to: (1) assign a medical care manager and a caseworker to each member of the Armed Forces who is undergoing medical treatment, recuperation, or therapy, or is otherwise in a medical hold or holdover status, for an injury, illness, or disease incurred or aggravated while on active duty (recovering member); and (2) undertake efforts to improve the speed and efficiency of the Department of Defense (DOD) physical disability evaluation system. Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit to the congressional defense and veterans' committees a plan to update the disability ratings schedule of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to reflect the effects on the modern workforce of mental health disorders, including traumatic brain injury (TBI) and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). Directs the Secretary of Defense to: (1) establish a system for the prioritization of processing the separation of members; (2) establish a medical record database to track and record the medical status of all members (and make such system accessible to the VA); (3) assess, both before and after, the mental health of each member who is deployed, or is expected to be deployed, to a combat theater; and (4) report, along with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, on plans to increase the role of private providers in the provision of rehabilitation to members and former members with TBI or PTSD when the VA is unable to provide such services. Requires the: (1) Secretary of the military department concerned to notify the appropriate Members of Congress of the hospitalization of any recovering member evacuated from a theater of combat; and (2) recovering member to consent to such notification.</summary>
</bill>
