<bill session="109" type="s" number="3931" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Electronic Surveillance bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Terrorist Surveillance Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish procedures for the review of electronic surveillance programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300045" joined="2006-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2006-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. pursuant to the order of September 21, 2006, as modified on September 22, 2006. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10044-10050" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-09-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="635">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 635.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3929"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2006--Introduced.
Terrorist Surveillance Act of 2006 - Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) to establish a new title relating to electronic surveillance programs (programs). Gives the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court (established under FISA) jurisdiction to review programs that seek to obtain foreign intelligence information or to protect against international terrorism. Allows the Court to issue an order that authorizes a program for up to 90 days, while allowing the Attorney General (AG) an unlimited number of times to seek reauthorization of an order with respect to a specific target. Outlines AG application requirements for approval of programs, including an explanation of how the program will ensure that communications acquired are of or with: (1) a foreign power, or agent of a foreign power, engaged in international terrorism; (2) a person believed to have communicated with or be associated with a foreign power or agent that engages in such activities; or (3) a foreign power or agent that poses an imminent threat of attack likely to cause death, serious bodily injury, or substantial economic damage to the United States. Provides for congressional oversight of approved programs through regular AG reports to the congressional intelligence committees. Directs the AG and the Director of National Intelligence to conduct a feasibility study to develop and implement a document management system that permits the prompt preparation, modification, and review of applications for orders approving programs by appropriate personnel of the Department of Justice (DOJ), Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), National Security Agency (NSA), and other applicable elements of the intelligence community. Includes as an "agent of a foreign power" under FISA a person other than a U.S. person who engages in the development or proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, or activities in preparation therefor.</summary>
</bill>
