<bill session="112" type="h" number="307" updated="2013-07-20T01:12:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Seed Availability and Competition Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require persons who seek to retain seed harvested from the planting of patented seeds to register with the Secretary of Agriculture and pay fees set by the Secretary for retaining such seed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400211"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-18">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition and Horticulture .</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Rural Development, Research, Biotechnology, and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Nutrition and Horticulture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG14" subcommittee="Rural Development, Research, Biotechnology, and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/18/2011--Introduced.
Seed Availability and Competition Act of 2011 - Permits a person who plants patented seed or seed derived from patented seed to retain harvested seed for replanting by such person if that person: (1) notifies the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) of the type and quantity of seed to be retained; and (2) pays the appropriate fee established by the Secretary. Establishes the Patented Seed Fund in the Treasury into which such fees shall be deposited and from which the Secretary shall pay appropriate fees to patent holders. Imposes an additional duty on the imported product of exported genetically modified seed on which royalties or other fees are charged by the patent owner to purchasers of the seed in the United States and on which no fees or lesser fees are charged to purchasers of the exported seed in a foreign country. Requires that such duties be deposited in the Fund for distribution to the appropriate patent holders.</summary>
</bill>
