<bill session="109" type="sr" number="467" updated="2013-07-19T20:10:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the President should use all diplomatic means necessary and reasonable to influence oil-producing nations to immediately increase oil production and that the Secretary of Energy should submit to Congress a report detailing the estimated production levels and estimated production capacity of all major oil-producing countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300045" joined="2006-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4077" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2006--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the President should use necessary and reasonable diplomatic means to influence oil producing nations to immediately increase oil production levels to increase world market supplies and lower prices; (2) a major oil-producing country is a country that had an average level of production of crude oil, oil sands, or natural gas to liquids that exceeded one million barrels per day during the previous calendar year, and has crude oil, shale oil, or oil sands reserves of at least six billion barrels; and (3) the Secretary of Energy should report to Congress detailing the estimated production levels and production capacity of all major oil-producing countries by June 30, 2006.</summary>
</bill>
