<bill session="112" type="h" number="4125" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting U.S. Missile Defense Information Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure the effectiveness of the missile defense system of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412395"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2012-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2012-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2012-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400439" joined="2012-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS29" subcommittee="Strategic Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2012--Introduced.
Protecting U.S. Missile Defense Information Act of 2012 - Prohibits Department of Defense (DOD) funds for FY2012-FY2013 from being used to provide the Russian Federation with access to: (1) U.S. missile defense technology, including hit-to-kill technology; or (2) data that supports U.S. missile defense capabilities. Prohibits such funds from being used to provide the Russian Federation with access to U.S. missile defense technology or data other than that described above unless, at least 30 days in advance, the President describes to Congress the data to be provided, along with a certification relating to the use of, and third-party access to, such data. Expresses the sense of Congress that an agreement regarding missile defense cooperation between the United States and the Russian Federation that is negotiated through the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) or a provision to amend the charter of the NATO-Russia Council shall not be legally or politically binding unless it is either specifically approved with the advice and consent of the Senate, or specifically authorized by an Act of Congress. Provides that no agreement with any country or international organization or amendment to the New START Treaty concerning limitations on U.S. missile defense capabilities shall be binding on the United States unless such agreement or amendment is either approved or authorized as above. Directs the President, beginning in 2013, to provide annual notification to Congress as to whether: (1) the Russian Federation has recognized the sovereign right of the United States to pursue improvements in missile defense capabilities; and (2) any Russian Federation representative has suggested that a treaty or other international agreement include provisions restricting U.S. missile defense capabilities or reducing the number of non-strategic nuclear weapons deployed in Europe. Prohibits DOD funds for FY2012 and thereafter from being used to implement a defense technology cooperation agreement between the United States and the Russian Federation until 60 days after the President transmits such agreement to Congress. Prohibits the use of any FY2012-FY2013 DOD or Department of State funds for travel expenses related to missile defense matters with the Russian Federation until 30 days after the President transmits to Congress the draft agreement discussed at Deauville, France, in May 2011.</summary>
</bill>
