<bill session="110" type="h" number="1484" updated="2013-07-19T21:16:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide consistent enforcement authority to the Bureau of Land Management, the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Forest Service to respond to violations of regulations regarding the management, use, and protection of public lands under the jurisdiction of these agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400394"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-12">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-12">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2241"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2007--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, the National Park Service Organic Act, the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966, and other federal law to provide that: (1) any person who knowingly violates or fails to comply with any of the provisions of such an Act or any regulation issued under such an Act concerning the management, use, and protection of Bureau of Land Management (BLM) lands, National Park System lands, National Wildlife Refuge lands, and National Forest lands shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor, subject to fine and/or imprisonment as provided under federal criminal law; and (2) any person who otherwise violates or fails to comply with any of the provisions of such an Act or any regulation issued under such an Act concerning the management, use, and protection of such lands shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor, subject to fine and/or imprisonment as provided under federal criminal law. Permits requiring persons adjudged guilty of a: (1) Class B misdemeanor on BLM or National Park System lands to pay all costs of the proceedings; and (2) a Class A or Class B misdemeanor on National Wildlife Refuge or National Forest lands to pay all costs of the proceedings. Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, the National Park Service Organic Act, and other federal law to set a minimum fine of $500 for certain fire usage violations on BLM, National Park System, and National Forest lands.</summary>
</bill>
