<bill session="113" type="hj" number="36" updated="2013-11-02T06:48:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution requiring that each agency and department's funding is justified.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412569"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412567" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2013-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution And Civil Justice.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hj" number="1"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hj" number="2"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hj" number="6"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hj" number="11"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hj" number="38"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hj" number="49"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="sj" number="20"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2013--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Prohibits total outlays for a fiscal year (except those for repayment of debt principal) from exceeding total receipts for that fiscal year (except those derived from borrowing) unless Congress, by a three-fifths rollcall vote of each chamber, authorizes a specific excess of outlays over receipts. Prohibits total outlays for any fiscal year from exceeding the following: for the first fiscal year for which this Amendment takes effect, 20% of the estimated gross domestic product (GDP) of the United States for that year, and for each subsequent fiscal year, a percentage of the estimated GDP equal to the applicable percentage for the preceding fiscal year reduced by .1%. States, however, that spending for any fiscal year is not required to be less than 16% of the estimated GDP. Requires a three-fifths rollcall vote of each chamber to increase the public debt limit. Directs the President to submit a balanced budget (budget plan) to Congress annually. Prohibits any bill to increase revenue from becoming law unless approved by a three-fifths majority of the whole number of each chamber by rollcall vote. Requires the budget plan to include a justification by each federal department or agency for any funding proposed in that plan. Authorizes waivers of these requirements: (1) when a declaration of war is in effect or under other specified circumstances involving military conflict, or (2) during declaration of a natural disaster.</summary>
</bill>
