<bill session="110" type="s" number="1818" updated="2013-07-19T22:36:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Missing Mercury in Manufacturing Monitoring and Mitigation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to phase out the use of mercury in the manufacture of chlorine and caustic soda, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-07-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9615"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5580"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Chlorine"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2007--Introduced.
Missing Mercury in Manufacturing Monitoring and Mitigation Act - Declares that the United States should develop policies and programs that will reduce: (1) mercury use and emissions; (2) mercury releases from the reservoir of mercury currently in use or circulation; and (3) exposures to mercury, particularly exposures of women of childbearing age and young children.Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to prohibit the manufacture of chlorine or caustic soda using mercury cells, effective January 1, 2012. Requires the owner or operator of each chlor-alkali facility to submit to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Administrator and the state in which the facility is located an annual report for 2008-2012 concerning mercury waste, emissions, and content in products.Requires EPA to conduct a comprehensive mercury inventory covering the life and closure of chlor-alkali facilities that cease operations on or after July 1, 2008. Establishes the Mercury Storage Advisory Committee, which shall report to Congress on: (1) requirements necessary to prevent the release of, or worker exposure to, elemental mercury; and (2) annual costs of, federal facilities needed for, barriers to, and an optimal plan for, mercury storage. Requires: (1) EPA to establish regulations to facilitate the transfer and storage of mercury located at closed facilities; and (2) beginning on July 1, 2008, the transfer of elemental mercury located at a closed facility that has ceased operations to a storage facility established by EPA in accordance with such regulations.Requires EPA, in coordination with the Administrator of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry Administrator, by July 1, 2009, to conduct a health assessment of employees at chlor-alkali facilities that continue to operate as of July 1, 2008.</summary>
</bill>
