<bill session="109" type="s" number="2259" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Ethics Enforcement Commission Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish an Office of Public Integrity in the Congress and a Congressional Ethics Enforcement Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2006-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S868"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2441-2442"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Contempt of legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="House Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Senate Ethics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2006--Introduced.
Congressional Ethics Enforcement Commission Act of 2006 - Establishes in the legislative branch the Office of Public Integrity and the Congressional Ethics Enforcement Commission, and vests in the latter the authority of the former. Grants the Commission authority to: (1) investigate lobbying disclosures filed with the Senate and the House of Representatives; (2) investigate Senate members and staff who violate restrictions on interactions with lobbyists; (3) conduct research concerning governmental ethics and implement any public educational programs it considers necessary to give effect to this Act; and (4) report annually to the Senate Select Committee on Ethics and the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct (ethics committees). Declares that investigation by the Commission shall be in lieu of the preliminary ethics investigation required for such ethics committees. Prohibits such committees from conducting preliminary investigations upon the Commission's establishment. Authorizes the Commission, upon a majority vote, to refer a case with evidence to the appropriate ethics committee. Authorizes the Office of Public Integrity, upon a majority vote of the Commission, to refer potential legal violations to the Department of Justice for civil enforcement. Subjects to fines, costs of the preliminary review, and penalties individuals who: (1) file false complaints with the Commission about alleged misconduct on the part of any legislator or other person; or (2) encourage another individual to do so.</summary>
</bill>
