<bill session="111" type="hr" number="875" updated="2013-07-19T23:03:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-29T14:29:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-10-29T14:29:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3854) to amend the Small Business Act and the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to improve programs providing access to capital under such Acts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412307"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-28T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-317, by Ms. Pingree (ME).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-28T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment. The Chair may entertain a motion that the Committee rise only if offered by the chair of the Committee on Small Business or her designee. The Chair may not entertain a motion to strike out the enacting words of the bill. It shall be in order at any time through the legislative day of October 30, 2009, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules relating to a measure addressing unemployment compensation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-10-28T16:42:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="124">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 124.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12069-12074" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 875.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29T14:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12074" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-10-29T14:29:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12069-12070" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29T14:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="3854"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3854) to amend the Small Business Act and the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to improve programs providing access to capital under such Acts.</summary>
</bill>
