<bill session="111" type="h" number="4791" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fort Hood Victims and Families Benefits Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that the victims and victims' families of the November 5, 2009, attack at Fort Hood, Texas, receive the same treatment, benefits, and honors as those Americans who have been killed or wounded in a combat zone overseas and their families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400068"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1416-1417, H1419, H1422"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4088"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="2807"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2010--Introduced.
Fort Hood Victims and Families Benefits Protection Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) any member of the Armed Forces who was killed or wounded in the attack at Fort Hood, Texas, on November 5, 2009, and the family members of those victims, should receive the same treatment and benefits as the victims and families of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks on the United States; (2) such members and families have made tremendous sacrifices, and the United States should provide them with the maximum level of benefits available, identical to that available to those killed or wounded in an overseas combat zone such as Iraq or Afghanistan; and (3) the Department of Defense (DOD) should honor the Americans killed or injured in such attack with awards that recognize their sacrifices, including the Purple Heart for members and the Secretary of Defense Medal for the Defense of Freedom for civilian DOD employees. Treats members and DOD civilian employees killed or wounded in the shootings at Fort Hood, Texas, as members killed or wounded in a combat zone or civilian employees killed or wounded in a terrorist attack or while serving in a contingency operation, respectively, for purposes of specified laws, regulations, and policies concerning compensation, awards, and other benefits for which such members and employees are eligible.</summary>
</bill>
