<bill session="110" type="h" number="6898" updated="2013-07-19T22:04:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health-e Information Technology Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote the adoption and meaningful use of health information technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2008-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2008-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2008-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2008-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2008-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2008-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1790"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2008--Introduced.
Health-e Information Technology Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish: (1) an Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology; and (2) an HIT Advisory Committee.Requires the National Coordinator to develop a Health Information Technology Resource Center and to recommend health information technology standards for adoption by the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Directs agencies to utilize, where available, health information technology systems and products that meet adopted standards.Requires the Director of the National Institute for Standards and Technology (NIST) to test adopted standards to assure the efficient implementation and use of such standards.Amends XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide for incentive payments to physicians and inpatient hospitals that meaningfully use a certified health information technology system.Authorizes the National Coordinator to award grants to purchase qualified health information technology and to implement regional or local health information plans.Provides for grants to develop academic curricula integrating qualified health information technology in the clinical education of health professionals.Revises provisions governing the privacy and security of health information, including to: (1) extend requirements to business associates of a covered entity; (2) require notification in the event of a breach of protected health information; (3) limit disclosure of such information to the minimum necessary to accomplish the intended purpose; and (4) revise penalties for violations.Requires the Secretary to appoint a Chief Privacy Officer of the Office of National Coordinator to assist in carrying out duties related to the privacy and security of health information.</summary>
</bill>
