<bill session="110" type="s" number="2101" updated="2013-07-19T22:38:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Savings Program Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to assist low-income Medicare beneficiaries by improving eligibility and services under the Medicare Savings Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-09-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12148-12149"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12149-12153" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3127"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Estates (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2007--Introduced.
Medicare Savings Program Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) with respect to the Qualified Medicare Beneficiaries (QMB) and Specified Low-Income Medicare Beneficiaries (SLMB) programs (Medicare Savings Program) to increase the income eligibility levels for: (1) QMBs to 135% of the federal poverty level (FPL); and (2) SLMBs to 150% of the FPL. Eliminates the application of estate recovery for Medicare Savings Program beneficiaries. Modifies the asset tests for QMBs and SLMBs. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide for expedited enrollment under the Medicare Savings Program through Social Security offices. Provides for treatment of QMBs, SLMBs, and other dual eligibles as Medicare beneficiaries.Amends SSA title XIX with respect to Medicaid treatment of certain Medicare providers.Directs the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services to examine and report on whether providers have attempted to make QMBs liable for deductibles, coinsurance, and co-payments in violation of applicable law. Requires the Secretary to report an enforcement plan of action to Congress regarding any QMBs that have been held so liable in violation of law.Requires states to provide medical assistance to dual eligibles in MedicareAdvantage (MA) plans.</summary>
</bill>
