<bill session="113" type="h" number="2733" updated="2013-11-02T06:42:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defending American Taxpayers From Abusive Government Takings Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac from purchasing, the FHA from insuring, and the Department of Agriculture from guaranteeing, making, or insuring, a mortgage that is secured by a residence or residential structure located in a county in which the State has used the power of eminent domain to take a residential mortgage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2767"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2013--Introduced.
Defending American Taxpayers From Abusive Government Takings Act of 2013 - Amends the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act, the National Housing Act, and the Housing Act of 1949, respectively, to prohibit the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) from purchasing, the Federal Housing Authority (FHA) from insuring, and the Department of Agriculture from newly guaranteeing, making, or insuring any mortgage secured by a structure or dwelling unit located in a county in which the state, including an agency or local government, has used the power of eminent domain to take a residential mortgage.</summary>
</bill>
