<bill session="112" type="s" number="1319" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Electronic Life Safety and Security Systems Federal Background Check Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Attorney General to establish a system of background checks for employers and employees of the electronic life safety and security system installation and monitoring industry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1331"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2011--Introduced.
Electronic Life Safety and Security Systems Federal Background Check Act of 2011 - Directs the Attorney General to establish a method to permit employers in the electronic life safety and security systems installation and monitoring industry to request state and federal fingerprint-based background checks and to provide any resulting relevant criminal history record information about employees and prospective employees. Requires that such method allow employers to: (1) discover if employees or prospective employees have been convicted of a felony or of an offense involving dishonesty or false statement or the use of force against another person during the 10-year period before the background check is conducted; and (2) obtain a background check of state and federal criminal history record information by submitting fingerprints to the Attorney General through the criminal history record repository of the state in which the employer is located. Prohibits such method from duplicating access by an employer where state licensing and regulation of an employee already requires a federal background check. Directs the Attorney General, in establishing such method, to give due consideration to privacy protections and employee rights, including by providing employees an effective means to dispute or seek a correction of the outcome of the background check.</summary>
</bill>
