<bill session="111" type="h" number="3993" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-23T16:59:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-23T16:59:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Calling Card Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Calling Card Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Calling Card Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require accurate and reasonable disclosure of the terms and conditions of prepaid telephone calling cards and services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2010-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2010-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15T17:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 111-507.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-06-15T17:20:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="290">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 290.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23T12:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Matsui moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23T12:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4698-4701" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23T12:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3993.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23T12:48:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4731-4732" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-06-23T16:59:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="383" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 381 - 41 (Roll no. 383).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4698-4700" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23T16:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="562"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2010--Passed House amended.
Calling Card Consumer Protection Act - (Sec. 3) Requires providers or distributors of prepaid calling cards, including cards that use interconnected Voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP) or a successor protocol, to accurately disclose in a clear and conspicuous manner information about: (1) the provider's name, customer service number, and hours of service; (2) the card's number of minutes or dollar value; (3) per minute rates or a toll-free number to obtain rates; (4) fees and charges; (5) time period limits, any predetermined decrease in value over a period of time, and expiration dates; and (6) refund and recharge policies. Prohibits false, misleading, or deceptive disclosures on any calling card, packaging, advertisement, or related promotional material. Requires disclosures to be clear and conspicuous and located on the prepaid calling card unless the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) determines otherwise. (Sec. 4) Treats a violation as an unfair or deceptive act or practice under the Federal Trade Commission Act and requires the FTC to enforce this Act. (Sec. 5) Authorizes a state to enforce the provisions of this Act through a civil action to: (1) enjoin a practice; (2) enforce compliance; (3) obtain damage, restitution, or other compensation; or (4) obtain other appropriate relief. Requires a state before bringing such an action to provide the FTC with written notice and a copy of the complaint (unless the provision of notice is not feasible). Authorizes the FTC to intervene in any such action, which shall include the right to: (1) be heard with respect to any matter that arises in the action; (2) remove the action to U.S. district court; and (3) petition for appeal. (Sec. 6) Applies the provisions of this Act, beginning 180 days after the date on which final regulations are promulgated, to: (1) any prepaid calling card issued or placed into the stream of commerce; and (2) any related advertising, promotion, point-of-sale material, or voice prompt. (Sec. 7) Prohibits a state, after the date on which final regulations are promulgated, from establishing or continuing any law regarding disclosures to be printed on prepaid calling cards or packaging unless such requirements are identical to the requirements under this Act. (Sec. 8) Requires studies and reports to Congress by: (1) the Comptroller General on the effectiveness of this Act and its required disclosures; and (2) the FTC on the extent to which the business practices of the prepaid calling card industry exist in the prepaid wireless industry.</summary>
</bill>
