<bill session="113" type="h" number="2838" updated="2013-11-02T06:42:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Puerto Rico Interstate Commerce Improvement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 46, United States Code, with respect to coastwise endorsements and Puerto Rico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412306"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2013--Introduced.
Puerto Rico Interstate Commerce Improvement Act of 2013 - Amends federal shipping law to revise coastwise endorsement requirements for certain vessels that transport liquified natural gas or liquified petroleum gas to Puerto Rico from other U.S. ports. Repeals authority to issue a certificate of documentation with a coastwise endorsement for a vessel to transport liquified natural gas or liquified petroleum gas to Puerto Rico from other ports in the United States, if the vessel: (1) is a foreign built vessel that was built before October 19, 1996; or (2) was documented before that date, even if it is placed under a foreign registry and subsequently redocumented for operation. Exempts from coastwise endorsement requirements self-propelled vessels that transport bulk cargo, including liquified natural gas or liquified petroleum bulk cargo, to Puerto Rico from another U.S. port or from Puerto Rico to another U.S. port.</summary>
</bill>
