<bill session="113" type="h" number="2967" updated="2013-11-02T06:44:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INFORM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Intergenerational Financial Obligations Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for fiscal gap and generational accounting analysis in the legislative process, the President's budget, and annual long-term fiscal outlook reports.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412314"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412547" joined="2013-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412428" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1351"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional Budget Office (CBO)"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
Intergenerational Financial Obligations Reform Act or INFORM Act - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to provide certain information on any legislation or resolution considered in either chamber which would impact revenues or mandatory spending by greater than 0.5% of gross domestic product (GDP) over the following 10-fiscal-year period, and upon request by the Chairmen or Ranking Members of the congressional budget committees. Requires such information to comprise: a fiscal gap and generational accounting analysis, including any change in the analysis relative to the baseline; and the federal deficit, at current spending levels, in the fiscal year that is 75 years after the fiscal year in which the legislation is being considered, as well as the stock of the debt in that 75th year. Requires: (1) CBO to produce an annual fiscal gap and generational accounting analysis within its annual "Long-Term Budget Outlook" and post it on the CBO public website, and (2) the Comptroller General to produce a separate similar analysis within its annual "Long-Term Fiscal Outlook" and post it on the General Accountability Office (GAO) public website. Requires the President's budget submission to Congress to include: a fiscal gap and generational accounting analysis of the full budget proposal; the same kind of analysis of specific policy changes that would impact revenues or mandatory spending by greater than 0.5% of GDP over the following 10-fiscal year period; and the federal deficit, at current spending levels, in the fiscal year that is 75 years after the fiscal year in which the legislation is being considered, as well as the stock of the debt in that 75th year.</summary>
</bill>
