<bill session="109" type="h" number="1960" updated="2013-07-19T19:21:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pension Preservation and Savings Expansion Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand pension coverage and savings opportunities and to provide other pension reforms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400325"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1961"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Golden parachutes"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2005--Introduced.
Pension Preservation and Savings Expansion Act of 2005 -Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise provisions relating to qualified retirement and employee benefit plans. Makes permanent: (1) pension and individual retirement account provisions enacted by the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 (EGTRRA); and (2) the tax credit for elective deferrals and individual retirement account contributions (saver's credit). Increases the amount of the saver's credit and makes such credit refundable. Renames Roth IRAs as Retirement Savings Accounts (RSAs) and allows for direct rollovers from qualified retirement plans to RSAs. Makes various changes to qualified pension plan provisions, including: (1) reducing the vesting period for employer contributions to defined contribution plans; (2) allowing rollovers from plans of deceased employees to non-spouses; (3) allowing disabled individuals without earned income to make tax deductible contributions to retirement savings accounts; (4) allowing exclusions from gross income for certain lifetime annuity payments; and (5) providing for automatic employee contributions to pension plans and automatic contribution increases. Revises rules and definitions relating to: (1) salary reduction plans; (2) matching contribution rules for IRAs and 401(k) plans; (3) withdrawals from plans for death, disability, and hardship; (4) minimum distribution rules; and (5) catch-up contributions. Imposes a penalty tax up to 50 percent of excessive employee remuneration paid by a company after a declaration of bankruptcy. Requires the administrators of defined benefit and defined contribution plans to provide plan participants with periodic statements of plan benefits. Directs the Secretary of Labor to develop a model benefit statement.</summary>
</bill>
