<bill session="111" type="sr" number="446" updated="2013-07-20T00:20:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution commemorating the 40th anniversary of the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1263-1264" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-04-13">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-04-13">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-04-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="345">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 345.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Reaffirms Senate support for the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons. Urges the President to: (1) work to achieve universal Treaty compliance; and (2) ensure that the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) has the necessary resources to conduct its Treaty oversight responsibilities. Encourages the President to work with: (1) international partners and Treaty states to promote the Model Additional Protocol to all Safeguards Agreements as the global standard for safeguards and a requirement for nuclear commerce; and (2) other Treaty states to strengthen compliance and enforcement mechanisms and develop collective responses in the U.N. Security Council and other multilateral fora to any notification of Treaty withdrawal.</summary>
</bill>
