<bill session="110" type="s" number="1876" updated="2013-07-19T22:36:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Security with Justice Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit extraterritorial detention and rendition, except under limited circumstances, to modify the definition of "unlawful enemy combatant" for purposes of military commissions, to extend statutory habeas corpus to detainees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2007-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9922-9923"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9923-9926" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Suspects' rights"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2007--Introduced.
National Security with Justice Act of 2007 - Prohibits, with specified exceptions, a U.S. officer or agent from: (1) engaging in the extraterritorial (outside of the United States) detention of any individual; or (2) rendering (transferring to another legal jurisdiction) or participating in the rendition of any individual. Authorizes a U.S. officer or agent to apply for an order of rendition, and a judge of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court (Court) to issue such an order, under specified procedures. Provides for: (1) authorizations and orders for emergency detention; (2) uniform standards for the interrogation of individuals detained by the U.S. government; (3) protection of government officials engaged in interrogations; (4) monitoring and reporting regarding the treatment, conditions of confinement, and status of legal proceedings of individuals rendered to foreign governments; and (5) additional judges and other personnel for the Court. Revises the definition of "unlawful enemy combatant" for purposes of military commissions. Extends statutory habeas corpus to persons detained by the United States who have been: (1) determined to have been properly detained as an enemy combatant; or (2) detained for more than 90 days without such a determination.</summary>
</bill>
