<bill session="110" type="h" number="5622" updated="2013-07-19T21:53:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Timely Access to Health Care Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to establish standards of access to care for veterans seeking health care from certain Department of Veterans Affairs medical facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400051"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2008--Introduced.
Veterans Timely Access to Health Care Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct a five-year pilot program to ensure that, for each veteran seeking primary care from a participating medical facility, the standard for access to such care, determined from the date that the veteran contacts the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) seeking an appointment until a visit with a primary-care provider is completed, is 30 days. Directs the Secretary to periodically review the performance of VA health-care facilities in meeting such standards. Authorizes the Secretary to contract for health care services in non-VA facilities when the Secretary is unable to meet access standards.</summary>
</bill>
