<bill session="110" type="s" number="3212" updated="2013-07-19T22:49:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bipartisan Electronic Voting Reform Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to provide for auditable, independent verification of ballots, to ensure the security of voting systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2008-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Rules and Administration. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Rules and Administration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3722"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Test facilities"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Voting machines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2008--Introduced.
Bipartisan Electronic Voting Reform Act of 2008 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require any voting system other than one using paper ballots personally marked by the voter to permit independent verification of cast ballots by various specified means, including paper or electronic.Requires each state to conduct an audit of every federal election to ensure that each certificate of election is justified by the vote totals. Directs the Federal Election Commission to establish an Audit Guidelines Development Task Force to assist the Commission in developing model audit guidelines.Prescribes election security requirements for voting systems, including: (1) chain of custody protocols; (2) disclosure of election-dedicated software; and (3) minimum state standards to ensure the integrity of the voting process and education and training of poll workers.Establishes accreditation requirements for laboratories involved in testing of voting system hardware and software. Directs the Commission to establish the Testing Escrow Account for payments to accredited laboratories for testing of such hardware and software.Requires the Commission to make grants for: (1) development and testing of new voting systems, technologies, and innovations to meet independent verification requirements under this Act; and (2) pilot programs for such testing.Directs the Commission to establish a task force to study and develop recommendations regarding the appropriate level of funding for requirements payments.Amends the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to prohibit state refusal to accept voter registration and absentee ballot applications and federal write-in absentee ballots for failure to meet nonessential requirements.</summary>
</bill>
