<bill session="113" type="h" number="1421" updated="2013-11-02T06:31:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Innovative Manufacturing Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To accelerate research, development, and innovation in advanced manufacturing, to improve the competitiveness of American manufacturers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412512" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400657" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412519" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412514" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY15" subcommittee="Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2013--Introduced.
Advancing Innovative Manufacturing Act of 2013 - Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to carry out a program to develop and support industry-led consortia that will identify, prioritize, and address long-term, precompetitive industrial research needs in the area of advanced manufacturing, including through the use of technology roadmaps and transfer of technology platforms and infrastructure. Requires the Director to carry out a pilot program (through the award of competitive, merit-reviewed grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts to small- or medium-sized manufacturers) to enhance the innovative capabilities and competitiveness of such manufacturers through support for research and development that will promote the field of advanced manufacturing and lead to the commercialization of new products, processes, or technologies. Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish an innovation voucher pilot program to accelerate innovative activities and enhance the competitiveness of small- and medium-sized manufacturers, which shall: (1) foster collaborations between such manufacturers and research institutions, and (2) enable the manufacturers to access technical expertise and capabilities that will lead to the development of innovative products or manufacturing processes. Amends the America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2010 to revise the program of grants for education and training in advanced manufacturing so that such grants are provided to community colleges for the development and implementation of innovative education reforms to ensure an adequate and well-trained advanced manufacturing workforce. Lists activities that may be supported by such grants, including for: (1) the development of teaching materials and methods, (2) faculty professional development, (3) centers to provide models and leadership, (4) activities to enhance student recruitment and retention, and (5) partnerships to ensure the development of an advanced manufacturing workforce with skills necessary to meet regional economic needs.</summary>
</bill>
