<bill session="110" type="h" number="6976" updated="2013-07-19T22:04:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preventing Manipulation in Commodity Markets Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Commodity Exchange Act to bring greater transparency and accountability to commodity markets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400396"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400092" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2008-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1851"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6604"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2008--Introduced.
Preventing Manipulation in Commodity Markets Act of 2008 - Amends the Commodity Exchange Act to define "energy commodity." Prohibits the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) from permitting a foreign board of trade to provide its U.S-located members with access to the CFTC electronic trading system and order matching system for energy or agricultural commodities unless such board meets requirements similar to those imposed upon U.S. exchanges. Subjects swap transactions, transactions for agricultural and energy commodities, and large traders in over-the-counter contracts to reporting and recordkeeping requirements. Directs the Commission to: (1) set position limits for any one person with respect to designated contract markets, derivative transaction execution facilities, and electronic trading facilities; (2) convene a Position Limit Agricultural Advisory Group and a Position Limit Energy Group; (3) appoint at least 100 new full-time employees; (4) review prior actions to ensure compliance with this Act; and (5) review over-the-counter markets. Revises the core principles applicable to position limits for contracts in agricultural and energy commodities to require position limits for speculators. Directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to conduct a study of: (1) the international regime for regulating the trading of energy commodity futures and derivatives; and (2) speculators' effects on agriculture and energy futures markets and prices. Directs the Commission to: (1) require regular reporting of fungible over-the-counter agricultural and energy transactions; and (2) determine if such transactions have the potential to disrupt market liquidity or cause market or price disturbances, and if so, to use its discretion to impose position limits. Authorizes the Commission to use expedited procedures to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
