<bill session="109" type="s" number="731" updated="2013-07-19T20:19:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tribal Colleges and Universities Teacher Loan Forgiveness Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Tribal Colleges and Universities Faculty Loan Forgiveness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to recruit and retain more qualified individuals to teach in Tribal Colleges or Universities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300015" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2006-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2005-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3314"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-12">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator McCain with amendments. With written report No. 109-205.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-12-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="323">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 323.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="College teachers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2005--Reported to Senate amended.
Tribal Colleges and Universities Faculty Loan Forgiveness Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for the cancellation of a specified percentage of the total amount of any Federal Perkins loan, Federal Family Education loan, or direct student loan for each year of employment (up to five) as a full-time faculty member at a tribal college or university if the borrower is not in default on such loan. Requires the Secretary to assume or cancel the obligation to repay: (1) 15% of the amount of all such loans made, insured, or guaranteed after enactment of this Act to a student for the first or second year of employment; (2) 20% for the third or fourth year of such employment; and (3) 30% for the fifth year. Limits the total amount of loan repayment or cancellation per student to $15,000. Allows for repayment or cancellation of consolidation loans only to the extent of the qualified student loans involved. Prohibits a borrower from receiving, for the same service, both a benefit from this Act and a benefit from the National Community Service Act of 1990. Amends the Public Health Service Act to provide for repayment by the Secretary of Health and Human Services of educational loans for nurse training costs on behalf of nursing instructors at tribal colleges or universities, or any land-grant institution listed in the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994. Provides that the amount of any loan forgiven under this Act shall not be treated as gross income for federal tax purposes.</summary>
</bill>
