<bill session="113" type="h" number="2688" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PATIENT's Health Care Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Accountability and Transparency to Incentivize Economically Necessary Transitions in Health Care Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve healthcare-related, tax-preferred savings accounts and to provide for cooperative governing of individual and group health insurance coverage across State lines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412411"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="762"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2835"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3165"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2013--Introduced.
Providing Accountability and Transparency to Incentivize Economically Necessary Transitions in Health Care Act of 2013 or the PATIENT's Health Care Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to health savings accounts (HSAs), to: allow a new tax deduction for premiums paid for a high deductible health care plan; repeal the requirement that an individual making a tax deductible contribution to an HSA be covered by a high deductible health care plan; increase the maximum HSA contribution level; allow Medicare beneficiaries to contribute to an HSA; allow a rollover of HSA amounts to a Medicare Advantage Medical Savings Account (MSA); allow a transfer of a flexible spending arrangement balance to an HSA upon separation from employment; allow payments of high deductible health plan premiums from HSAs; repeal the prohibition against payment of over-the-counter drugs from HSAs, Archer MSAs, and health flexible spending and reimbursement arrangements; allow payment of long-term care premiums from health flexible spending arrangements; allow a rollover of Archer MSA and HSA amounts to adult children of an account holder; allow a carryover of up to $500 of unused health benefits in cafeteria plans and flexible spending arrangements; allow Medicare beneficiaries to contribute to a Medicare Advantage MSA; and establish child health savings accounts and allow tax deductible contributions to such accounts. Amends the Public Health Service Act to permit the operation of individual and group health insurance plans across state lines. Sets forth requirements and limitations applicable to issuers of such plans in the primary and secondary states governing such issuers. Extends through December 31, 2016, the Preexisting Condition Insurance Plan (PCIP program) established by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</summary>
</bill>
