<bill session="113" type="h" number="1205" updated="2013-11-02T06:29:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patients Right to Know Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to require health insurance issuers and group health plans to disclose information regarding how certain taxes and fees impact the amount of premiums, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400419"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412427" joined="2013-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2013-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="764"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2013--Introduced.
Patients Right to Know Act of 2013 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require health plans to include in their annual summary of benefits and coverage explanations: (1) the annual fee on health insurance providers under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, (2) the annual fees imposed on health insurance policies, (3) required contributions by health plans to the reinsurance program, (4) user fees on health plans participating in health insurance exchanges, (5) payments by health plans whose costs are lower than the target amount (premiums collected minus administrative costs), and (6) charges assessed by states on health plans whose enrollees have a lower actuarial risk than the average actuarial risk of all enrollees in a state. Allows such costs to be calculated separately for individual, small group, or large group markets. Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to study the methods of calculating the impact on average premium costs associated with: (1) guaranteed issuance of coverage and community rated premiums, (2) limitations on age rating, (3) required coverage of women's preventive services, and (4) the requirement that plans cover at least 60% of the actuarial value of essential health benefits.</summary>
</bill>
