<bill session="111" type="h" number="14" updated="2013-07-19T23:12:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FOARAM Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for ocean acidification research and monitoring, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2009-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2009-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2009-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2009-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2009-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International scientific cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/2009--Introduced.
Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2009 or FOARAM Act - Defines "ocean acidification," for this Act, as the decrease in pH of the Earth's oceans and changes in ocean chemistry caused by chemical inputs from the atmosphere, including carbon dioxide. Requires the Joint Subcommittee on Ocean Science and Technology of the National Science and Technology Council to develop a strategic plan for federal ocean acidification research and monitoring that provides for an assessment of ocean acidification impacts on marine organisms and ecosystems and the development of adaptation and mitigation strategies to conserve marine organisms and ecosystems. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to conduct research and monitoring and authorizes the Secretary to establish an ocean acidification program in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) consistent with the strategic research plan, including: (1) providing grants for critical research projects exploring the effects of ocean acidification on ecosystems and the socioeconomic impacts of increased ocean acidification; and (2) incorporating a competitive merit-based process for awarding grants that may be conducted jointly with other participating agencies or under the National Oceanographic Partnership Program. Requires the National Science Foundation (NSF) director to continue to carry out ocean acidification research supporting competitive, merit-based, peer-reviewed proposals for research and monitoring of ocean acidification and its impacts. Requires the administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to ensure that space-based monitoring assets are used in as productive a manner as possible for monitoring of ocean acidification and its impacts.</summary>
</bill>
