<bill session="109" type="s" number="3649" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bolster Our Energy Security for Tomorrow Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to expedite the consideration of permits for refineries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300004"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9242"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2006--Introduced.
Bolster Our Energy Security for Tomorrow Act - Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), upon state request, to provide financial assistance to facilitate hiring additional personnel with expertise in fields relevant to consideration of federal refinery authorizations. Directs a federal agency responsible for federal refinery authorization, upon state request, to provide technical, legal, or other nonfinancial assistance to facilitate such consideration. Directs the President to: (1) appoint a federal coordinator to coordinate refinery authorization procedures; and (2) designate at least three closed military installations, or portions of them, as potentially suitable for the construction of a refinery. Requires that at least one such site be designated as potentially suitable for construction of a biomass refinery. Requires the appropriate redevelopment authority to consider the feasibility and practicability of siting a refinery on the closed military installation when preparing or revising the redevelopment plan for it. Prescribes guidelines for the management and disposal of real property. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to repeal its refinery revitalization authority.</summary>
</bill>
