<bill session="109" type="h" number="2875" updated="2013-07-19T19:29:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Lands Corps Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Public Lands Corps Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Lands Corps Act of 1993 to provide for the conduct of projects that protect forests, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400419"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2005-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-11-07T19:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-273, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-07T19:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-07T19:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Education and the Workforce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-11-07T19:31:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="149">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 149.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Dairy, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="21st Century Competitiveness" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="1238"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1238"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1238"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Tree diseases"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/7/2005--Reported to House amended.
Public Lands Corps Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2005 - Amends the Public Lands Corps Act of 1993 to: (1) allow the Secretary (the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to National Forest System land or the Secretary of the Interior with respect to Indian lands, Hawaiian home lands, or lands administered by the Department of the Interior) for purposes of entering into contracts and cooperative agreements under such Act, to give preference to qualified youth or conservation corps located in a specific area that have a substantial portion of members who are economically, physically, or educationally disadvantaged to carry out projects within the area; (2) require the Secretary, in carrying out priority projects (as defined by this Act) in a specific area, to give preference to qualified youth or conservation corps located in that specific area that have a substantial portion of such members; (3) allow the Secretary to authorize appropriate conservation projects and other appropriate projects to be carried out on federal, state, local, or private land as part of a federal disaster prevention or relief effort; (4) modify requirements for the establishment and use of conservation centers; (5) authorize the Secretary to provide any appropriate services, facilities, equipment, supplies, technical assistance, oversight, monitoring, or evaluations to carry out such Act; (6) require the Secretary to provide each participant in the Public Lands Corps and each resource assistant with a living allowance as established by the Secretary; and (7) permit the Secretary to grant members of the Public Lands Corps credit for time served with the Corps, which may be used toward future federal hiring and to provide to a former member of the Corps noncompetitive hiring status for a specified period after the date on which such member's service with the Corps is complete. Provides that amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under this Act are in addition to amounts allocated to the Public Lands Corps through other federal programs or projects. Authorizes appropriations to carry out such Act. Instructs that not less than two-thirds of such appropriated amounts shall be used to conduct priority projects.</summary>
</bill>
