<bill session="109" type="h" number="3516" updated="2013-07-19T19:35:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Substance Abuse Group Homes Amendments of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to the participation of the public in governmental decisions regarding the location of group homes established pursuant to the program of block grants for the prevention and treatment of substance abuse.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Community life"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Group homes"/>
    <term name="Halfway houses"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2005--Introduced.
Substance Abuse Group Homes Amendments of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require states receiving substance abuse grants for the establishment of group homes for recovering substance abusers to ensure that state or local officials: (1) provide the public with an opportunity to consult with officials on policies for the location of such housing; (2) notify community members that the community is under consideration as a proposed site for such a home and allow them to consult with officials on the proposal before a decision is made; (3) monitor the group home to determine residents' compliance with the conditions upon which the permission to establish the home was granted; and (4) provide community members and the home's residents with opportunities to consult with officials on the group home's effects on the community.</summary>
</bill>
