<bill session="112" type="s" number="1427" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Farming Flexibility Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to authorize producers on a farm to produce fruits and vegetables for processing on the base acres of the farm.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2675"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2011--Introduced.
Farming Flexibility Act of 2011 - Amends the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to consider mung beans and pulse crops as covered commodities whose planting on base acres is prohibited unless the commodity, if planted, is destroyed before harvest. Provides that: (1) as of crop year 2012 producers on a farm may reduce the base acres for any covered commodity for a crop year by one acre for each acre used for the production of fruits or vegetables (other than potatoes) for processing; (2) such acres devoted to fruits or vegetables shall be included in base acres for the covered commodity for the subsequent crop year unless the producers on the farm make the election to produce fruits and vegetables for the subsequent crop year; and (3) if a farm's base acres are recalculated the production of fruits or vegetables shall be considered to be the same as the planting, prevented planting, or production of a covered commodity. Requires producers to: (1) demonstrate that they have entered into a contract to produce a fruit or vegetable crop for processing, (2) produce such crop as part of a crop rotation program to achieve agronomic and pest and disease management benefits, and (3) provide evidence of the crop's disposition.</summary>
</bill>
