<bill session="112" type="h" number="3595" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mandatory Foreclosure Mediation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a mandatory mediation process for servicers of residential mortgages and borrowers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2012-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3789"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="967"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/7/2011--Introduced.
Mandatory Foreclosure Mediation Act - Prohibits a servicer from initiating a foreclosure action against a borrower unless the servicer has: (1) made a reasonable effort to initiate mediation proceedings to determine if the borrower is eligible for a loan modification or an alternative to foreclosure; and (2) offered the borrower, if eligible, such a modification or alternative. Requires a servicer to suspend a foreclosure action initiated before the enactment of this Act until the servicer: (1) completes such a mediation proceeding; and (2) offers the borrower, if eligible, a modification or alternative. Prohibits a servicer, during the suspension period, from: (1) sending the borrower a notice of foreclosure, (2) conducting or scheduling a sale of the real property securing the mortgage, or (3) causing final judgment to be entered against the borrower. Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish such a mediation process. Declares that a servicer is not required to suspend a foreclosure action if the servicer makes a reasonable effort to schedule a mediation proceeding and documents that the borrower has not agreed to one. Makes a violation of this Act a bar to a foreclosure action. Allows a servicer in compliance with this Act, however, to bring or proceed with a foreclosure action, regardless of any prior violation.</summary>
</bill>
