<bill session="112" type="s" number="1773" updated="2013-07-20T02:31:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Local Farms, Food, and Jobs Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote local and regional farm and food systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2012-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2011-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2011-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3286"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/2011--Introduced.
Local Farms, Food, and Jobs Act of 2011 - Provides for the inclusion of locally or regionally produced agricultural food products under specified agricultural, rural development, agricultural research, crop insurance, and nutrition programs. Directs the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation to offer a whole farm adjusted revenue risk management insurance plan that allows a producer to qualify for an indemnity if actual gross farm revenue is below 85% of the producer's average gross farm revenue. Prohibits the Corporation from requiring organic crop insurance premium surcharges. Directs the Corporation to offer organic crop producers price elections that reflect actual retail or wholesale prices. Amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (formerly known as the Food Stamp Act of 1977) to require state agencies to treat wireless retailers in the same manner as wired program retail food stores for purposes of supplemental nutrition assistance (SNAP, formerly food stamp) benefits. Defines "wireless retailer" to include: (1) a farmers market, (2) a farm stand, (3) a green cart, (4) a route vendor, (5) an entity operating a community-supported agriculture or fishery program, (6) a buying club, and (7) a farmer affiliated with such entities. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a wireless retailer electronic benefit transfer pilot program for smartphone technology. Extends: (1) the program of fresh fruit and vegetable purchases for distribution to schools and service institutions; (2) the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC) farmers' market nutrition program; (3) the seniors farmers' market nutrition program; (4) the rural business opportunity grant program; (5) the value-added agricultural product market development grant program; (6) the Agriculture and Food Research Initiative; (7) the specialty block grant program; and (8) the national organic certification cost-share program. Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to permit schools to use an amount equal to 15% of their commodity dollars for purchases of locally grown food. Increases the annual fiscal year limit for community food project grants. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to direct the Secretary to make and guarantee loans for the production of locally or regionally produced agricultural food products. Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to evaluate how the credit needs of young, beginning, and small farmers and local and regional farm and food systems are being met by the Farm Credit System, USDA, the Department of the Treasury, and any other federal agencies. Amends the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 to direct: (1) the Secretary to distribute price reporting of locally or regionally produced agricultural food products, and (2) the Under Secretary to establish a special initiative to coordinate USDA research relating to classical plant and animal breeding. Amends the Rural Development Act of 1972 to direct the Secretary to increase technical assistance for sustainable local and regional food systems. Amends the the Farmer-to-Consumer Direct Marketing Act of 1976 to establish the local marketing promotion program (in lieu of the farmers market promotion program) to promote producer-to-consumer marketing, including farmers markets and other local and regional food markets. Directs the Secretary to establish in the Food Safety and Inspection Service technical assistance divisions to provide directly or through grants outreach, education, and training to very small or certain small meat and poultry processing plants. Directs the Secretary to establish an electronic option for meat and poultry label preapproval. Amends the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 to provide funding for the national food safety training, education, outreach, and technical assistance program.</summary>
</bill>
