<bill session="112" type="h" number="6235" updated="2013-07-20T02:03:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Lands Energy Regulatory Certainty Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To delay further action on the proposed rule regarding well stimulation on Federal and Indian lands until such date the Secretary of the Interior submits a report examining certain effects of such rule.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2012--Introduced.
Federal Lands Energy Regulatory Certainty Act of 2012 - Bars the Secretary of the Interior, before submitting the final report on the study specified below, from taking any action to finalize or otherwise implement provisions contained in the proposed rule entitled "Oil and Gas; Well Stimulation, Including Hydraulic Fracturing, on Federal and Indian Lands". Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to study, for the 10-year period following enactment of this Act, as if such rule was applied: (1) the anticipated expenditure of resources by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM); (2) the anticipated rates of development and production of oil and natural gas resources in the United States; (3) the anticipated revenue to the Treasury resulting from the production of oil and natural gas resources; and (4) any potential conflicts that may exist between the proposed rule and existing federal and state regulations. Requires the Secretary to submit a preliminary and final report to Congress on the results of such study and to solicit public comments regarding the preliminary report.</summary>
</bill>
