<bill session="112" type="s" number="1311" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving Student Achievement and Engagement through Expanded Learning Time Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 regarding 21st century community learning centers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2011-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2011-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2011-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2011--Introduced.
Improving Student Achievement and Engagement through Expanded Learning Time Act of 2011 - Amends the 21st Century Community Learning Centers program under part B of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Requires states to use at least 95% of the grant allotted to them under part B to award subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs), nonprofit organizations, or partnerships between LEAs and nonprofit organizations or local governmental entities. Creates two types of subgrants: (1) one-year planning subgrants for use in developing and implementing expanded learning time programs as part of a community learning center; and (2) renewable, multi-year implementation subgrants for use in creating expanded learning time, before and after school, summer enrichment, or summer school programs as part of a community learning center. Defines an "expanded learning time program" as a program that: (1) applies to all students in a school; (2) increases total school hours by at least 300 hours through an expanded school day, week, or year schedule; and (3) provides additional time for instruction in core academic subjects and additional time for school staff to collaborate, plan, and engage in professional development across grades and subjects. Establishes specified community learning center performance indicators to assess success in creating additional learning time and improving student achievement. Reauthorizes appropriations for the 21st Century Community Learning Centers program for FY2012-FY2017.</summary>
</bill>
