<bill session="111" type="hr" number="463" updated="2013-07-19T23:00:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21T10:51:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-21T10:51:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the conference report to accompany the bill (S. 454) to improve the organization and procedures of the Department of Defense for the acquisition of major weapon systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412307"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-125, by Ms. Pingree (ME).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of the conference to accompany S.454. The resolution waives all points of order against the conference report and against its consideration and provides that the conference report shall be considered as read. The resolution provides that the Chair may postpone further consideration of the conference report to such time as may be designated by the Speaker.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-05-20T18:31:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="58">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 58.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T10:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5898-5900" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T10:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 463.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T10:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5900" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-05-21T10:51:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5898" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T10:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="454"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the conference report to accompany the bill (S. 454) to improve the organization and procedures of the Department of Defense for the acquisition of major weapon systems.</summary>
</bill>
