<bill session="113" type="h" number="2060" updated="2013-11-02T06:36:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop the Sequester Job Loss Now Act Through 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to restore for the remainder of fiscal year 2013 budgetary resources sequestered on March 1, 2013, for that fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400415"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412514" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="699"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="766"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1426"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="321"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2013--Introduced.
Stop the Sequester Job Loss Now Act Through 2014 - Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) to repeal the FY2013-FY2014 sequesters. Makes the budgetary resources for FY2013, which were sequestered by the presidential sequestration order, available for obligation for the same purpose, in the same amount as otherwise would have been available on the date of enactment of this Act and before October 1, 2013, and in the same manner as if such order had not been issued. Reduces the defense discretionary spending limits for the security category for FY2017-FY2021. Eliminates the 2% maximum permissible reduction in budget authority for veterans' medical care. Extends through FY2014 agricultural commodity programs generally under the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008, but not the direct payment programs for wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, upland cotton, long and medium grain rice, soybeans, other oilseeds, and peanuts. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) prohibit the use of the last-in, first out (LIFO) accounting method by major integrated oil companies, (2) deny such oil companies a tax deduction for income attributable to the domestic production of oil and gas, and (3) deny them also the tax deduction for intangible drilling and development costs. Requires an individual high-income taxpayer whose adjusted gross income exceeds $1 million (adjusted annually for inflation) to pay a minimum (fair share) tax rate of 30% of the excess of the taxpayer's adjusted gross income over the taxpayer's modified charitable contribution deduction for the taxable year. Declares that it is the sense of the House that Congress should replace the entire 10-year sequester established by the Budget Control Act of 2011 with a balanced approach that would: (1) increase revenues without increasing the tax burden on middle-income Americans; and (2) decrease long-term spending while maintaining the Medicare guarantee, protecting Social Security and a strong social safety net, and making strategic investments in education, science, research, and critical infrastructure necessary to compete in the global economy.</summary>
</bill>
