<bill session="110" type="s" number="3225" updated="2013-07-19T22:49:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to prohibit the importation of certain low-level radioactive waste into the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300002"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5632"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/2008--Introduced.
Amends Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to prohibit the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) from issuing a license authorizing the importation into the United States of: (1) low-level radioactive waste; or (2) specific radioactive waste streams exempted from regulation under the Low-Level Radioactive Waste Policy Act. Exempts from such prohibition low-level radioactive waste: (1) that is being returned to a U.S. government or military facility authorized to possess it; or (2) resulting from the use in a foreign country of nuclear material obtained by the foreign user from an entity in the United States that is being returned to the United States for management and disposal. Authorizes the President to waive the prohibition and authorize the grant of a specific license only after finding that such importation would meet an important national or international policy goal.</summary>
</bill>
