<bill session="109" type="h" number="714" updated="2013-07-19T19:10:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect the civil rights of victims of gender-motivated violence and to promote public safety, health, and regulate activities affecting interstate commerce by creating employer liability for negligent conduct that results in an individual's committing a gender-motivated crime of violence against another individual on premises controlled by the employer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E202"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Employee crimes"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Violence in the workplace"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2005--Introduced.
Declares an employer liable to a party injured in a crime of violence motivated by gender if: (1) the employer's business is in or affects interstate or foreign commerce; and (2) the employer's negligent conduct results in the perpetration of a gender-motivated crime of violence against an individual upon premises under the employer's control. States that nothing in this Act: (1) entitles a person to a cause of action for random acts of violence unrelated to gender or for acts that cannot be demonstrated to be motivated by gender; or (2) requires a prior criminal complaint, prosecution, or conviction. Gives the Federal and State courts concurrent jurisdiction over actions brought pursuant to this Act. Directs the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission to create and provide to employers materials regarding personnel policies and safety standards to assist them in avoiding liability under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
