<bill session="110" type="h" number="1835" updated="2013-07-19T21:19:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rim of the Valley Corridor Study Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a resource study of the area known as the Rim of the Valley Corridor in the State of California to evaluate alternatives for protecting resources of the corridor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2007-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2007-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="1053"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1053"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Mountains"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2007--Introduced.
Rim of the Valley Corridor Study Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a resource study of and submit a report on the Rim of the Valley Corridor in California to evaluate a range of alternatives for protecting the Corridor's resources, including the alternative of establishing all or part of the Corridor as a unit of the Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area. Lists the objectives the Secretary shall seek to achieve in conducting the study. Directs the Secretary to analyze the potential impact that establishment of all or part of the Rim of the Valley Corridor as a unit of the Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area is likely to have on land within or bordering the area that is privately owned at the time such study is conducted. Requires the report to discuss the concerns of private landowners within the existing boundaries of the Recreation Area. Instructs the Secretary, as part of evaluating each alternative considered under such study, to estimate the impact of implementing the alternative on staffing and other potential costs to federal, state, and local agencies and other organizations.</summary>
</bill>
