<bill session="111" type="s" number="660" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Pain Care Policy Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to pain care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3571"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="756"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2009--Introduced.
National Pain Care Policy Act of 2009 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to seek an agreement with the Institute of Medicine to convene a Conference on Pain to: (1) increase the recognition of pain as a significant public health problem in the United States; (2) evaluate the adequacy of assessment, diagnosis, treatment, and management of acute and chronic pain; (3) identify barriers to appropriate pain care; and (4) establish an agenda to reduce such barriers and significantly improve the state of pain care research, education, and clinical care in the United States. Allows the Secretary to enter into an agreement with another appropriate entity if the Institute of Medicine declines. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to continue and expand, through the Pain Consortium, an aggressive program of basic and clinical research on the causes of and potential treatments for pain. Requires the Pain Consortium to develop and make recommendations on appropriate pain research initiatives. Requires the Secretary to establish the Interagency Pain Research Coordinating Committee to: (1) develop a summary of advances in federal pain care research relevant to the diagnosis, prevention, and treatment of pain and diseases and disorders associated with pain; and (2) identify critical gaps in basic and clinical research on the symptoms and causes of pain. Allows the Secretary to provide for education and training to health care professionals in pain care. Requires the Secretary to establish and implement a national pain care education outreach and awareness campaign to educate consumers, patients, their families, and other caregivers.</summary>
</bill>
