<bill session="112" type="h" number="4913" updated="2013-07-20T01:52:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require designated military command responsibility and accountability for the care, handling, and transportation of the remains of a deceased member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps who died overseas, from the place of death, through the defense mortuary system, until the remains are accepted by the member's next of kin, in order to ensure that the deceased member is treated with dignity, honor, and respect.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2012-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E663"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2012--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of Defense (DOD), within 60 days after the enactment of this Act, to ensure the continuous military command responsibility and accountability for the care, handling, and transportation of the remains of each deceased member of the Armed Forces who dies overseas, beginning with initial recovery of the remains, through the defense mortuary system, until their interment or when the remains are otherwise accepted by the person designated to direct their disposition.</summary>
</bill>
