<bill session="110" type="h" number="6639" updated="2013-07-19T22:01:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Agency Performance Review and Efficiency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Inspector General Act of 1978 to require annual reviews by Inspectors General of the operations, efficiency, and effectiveness of Federal programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412226"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO24" subcommittee="Government Management, Organization, and Procurement" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6638"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2008--Introduced.
Federal Agency Performance Review and Efficiency Act - Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to make it the principal duty and responsibility of each Inspector General to review annually the operations, efficiency, and effectiveness of all federal programs within his or her establishment and to report to Congress and the President any recommendations, along with proposed legislation, on whether an abolishment, reorganization, consolidation, or transfer of existing federal programs and agencies is necessary to: (1) reduce federal expenditures; (2) increase efficiency of government operations; (3) eliminate overlap and duplication in federal programs and offices; (4) abolish agencies or programs that no longer serve an important governmental purpose; and (5) identify reductions in amounts of discretionary budget authority or direct spending that can be dedicated to federal deficit reduction.</summary>
</bill>
