<bill session="110" type="s" number="2642" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Renewable Energy Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Renewable Energy Tax Incentives Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a national renewable energy standard, to extend and create renewable energy tax incentives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1059-1061"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Expatriation"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free ports and zones"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Ocean energy resources"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax havens"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2008--Introduced.
American Renewable Energy Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to require that electric utilities that sell electricity to consumers generate or purchase a specified percentage (increasing from 2% in 2010 to 20% in 2024) of their electricity from renewable resources (e.g., solar, wind, geothermal, ocean, biomass, landfill gas, or incremental hydropower or geothermal energy).Renewable Energy Tax Incentives Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide tax incentives for investment in renewable energy sources and conversation, including by: (1) extending the tax credit for producing electricity from renewable resources, the energy tax credit, the small ethanol producer tax credit, and the tax credits for investment in clean new renewable energy bonds, biodiesel used as fuel, alternative fuel motor vehicles and refueling property, nonbusiness energy property, and new energy efficient homes, and the tax deduction for energy efficient commercial buildings; (2) allowing accelerated depreciation of qualified energy management devices and certain reuse and recycling property; and (3) allowing new tax credits for residential wind property, production of cellulosic biomass alcohol, fossil free alcohol production, and plug-in electric drive motor vehicles.Extends the tariff duty on ethanol until 2011. Denies major integrated oil companies the tax deduction for income attributable to domestic production of oil, natural gas, and related products. Increases and extends through 2017 the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund tax. Imposes taxes on: (1) crude oil and natural gas produced from the outer Continental Shelf in the Gulf of Mexico; and (2) taxable fuels in foreign trade zones. Revises tax rules relating to: (1) penalties for sale of fuel failing to meet Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) regulations; (2) tax credits for fuels produced outside the United States and foreign oil and gas extraction income; (3) treatment of alcohol and biodiesel fuel mixtures as taxable fuels; (3) foreign corporation inversion transactions; (4) leasing of tax-exempt use property to foreign entities; and (5) taxation of U.S. citizens and permanent residents who revoke citizenship or resident status to avoid U.S. taxation (expatriates).</summary>
</bill>
