<bill session="109" type="h" number="125" updated="2013-07-19T19:05:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-13T15:05:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-13T15:05:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to construct facilities to provide water for irrigation, municipal, domestic, military, and other uses from the Santa Margarita River, California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2005-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16T16:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-297, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16T16:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-11-16T16:28:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="164">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 164.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-13T15:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Drake moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-13T15:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11441-11442" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-13T15:03:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 125.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-12-13T15:05:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11441-11442" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-13T15:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-17">
      <text>Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7626" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military construction operations"/>
    <term name="Navy"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water rates"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2005--Passed House amended.
(Sec. 2) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to construct, operate, and maintain the Santa Margarita River Project in accordance with the final feasibility report and this Act. Authorizes Project construction only after the Secretary determines that: (1) the Fallbrook Public Utility District, San Diego County (District), has entered into a contract to repay to the United States appropriate portions of the costs of constructing, operating, and maintaining the Project, with interest; (2) the authorized California officer or agency has granted water use permits to the Bureau of Reclamation for the benefit of the Department of the Navy and the District; (3) the District has agreed that it will not assert against the United States any prior right to water in excess of the quantity deliverable under this Act and will share water based on equal priority and a specified ratio; and (4) the Secretary has determined that the Project has economic, environmental, and engineering feasibility. (Sec. 3) Shields the Department of the Navy (the Department) from responsibility for any costs in connection with the Project, except upon completion and then in reasonable proportion to its use of the Project under regulations agreed upon by the Secretary and the Secretary of the Navy. (Sec. 4) Permits operation of the Project by the Secretary, the District, or a third party consistent with this Act. Requires the Department and the District to participate in the Project yield on the basis of equal priority, with 60% of the Project's yield allotted to the Navy Secretary and 40% allotted to the District. Provides that if the Navy Secretary certifies that the Department does not have immediate need for its portion, the administering official may enter into temporary contracts for the sale and delivery of excess water. Allows the rights and obligations of the United States and the District regarding the ratio or amounts of Project yield delivered to be modified by agreement between the parties. Requires moneys paid to the United States under such a contract to be deposited in the special account established for the Department. (Sec. 5) Requires the District's general repayment obligation to be determined by the Secretary consistent with the Water Supply Act of 1958. Provides that there shall be no repayment obligation for water delivered to the District under a contract for delivery of excess water. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary to transfer to the District or a mutually agreed upon third party the care, operation, and maintenance of the Project under conditions satisfactory to the Secretary and the District (and the Navy Secretary with respect to the portion located within the boundaries of Camp Pendleton). Entitles the District, if such a transfer takes place, to an equitable credit for the costs associated with the Secretary's proportionate share of the Project's operation and maintenance. (Sec. 7) Provides that the basis, measure, and limit of all U.S. rights pertaining to the use of water shall be California law. (Sec. 8) Requires, unless otherwise agreed by the Navy Secretary, that the Project be operated in a manner which: (1) allows the free passage of all of the water the United States is entitled to use under California law either as a result of its acquisition of the lands comprising Camp Joseph H. Pendleton and adjoining naval installations or through actual use or prescription; and (2) does not impair or deplete the quantities of water the United States would be entitled to use had the Project not been built. (Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations to construct, operate, and maintain the Project. (Sec. 10) Directs the Secretary and the Navy Secretary to each report to Congress periodically regarding if and how the conditions for Project construction have been met. (Sec. 11) Terminates the Secretary's authority to complete Project construction 10 years after this Act's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
