<bill session="109" type="h" number="1102" updated="2013-07-19T19:13:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patriot Penalty Elimination Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to protect the financial condition of members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces who are ordered to long-term active duty in support of a contingency operation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2005-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="624"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Employment subsidies"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2005--Introduced.
Patriot Penalty Elimination Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned to pay income preservation pay to a member of the reserves: (1) who is called or ordered to active duty (other than voluntarily); (2) who serves on such duty outside the United States during at least six out of 12 consecutive months; and (3) whose preservice income exceeds the amount earned from the military service. Provides a formula for determining the appropriate income preservation amount, with a limit of $50,000. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a Ready Reserve-National Guard employee credit equal to 50 percent of the lesser of the actual compensation amount with respect to the employee for the taxable year, or $30,000. Provides such credit, with respect to such employee, for: (1) active duty outside the United States under a call or order for a period in excess of 179 days or for an indefinite period, in connection with which the employee is entitled to reemployment rights and other benefits or to a leave of absence from employment; and (2) hospitalization incident to such duty.</summary>
</bill>
