<bill session="110" type="h" number="6534" updated="2013-07-19T22:00:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Resist Offsetting with Additional Debt Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ROAD Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To rescind certain earmark projects under SAFETEA-LU for the purpose of eliminating the shortfall in the Highway Trust Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2008-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2008-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6472"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2008--Introduced.
Resist Offsetting with Additional Debt Act or the ROAD Act - Rescinds unobligated balances of certain earmarked surface transportation projects under the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU) and certain other appropriations Acts (in order to eliminate the deficit in the Highway Trust Fund (HTF)). Prohibits: (1) recalculation of amounts allocated for surface transportation projects under the Equity bonus program for a fiscal year to take such rescissions into account; and (2) the transfer of funds from the General Fund of the Treasury in order to alleviate the deficit in the HTF (except amounts equivalent to certain taxes and penalties). Expresses the sense of Congress that state transportation departments should consider implementing certain projects under the highway bridge program and the surface transportation program that improve transportation safety.</summary>
</bill>
