<bill session="111" type="h" number="872" updated="2013-07-19T23:19:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stem Cell Research Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for human embryonic stem cell research, to direct the National Institutes of Health to issue guidelines for such stem cell research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400101"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412192" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2010-03-04" withdrawn="2010-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4808"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cell biology and embryology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2009--Introduced.
Stem Cell Research Improvement Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct and support research that utilizes human embryonic stem cells, regardless of the date on which the stem cells were derived from a human embryo. Limits such research to stem cells that meet the following requirements: (1) the stem cells were derived from human embryos donated from in vitro fertilization clinics, were created for the purposes of fertility treatment, and were in excess of the needs of the individuals seeking such treatment; (2) prior to donation, it was determined that the embryos would never be implanted in a woman and would otherwise be discarded; and (3) the individuals seeking fertility treatment donated the embryos with written informed consent and received no financial or other inducements.Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to issue guidelines on research involving human embryonic stem cells. Authorizes the Director to issue guidelines on research involving other human stem cells, as scientifically warranted. Provides for updates of guidelines under this Act. Directs the Secretary to take into consideration guidelines on human stem cell research developed by nationally- and internationally- recognized scientific organizations.Requires NIH research to comply with guidelines under this Act.Requires the Director to: (1) determine the extent to which the guidelines under this Act apply to research on human embryonic stem cells derived before the effective date of such guidelines; and (2) include in its biennial report to Congress a summary of research activities on human stem cells.</summary>
</bill>
