<bill session="110" type="s" number="3654" updated="2013-07-19T22:53:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Research, Hazard Intervention, and National Outreach for Healthier Homes Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve research on health hazards in housing, to enhance the capacity of programs to reduce such hazards, to require outreach, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10074-10075"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10075-10078" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural colleges"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Building materials"/>
    <term name="Carbon monoxide"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer goods"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Integrated pest management"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2008--Introduced.
Research, Hazard Intervention, and National Outreach for Healthier Homes Act of 2008 - Directs the Director of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to evaluate the health effects of housing-related health hazards for which limited research or understanding of causes or associations exists. Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to implement studies by the Office of Healthy Homes and Lead Hazard Control of the assessment, prevention, and control of housing-related health hazards. Directs the Administrator of the EPA to study how sustainable building features in existing housing affect the quality of the indoor environment, the prevalence of housing-related health hazards, and the health of occupants. Directs the Secretary of HUD to complete the analysis of data collected for the National Survey on Lead and Allergens in Housing and the American Healthy Housing Survey. Directs the Administrator of the EPA to expand current indoor environmental monitoring efforts to establish baseline levels of indoor chemical pollutants and their sources. Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to determine the data and resources needed to establish a healthy housing data collection system. Directs the Secretary of HUD to: (1) develop improved methods for evaluating, reducing, and preventing health hazards in housing; (2) support development of objective measures for a healthy residential environment; (3) promote the incorporation of healthy housing principles in post-disaster environments as well as ongoing practices and systems, and of health considerations into green and energy-efficient construction and rehabilitation; (4) improve the dissemination of healthy housing information; and (5) promote state and local level healthy housing efforts. Amends the Public Health Service Act with respect to the CDC Program Capacity on Housing-Related Health Hazard. Directs the Administrator of the EPA, acting through the director of the Office of Children's Health Protection and Environmental Education, to address health hazards in the home environment, with particular attention to children, the elderly, and families with limited resources. Directs the Secretary of HUD to award health hazard reduction grants to reduce significant structural, health, and safety hazards in the home. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Cooperative State Research, Education, and Extension Service, to establish a competitive grant program to promote education and outreach on housing-related health hazards. Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 with respect to enforcement of the lead disclosure rule. Establishes within the EPA voluntary products and materials and housing labeling programs. Specifies the duties of the EPA Administrator with respect to the Healthy Home Seal of Approval. Directs the EPA Administrator to provide public education and outreach on environmental health risks experienced by the elderly, and low-cost methods for addressing them. Directs the Secretary of HUD to award funds for a Health Hazards Outreach competitive grant program. Directs the Secretary of HUD, the Director of the CDC, and the Administrator of the EPA to establish a national healthy housing media campaign.</summary>
</bill>
