<bill session="110" type="s" number="2648" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STEP UP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Supporting Training and Employment Potential for Underemployed Populations Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Earned Income Tax Credit Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to improve programs carried out through youth opportunity grants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1061-1063"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1063-1067" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2008--Introduced.
Supporting Training and Employment Potential for Underemployed Populations Act, or the STEP UP Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to revise Youth Opportunity Grant Program requirements to direct the Secretary of Labor to make grants to local boards and eligible entities to carry out programs that provide job training and employment activities and related services to youth and young adults (allows up to 25% of funds to be made available for hard-to-serve young adults) as defined in this Act who live in empowerment zones, enterprise communities, or high poverty areas. Earned Income Tax Credit Enhancement Act of 2007 - Amends provisions of the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to revise requirements with respect to the earned income tax credit, including to increase the maximum earned income tax credit amount for certain taxpayers without qualifying children. Allows the unused portion of an eligible taxpayer's standard deduction and personal exemption deductions that exceeds his or her adjusted gross income to be carried back to the preceding taxable year and carried forward to each of the two taxable years following the unused deduction year. Allows an employment tax credit and an advanced employment tax credit of $500, respectively, for members of targeted groups as defined under the IRC. Expands the work opportunity credit for employers who hire: (1) a youth opportunity program participant; (2) a qualified Workforce Investment Act (WIA) youth activity participant; or (3) a qualified young offender. Allows an additional work opportunity credit of $500 for each retained employee of a targeted group.</summary>
</bill>
