<bill session="112" type="h" number="6041" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Obtaining Information Through Leasing on Money and Disclosure Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">OIL Money Disclosure Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that the Secretary of the Interior shall require the disclosure of political contributions as a condition of accepting bids for oil and gas leases of Federal onshore and offshore lands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2012-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2012--Introduced.
Obtaining Information Through Leasing on Money and Disclosure Act or OIL Money Disclosure Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to issue new oil and gas leases on federal lands under the Mineral Leasing Act and submerged lands under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act only to a bidder that has submitted a list containing the date, amount, and recipient during the previous five years of: (1) any payments consisting of a contribution, expenditure, independent expenditure, or disbursement for an electioneering communication made by the bidder in connection with any election for federal office; and (2) any disbursement of other funds made by the bidder with the reasonable expectation that the individual or entity will use them to make such a payment. Requires the Secretary to publish each such list within 10 days after its receipt.</summary>
</bill>
