<bill session="110" type="hr" number="78" updated="2013-07-19T20:51:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-24T15:07:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-01-24T15:07:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to permit Delegates and the Resident Commissioner to the Congress to cast votes in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400021" joined="2007-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="2007-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2007-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2007-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2007-01-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-23T16:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 86 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 78 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24T12:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 86 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24T13:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 86, Mr. Hastings (FL) called up H.Res. 78 for consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24T13:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McHenry demanded that the Chair put the question on consideration of the measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24T13:28:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to consider the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 224 - 186 (Roll no. 56).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H902-903" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24T13:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 86.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H903-913" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24T13:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 78 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24T13:29:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 86, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.Res. 78.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24T14:35:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H912" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2007-01-24T15:07:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="57" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 191 (Roll no. 57).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H904" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24T15:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="86"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee chairmen"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2007--Passed House without amendment.
Amends Rule III (The Members, Delegates, and Resident Commissioner of Puerto Rico) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide that, in a Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union, each Delegate and the Resident Commissioner shall possess the same powers and privileges (including voting) as Members of the House. Amends Rule XVIII (The Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union) to allow a Delegate or the Resident Commissioner to preside as Chairman of such Committee. Declares that, whenever a recorded vote on any question has been decided by a margin within which the votes cast by the Delegates and the Resident Commissioner have been decisive, the Committee of the Whole shall rise and the Speaker shall put such question de novo without intervening motion. Requires the Committee to resume its sitting, without intervening motion, upon the announcement of the vote on that question.</summary>
</bill>
