<bill session="111" type="h" number="4625" updated="2013-07-19T23:54:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Civil Service Reform and Government Reorganization Commission Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a commission to conduct a study and make recommendations concerning ways to improve the civil service and organization of the Federal Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400404"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2010-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-09">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-09">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2010--Introduced.
Civil Service Reform and Government Reorganization Commission Act of 2009 - Establishes the Civil Service Reform and Government Reorganization Commission to study and report to the President and Congress on: (1) the federal compensation system; (2) recruiting individuals for the federal workforce; (3) expediting and improving hiring processes; (4) retaining a high-quality federal workforce and providing continuing professional education to maintain the quality of such workforce and ensure the efficient conduct of the government; (5) policies and barriers related to the termination of under-performing workers; (6) the role and oversight of federal contractors and issues related to contractor assumption of federal duties to ensure delineation between functions that are inherently governmental functions and those that are not; (7) the extent to which greater efficiencies can be achieved by the process of attrition; and (8) proposed legislation to implement recommended improvements. Prohibits the Commission's recommendations from including any provisions which would have the effect of creating any new tax or providing for any increase in a tax rate. Sets forth expedited procedures for legislation to implement Commission's recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
