<bill session="109" type="s" number="519" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lower Rio Grande Valley Water Resources Conservation and Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Lower Rio Grande Valley Water Resources Conservation and Improvement Act of 2000 to authorize additional projects and activities under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300054"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2026"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2027" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-96.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="386"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2005--Introduced.
Lower Rio Grande Valley Water Resources Conservation and Improvement Act of 2005 - Amends the Lower Rio Grande Valley Water Resources Conservation and Improvement Act of 2000 to authorize specified additional projects, including projects for water conservation and improvement in Cameron, Hidalgo, Willacy, Hudspeth, and El Paso counties, Texas. Permits each project that the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation, conducts or participates in to include: (1) the replacement of irrigation canals and lateral canals with buried pipelines; (2) the impervious lining of irrigation canals and lateral canals; (3) the installation of water level, flow measurement, pump control, and telemetry systems; (4) the renovation and replacement of pumping plants; and (5) other activities that will result in water conservation or an improved water supply.</summary>
</bill>
