<bill session="111" type="h" number="5577" updated="2013-07-20T00:02:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Genetically Engineered Food Right to Know Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, the Federal Meat Inspection Act, and the Poultry Products Inspection Act to require that food that contains a genetically engineered material, or that is produced with a genetically engineered material, be labeled accordingly.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400227"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2010-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2010-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2010-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2010-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2010-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2010-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2010-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Rural Development, Biotechnology, Specialty Crops, and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG14" subcommittee="Rural Development, Biotechnology, Specialty Crops, and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG29" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2010--Introduced.
Genetically Engineered Food Right to Know Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FDCA), the Federal Meat Inspection Act, and the Poultry Products Inspection Act to deem a food misbranded if it contains or was produced with a genetically engineered material unless its labeling contains statements meeting specified requirements. Requires the periodic testing of such foods transferred along a chain of distribution to assure accuracy of labels, subject to specified exceptions. Excludes, in all three Acts, food: (1) served in restaurants; or (2) prepared primarily in a retail establishment, ready for human consumption, but not offered for sale for immediate consumption in the establishment. Excludes, for purposes of the FDCA, a medical food as defined in the Orphan Drug Act. Subjects violators to civil monetary penalties, exempting recipients who accept a guarantee of the absence of genetically engineered material in good faith or producers whose food inadvertently becomes contaminated by genetically engineered material. Authorizes citizen suits as specified.</summary>
</bill>
