<bill session="113" type="h" number="3214" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserve our National Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations for personnel critical to national security during a Government shutdown.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412577"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3230"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2013--Introduced.
Preserve our National Security Act - Makes appropriations for FY2014 for pay and allowances to: (1) members of the Armed Forces, including reserve components, who perform active service during FY2014, as well as employees of agencies part of the National Intelligence Program, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA); and (2) civilian personnel and contractors of the Department of Defense (DOD), employees of agencies within the National Intelligence Program, and employees of DHS and VA who are providing support or benefits to veterans or support to U.S. national security interests related to military, intelligence services, and securing and staffing borders and ports of entry. Makes such appropriations, funds, and authority granted by this Act available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment of an appropriation for any purpose for which amounts are made available by this Act, (2) enactment of the applicable regular or continuing appropriations resolution or other Act without any appropriation for such purpose, or (3) January 1, 2015.</summary>
</bill>
