<bill session="110" type="h" number="560" updated="2013-07-19T21:08:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Freedom to Lend Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a pilot program to eliminate certain restrictions on eligible certified development companies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate governance"/>
    <term name="Corporate management"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/18/2007--Introduced.
Small Business Freedom to Lend Act of 2007 - Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish a three-year pilot program to permit an eligible certified development company (CDC) to make loans (for small business development) in any state that is contiguous to its the state of incorporation. Makes eligible CDCs that are designated as either an accredited or premier certified lender under the Small Business Investment Act of 1958. Removes the requirement that such a CDC maintain, in each state in which it makes or intends to make loans, separate and distinct memberships, officers, boards of directors, and loan committees. Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to allow an officer, director, or manager of one qualified state or local development company to serve as an officer, director, or manager of another qualified state or local development company.</summary>
</bill>
