<bill session="110" type="s" number="2921" updated="2013-07-19T22:46:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Caring for Wounded Warriors Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require pilot programs on training and certification for family caregiver personal care attendants for veterans and members of the Armed Forces with traumatic brain injury, to require a pilot program on provision of respite care to such veterans and members, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2008-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Brain"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Head injuries"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Occupational therapy"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Physical therapy"/>
    <term name="Respite care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2008--Introduced.
Caring for Wounded Warriors Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out up to three pilot programs to assess the feasibility and advisability of providing training and certification for family caregivers of veterans and members of the Armed Forces with traumatic brain injury (TBI). Requires each pilot program to be carried out in a medical facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA). Requires the Secretary to develop curricula for the training of such caregivers as personal care attendants. Makes a family caregiver who receives certification as a personal care attendant eligible for compensation from the VA for the care provided. Directs the Secretary to carry out a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of providing respite care to members and veterans who have been diagnosed with TBI through students enrolled in graduate programs in mental health or rehabilitation-related fields. Requires such students to provide: (1) relief to the family caregivers; and (2) socialization and cognitive skill development to the members and veterans. Allows such students to receive coursework credit for such participation.</summary>
</bill>
