<bill session="111" type="s" number="2967" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Boosting Entrepreneurship and New Jobs Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a refundable credit for small business job growth, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S346-347"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/28/2010--Introduced.
Boosting Entrepreneurship and New Jobs Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow certain small businesses a refundable tax credit for 15% of the first-year wages paid to new employees and a business-related tax credit for employee health insurance expenses; and (2) impose an additional tax on individuals with modified adjusted gross incomes exceeding $500,000 ($1 million for married couples filing a joint tax return) sufficient to render the provisions of this Act budget neutral. Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) and the Secretary of the Treasury to jointly establish a loan program for small business concerns (i.e., businesses with fewer than 25 employees). Amends the Small Business Act to expand: (1) the authority of the Administrator to guarantee small business loans; and (2) the microloan program for women, low-income individuals, veterans, and minority entrepreneurs. Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to obligate to be expended by September 30, 2010, certain funds for research and development by the National Institutes of Health (NIH). Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to increase the maximum loan amounts available to small businesses for plant acquisition, construction, conversion, and expansion. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the President should designate the SBA Administrator as a member of the Cabinet; and (2) financial institutions that have received financial assistance from the federal government should provide needed capital and loans to small business concerns.</summary>
</bill>
