<bill session="111" type="s" number="298" updated="2013-07-20T00:25:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financial Markets Commission Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a Financial Markets Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2009-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2009-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2009-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2009-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2009-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2253"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/2009--Introduced.
Financial Markets Commission Act of 2009 - Establishes in the legislative branch the Financial Markets Commission to: (1) examine all causes, domestic and global, of the current financial and economic crisis in the United States, including the collapse of major financial and commercial firms and the deterioration of the credit and housing markets; and (2) investigate the role in the crisis, if any, of the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), nationally recognized statistical rating organizations, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), trading facilities for commodities and self-regulatory organizations, the federal banking agencies, any financial or commercial corporation, partnership, or entity, and any other governmental or non-governmental entity. Requires the Commission to: (1) report its findings and recommendations to the President and Congress; and (2) refer to the U.S. Attorney General and any appropriate state attorney general any person that the Commission finds may have violated federal laws in relation to the crisis.</summary>
</bill>
