<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1423" updated="2013-07-19T23:08:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Observing the 15th anniversary of the Srebrenica genocide and expressing support for "Srebrenica Remembrance Day" in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2010-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="World history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/28/2010--Introduced.
Observes the 15th anniversary of the Srebrenica genocide. Supports the designation of Srebrenica Remembrance Day in the United States. Commends the official bodies that have recognized the Srebrenica genocide, including the European Parliament which declared a Srebrenica Remembrance Day in the European Union (EU). Honors the memory of the thousands of innocent people who died at Srebrenica in Bosnia and Herzegovina in July 1995, along with all individuals who were killed during the 1992-1995 conflict in Bosnia and Herzegovina. Extends condolences to the families and friends of those who died at Srebrenica and during the conflict in Bosnia and Herzegovina. Reaffirms support for: (1) the independence and territorial integrity of Bosnia and Herzegovina; (2) peace in southeastern Europe; and (3) the right of all people living in the region to return to their homes and enjoy the benefits of democratic institutions. Thanks the International Commission on Missing Persons for outstanding achievement in identifying persons missing from Srebrenica and from the conflict in the western Balkans in the 1990s. Expresses satisfaction at the apprehension and transfer of Radovan Karadzic to the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (ICTY) and urges all countries to cooperate fully with the ICTY and apprehend all persons indicted by the ICTY, including Ratko Mladic.</summary>
</bill>
