<bill session="109" type="h" number="4471" updated="2013-07-19T19:43:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair and Responsible Lending Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Expanding Housing Opportunities Through Education and Counseling Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Uniform National Mortgage Lending Standards Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Home Ownership and Equity Protection Act of 1994 and other sections of the Truth in Lending Act, so as to enact the "Fair and Responsible Lending Act;" to provide for definitions; to provide for prohibited practices and limitations relating to high-cost home loans; to provide for prohibited practices and limitations relating to home loans; to provide for penalties and remedies and enforcement; to provide for corrections of certain unintentional violations; to provide for coordination with state laws; to provide for related matters; to provide for consumer counseling requirements; to expand housing counseling opportunities; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400074"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1295"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Credit insurance"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Settlement costs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2005--Introduced.
Fair and Responsible Lending Act - Uniform National Mortgage Lending Standards Act - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to define high-cost home loans. Revises guidelines regarding: (1) requirements for high-cost home loans; (2) dispute and error resolution; (3) damages, rescission, and liability; (4) state law coordination; (5) state enforcement authority; and (6) disclosure guidelines. Prescribes consumer counseling requirements. Expanding Housing Opportunities Through Education and Counseling Act - Amends the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act to establish, in the Office of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), the Office of Housing Counseling to carry out homeownership and rental counseling functions, including related research, grant administration, public outreach, and development of policy and performance measures. Amends the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968 to direct the Secretary to: (1) establish homeownership and rental counseling procedures, and a related a toll-free telephone number and World Wide Web site; (2) certify computer software programs for consumer evaluation of residential mortgage loans; (3) establish a housing counseling multimedia outreach program for vulnerable populations; (4) assist states, local government, and non-profit organizations with consumer education programs about mortgage, refinancing, home equity, or home repair loans; and (5) make grants for state, local government, and nonprofit organization housing counseling assistance. Requires organizations to use HUD-certified counselors in order to qualify for specified HUD assistance. Amends the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 to: (1) direct the Secretary to prepare an updated booklet to help consumers applying for federally related mortgage loans to understand the nature and costs of real estate settlement services; and (2) prescribe guidelines governing an option for notice of foreclosure prevention counseling availability.</summary>
</bill>
