<bill session="109" type="h" number="4829" updated="2013-07-19T19:46:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reducing Fraudulent and Imitation Drugs Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to require the incorporation of counterfeit-resistant technologies into the packaging of prescription drugs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2006-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400294" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2006-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="2668"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug advertising"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Product counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2006--Introduced.
Reducing Fraudulent and Imitation Drugs Act of 2006 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to require prescription drug packaging to incorporate: (1) radio frequency tagging technology or similar trace and track technologies; (2) tamper-indicating technologies; and (3) blister security packaging when possible. Directs the Secretary to: (1) require that such technologies be used exclusively to authenticate the pedigree of prescription drugs; and (2) prohibit such technologies from containing or transmitting any identifying information of a health care practitioner or consumer, or any advertisement or information about indications or off-label uses. Requires the Secretary to encourage prescription drug manufacturers and distributors to incorporate: (1) overt optically variable counterfeit-resistant technologies into packaging; and (2) required prescription drug packaging technologies into multiple elements of the physical packaging of the drugs. Requires prescription drug shipments to include a label on the shipping container that incorporates packaging technologies. Deems a prescription drug to be misbranded if the packaging or labeling of the drug is in violation of a requirement or prohibition of this Act. Requires the Secretary to publish the National Specified List of Susceptible Prescription Drugs, consisting of not less than 30 of the most frequently counterfeited prescription drugs in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
