<bill session="110" type="h" number="15" updated="2013-07-19T21:03:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Health Insurance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a program of national health insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Dentists"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="National health insurance"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Patient satisfaction"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Value-added tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
National Health Insurance Act - Requires that medical services, hospital services, and other personal health services be made available to eligible individuals in all U.S. health-service areas as rapidly as possible. Sets forth minimum income requirements for eligibility. Allows health care professionals and hospitals to enter into agreements to furnish services to eligible individuals. Gives responsibility for administration of the benefits provided under this Act to local administrative committees or officers. Allows a state to assume responsibility for administration of the personal health benefits provided under this Act. Establishes: (1) the National Health Insurance Board in the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS); and (2) the National Advisory Medical Policy Council. Requires the Secretary of HHS to determine the eligibility of any individual for benefits under this Act. Limits benefits under this Act for an individual to only those services for which the individual is not eligible under Medicare. Requires the Board to: (1) determine the sums to be made available for the provision of personal health-service benefits; and (2) allot amounts to each state based on population, available professional services and facilities, and the cost of compensation. Allows the Board to make grants for the training of professionals providing benefits under this Act. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a value added tax of five percent on each sale of property, performance of services, and importation of property in the United States by a taxable person in a commercial-type transaction. Sets forth exceptions, including for food, housing, medical care, exports, interest, governmental entities, and certain tax-exempt organizations. Establishes the National Health Care Trust Fund and appropriates to it amounts equal to the revenue received by the Treasury from such tax. Requires the Secretary to study and report on the various methods to control the costs of providing personal health benefits under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
