<bill session="111" type="s" number="3076" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Silence Helps Us Hear Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct studies of natural soundscape preservation in the National Park Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2010--Introduced.
Silence Helps Us Hear Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary), through the Director of the National Park Service (NPS), to conduct a study to identify NPS natural soundscape values and resources. Instructs the Secretary to analyze and identify NPS natural soundscapes that have been the least degraded by unnatural sounds and undesirable sounds caused by humans. Instructs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT), through the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), to provide technical assistance to the Secretary in carrying out such study to the extent that aviation or aircraft noise has been identified as one of the sources of natural soundscapes degradation. Requires the Secretary, in coordination with the DOT Secretary, to the extent aviation or aircraft noise has been identified as one of the sources of NPS natural soundscapes degradation, to conduct a study identifying methods of preserving the natural soundscapes that have been the least degraded by unnatural sounds and undesirable sounds caused by humans.</summary>
</bill>
