<bill session="110" type="h" number="3247" updated="2013-07-19T21:32:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-29T16:23:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-10-29T16:23:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hurricanes Katrina and Rita Recovery Facilitation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Hurricanes Katrina and Rita Recovery Facilitation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Hurricanes Katrina and Rita Recovery Facilitation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Hurricanes Katrina and Rita Recovery Facilitation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the provision of disaster assistance for Hurricanes Katrina and Rita, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2007-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400634" joined="2007-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400635" joined="2007-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2007-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="2007-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-08-02">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-10-18T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 110-387.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-10-18T11:54:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="241">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 241.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-10-29T16:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Norton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-29T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12124-12128" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-29T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3247.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-10-29T16:23:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12124-12125" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-10-29T16:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-471.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1031">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1031.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2008--Reported to Senate amended.
Hurricanes Katrina and Rita Recovery Facilitation Act of 2008 - Directs the President to increase the amount of federal in-lieu contributions under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act for covered hurricane damages suffered in Louisiana or Mississippi as a result of Hurricanes Katrina or Rita to 90% of the cost of repairing any state or local government controlled property that will be replaced instead of repaired.Makes a pilot program established under the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2007 that was designed to make better use of existing rental housing located in areas covered by a major disaster declaration applicable to any assistance being provided under any major disaster declaration relating to Hurricanes Katrina or Rita that otherwise qualifies for participation under such program.Authorizes and encourages the President to use alternative dispute resolution (ADR) procedures for an appeal of a decision made under the Stafford Act regarding assistance provided to a state, local government, or owner or operator of a private facility for covered hurricane damages for a project the total assistance for which exceeds $500,000. Directs the President to: (1) provide written notice of and the reasons for the denial of any request by a state, local government, or owner or operator of a private facility to use ADR procedures for an appeal; (2) report to specified congressional committees annually on denials; and (3) report to such committees within one year on how ADR procedures are being used under this Act and on whether the President should be given authority to use such procedures under the Stafford Act on a permanent basis.Permits the President to use simplified procedures under the Stafford Act for a project for which the federal cost estimate is less than $100,000 for covered damages if requested by a state or local government or an owner or operator of a private nonprofit facility. Authorizes the President, in providing assistance under the Stafford Act for covered hurricane damages, to provide temporary housing units purchased under that Act that are determined through appropriate testing to be safe for occupancy to state and local governments and private nonprofit entities to provide housing to volunteers assisting in the recovery (but only upon determining that such assistance is appropriate, cost effective, and would not unduly interfere with the ability of the Federal Emergency Management Agency [FEMA] to provide housing with respect to other major disasters). Requires the President to report to specified congressional committees regarding the status of recovery for Louisiana and Mississippi from Hurricanes Katrina and Rita.(Sec. 4) Directs the President, within 30 days after submission of a request, to provide a single payment for eligible costs under the Stafford Act for a fire station, police station, or criminal justice facility damaged by Hurricanes Katrina or Rita. Prohibits the President from reducing the amount of: (1) federal in-lieu assistance provided under the Stafford Act for such a facility; or (2) flood assistance provided to a local government under that Act more than once for each such facility for which that local government is receiving assistance relating to Hurricane Katrina or Rita.Authorizes the President to provide case management services or assistance for victims of any major disaster relating to Hurricanes Katrina or Rita.</summary>
</bill>
