<bill session="109" type="s" number="250" updated="2013-07-19T20:15:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-12">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-08-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Improvement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Technical Education Act of 1998 to improve the Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300015" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300097" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2005-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S755-756"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S756-766" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-03-09">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-03-09">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Enzi with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-03-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="39">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 39.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-03-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2428-2459, S2462" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2428-2449" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2005-03-10" how="roll" result="pass" roll="43" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 99 - 0. Record Vote Number: 43.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-03-14T12:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-14">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-14T19:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>By Senator Enzi from Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions filed written report. Report No. 109-65.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McKeon asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5062-5078, H5080"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The House struck all after the enacting clause and inserted in lieu thereof the provisions of a similar measure H.R. 366. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2006-07-12T11:48:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5062-5073" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T11:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McKeon asked unanimous consent that the House insist upon its amendments, and request a conference.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5073"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T11:49:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House insist upon its amendments, and request a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller, George moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5073-5078, H5080" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5073" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the George Miller (CA) motion to instruct conferees. Instructions seek to direct the managers on the part of the House to include in the conference substitute recommended by the committee of conference the following: In section 3(2) of the bill, after the phrase "high wage" insert "(in no case less than $7.25 an hour)".</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the George Miller (CA) motion to instruct, the Chair put the question on adoption of the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. George Miller (VA) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T13:19:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 260 - 159 (Roll no. 366).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T13:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: McKeon, Castle, Souder, Osborne, Musgrave, Miller, George, Woolsey, and Kind.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendments to Senate bill House requests a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Senate disagreed to House amendments, agreed to request for conference, and appointed conferees. Enzi; Gregg; Frist; Alexander; Burr; Isakson; DeWine; Ensign; Hatch; Sessions; Roberts; Kennedy; Dodd; Harkin; Mikulski; Jeffords; Bingaman; Murray; Reed; Clinton.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-14">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 109-597 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5773-5790" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25T19:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 946 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to S. 250. Upon the adoption of this resolution, it shall be in order to consider the conference report to accompany S. 250. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and manager's statement official papers held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:SENATE" datetime="2006-07-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8321-8328" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27T10:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 946 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27T12:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McKeon brought up conference report H. Rept. 109-597 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 946.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5973-5978" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27T12:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report to accompany S. 250.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5978" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate the Chair put the question on adoption of the conference report and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Castle made a point of order that a quorum was not present and pursuant to the rule the yeas and nays were ordered and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the conference report until later in the legislative day. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2006-07-29T01:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The House proceeded to consider the conference report H.Rept. 109-597 as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/28/2005 H6221" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2006-07-29T01:48:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="426" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by recorded vote: 399 - 1 (Roll no. 426).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-29T01:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-08-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-08-12">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2006-08-12" type="public" number="109-270">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-270.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="946"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="366"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="109" type="h" number="366"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="366"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Antennas"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Career education"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Community colleges"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governors"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Industry-university relations"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Palau Islands"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Student employment"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/12/2006--Public Law.
Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Improvement Act of 2006 - Amends the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Technical Education Act of 1998 (the Act) to reauthorize and revise its programs. Renames the Act the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Improvement Act of 2006. Sets forth definitions for: (1) career and technical education (CTE), requiring that course content be aligned with challenging academic standards; (2) career guidance and academic counseling, which shall include information on baccalaureate degree programs; (3) articulation agreements; (4) scientifically based research; and (5) secondary and postsecondary tech prep students. Excludes the Marshall Islands and Micronesia from the definition of outlying areas, thus excluding them from CTE funding. Repeals a prohibition against use of funds to: (1) provide funding under the School-to-Work Opportunities Act of 1994; or (2) carry out activities that were funded under such Act through programs funded under this Act, unless such programs only serve participants eligible under this Act. Revises, reauthorizes, and renames title I of the Act as Career and Technical Education Assistance to the States. Revises requirements relating to reservations and state allotments. Reduces the percentage of appropriations set aside for outlying areas from .20% to .13%. Establishes a separate formula for determining a state's minimum allotment in years when there are additional unreserved appropriated amounts. Authorizes states to use a portion of the funds allowed for administrative costs for the support and development of state data systems relevant to this Act. Provides for separate local, as well as state, performance accountability systems, including core performance indicators, adjusted performance levels, and annual reports. Requires certain core indicators of performance for secondary and postsecondary CTE students to be identified in state plans and to include measures of specified matters. Includes, among such measures of secondary CTE student performance, student attainment of challenging academic content standards and student academic achievement standards, as adopted by the state under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA). Requires eligible local recipients to accept state-adjusted performance levels as local-adjusted performance levels, or negotiate with the state to reach agreement on new local-adjusted performance levels, for each of specified core indicators of performance for CTE activities. Requires state performance level reports, with respect to additional indicators of performance, to: (1) disaggregate data by special populations and by categories described in specified ESEA provisions; and (2) identify disparities in performance between any such category of students and the general population of students. Revises requirements for an independent advisory panel that is to conduct an evaluation and assessment of CTE programs under this Act. Extends through FY2012 the authorization of appropriations for national CTE activities. Provides grants directly to outlying areas rather than through the Pacific Region Educational Laboratory in Hawaii, beginning with the second fiscal year following the enactment of this Act. Makes a grant to the Republic of Palau, but terminates its eligiblity for such funding upon its entering into an agreement for an extension of U.S. educational assistance under the Compact of Free Association. Eliminates recognition by the Governor of the state of Hawaii as an eligibility condition for receipt by organizations primarily serving and representing Native Hawaiians of CTE grants and contracts from the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to establish a complaint resolution procedure for grant determinations and calculations for tribally controlled postsecondary CTE institutions. Alters the method of determining the student counts of such institutions, which is used in determining their grant amounts. Extends through FY2012 the authorization of appropriations for such grants for such institutions. Revises requirements for occupational and employment information and state applications. Revises requirements for state administrative responsibilities. Increases from five years to six the period a state plan is required to cover. Allows submission of transition plans for the the first full fiscal year following the enactment of this Act. Allows annual revisions in state plans and requires a review of federally-assisted CTE activities during the second year of a plan. Revises requirements for state plan contents, consultation, and options. Requires state plans to include rigorous CTE content aligned with challenging academic standards that allows for a coordinated, nonduplicative progression of courses aligning secondary education with postsecondary education. Revises requirements for state and local program improvement plans. Provides for withholding all or a portion of funds where a state agency or local recipient fails to meet at least 90% of adjusted performance levels for certain core indicators of performance and has: (1) not implemented an improvement plan; (2) shown no improvement within one year after implementing such a plan; or (3) failed to meet at least 90% of an adjusted performance level for the same core indicator for three consecutive years. Allows waivers of such sanctions in exceptional circumstances. Requires technical assistance in improvement activities to be provided by the Secretary to state agencies and by state agencies to local recipients. Revises required and permissible uses of funds for state leadership activities. Changes the formula for allocating CTE funds to secondary education programs within a state to base it on the proportion of individuals aged 5 through 17 residing in a school district, rather than those aged 15 through 19. Revises requirements for local plans for CTE programs. Revises required and permissible local uses of funds. Revises requirements relating to tech prep programs. Allows an apprenticeship program of at least two years to substitute for the minimum two years of postsecondary education in tech prep programs. Requires states to describe how the tech prep programs will be coordinated with the CTE program. Authorizes states to consolidate all, or a portion of, funds received under both programs to carry out the state CTE plan. Requires each consortium of tech prep applicants to submit a six-year (currently, five-year) plan for the use of a grant. Favors consortiums that coordinate their activities with local CTE fund recipients. Requires a consortium which fails for three consecutive years to meet a minimum state-approved level of performance pursuant to specified indicators under the CTE and tech prep programs to reapply for funding, though the state may terminate its funding upon such failure. Eliminates the tech prep demonstration program. Extends through FY2012 the authorization of appropriations for tech prep programs. Repeals requirements that the Secretary: (1) receive funds collected from fees for use of property, rights-of-way, and easements under federal control to place telecommunications services dependent on use of general spectrum rights for transmission or reception; and (2) use such funds to increase and expand use of technology in vocational and technical education instruction and personnel training. Authorizes an eligible CTE fund recipient to allow, except as prohibited by state or local law, the meaningful participation in CTE programs of secondary school students attending nonprofit private schools in the area served by such recipient.</summary>
</bill>
