<bill session="113" type="h" number="1954" updated="2013-11-02T06:35:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sunset Wasteful Executive Expenditures and Programs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 7 of title 31, United States Code, to require the Comptroller General to assist Congress and the President in eliminating agencies and programs in Executive departments that no longer serve a public need, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412550"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2013--Introduced.
Sunset Wasteful Executive Expenditures and Programs Act of 2013 - Requires the Comptroller General (GAO): (1) each year, beginning in 2014, to review three executive departments to identify agencies and programs that perform similar or related functions and that no longer serve a public need; (2) to review every executive department at least once every five years; and (3) each year, beginning on February 1, 2015, to report to Congress on the results of the reviews of executive departments carried out during the preceding year with recommendations for abolishing agencies and programs that perform similar or related functions and no longer serve a public need. Abolishes by December 31 of each year, beginning with 2015, the three executive departments reviewed by the Comptroller General during the preceding year. Requires the President to direct procedures for the winding down of the operations of each abolished department. Allows Congress to authorize the continued existence of an executive department scheduled for abolishment. Sets forth the process for congressional consideration of the Comptroller General's report, including an expedited procedure for consideration of resulting legislation to be known as a wasteful expenditures bill.</summary>
</bill>
