<bill session="112" type="s" number="1306" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Secondary School Reform Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for secondary school reform.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2011-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2011-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2011--Introduced.
Secondary School Reform Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive, matching, five-year grants to high-need local educational agencies that partner with public or private nonprofit organizations to assist schools in implementing innovative secondary school reform strategies. Requires grantees to use up to 25% of their grant funds to: (1) implement an early warning indicator and intervention system to identify and assist struggling middle and secondary school students; (2) provide support and credit recovery opportunities for struggling secondary school students; (3) establish secondary school dropout recovery or reentry programs; (4) establish grade and school transition programs and supports from kindergarten through high school graduation; and (5) keep school staff, students, and families apprised of certain education requirements, processes, and opportunities. Requires grantees to use at least 75% of their grant funds on certain efforts to: (1) reform secondary schools that have a graduation rate below 75% and they identify as needing improvement, and (2) improve the academic performance of students who attend middle schools that feed a majority of their students to those secondary schools. Requires those secondary school reforms to include: (1) personalized learning environments attuned to the needs of each student; (2) student engagement through service, experiential, and work-based learning; (3) flexible budget and hiring authority for school leaders; (4) training and collaborative opportunities for school staff; (5) improved curriculum and instruction; (6) an individual graduation plan for each student; and (7) Graduation Promise Academies, Career Academies, or Early College Schools which represent specified strategies that have proven effective in preparing students for graduation, college, and a career.</summary>
</bill>
