<bill session="111" type="s" number="835" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">OFS Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Open Fuel Standard Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require automobile manufacturers to ensure that not less than 80 percent of the automobiles manufactured or sold in the United States by each such manufacturer to operate on fuel mixtures containing 85 percent ethanol, 85 percent methanol, or biodiesel.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2009-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1476"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/20/2009--Introduced.
Open Fuel Standard Act of 2009 or the OFS Act - Requires each light-duty automobile manufacturer's annual covered inventory to comprise at least: (1) 50% fuel choice-enabling automobiles in years 2012-2014; and (2) 80% fuel choice-enabling automobiles in 2015, and in each subsequent year. Defines "fuel choice-enabling automobile" as: (1) a flexible fuel automobile capable of operating on gasoline, E85, and M85; or (2) an automobile capable of operating on biodiesel fuel. Authorizes a manufacturer to request an exemption from such requirement from the Secretary of Transportation. Extends limited liability protection to the use of fuel containing ethanol or renewable fuel in the operation of internal combustion engines by declaring that such fuel shall not be deemed to be a defective product or subject to a failure to warn due to such ethanol or renewable fuel content, unless it violates a control or prohibition imposed under the Clean Air Act.</summary>
</bill>
