<bill session="109" type="h" number="1735" updated="2013-07-19T19:19:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide that an officer of the Army or Air Force on the active-duty list may not be promoted to brigadier general unless the officer has had a duty assignment of at least one year involving the administration of the National Guard or Reserves.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400186"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military promotions"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/20/2005--Introduced.
Requires officers on the active-duty list of the Army or Air Force to complete a tour of duty of at least one year in a Guard or Reserve duty assignment (other than a Reserve Officers Training Corps unit) in order to be eligible for promotion to brigadier general. Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to waive this requirement: (1) when necessary for the good of the service; (2) in cases where the proposed promotion is based primarily upon scientific and technical qualifications for which Guard or Reserve requirements do not exist; (3) in the case of specified medical, chaplaincy, or judge advocate positions; or (4) if the officer selected for appointment to brigadier general by a promotion board had completed at least 180 days of a Guard or Reserve duty assignment on the date such board was convened. Requires the Secretary to prescribe regulations to carry out this Act that specifically identify those categories of officers for whom the waiver applicable to scientific and technical qualifications is available.</summary>
</bill>
