<bill session="111" type="s" number="3329" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cleanfields Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide triple credits for renewable energy on brownfields, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2010-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2010-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2010-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2010-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2010--Introduced.
Cleanfields Act - Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978, as it would be amended by the American Clean Energy Leadership Act of 2009 as reported to the Senate as an original measure on July 16, 2009 (S.1462), to: (1) define "brownfield site generation facility," for purposes of provisions concerning the Federal Renewable Electricity Standard, as a facility that generates renewable electricity from wind energy, solar energy, or geothermal energy and that occupies a brownfield site; and (2) require the Secretary of Energy to allow triple credits under the federal renewable energy credit trading program for the generation of energy from brownfield site generation facilities. Limits the amount of total renewable electricity generation that is eligible for consideration for the triple credit multiplier for brownfields to 1%. Requires the Secretary to submit to Congress recommendations on whether such limitation should be revised.</summary>
</bill>
