<bill session="112" type="h" number="6222" updated="2013-07-20T02:03:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Heating Oil Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Clean Air Act with respect to the sulfur fuel content of heating oil.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2012-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2012--Introduced.
Clean Heating Oil Act of 2012 - Amends the Clean Air Act to prohibit, effective June 1, 2016, any person from manufacturing, selling, supplying, offering for sale or supply, dispensing, transporting, or introducing into commerce heating oil which contains a concentration of sulfur in excess of: (1) 15 parts per million, or (2) a lesser concentration that may be established by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) (but not below the concentration of sulfur in diesel fuel permissible under renewable fuel standards) to ensure that such concentration is not reasonably anticipated to endanger the public health or welfare. Allows the Administrator to: (1) provide for the issuance of credits to refiners and importers for amounts of heating oil manufactured or imported before June 1, 2016, in accordance with such limitation; and (2) allow a refiner or importer to use such credits, or transfer such credits to another refiner or importer for use, for the purpose of complying with this Act. Terminates such credits on June 1, 2019. Defines "heating oil" to mean any number 1 distillate, number 2 dyed distillate, or non-petroleum diesel blend that is: (1) sold for use in furnaces, boilers, stationary diesel engines, or similar applications; and (2) commonly or commercially known or sold as heating oil or fuel oil or using a similar trade name. Allows the Administrator to: (1) temporarily waive the requirements of this Act if the Administrator determines, and the Secretary of Energy (DOE) concurs, that the criteria for fuels and fuel additives is met with respect to heating oil; and (2) waive requirements of this Act with respect to any heating oil manufactured by a small refinery until June 1, 2019. Applies penalty and injunction provisions for violations of fuel regulations under the Clean Air Act to violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
