<bill session="111" type="s" number="2897" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Efficiency Modernization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish incentives to increase the energy efficiency of federally assisted housing.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4099"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/17/2009--Introduced.
Energy Efficiency Modernization Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to make: (1) payments (green dividends) to owners of assisted multifamily rental housing projects who undertake utility cost-saving measures; and (2) review HUD regulations and agreements concerning residual receipts accounts in assisted rental housing and revise HUD policy on the use of such accounts for energy efficiency items. Directs the Comptroller General to conduct a study and report to Congress on the benefits of a federal statutory exemption from compliance with state and local building codes to enable and encourage the construction and installation in assisted multifamily rental housing projects of distributive energy generation and water efficiency measures. Requires owners of assisted multifamily rental housing projects to report to the Secretary on consumption of electricity, water, gas, and other utilities by such projects.</summary>
</bill>
