<bill session="109" type="s" number="3519" updated="2013-07-19T20:44:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Agriculture Small Business Opportunity and Enhancement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reform the State inspection of meat and poultry in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300015" joined="2006-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2006-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2006-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2006-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2006-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2006-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2006-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2006-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300097" joined="2006-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2006-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2006-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5957"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="6130"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Meat inspection"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2006--Introduced.
Agriculture Small Business Opportunity and Enhancement Act of 2006 - Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to approve a qualifying State meat inspection program and allow the shipment in commerce of carcasses, parts of carcasses, meat, and meat food products so inspected. Requires the Secretary to review approved plans annually. Prohibits from state inspection plan participation: (1) establishments that have more than 50 employees, except for those subject to state inspection as of January 1, 2007; and (2) federally inspected establishments after such date that have more than 50 employees. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into a cooperative agreement to establish the relationship between a state program and the Secretary; and (2) provide partial reimbursement for state costs to meet federal requirements. Sets forth provisions with respect to: (1) sampling; (2) noncompliance; (3) acceptance of interstate shipments of meat and meat food products; and (4) advisory committees. Directs the Secretary to temporarily suspend or take over a noncomplying state program (or an establishment). Makes similar amendments to the Poultry Products Inspection Act. Terminates the Secretary's authority to establish interstate meat and poultry inspection programs under this Act if approval and cooperative agreements have not been concluded by January 1, 2007.</summary>
</bill>
