<bill session="112" type="hr" number="706" updated="2013-07-20T01:09:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-28T17:35:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-06-28T17:35:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Authorizing the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform to initiate or intervene in judicial proceedings to enforce certain subpoenas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-27T20:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 708 Reported to House. The resolution provides for consideration of the resolution accompanying H. Rept. 112-546, under a closed rule. The resolution provides 50 minutes of debate on the resolution equally divided and controlled. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the resolution accompanying the report and the resolution shall be considered as read. The resolution provides for one motion to refer, if offered by Representative Dingell of Michigan, debatable for 10 minutes. The resolution provides for consideration of H. Res. 706.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T14:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 708 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T16:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 708.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4418-4421" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T16:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of the resolution accompanying H. Rept. 112-546, under a closed rule. The resolution provides 50 minutes of debate on the resolution equally divided and controlled. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the resolution accompanying the report and the resolution shall be considered as read. The resolution provides for one motion to refer, if offered by Representative Dingell of Michigan, debatable for 10 minutes. The resolution provides for consideration of H. Res. 706.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T16:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 708, the House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on H. Res. 706.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T17:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4420" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-06-28T17:35:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="442" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 258 - 95, 5 Present (Roll no. 442).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4418" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="708"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2012--Passed House without amendment.
Authorizes the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform to initiate or intervene in judicial proceedings in any federal court of competent jurisdiction on behalf of the Committee to seek declaratory judgments affirming the duty of Attorney General Eric H. Holder, Jr., to comply with any subpoena that is a subject of the resolution accompanying H.Rept. 112-546 issued to him by the Committee as part of its investigation into the Department of Justice (DOJ) operation known as "Fast and Furious" and related matters, and to seek appropriate ancillary relief, including injunctive relief. Requires the Committee to report as soon as practicable to the House with respect to any such judicial proceedings it initiates or in which it intervenes. Directs the House Office of General Counsel, at the authorization of the Speaker, to represent the Committee in any litigation pursuant to this resolution. Requires the Speaker, in giving such authorization, to consult with the Bipartisan Legal Advisory Group.</summary>
</bill>
