<bill session="113" type="h" number="1153" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water Infrastructure Now Public-Private Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WIN P3 Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a pilot program to evaluate the cost-effectiveness of allowing non-Federal interests to carry out certain water infrastructure projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412537"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412544" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2013-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1416"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="566"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2013--Introduced.
Water Infrastructure Now Public-Private Partnership Act or the WIN P3 Act - Directs the Chief of Engineers to establish a pilot program to evaluate the cost-effectiveness and project delivery efficiency of allowing non-federal interests to carry out authorized flood damage reduction, hurricane and storm damage reduction, and navigation projects. Requires the Chief: (1) to identify not more than 15 projects authorized for construction; (2) to develop a detailed project management plan for each identified project that outlines the scope, budget, design, and construction resource requirements necessary for the non-federal interest to execute the project or an element of the project; (3) to enter into a project partnership agreement with the non-federal interest at such interest's request to provide full project management control for construction of the project or element in accordance with plans approved by the Chief; (4) following execution of such agreement, to transfer specified amounts to the non-federal interest to carry out project construction; and (5) to regularly monitor and audit each such project being constructed by a non-federal interest. Sets forth restrictions on projects selected. Authorizes the Chief to: (1) provide technical assistance to the non-federal interests for compensation, and (2) waive or modify applicable federal regulations if doing so would provide public and financial benefits. Directs the Chief, before entering into a project partnership agreement, to enter into an arrangement with an independent third party to conduct an assessment and provide justification that the proposed agreement would represent a better public and financial benefit than a similar transaction using public funding. Terminates authority to commence a project under this Act five years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
