<bill session="109" type="h" number="3184" updated="2013-07-19T19:32:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that countries that have signed a Small Quantities Protocol also sign, ratify, and implement the Additional Protocol and provide access by IAEA inspectors to their nuclear-related facilities and to direct the United States Permanent Representative to the IAEA to make every effort to rescind and eliminate the Small Quantities Protocol and ensure compliance by all Member States of the IAEA with IAEA obligations and the purposes and principles of the Charter of the United Nations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2005-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2005-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2005-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2005-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2005-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2005-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2005-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2005-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2005-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms control verification"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Nuclear exports"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2005--Introduced.
Directs the President to use all available political, economic, and diplomatic tools to ensure that each U.S. ally or recipient of certain U.S. assistance that has signed a Small Quantities Protocol with the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) also signs and implements the Additional Protocol and provides immediate access for IAEA inspectors to its nuclear-related facilities. Prohibits certain defense and dual use assistance to a country that has signed a Small Quantities Protocol but does not satisfy such implementation and inspection requirements. Authorizes the President to waive such prohibitions for up to one fiscal year for reasons of national security. Directs the President to require the U.S. Permanent Representative to the IAEA to use U.S. influence to change IAEA policy regarding the Small Quantities Protocol in order to: (1) eliminate the Small Quantities Protocol; (2) require that any IAEA member state that has signed a Small Quantities Protocol sign and implement the Additional Protocol, and provide IAEA inspectors with access to its nuclear-related facilities; and (3) require that any IAEA member state that does not comply with such implementation and inspection requirements be ineligible to receive nuclear material, technology, equipment, or assistance from any IAEA member state, and be subject to penalties as provided for by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
