<bill session="109" type="s" number="928" updated="2013-07-19T20:21:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Estate Tax Repeal Acceleration (ExTRA) for Family-Owned Businesses and Farms Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the immediate and permanent repeal of the estate tax on family-owned businesses and farms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300068"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4422-4423"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4423-4425" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1624"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family enterprises"/>
    <term name="Family farms"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2005--Introduced.
Estate Tax Repeal Acceleration (ExTRA) for Family-Owned Businesses and Farms Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise the estate tax exclusion provisions applicable to family-owned business interests. Allows an exclusion from the gross estate for the adjusted value of certain family business interests acquired from a decedent (carryover business interests). Defines "carryover business interests" and revises ownership requirements and material participation rules applicable to such interests. Provides that carryover business interests acquired from a decedent shall be treated as transferred by gift and that the basis of such property shall be the lesser of the adjusted basis of the decedent, or the fair market value of such property at the date of the decedent's death (thus eliminating the estate tax on such property).</summary>
</bill>
