<bill session="111" type="h" number="5151" updated="2013-07-19T23:58:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Oversight and Spending Transparency (COST) Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit the amount which may be made available for the Members' Representational Allowance for fiscal year 2011, to prohibit the use of such Allowance for expenses of official mail of any material other than a document transmitted under the official letterhead of the Member involved, and to require the quarterly statement of costs incurred for official mail by offices of the House of Representatives to provide a separate breakdown of the costs incurred for each method of mass communication covered by the statement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2010-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2010--Introduced.
Congressional Oversight and Spending Transparency (COST) Act of 2010 - Prohibits the amount authorized to be appropriated for FY2011 for the Members' Representational Allowance under the House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act from exceeding the appropriated amount for FY2009. Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991 to prohibit the use of funds of the House of Representatives for official mail of a Member of the House for any material other than a document transmitted under the official letterhead used for the Member's stationery. Requires quarterly reports by the Chief Administrative Officer of receipts and expenditures for official mail of the House to include, in the required statement of costs incurred for official mail by each person entitled to use the congressional frank, a breakdown of the costs incurred for each category of mass mailings and communications covered by the statement.</summary>
</bill>
