<bill session="109" type="s" number="1589" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Affordability in Medicare Premiums Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security to provide for reductions in the medicare part B premium through elimination of certain overpayments to Medicare Advantage organizations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2005-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="2005-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9510" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Introduced.
Affordability in Medicare Premiums Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, for each year beginning with 2006, to reduce the monthly Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) premium rate for each month in the year for individuals not enrolled in a Medicare Advantage plan so that the aggregate amount of such reductions in the year equals an amount computed according to a specified formula involving reduced payments to Medicare Advantage organizations. Requires the Secretary, in applying risk adjustment factors to payments to Medicare Advantage organizations, to ensure that such payments are adjusted to reflect the enrollee's health status, including adjusting for the difference between the health status of the enrollee and individuals enrolled under the original Medicare fee-for-service program under Medicare parts A (Hospital Insurance) and B. Requires payments to such organizations, in the aggregate, to reflect such differences. Eliminates the MA Regional Plan Stabilization Fund (Slush Fund).</summary>
</bill>
