<bill session="111" type="h" number="5757" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Renewable Fuels for America's Future Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend and modify the credits for alcohol used as a fuel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400640"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1627"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2010--Introduced.
Renewable Fuels for America's Future Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) require a reduction in the income and excise tax credits for alcohol used for fuel by the amount of alcohol used to meet the taxpayer's renewable fuel obligation under the Clean Air Act; and (2) extend such credits through 2015. Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to extend until 2016 the additional tariff on ethyl alcohol blends (ethanol) used as fuel. Requires automobile manufacturers to ensure that at least 50% of 2012 and 2013 model year automobiles and light duty trucks manufactured for sale in the United States are dual fueled. Increases the minimum to 90% for later model years. (Excludes automobiles and light duty trucks that operate only on electricity.) Requires the Secretary of Energy to make grants to eligible facilities to pay the federal share of: (1) installing blender pump fuel infrastructure, including infrastructure necessary for the direct retail sale of ethanol fuel blends (including E-85 fuel) and to directly market such fuels to gas retailers; and (2) providing subgrants to direct retailers of such fuels for the installation of fuel infrastructure for the direct retail sale of such fuels. Amends the Clean Air Act to define: (1) "E-85 fuel" as a blend of gasoline at least 85% derived from ethanol; and (2) "ethanol fuel blend" as a blend of gasoline and ethanol, with a minimum of 0% and maximum of 85% derived from denatured ethanol. Requires the Secretary to promulgate regulations to ensure that each major fuel distributor that sells or introduces gasoline into commerce in the United States through majority-owned stations or branded stations installs one or more blender pumps that dispense E-85 fuel and ethanol fuel blends at specified minimum percentages of such stations for specified years in each state. Allows major fuel distributors to earn and sell credits if they exceed such percentages.</summary>
</bill>
