<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1190" updated="2013-07-19T23:06:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-18T14:33:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-18T14:33:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400263"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-17T17:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-441, by Mr. McGovern.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-17T17:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution authorizes the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules at any time through the Calendar day of March 21, 2010. The resolution also provides that the Speaker or her designee shall consult with the Minority Leader or his designee on the designation of any matter for consideration under suspension of the rules pursuant to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-03-17T17:10:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="174">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 174.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18T10:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1600-1605" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18T10:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1190.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18T11:35:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1190, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Foxx demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1609-1611" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 222 - 203 (Roll no. 129).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1610" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-03-18T14:33:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="130" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 232 - 187 (Roll no. 130).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1600" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18T14:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2010--Introduced.
Makes it in order at any time through the calendar day of March 21, 2010, for the Speaker of the House of Representatives to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules.</summary>
</bill>
