<bill session="109" type="h" number="5971" updated="2013-07-19T19:57:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HIT for Small Business Health Care Providers Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Health Information Technology Loan Program within the Small Business Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="2006-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2006--Introduced.
HIT for Small Business Health Care Providers Act of 2006 - Instructs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to ensure that a portion of certain loan amounts secured by the SBA under the Microloan program and under the 504 loan program (which finances small business concerns through loan guarantees under the Small Business Investment Act of 1958), respectively, are secured by certain guarantees. Includes among the guarantee requirements that: (1) the purpose of the guarantee is to help a small business acquire capital for the purchase of materials relating to health information technology; and (2) purchase of materials is made pursuant to a plan certified by the Certification Commission for Healthcare Information Technology. Requires the SBA Inspector General to review periodically a representative sample of such guaranteed loans in order to mitigate fraud and to ensure the safety and soundness of the program.</summary>
</bill>
