<bill session="112" type="s" number="235" updated="2013-07-20T02:18:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lieutenant Colonel Dominic "Rocky" Baragona Justice for American Heroes Harmed by Contractors Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide personal jurisdiction in causes of action against contractors of the United States performing contracts abroad with respect to members of the Armed Forces, civilian employees of the United States, and United States citizen employees of companies performing work for the United States in connection with contractor activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2011-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2011--Introduced.
Lieutenant Colonel Dominic "Rocky" Baragona Justice for American Heroes Harmed by Contractors Act - Directs the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to amend the Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) to: (1) permit the debarment or suspension of U.S. government contractors for evading service of process in civil or criminal proceedings brought against them by a U.S. citizen or national in connection with a contract obligation, or for failing to appear in federal court in such proceedings; and (2) require such contractors performing federal contracts of $5 million or more outside the United States to consent to personal jurisdiction over them by the federal courts in any future action brought by the United States alleging wrongdoing associated with contract performance and in any future civil action alleging a rape or sexual assault of or serious bodily injury to a member of the Armed Forces, a federal civilian employee, or an employee of a company performing work for the United States who is a U.S. citizen or national.</summary>
</bill>
