<bill session="110" type="s" number="1905" updated="2013-07-19T22:37:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regional Presidential Primary and Caucus Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for a rotating schedule for regional selection of delegates to a national Presidential nominating convention, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2007-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300003" joined="2007-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-19">
      <text>Committee on Rules and Administration. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Rules and Administration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3487"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Political conventions"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Primaries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2007--Introduced.
Regional Presidential Primary and Caucus Act of 2007 - Divides the United States into four regions of specified states (including the District of Columbia) for holding presidential primaries in each presidential election year. Requires four successive presidential primaries in each such year, to be held during the period beginning on the first Tuesday of March, April, May, and June and ending on the sixth day following such Tuesday. Directs the Election Assistance Commission to establish procedures for the conduct of a lottery by March 1, 2010, to select which of four regions will hold the first primary. Sets forth a rule for subsequent election cycles. Provides that, in the case where a state elects to select delegates to a political party's national presidential nominating convention through a caucus, the state shall hold a caucus during the period in which its region is scheduled to hold a primary.</summary>
</bill>
