<bill session="113" type="s" number="1308" updated="2013-11-02T07:03:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Savings Through Public-Private Partnerships Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to encourage the increased use of performance contracting in Federal facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412390"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2689"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2013--Introduced.
Energy Savings Through Public-Private Partnerships Act of 2013 - Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to direct each federal facility energy manager to consider, not later than two years after completion of a comprehensive energy evaluation of a federal agency's facilities: (1) implementing any energy-saving or conservation measure that the agency identified in the evaluation that is life cycle cost-effective, and (2) bundling individual measures of varying paybacks together into combined projects. (Under current law, the energy manager is not required to consider such actions.) Requires the energy manager, as part of the Web-based compliance certification system, to provide reasons for not implementing life cycle cost-effective measures. Requires each agency to: (1) use the benchmarking systems selected or developed for the agency under the Act to track energy savings realized by the agency through the implementation of energy-saving or conservation measures and submit information regarding such savings for publication on a website of the Department of Energy (DOE), and (2) consider using energy savings performance or utility energy service contracts to implement such measures. Establishes a goal of entering into energy savings performance contracts or utility energy service contracts equal to $1 billion in each year during the 5-year period beginning on January 1, 2014. Requires each agency to report annually to DOE, and DOE to report to Congress, on progress towards achieving such goal.</summary>
</bill>
