<bill session="111" type="h" number="5211" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Engagement in Education Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen families' engagement in the education of their children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412268" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2010-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2010-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2010-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412220" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2010-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2010--Introduced.
Family Engagement in Education Act of 2010 - Amends title I (Improving the Academic Achievement of the Disadvantaged) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to allocate funds to states and, through them, local educational agencies (LEAs) to develop certain policies and practices to strengthen family engagement in their children's education. Requires states and correctional facilities to work with family members and aftercare providers in developing educational services and transition plans for youth following their stay in state and local institutions for neglected or delinquent youth. Requires states to use part of their grant under part A (Teacher and Principal Training and Recruiting Fund) of title II of the ESEA to train teachers and principals to effectively engage families in their children's education. Establishes a new part E (Family Engagement in Education Programs) under title V of the ESEA requiring the Secretary of Education to provide funding to each state to establish a State Family Engagement Coordinating Council to assure coordination and integration of family engagement activities across the education spectrum. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to: (1) statewide nonprofit organizations to establish Statewide Family Engagement Centers to provide comprehensive training, technical assistance, and capacity building to states, LEAs, schools, and organizations that support family-school partnerships to assist parents in participating effectively in their children's education; and (2) local nonprofit parent organizations to create Local Family Engagement Centers which are to be assessed on their ability to assist parents in overcoming barriers to engaging in their children's education. Directs the Secretary to issue rules that specify research-based metrics on family engagement in education for entities receiving this Act's funding. Requires that there be established in the Department of Education dedicated staff, including a Director, for family and community engagement within the Office of Elementary and Secondary Education.</summary>
</bill>
