<bill session="109" type="h" number="3366" updated="2013-07-19T19:34:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Western New York Redevelopment Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Niagara Redevelopment Act to encourage economic development and recovery in western New York, to promote fiscal transparency, to enhance the safety and security of the Niagara Power Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400641"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Brownfields"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Greenways"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Power marketing administrations"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Waterfronts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2005--Introduced.
Western New York Redevelopment Act of 2005 - Modifies the statutory licensing conditions governing operation of a power project by the New York Power Authority regarding utilization of the federal share of the water of the Niagara River whose use is permitted by international agreement. Directs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to include among additional conditions imposed on any license issued subsequent to the original license: (1) specified mandatory annual payments from the gross proceeds of the Authority to the Erie Canal Harbor Development Corporation; (2) the payment of one percent of gross proceeds, to be split evenly by the Industrial Development Agencies for the counties of Niagara, Erie, Chautauqua, and Cattaraugus, New York; and (3) a requirement that the licensee acquire property or interests sufficient to provide an effective zone of separation between all project control, switching or generating facilities, and any privately owned real property not used for the generation, transmission, or control of electric energy. Requires the Secretary of Energy to conduct: (1) an audit of Niagara Power Project finances and operations since project inception; and (2) subsequent annual audits to verify payments to host communities. Requires the New York Power Authority to provide to First Responders serving the local jurisdictions in which the Niagara Power Project facilities are located adequate resources and assistance to acquire, operate, maintain, and replace the assets needed to protect human life and property from harm should any feature or facility of the Niagara Power Project be subject to damage of any type because of an act of terror or other criminal behavior.</summary>
</bill>
