<bill session="111" type="s" number="3268" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Motor Vehicle Safety Integrity Employment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to prohibit individuals who have worked on motor vehicle safety issues at NHTSA from assisting motor vehicle manufacturers with NHTSA compliance matters for a period of 3 years after terminating employment at NHTSA, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2759-2760"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2010--Introduced.
Motor Vehicle Safety Integrity Employment Act - Prohibits National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) employees, during the 36-month period following the employee's termination of employment with NHTSA, from commencing employment with, or otherwise advising, assisting, or representing for compensation a manufacturer or other person subject to federal motor vehicle safety regulation, if such position or activity involves: (1) communicating with NHTSA regarding motor vehicle safety compliance; (2) representing or advising a manufacturer regarding compliance with motor vehicle safety or average fuel economy standards; or (3) assisting a manufacturer in responding to a NHTSA request for information. Prohibits a motor vehicle manufacturer or other person from employing NHTSA employees in any such prohibited capacity during the 36-month period following the employee's termination of employment with NHTSA. Prescribes civil penalties for violations of this Act. Directs the Inspector General of the Department of Transportation (DOT) to study and report to specified congressional committees on DOT policies and procedures regarding: (1) official communication with former motor vehicle safety employees concerning motor vehicle safety compliance matters for which they had responsibility during the last 12 months of their tenure at DOT; and (2) post-employment restrictions on employees who perform transportation safety functions.</summary>
</bill>
