<bill session="111" type="hr" number="909" updated="2013-07-19T23:03:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-18T12:51:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-11-18T12:51:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3791) to amend sections 33 and 34 of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412307"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-17T16:30:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-340, by Ms. Pingree (ME).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-17T16:30:00-05:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule, the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Science and Technology now printed in the bill modified by the amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying the resolution. The Chair may entertain a motion that the Committee rise only if offered by the chair of the Committee on Science and Technology or his designee. The Chair may not entertain a motion to strike out the enacting words of the bill (as described in clause 9 of rule XVIII).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-11-17T16:30:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="133">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 133.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18T11:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13086-13090" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18T11:40:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 909.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18T12:08:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 909, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Dreier demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question on H. Res. 909 until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18T12:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13091-13092" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18T12:44:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 242 - 174 (Roll no. 897).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13090, H13092" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-11-18T12:51:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="898" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 245 - 173 (Roll no. 898).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13087" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18T12:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="3791"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3791) to amend sections 33 and 34 of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974.</summary>
</bill>
