<bill session="112" type="h" number="6415" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">CLAIM Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Claims Licensing Advancement for Interstate Matters Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate prompt and efficient adjusting of insurance claims in the case of natural and other disasters and losses, to encourage licensing of insurance claims adjusters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412479"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2012-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1543-1544"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2012--Introduced.
Claims Licensing Advancement for Interstate Matters Act or CLAIM Act - Authorizes an independent claims adjuster meeting specified requirements to adjust claims for losses related to any disaster occurring in any jurisdiction designated by the President as a major disaster pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, regardless of state licensure requirements governing the major disaster area. Requires an adjuster to: (1) hold a valid license in his or her home state, and (2) have passed any multi-state examination established and administered by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC). Urges NAIC to: (1) adopt a certain model independent claims adjuster licensing Act, and (2) develop and administer a multi-state examination for an independent claims adjuster seeking to adjust claims in a jurisdiction other than his or her home state. Sets forth criteria for state compliance with this Act, including reciprocity. Authorizes any independent claims adjuster meeting the requirements of this Act to ascertain, determine, negotiate, or settle a claim in a state that is not in compliance with this Act. Prohibits such a state from imposing additional requirements upon such an adjuster.</summary>
</bill>
