<bill session="112" type="h" number="2328" updated="2013-07-20T01:30:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">End Excessive Oil Speculation Now Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Chairman of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to impose unilaterally position limits and margin requirements to eliminate excessive oil speculation, and to take other actions to ensure that the price of crude oil, gasoline, diesel fuel, jet fuel, and heating oil accurately reflects the fundamentals of supply and demand, to remain in effect until the date on which the Commission establishes position limits to diminish, eliminate, or prevent excessive speculation as required by title VII of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400178"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2012-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2012-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2011-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG16" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities and Risk Management" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="1200"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2011--Introduced.
End Excessive Oil Speculation Now Act of 2011 - Directs the Chairman of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) to establish speculative position limits: (1) in any registered trading entity on or through which crude oil, gasoline, diesel fuel, jet fuel, or heating oil futures or swaps are traded that are equal to the position accountability levels or position limits established by the New York Mercantile Exchange (Exchange); and (2) that are equal to the position accountability levels or position limits established by such Exchange upon the aggregate number or amount of positions in contracts based upon the same underlying commodity that may be held by any person (including any group or class of traders) for each month across specified contracts, transactions, and swap contracts. Directs the Chairman to: (1) establish margin requirements of 12% for speculative swaps and futures trading in crude oil, gasoline, diesel fuel, jet fuel, and heating oil; (2) require each bank holding company, investment bank, hedge fund, or swaps dealer trading energy futures or swaps for its own benefit, or on behalf of, or as counterparty to, an index fund, exchange traded fund, or other noncommercial participant, to register with the CFTC as a noncommercial participant and be subject to position limits and margin requirements under this Act. Exempts bona-fide hedge trading from such position limits and margin requirements. Expresses the sense of Congress that, if finalized, the proposed position limits for derivatives that the CFTC included in a specified notice of proposed rulemaking do not fulfill the requirements of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to diminish, eliminate, or prevent excessive speculation.</summary>
</bill>
