<bill session="112" type="h" number="3464" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sandra Day O'Connor Civic Learning Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Education to award grants to promote civic learning and engagement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400185"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2012-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2012-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2011--Introduced.
Sandra Day O'Connor Civic Learning Act of 2011 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the Commissioner for Education Statistics, in administering the National Assessment of Educational Progress, should increase the number of students tested to improve disaggregation and analysis of data regarding progress in history and civics. Amends part C (Innovation for Teacher Quality) of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to repeal We the People, a Civic Education program, and replace it with a program awarding competitive grants to nonprofit educational organizations to develop and implement programs that promote civic learning and engagement through instruction, professional development, and evaluations. Requires such programs to promote: (1) equity through access to funding and program benefits; (2) innovation through design, settings, and delivery; (3) scalability through broad, cost-effective implementation and institutionalization; and (4) accountability through program assessments and the identification of best practices.</summary>
</bill>
