<bill session="113" type="s" number="1210" updated="2013-11-02T07:02:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">A PLUS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Academic Partnerships Lead Us to Success Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow a State to submit a declaration of intent to the Secretary of Education to combine certain funds to improve the academic achievement of students.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412573" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2013-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4795-4796" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="2456"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2013--Introduced.
Academic Partnerships Lead Us to Success Act or the A PLUS Act - Allows each state to submit to the Secretary of Education a declaration of intent, applicable for up to five years, permitting it to receive federal funds on a consolidated basis that would otherwise be directed toward specific programs furthering the stated purpose of title I (Improving the Academic Achievement of the Disadvantaged) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Requires each declaration to be formulated by a combination of specified State Authorizing Officials or by referendum and to list the programs for which consolidated funding is requested. Allows states to use such funds for any educational purpose permitted by state law, but requires them to make certain assurances that they will use fiscal control and fund accounting procedures, abide by federal civil rights laws, and advance educational opportunities for the disadvantaged. Allows states to amend their declarations. Allows each declaration state to adopt new academic assessments and standards or apply those described under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, but requires each state to have a single system of assessments and standards that includes student proficiency goals. Requires each declaration state to: (1) inform the public about its student achievement assessment system; (2) report annually on student progress toward the state's proficiency standards, disaggregating performance data by specified student groups; and (3) keep aggregate spending on elementary and secondary education at no less than 90% of such spending for the school year coinciding with this Act's enactment. Limits administrative expenses. Requires each declaration state to provide for the equitable participation of private school children and teachers in the activities assisted under its declaration of intent.</summary>
</bill>
