<bill session="110" type="h" number="3645" updated="2013-07-19T21:35:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthier Heroes Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To implement recommendations of the President's Commission on Care for America's Returning Wounded Warriors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412229"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2007-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2008-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2007-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="2007-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2008-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2007-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs, Education and Labor, House Administration, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3481"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1975"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family leave"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2007--Introduced.
Healthier Heroes Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to develop a single medical examination for members of the Armed Forces to be used by: (1) Department of Defense (DOD) medical evaluation boards and physical evaluation boards to determine the fitness of a member of the Armed Forces to perform the duties of the member's office, grade, rank, or rating; and (2) the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish the disability rating, compensation, and benefits programs for a member who is retired or separated because of physical disability. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide appropriate medical care to any veteran of Operation Iraqi Freedom or Operation Enduring Freedom for post-traumatic stress disorder regardless of the length of time the veteran has been separated from active duty service. Provides extended benefits under TRICARE (a DOD managed care program) for the primary caregivers of members who incur a serious injury or illness while on active duty. Amends the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to entitle an eligible employee who is the spouse, son, daughter, parent, or next of kin of a covered servicemember to a total of 26 workweeks of leave during a single 12-month period to care for the servicemember. Defines covered servicemember as a member of the U.S. Armed Forces, including a member of the National Guard or a Reserve, who is undergoing medical treatment, recuperation, or therapy, is otherwise in medical hold or medical holdover status, or is otherwise on the temporary disability retired list, for a serious injury or illness incurred in the line of duty on active duty that may render the member medically unfit to perform his or her duties. Provides for the substitution of accrued paid vacation, personal, family leave, or medical or sick leave for any part of the 26-week period. Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the availability of such leave during any other 12-month period. Amends federal civil service law to entitle civilian federal employees to the same leave allowance. Provides for the substitution of accrued paid annual or sick leave for any part of the 26-week period.</summary>
</bill>
