<bill session="112" type="h" number="3002" updated="2013-07-20T01:36:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Fiscal Year 2012 Local Funds Continuation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make local funds of the District of Columbia for fiscal year 2012 available for use by the District at the beginning of the fiscal year at the rate of operations provided under the local budget act for such fiscal year if the regular District of Columbia appropriation bill for such fiscal year does not become law prior to the beginning of such fiscal year.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health Care, District of Columbia, Census and the National Archives     .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO27" subcommittee="Health Care, District of Columbia, Census and the National Archives" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2011--Introduced.
District of Columbia Fiscal Year 2012 Local Funds Continuation Act - Appropriates, out of any moneys of the District of Columbia government not otherwise appropriated, and out of applicable corporate or other revenues, receipts, and funds, the amount provided for any project or activity for which funds are provided in the local budget act for such fiscal year, if the regular District of Columbia appropriation bill for FY2012 does not become law before the beginning of such fiscal year. Declares that an appropriation and funds made available or authority granted for a project or activity for a fiscal year under this Act shall be at the rate of operations provided for it under the FY2012 Budget Request Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-92), as modified as of the enactment of this Act. Makes such an appropriation and funds available for the period: (1) beginning with October 1, 2011; and (2) ending with the enactment of the regular District of Columbia appropriation bill for FY2012. Specifies restrictions on programs or activities subject to other appropriations Acts. States that nothing in this Act shall be construed to effect obligations of the District government mandated by other law.</summary>
</bill>
