<bill session="112" type="h" number="3850" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Government Efficiency through Small Business Contracting Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Government Efficiency through Small Business Contracting Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act with respect to goals for procurement contracts awarded to small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412486" joined="2012-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412423" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412405" joined="2012-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412424" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412413" joined="2012-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21T15:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 112-720, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21T15:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Oversight and Government discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-12-21T15:37:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="523">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 523.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3213"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2012--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Government Efficiency through Small Business Contracting Act of 2012 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Small Business Act to raise from 23% to 25% the governmentwide prime contract award goal for participation by small business concerns and to make the governmentwide subcontract participation award goal 40% for such businesses. Revises percentage goals for awards to small businesses owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, qualified HUBZone (historically underutilized business zone) small businesses, small businesses owned by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, and small businesses owned by women (small business categories). Requires the small business procurement goals established by the head of each federal agency participating in federal procurement contracts to: (1) be in the same format as the goals established by the President; (2) address both prime contract and subcontract awards; and (3) meet or exceed the government-wide goals for each small business category. Requires each agency head to: (1) consult with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) in establishing agency goals, and (2) develop a plan for achieving agency goals. (Sec. 3) Revises requirements concerning information required to be included in annual reports from: (1) agency heads to the Administrator concerning the extent of small business participation in that agency's procurement contracts; and (2) the Administrator to the President and Congress on whether individual agency goals were achieved, as well as reasons for any failure to achieve such goals. Requires, with respect to the latter reports: (1) that all such information be made available on a public website, and (2) the inclusion of information concerning the number and dollar amounts of prime contracts awarded to small businesses owned by an Alaska Native Corporation. (Sec. 4) Requires training programs established for the development of federal senior executives to include training with respect to federal procurement requirements, including those under the Small Business Act. Prohibits the granting of sabbaticals or incentive awards to a senior executive whose agency did not achieve its small business procurement contracting and subcontracting goals in the preceding fiscal year. (Sec. 5) Expresses the sense of Congress that the contracting provisions of the Small Business Act shall apply to the leasing of buildings and office space by the United States and shall not apply to any leasing transaction between private parties.</summary>
</bill>
