<bill session="112" type="s" number="1379" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-28">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-12-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">D.C. Courts and Public Defender Service Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">D.C. Courts and Public Defender Service Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">D.C. Courts and Public Defender Service Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">D.C. Courts and Public Defender Service Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">D.C. Courts and Public Defender Service Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 11, District of Columbia Official Code, to revise certain administrative authorities of the District of Columbia courts, and to authorize the District of Columbia Public Defender Service to provide professional liability insurance for officers and employees of the Service for claims relating to services furnished within the scope of employment with the Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-10-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-06-25">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment. With written report No. 112-178.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-06-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="436">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 436.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2012-07-09" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4790-4791" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 7/10/2012 S4831-4832" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10T10:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-13T09:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-13T09:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6772-6775" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-13T09:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1379.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2012-12-13T09:31:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6772-6773" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-12-13T09:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2012-12-17">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2012-12-28">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2012-12-28" type="public" number="112-229">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-229.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/28/2012--Public Law.
D.C. Courts and Public Defender Service Act of 2011 - Amends the District of Columbia Official Code to require the chief judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals to: (1) call biennial or, as under current law, annual judicial conferences; and (2) summon active magistrate judges to such conferences. Authorizes the chief judges of the District Superior Court and of the District Court of Appeals to toll or delay judicial proceedings in certain natural disaster or other emergency situations. Limits such toll or delay to 14 days, unless the chief judge determines, with the consent of the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration, that an emergency situation requires additional extensions. Authorizes the Executive Officer of the District of Columbia courts to enter into agreements to provide the Mayor of the District with equipment, supplies, and services and credit reimbursements received from the Mayor for them to the appropriation of the District of Columbia courts against which they were charged. Amends the District of Columbia Court Reform and Criminal Procedure Act of 1970 to require the District of Columbia Public Defender Service, to the extent its Director considers appropriate, to provide representation for and hold harmless, or provide liability insurance for, any employee, member of the Board of Trustees, or officer of the Service for money damages arising out of any claim, proceeding, or case at law relating to the furnishing of representational, management, or related services while acting within the scope of that person's office or employment, including employment actions, injury, loss of liberty, property damage, loss of property, personal injury, or death arising from the officer's or employee's malpractice or negligence. Reduces from five to three years the term an individual may be assigned to serve as a judge of the Family Court of the Superior Court.</summary>
</bill>
