<bill session="109" type="h" number="3916" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Millennium Challenge Environmental Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 to promote environmental sustainability in the implementation of programs and activities carried out under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2005-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2005-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2005-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2005-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2005--Introduced.
Millennium Challenge Environmental Accountability Act - Amends the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 (the Act) to apply the environmental procedures applicable to programs, projects, and activities of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to the provision of economic growth and poverty reduction assistance authorized under the Act. Requires each Millennium Challenge Compact (a compact required to be entered into by each participating country) to include a plan to promote environmental sustainability, including prevention, minimization, mitigation, or compensation for the potential adverse impact on natural resources in the implementation of programs and activities funded under the Compact. Provides for the input of non-governmental organizations concerning Compact creation. Requires the inclusion, in an annual report under the Act, of information on progress made toward implementing the country's plan for environmental sustainability. Directs that each report be published in the Federal Register and made available on the Internet.</summary>
</bill>
