<bill session="112" type="h" number="836" updated="2013-07-20T01:17:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-11T12:32:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-03-11T12:32:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Mortgage Relief Program Termination Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Emergency Mortgage Relief Program Termination Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Emergency Mortgage Relief Program Termination Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To rescind the unobligated funding for the Emergency Mortgage Relief Program and to terminate the program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2011-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 22.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-03-07T18:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 112-26.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-03-07T18:55:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="14">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 14.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-03-08T19:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 151 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 836 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-09T13:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 151 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T09:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 151.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1731-1751" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="text of Section 1"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1739" label="as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="text of Section 2"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1740" label="as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="text of Section 3"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1742" label="as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T09:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 836 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T09:13:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 151 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T09:13:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lynn A. Westmoreland to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T09:13:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 836.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T10:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 151, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Canseco amendment number 5 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T10:46:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 151, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Neugebauer amendment number 3 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T10:49:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 151, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Waters amendment number 4 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T11:18:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Waters amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Ms. Waters demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T11:19:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 151, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Loretta Sanchez amendment number 7 under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T11:32:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T11:54:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 836.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T11:55:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1748" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T11:55:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T11:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Connolly (VA) moved to recommit with instructions to Financial Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1748-1750" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1748" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T11:57:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with amendments which provide a continuation of the provisions of the program for military veteran homeowners.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T12:10:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1749" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T12:26:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 182 - 238 (Roll no. 173).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1750" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-03-11T12:32:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="174" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 242 - 177 (Roll no. 174).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T12:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T12:33:00-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 830.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="151"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h186"/>
    <amendment number="h187"/>
    <amendment number="h188"/>
    <amendment number="h189"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/11/2011--Passed House amended.
Emergency Mortgage Relief Program Termination Act - Rescinds and permanently cancels all unobligated funding remaining available under the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act for the Emergency Mortgage Relief Program. Terminates the program. Requires all such unobligated balances so rescinded and permanently canceled to be retained in the general fund of the Treasury for reducing the debt of the federal government. Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to study: (1) the extent to which the Emergency Mortgage Relief Program is used by homeowners who are active duty members of the Armed Forces (or their spouses or parents), veterans, or Gold Star-eligible widows, parents, or next of kin of Armed Forces members who died in military operations or members or veterans with service-connected injuries (and their survivors and dependents); and (2) the impact of the program on such homeowners.</summary>
</bill>
