<bill session="109" type="s" number="389" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cigarette Fire Safety Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for fire safety standards for cigarettes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2006-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1430-1431"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1431" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1850"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tobacco industry"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2005--Introduced.
Cigarette Fire Safety Act of 2005 - Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission to prescribe fire safety standards for cigarettes that, except as provided in this Act, are substantively the same as specified standards promulgated by the State of New York. Directs sponsors of testing methodologies employed under this Act to notify the Commission of any modifications in such methodologies. Authorizes the Commission to modify established fire safety standards to incorporate modifications that will enhance those standards. Requires fire safety standards promulgated under this Act to be treated as consumer product safety standards, and directs that cigarettes shall be treated as consumer products, under the Consumer Product Safety Act (CPSA). Precludes the preemption by this Act of the New York standard or more stringent fire safety standards for cigarettes promulgated by any State. Makes the CPSA's private remedy provisions applicable to fire safety standards promulgated under this Act. Denies the Commission any jurisdiction over tobacco or tobacco products except as provided in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
