<bill session="109" type="s" number="3781" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disaster Preparedness and Hazard Mitigation Improvement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for hurricane and flood protection and coastal restoration projects in the State of Louisiana, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Homestead law"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban housing"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2006--Introduced.
Disaster Preparedness and Hazard Mitigation Improvement Act of 2006 - Authorizes the President to provide assistance under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act for hazard mitigation activities in response to Hurricanes Katrina and Rita, except that: (1) the President may contribute up to 90% of the cost of hazard mitigation measures; (2) the assistance shall be available for at least five years; and (3) the total contributions for a major disaster shall not exceed 15% of the estimated aggregate amount of grants to be made under that Act for such hurricanes. Deems an enhanced mitigation plan of Louisiana or Mississippi to have been approved when the President declared a major disaster relating to such hurricanes if such a plan is approved within 180 days after enactment of this Act. Allows funds made available for hazard mitigation for Louisiana in excess of $500 million to be made available for: (1) the design and construction of hurricane and flood protection projects and coastal restoration projects to reduce storm surge in any area in the state in which a major disaster relating to such hurricanes was declared by the President; (2) the construction and improvement of federal-aid highways or state highways within such area that the governor determines to be integral for the evacuation of southern Louisiana in response to a disaster; and (3) carrying out any coordinated effort authorized by the governor relating to environment or land use management, economic development, the acquisition or disposition of property, property management, or urban homesteading.</summary>
</bill>
