<bill session="109" type="s" number="2313" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Drug Honest Pricing Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to permit medicare beneficiaries enrolled in prescription drug plans and MA-PD plans that change their formalities or increase drug prices to enroll in other plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2006-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1432-1433" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2006--Introduced.
Medicare Drug Honest Pricing Act of 2006 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to permit Medicare beneficiaries enrolled in prescription drug plans (PDP's) and Medicare Advantage-Prescription Drug Plans that change their formularies or increase drug prices to enroll in other plans. Requires PDP sponsor, every November, to disclose to the Secretary of Health and Human Services the negotiated price of each covered part D drug for the following year, and the Secretary, the same month of every year, to make such disclosure available to the public through the Internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services. Requires each PDP sponsor also to inform, by January 10 of each year, part D eligible enrollees in its plan of such negotiated prices.</summary>
</bill>
