<bill session="111" type="h" number="6183" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Employees Responsible Investment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for a corporate responsibility investment option under the Thrift Savings Plan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2010-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1692"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2010--Introduced.
Federal Employees Responsible Investment Act - Provides for the establishment of a Corporate Responsibility Stock Index Fund as an investment option under the Thrift Savings Plan (TSP). Directs the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board to select a minimum of one index which is a commonly recognized, passively managed index comprised of stocks based on criteria which shall at a minimum include corporate governance, environmental practices, workplace relations and benefits, product safety and impact, international operations and human rights, involvement with repressive regimes, and community relations. Requires that the index's financial track record be comparable to that of the other options available under TSP. Directs that the Fund be invested in a portfolio which shall be designed such that the percentage of the Fund that is invested in each stock is the same as the percentage determined by dividing the aggregate market value of all shares of that stock by the aggregate market value of all shares of all stocks included in such index.</summary>
</bill>
