<bill session="112" type="s" number="1117" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TAA Health Coverage Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend section 35 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve the health coverage tax credit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2011-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3439-3440"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
TAA Health Coverage Improvement Act of 2011 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the tax credit for the health insurance costs of trade adjustment assistance (TAA) workers, to: (1) increase the rate of such credit form 65% to 95% of health insurance costs; (2) allow a 100% tax credit and a full payment of TAA worker health insurance premiums for months prior to the issuance of a qualified health insurance costs credit eligibility certificate; and (3) set forth new tax credit eligibility rules for TAA workers and their family members, including for TAA workers who are not enrolled in training programs. Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to: (1) prevent a lapse of health care coverage for TAA workers and Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC) recipients, (2) allow a permanent extension of COBRA coverage (health insurance continuation benefits) for certain TAA workers and PBGC recipients, and (3) align COBRA coverage periods under such Act with eligibility periods for TAA workers. Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), jointly with the Secretary of the Treasury, to establish a program to offer TAA workers enrollment in the Federal Employees Health Benefit Program (FEHBP) and to conduct a study of the impact of such program on FEHBP. Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to: (1) require a state or entity to use national emergency grant funds to provide TAA workers and their family members with health insurance coverage for periods prior to their first eligibility month, and (2) require the Secretary of Labor to report to Congress on failures to provide assistance to states in expediting applications for national emergency grants.</summary>
</bill>
