<bill session="109" type="h" number="4686" updated="2013-07-19T19:45:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Multi-State and International Fisheries Conservation and Management Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Multi-State and International Fisheries Conservation and Management Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize various fisheries management laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400149"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="2006-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries and Oceans Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-04-27T16:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-444.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-04-27T16:56:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="248">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 248.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishery agreements"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Overfishing"/>
    <term name="Shellfish"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tuna"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2006--Reported to House amended.
Multi-State and International Fisheries Conservation and Management Act of 2006 - Reauthorizes through FY2012: (1) the Interjurisdictional Fisheries Act of 1986, including authorization of appropriations to the Department of Commerce for management of interjurisdictional fishery resources and the development of interstate fishery management plans for interjurisdictional fishery resources; (2) the Anadromous Fish Conservation Act, including authorization of appropriations for preservation of fishery resources; (3) the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975, including authorization of appropriations for the International Convention for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas and including use for the payment of the U.S. share of the joint expenses of the International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas; and (4) the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Act of 1995, including authorization of appropriations for the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention and including use for the payment of the U.S. contribution to the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization. Reauthorizes through FY2016 the Dungeness Crab Fishery Management Act of 1996, allowing the states of Washington, Oregon, and California to enforce state laws governing fishing and processing of Dungeness crab fisheries where there is no fishery management plan in effect. Requires the Pacific State Marine Fisheries Commission to report biennially to Congress on the status and management of the Dungeness Crab fishery located off the coasts of such states, including stock status and trends throughout its range, a description of research and scientific review processes used to determine such stock status and trends, and measures implemented or planned to prevent or end overfishing in the fishery. Expresses the sense of Congress that the U.S. Commissioners to the Atlantic Tunas Convention should seek to include ecosystem and conservation of fish habitat considerations in fisheries management.</summary>
</bill>
