<bill session="113" type="h" number="517" updated="2013-11-02T06:23:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Employees Paid Parental Leave Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that 4 of the 12 weeks of parental leave made available to a Federal employee shall be paid leave, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2013-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2013-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2013-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E99"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/2013--Introduced.
Federal Employees Paid Parental Leave Act of 2013 - Allows federal employees to substitute any available paid leave for any leave without pay available for either the: (1) birth of a child, or (2) placement of a child with the employee for either adoption or foster care. Makes available (subject to specified requirements) for any of the 12 weeks of leave an employee is entitled to for such purposes: (1) four administrative weeks of paid parental leave in connection with the birth or placement involved, and (2) any accumulated annual or sick leave. Authorizes the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to promulgate regulations to increase the amount of paid parental leave available to such an employee to a total of eight administrative workweeks, based on the consideration of: (1) the benefits to the federal government, including enhanced recruitment and employee retention; (2) the cost to the government; (3) trends in the private sector and in state and local governments; (4) the federal government's role as a model employer; and (5) the impact of increased paid parental leave on lower-income and economically disadvantaged employees and their children. Amends the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 and the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to allow the same substitution for covered congressional employees, Government Accountability Office (GAO) employees, and Library of Congress employees. Counts certain service by an employee of the executive branch, Congress, GAO, or the Library of Congress while on active duty as a member of the National Guard or Reserves as service for that branch or agency for purposes of determining such employee's eligibility to take or substitute leave as provided under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
