<bill session="109" type="h" number="3910" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Verifying the Outcome of Tomorrow's Elections Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require individuals to present a government-issued photo identification as a condition of voting in elections for Federal office, to prohibit any individual from tabulating votes in an election for Federal office unless the individual has been subject to a criminal background check, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400131"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2005-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2006-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2005-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400642" joined="2005-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2005-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting machines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2005--Introduced.
Verifying the Outcome of Tomorrow's Elections Act of 2005 - Amends the Help Vote Act of 2002 to prohibit the appropriate state or local election official from providing a ballot for an election for federal office to an individual who desires to vote in person, unless the individual presents to the official a current, valid, state-issued photo identification. Imposes similar requirements with respect to individuals voting by mail. Requires each state to conduct regular tests of the equipment used to tabulate votes in voting systems to ensure that a system meets specified error rate standards, and that the equipment works correctly. Prohibits a state from permitting any individual to tabulate votes cast on a voting system, or to certify the tabulation of votes, unless that individual has satisfactorily undergone a criminal history background check using the national criminal history background check system and the state criminal history repositories of all states in which the individual has resided. Requires a state to permit a representative of each political party with a candidate on the ballot used at a precinct during an election to observe the tabulation of the votes cast on the voting system, and the certification of such tabulation. Makes it unlawful for any person to pay any other person for distributing voter registration applications in federal elections, or for collecting completed or partially completed applications, if the amount of the payment is determined on the basis of the number of applications distributed or collected. Requires production of a permanent, individually verifiable paper record of each vote cast. Requires voluntary voting system guidelines to ensure the security of any data transmitted or received electronically by voting systems.</summary>
</bill>
