<bill session="110" type="s" number="3707" updated="2013-07-19T22:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Principal Recruitment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to recruit, train, and support principals for high-need schools who are effective in improving student academic achievement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-11-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10670-10671"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-11-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2008--Introduced.
National Principal Recruitment Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to establish a National Principal Recruitment program awarding matching grants to up to three partnerships each of which consist of a nonprofit organization working with a research organization and local educational agencies to: (1) recruit new principals for high-need schools and provide them with a year-long preservice residency and ongoing support and professional development; and (2) rigorously research, evaluate, and report on such activities so that successful practices can be replicated and each grantee's success in improving student academic performance can be measured. Increases a grant by 50% after the third full school year of its implementation if: (1) such research and evaluation demonstrates that students in high-need schools led, for at least two years, by principals recruited, trained, and supported by the grantee are making greater academic gains than comparable students elsewhere; and (2) the grantee has the capacity to scale up its services. Terminates a grant by the end of the fourth year of its implementation if the students in high-need schools led, for at least two years, by such principals are not making greater academic gains than comparable students elsewhere. Defines "high-need schools" as public elementary or secondary schools where at least 40% of the students receive a free or reduced price lunch under the school lunch program.</summary>
</bill>
