<bill session="113" type="h" number="2282" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Internet Gambling Regulation, Enforcement, and Consumer Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To regulate Internet gambling, to provide consumer protections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2013-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2666"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/2013--Introduced.
Internet Gambling Regulation, Enforcement, and Consumer Protection Act of 2013 - Prohibits operation of an Internet gambling facility that offers services to persons in the United States, except as authorized under this Act. Provides exceptions with respect to licensed race tracks, operators offering lottery transactions or services relating to bets or wagers by a state or Indian tribe, and persons engaged outside the United States in bet or wager activities that are initiated, received, or made solely by individuals outside the United States. Establishes within the Treasury the Office of Internet Gambling Oversight, headed by an Executive Director. Outlines requirements for the designation of entities for the regulation and oversight of authorized Internet gambling facilities. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to withdraw such designation in appropriate circumstances. Includes the Office as such an entity. Directs the Secretary to establish and carry out an application and licensing program for such facilities, including suitability qualifications and disqualification standards. Provides for disciplinary procedures and civil penalties against licensee violators. Requires each designated entity, before issuing a facility license, to provide for the development of a compulsive gaming, responsible gaming, and self-exclusion program, to be implemented by each licensee. Allows gambling at such facilities only with respect to bets or wagers from individuals located in states and Indian lands that have opted-in for participation in such gaming. Provides for opt-in and opt-out elections. Prohibits this Act from being construed to authorize a licensee to accept a wager on any sporting event in violation of a federal or state law. Makes it a violation of this Act to operate a place of public accommodation in which computer terminals or similar devices are made available principally for accessing such facilities. Prohibits Internet gambling cheating and the use of cheating devices and provides enforcement authority. Authorizes designated entities to issue initial licenses before the authorized date of first issuance under this Act (270 days after enactment). Requires annual reports from the Secretary to Congress on the licensing and regulation of such facilities and on practices to protect consumers with respect to such gambling. Directs the Secretary to require the independent testing of hardware, software, communications equipment, and other necessary devices for such facilities to ensure their integrity, accountability, randomness of play, and network security. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish and implement programs for the identification, prevention, and treatment of pathological and other problem gambling. Directs the Treasury Secretary to compile and make publicly available datasets on player gambling behavior. Provides for enforcement of provisions of this Act through the federal criminal code and federal financial transaction requirements.</summary>
</bill>
