<bill session="111" type="s" number="4034" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SMART Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening Manufacturing and Rebuilding Transit Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to support United States manufacturing by providing rules and guidance, waiver notices, and departmental and agency actions applicable to the domestic content standards of Federal grants administered by the Department of Transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2010--Introduced.
Strengthening Manufacturing and Rebuilding Transit Act of 2010 or SMART Act - Requires the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to give preference to the award of discretionary or competitive grants, loans, loan guarantees, and lines of credit to transportation infrastructure projects, including the purchase of transit vehicle rolling stock, rail, and supporting equipment, in which manufactured goods to be purchased have a domestic content percentage that: (1) exceeds applicable federal requirements; and (2) in the case of rolling stock, is consistent with industry-recognized standards, if available. Directs the Secretary to establish a centralized website that provides rules and guidance, waiver notices, and agency actions of the domestic content standards (Buy America) for DOT federal-aid programs. Requires a federal agency head to subject to public notice and comment any request for waiver, and to publication in the Federal Register and notification to Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) of any waiver, of Buy America requirements involving: (1) federal-aid highway and public transportation projects, (2) AMTRAK acquisition and maintenance of equipment and facilities, and (3) intercity passenger rail service corridor capital assistance projects. Directs the DOT Inspector General to report annually to Congress on acquisitions funded by federal transportation infrastructure investments that do not comply with Buy American requirements. Authorizes the Secretary to work with the Hollings Manufacturing Partnership Program and other manufacturing-related local intermediaries to develop a multi-agency comprehensive plan to expand domestic manufacturer rail and transit vehicle supply chains.</summary>
</bill>
