<bill session="113" type="h" number="2823" updated="2013-11-02T06:42:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gas Accessibility and Stabilization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Energy to conduct a fuel system requirements harmonization study, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400400"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412538" joined="2013-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1319"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2013--Introduced.
Gas Accessibility and Stabilization Act of 2013 - Amends the Clean Air Act to revise procedures for waiver by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) of a control or prohibition regarding the use of a fuel or fuel additive by: (1) allowing waiver if the Administrator determines that extreme and unusual fuel or fuel additive supply circumstances are the result of a problem with distribution or delivery equipment necessary for the transportation or delivery of such fuel or additives, (2) allowing extension of a waiver for more than 20 days if it is determined that the waiver conditions will exist beyond 20 days, and (3) deeming a request for a waiver that is not approved or denied within 3 days to be approved for the period requested. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to modify a fuel system requirements harmonization study to: (1) include consideration of biofuels, (2) add consideration of the projected effects of EPA Tier III requirements on air quality and motor fuel prices, and (3) extend to June 1, 2014, the date for submission to Congress of a report on the results of the study.</summary>
</bill>
