<bill session="112" type="s" number="1999" updated="2013-07-20T02:33:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Senior Medicare Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to apply the frailty adjustment under PACE payment rules to certain specialized MA plans for special needs individuals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3691"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2011--Introduced.
Senior Medicare Fairness Act - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act for plan year 2013 and subsequent plan years with respect to payments to Medicare + Choice organizations for original fee-for-service benefits under a specialized Medicare Advantage plan for special needs individuals that: (1) offers integrated Medicare and Medicaid services under contract with the state agency under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act; and (2) is offered by a Medicare Advantage organization that as of January 1, 2010, had a contract with such state Medicaid agency that participated in the "Demonstrations Serving Those Dually-Eligible for Medicare and Medicaid." Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to apply the frailty adjustment under payment rules for programs of all-inclusive care for the elderly (PACE) rather than those which would otherwise apply for plan enrollees.</summary>
</bill>
