<bill session="111" type="h" number="4493" updated="2013-07-19T23:53:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bonitan Tasi</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Marianas Trench Marine National Monument Management Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Bunitan Tasi Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the enhancement of visitor services, fish and wildlife research, and marine and coastal resource management on Guam related to the Marianas Trench Marine National Monument, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2010-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-05-18T14:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-484.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-05-18T14:39:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="275">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 275.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/2010--Reported to House amended.
Bunitan Tasi Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce to treat the government of Guam as a cooperating agency with responsibilities and roles similar to the government of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, including with respect to membership on the Mariana Monument Advisory Council. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) enhance visitor services programs at Guam National Wildlife Refuge; and (2) initiate a comprehensive program to facilitate natural resource exploration and research, as well as encourage tourism, recreation, and economic opportunities to build public awareness and appreciation of the natural resources under the jurisdiction of the Interior and Commerce Departments. Permits, under the enhancement of such programs and the comprehensive program, the inclusion of activities for: (1) enhanced resource management, research, and visitor services programs for the promotion and interpretation of the fish and wildlife resources of Guam, including activities to improve the conservation of coral reef ecosystems and activities to conserve Guam's marine resources; and (2) the facilitation of environmental education for students on Guam in partnership with the University of Guam, Guam Community College, and the Guam Department of Education. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to accept and spend donated funds and use donated property or services from private persons and entities or from public entities to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
