<bill session="111" type="h" number="5795" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Personalize Your Care Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of voluntary advance care planning consultation under Medicare and Medicaid, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2010-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1375-1376"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6287"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2010--Introduced.
Personalize Your Care Act of 2010 - Amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid), as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to cover a Voluntary Advance Care Planning Consultation. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to eligible entities to: (1) establish statewide programs for physician orders for life-sustaining treatment; or (2) expand or enhance existing programs for physician orders for life-sustaining treatment. Directs the Secretary to adopt, by rule, standards for a qualified electronic health record, with respect to patient communications with a health care provider about values and goals of care, to adequately display the patient's current: (1) advance directive; and/or (2) physician order for life-sustaining treatment. Requires under Medicare and Medicaid that an advance directive validly executed outside the state in which the directive is presented must be given effect by a service provider or an organization to the same extent as an advance directive validly executed under the law of the state in which it is presented. Requires that, in the absence of a validly executed advance directive, any authentic expression of a person's wishes with respect to health care be honored.</summary>
</bill>
