<bill session="111" type="h" number="6019" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Accountability and Transparency in Ethics Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to extend the post-employment restrictions on certain executive and legislative branch officers and employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on House Administration, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
Accountability and Transparency in Ethics Act of 2010 - Amends the federal criminal code to revise post-employment restrictions on former officers, employees, and elected officials of the executive and legislative branches. Increases from one to two years the ban on lobbying contacts by the following individuals with a Member, officer, or employee of the entity in which they served before his or her tenure terminated: (1) former senior and very senior personnel of the executive branch and independent agencies (except for special government employees who serve less that 60 days in the two-year period before termination); (2) former Members of the House of Representatives or elected officers; (3) former elected officers and employees of the Senate; (4) former personal staff of House Members; (5) former employees of House committees or congressional joint committees; (6) House leadership staff; and (7) employees of other legislative offices. Increases from one to two years the lobbying ban on former officers, employees, and elected officials of the executive and legislative branches for foreign entities. Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit payment of campaign funds, except reimbursements under $500, to immediate family members of candidates. Requires the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to provide an ethics training course to registered lobbyists. Expresses the sense of Congress that any changes to the duties and responsibilities of the Office of Congressional Ethics (OCE) should strengthen, not undermine, its powers to further improve accountability and transparency in Congress. Grants subpoena power to the OCE board to carry out its duties.</summary>
</bill>
