<bill session="113" type="s" number="793" updated="2013-11-02T06:58:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-02">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Organization of American States Revitalization and Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Organization of American States Revitalization and Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Organization of American States Revitalization and Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Organization of American States Revitalization and Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support revitalization and reform of the Organization of American States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez without amendment. With written report No. 113-43.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="87">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 87.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2013-07-08" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5529-5530" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5529-5530" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-07-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-09T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5567-5569" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 793.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17T17:34:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5574-5575" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="462" datetime="2013-09-17T19:16:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 383 - 24 (Roll no. 462).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5567-5568" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-09-18">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="pingpong" datetime="2013-09-25" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Senate agreed to House amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/24/2013 S6901" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-09-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2013-09-26">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2013-10-02">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-41" type="public" datetime="2013-10-02" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-41.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2013--Public Law.
Organization of American States Revitalization and Reform Act of 2013 - States that it is U.S. policy to: (1) promote democracy, the rule of law, and human rights in the Western Hemisphere; and (2) support the practices and principles expressed in the Charter of the Organization of American States, the American Declaration on the Rights and Duties of Man, the Inter-American Democratic Charter, and other fundamental instruments of democracy. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Organization of American States (OAS) should be the primary multi-lateral diplomatic entity for regional dispute resolution and promotion of democratic governance; (2) the Summit of the Americas process should be formally and more effectively integrated into the work of the OAS, the Inter-American Development Bank, and other Members of the Joint Summit Working Group; (3) the OAS has historically accepted too many member state mandates creating unclear priorities and loss of institutional focus; and (4) it is in the interest of the United States and the OAS and its member states to move toward an assessed fee structure that assures financial sustainability and establishes, within five years, that no member state pays more than 50% of the organization's assessed fees. Directs the Secretary of State to submit to Congress a multiyear strategy that: (1) leads to such assessed fee structure, (2) identifies a path toward the adoption of necessary reforms that prioritize the core competencies of the OAS, (3) outlines a results-based budgeting process to prioritize current and future mandates and transparent hiring and promotion practices, and (4) reflects the inputs and coordination from other executive branch agencies. Directs the Secretary to: (1) carry out diplomatic engagement to build support for reforms and budgetary burden sharing among OAS member states and observers, and (2) promote donor coordination among OAS member states.</summary>
</bill>
