<bill session="112" type="s" number="1023" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Haiti Reforestation Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Haiti Reforestation Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the President to provide assistance to the Government of Haiti to end within 5 years the deforestation in Haiti and restore within 30 years the extent of tropical forest cover in existence in Haiti in 1990, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2011-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2012-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2011-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2011-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2012-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2012-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3163"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3110-3112" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-02-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry without amendment. With written report No. 112-165.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-05-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="399">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 399.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2012--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Haiti Reforestation Act of 2011 - Title I: Forestation and Watershed Management Assistance to Government of Haiti - (Sec.101) Authorizes the President to provide the government of Haiti with financial assistance, technology transfers, or capacity building assistance to reduce deforestation and increase reforestation in Haiti. Includes among eligible activities fire reduction, forest monitoring, market-based reforestation, and watershed restoration. Directs the President, if assistance is provided and in cooperation with the government of Haiti, to develop performance metrics to verify: (1) the conduct of policies and initiatives to be carried out by the government of Haiti, and (2) their impact on tropical forests and on local communities. Authorizes the President to provide financial and other assistance to the government of Haiti, local government bodies, or nongovernmental organizations to: (1) inform local communities about policies and initiatives to be carried out by the government of Haiti; (2) promote local participation in the design, implementation, and independent monitoring of policies and initiatives; and (3) promote enhanced watershed governance, national planning, and community action programs. Title II: Grants for Reforestation - (Sec. 201) Authorizes the President to establish a grant program to carry out the purposes of this Act, including reversing deforestation and improving reforestation and afforestation in Haiti. Includes among eligible activities: (1) providing financial incentives to protect trees, (2) promoting sustainable income-generating growth, (3) promoting improved cooking stove technologies, and (4) securing local community involvement in protecting existing forests and carrying out afforestation and reforestation activities. (Sec. 202) Amends the the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to: (1) direct the President to invite the government of Haiti to submit a list of areas in which tropical forests are seriously degraded or threatened, and (2) authorize the President to make grants to nongovernmental organizations to purchase discounted commercial debt of the government of Haiti in exchange for government commitments to restore identified forests or to develop plans for their sustainable use. Title III: Administration Provision - (Sec. 301) Authorizes the President, or the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) or the Secretary of State as the President's delegee, to draw on the expertise of the United States Forest Service in designing and implementing programs pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
