<bill session="113" type="s" number="318" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Protection Agency Accountability Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to rescind funds made available to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency if the Administrator fails to meet certain deadlines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412320"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S713-714"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2013--Introduced.
Environmental Protection Agency Accountability Act of 2013 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to ensure that the following regulatory requirements are satisfied: (1) Executive Order 13563 (concerning regulatory principles) and the regulatory planning procedures of Executive Order 12866, as well as successor Executive Orders concerning reporting of regulatory and deregulatory agendas; (2) regulatory flexibility agenda requirements; (3) requirements of Executive Order 13132 concerning certifications by agencies upon transmittals of draft final regulations of adherence to federalism principles; and (4) portions of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 that require agencies to publish statements describing and assessing state, local, and tribal compliance costs before promulgating any general notice of proposed rulemaking. Imposes financial penalties, in the form of funding rescissions, upon the Office of the Administrator if the Comptroller General determines that any of the above requirements have not been satisfied. Requires EPA Inspector General audits for any fiscal year in which funds were so rescinded.</summary>
</bill>
