<bill session="110" type="h" number="120" updated="2013-07-19T21:04:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ICARE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Intercountry Adoption Reform Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reform Federal procedures relating to intercountry adoption.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400095"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Abandonment of family"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Emigration"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International employees"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Orphans"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Support of dependents"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Treaty-making power"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Intercountry Adoption Reform Act of 2007 or the ICARE Act - Establishes an Office of Intercountry Adoptions within the Department of State to be headed by the Ambassador at Large for Intercountry Adoptions. Transfers to the Office all functions with respect to intercountry adoptions currently performed by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to revise: (1) conditions for automatic citizenship for children born outside the United States, including for adopted children; and (2) requirements concerning the history of parents' physical presence in the United States or its possessions. Defines the term "full and final adoption." Prescribes procedural requirements for the adoption of foreign-born children by U.S. citizens.Establishes a nonimmigrant W-visa for an adoptable child coming into the United States for adoption by a U.S. citizen and spouse or by an unmarried U.S. Citizen at least 25 years of age who has been approved by the Office of International Adoption of the Department of State. Sets forth the period of authorized admission for such a nonimmigrant.Exempts adopted children of 18 years of age or younger (currently, 10 years of age or younger) from immunization requirements.Redefines the term "adoptable child."Requires U.S. Citizen adoptive parents to obtain approval of an adoption petition prior to issuance of a visa or a full and final adoption decree. Subjects such petitions to the terms applicable to orphan petitions. Directs the Secretary of State to issue regulations: (1) establishing an expedited reapproval process for families whose prior approvals to adopt have expired; and (2) governing the appeal of petition denials.Prescribes procedural requirements for the issuance of a visa and a full and final adoption decree for foreign-born children, including requirements for the Ambassador to: (1) determine whether a child is an adoptable child; and (2) work with the competent authorities of the child's country of residence to establish a process for the exchange and approval of a certification that the child sought to be adopted meets the definition of an adoptable child.Requires the Secretary to issue a final decision regarding the child's eligibility as an adoptable child within 30 days. Allows an appeal.Provides for civil penalties and enforcement.</summary>
</bill>
