<bill session="110" type="h" number="200" updated="2013-07-19T21:05:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Education for the 21st Century (E-21) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enable America's schools to use their computer hardware to increase student achievement and prepare students for the 21st century workplace, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400346"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Citizenship education"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social sciences"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="World Wide Web"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Education for the 21st Century (E-21) Act - Establishes assistance programs for: (1) middle school computer literacy; and (2) high-quality educational software for all schools.Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to states (especially those with a priority on training middle school teachers) that integrate into the state curriculum the goal of making all middle school graduates in the state technologically literate. Requires use of such grants for teacher training in technology, emphasizing programs preparing teachers in elementary, middle, and secondary schools to become technology leaders and then serve as experts and train other teachers. Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive grants for students at secondary schools and institutions of higher education (IHEs) to work with IHE faculty, software developers, and experts in educational technology in developing high-quality educational software and Internet websites. Directs the Secretary to recognize outstanding software and websites developed with such assistance that focus on core curriculum areas, especially: (1) for the first year of awards, mathematics, science, and reading; and (2) for the second and third years of awards, again mathematics, science, and reading, but also social studies, the humanities, and the arts. Requires: (1) such recognized educational software to be made available to local educational agencies for free downloading from the Department of Education's website; and (2) such recognized websites to be accessible to any Web user.</summary>
</bill>
