<bill session="110" type="h" number="6382" updated="2013-07-19T21:59:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-09T11:49:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-09T11:49:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pension Protection Technical Corrections Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Pension Protection Technical Corrections Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical corrections related to the Pension Protection Act of 2006, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-09T11:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pomeroy moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-09T11:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6243-6252" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-09T11:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6382.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-07-09T11:49:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6243-6249" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-07-09T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3361"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="7327"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1974"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Airline employees"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Defined benefit pension plans"/>
    <term name="Defined contribution plans"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2008--Passed House without amendment.
Pension Protection Technical Corrections Act of 2008 - Title I: Technical Corrections Related to the Pension Protection Act of 2006 - (Sec. 101) Makes technical corrections to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code to conform to the Pension Protection Act of 2006 regarding various specified items, including: (1) the target normal cost of benefits; (2) specified implementation and effective dates for certain requirements; (3) one-participant retirement plans; (4) special age-related rules in accrued benefit requirements for applicable defined benefit plans; (5) inapplicability in certain cases of the limitation on income deductions (for tax purposes) for employer contributions to one or more defined contribution plans; and (6) adjustments to averaging in the determination of the value of the assets of single-employer defined benefit pension plans for minimum funding purposes. (Sec. 110) Makes technical corrections to the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 with respect to railroad retirement payments to persons not entitled to an annuity. Title II: Other Provisions - (Sec. 201) Requires that the value of assets for any ERISA plan under the averaging method be adjusted for expected earnings (in addition to contributions and distributions, as under current law). (Sec. 202) Modifies the interest rate assumption required with respect to certain small employer plans. (Sec. 203) Makes technical corrections to the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 with respect to special age-related rules for determination of the market rate of return in the calculation of interest credits in governmental defined benefit plans. (Sec. 204) Prescribes a special rule for exclusion from gross income of certain reimbursements from governmental plans for health care expenses of a deceased plan participant's beneficiary. (Sec. 205) Requires treatment as a qualified rollover contribution of any airline payment amount received by a qualified airline employee in an airline carrier bankruptcy which is transferred to a Roth IRA. (Sec. 206) Increases by $4 the penalties for failure to file partnership returns and S corporation returns.</summary>
</bill>
