<bill session="109" type="s" number="1067" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Options for Rural Elders Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">CORE Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to undertake activities to ensure the provision of services under the PACE program to frail elders living in rural areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2005-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2005-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2005-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="2005-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Patient satisfaction"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Welfare waivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/2005--Introduced.
Community Options for Rural Elders Act of 2005 or the CORE Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide for the Administrator of Health Resources and Services to work with the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services to establish Programs for All-Inclusive Care for Elderly (PACE) providers in rural areas. Directs the Secretary to permit a rural PACE provider applicant to adapt its PACE program to the unique requirements of eligible participants residing in rural areas and the challenges of providing services to them. Requires the Secretary to waive certain requirements of titles XI, XVIII (Medicare), and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act as necessary to support the delivery of PACE services in rural areas. Directs the Secretary to award site development grants to rural PACE providers. Directs the Secretary, through the Office of Rural Health Policy, to make awards to tax-exempt organizations for the purpose of establishing a technical assistance outreach and education program. Requires the Secretary to establish a fund to reimburse rural PACE providers awarded a site development grant for outlier costs with respect to eligible enrollees in rural areas. Directs the Secretary to establish an advisory group.</summary>
</bill>
