<bill session="112" type="s" number="1976" updated="2013-07-20T02:33:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize educational assistance under the Armed Forces Health Professions Scholarship program for pursuit of advanced degrees in physical therapy and occupational therapy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8462-8463"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2011--Introduced.
Requires, in accordance with guidance issued by the Secretary of Defense (DOD), that assistance be available under the Armed Forces Health Professions Scholarship program for pursuit of a master's and doctoral degree in the disciplines of physical and occupational therapy. Terminates the availability of assistance for either such discipline when the Secretary certifies that there no longer exists a current or projected shortfall in qualified personnel in that discipline in either the military departments or any major military medical treatment facility specializing in the rehabilitation of wounded Armed Forces members. Declares that assistance under this Act, if not already terminated, shall expire two years after enactment of this Act, provided that such expiration is not construed to terminate ongoing assistance to persons provided assistance before or as of such date.</summary>
</bill>
