<bill session="112" type="h" number="5804" updated="2013-07-20T02:00:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preparedness Coordination With Local Educational Agencies and School Districts Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to provide guidance to and coordination with local educational agencies and school districts that are at high risk of acts of terrorism or other incidents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response and Communications.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM12" subcommittee="Emergency Preparedness, Response, and Communications" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5806"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5806"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2012--Introduced.
Preparedness Coordination With Local Educational Agencies and School Districts Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to provide guidance to and coordinate with local educational agencies and school districts that are at a high risk of acts of terrorism or other incidents in order to enhance domestic preparedness for and the collective response to such incidents.</summary>
</bill>
