<bill session="109" type="s" number="4053" updated="2013-07-19T20:48:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Summer of Service Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the National and Community Service Act of 1990 to establish a Summer of Service State grant program, a Summer of Service national direct grant program, and related national activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2006-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-11-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10966"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-11-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10966-10971" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="6358"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Ethics"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Leadership"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Service learning"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2006--Introduced.
Summer of Service Act of 2006 - Amends the National and Community Service Act of 1990 to create Summer of Service programs providing at least 100 hours of summer community service learning opportunities to youth who will subsequently enroll in grades six through nine. Requires the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service to provide competitive three-year grants to: (1) states under a State Grant program; and (2) public or private organizations under a National Direct Grant program, when a state does not apply for funding or the community service program includes multiple states. Requires states and organizations, in making project subgrants, to favor entities with established track records that: (1) have leadership positions in the communities from which participating youth will be drawn; (2) focus on youth service during the transition year before high school; (3) encourage or enable youth to continue providing community service throughout the school year; (4) involve youth in the design and operation of the community service project; and (5) include youth of diverse backgrounds, at least 50% of which are from low-income families. Permits such entities to charge the parents of participants an income-based fee to contribute to the nonfederal share of project costs. Makes each youth serving at least 100 hours in a service-learning project eligible for an educational award of up to $500.</summary>
</bill>
