<bill session="111" type="h" number="5607" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SOS Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Oil Spills Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of a program to support the development, demonstration, and commercialization of innovative technologies to prevent, stop, or capture large-scale accidental discharges of oil or other hydrocarbons from offshore oil and gas drilling operations, including deepwater and ultra-deepwater operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1211-1212"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2010--Introduced.
Stop Oil Spills Act or the SOS Act - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to revise provisions concerning ultra-deepwater and unconventional natural gas and other petroleum resources. Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to establish: (1) a program of awards to support the development, demonstration, and commercialization of innovative technologies to prevent, stop, or capture large-scale accidental discharges of oil or other hydrocarbons from offshore oil and gas drilling operations, including deepwater and ultra-deepwater operations; and (2) an independent SOS Fund Technical Advisory Committee to advise on the development and implementation of programs under this Act. Requires the awards to focus on new technologies or innovative improvements to existing technologies, including: (1) blowout preventers; (2) secondary control systems; (3) remotely operated vehicles; and (4) prefabricated systems or technologies to stop or capture a large-scale discharge from an offshore well, at or near the source of such discharge, in the event of failure of a blowout preventer. Establishes in the Treasury a Safety and Offshore Spill (SOS) Fund into which shall be transferred, for each of FY2011-FY2017, $50 million from amounts of federal royalties, rents, and bonuses derived from federal onshore and offshore oil and gas leases issued under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act that are deposited in the Treasury.</summary>
</bill>
