<bill session="110" type="s" number="3494" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Restoring the Value of Every American in Environmental Decisions Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to restore the value of every American in environmental decisions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3564"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pollution"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2008--Introduced.
Restoring the Value of Every American in Environmental Decisions Act - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), when using any value of statistical life in decisionmaking, to: (1) not reduce that value below the highest value of statistical life used in a decisionmaking before the enactment of this Act; and (2) increase that value at least once each year, by adjusting the value to reflect the average annual total compensation of individuals, the average capital that may be liquidated upon the death of an individual, and the value of nonpaid activities, including the relevant activities described in the American Time Survey Results published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor.Prohibits the Administrator from decreasing the value of statistical life based on age, income, race, illness, disability, date of death, or any other personal attribute or relativistic analysis of the value of life.Requires the Administrator to: (1) ensure that the process for establishing a value of statistical life is open to the public; and (2) provide to specified congressional committees, concurrently with public notice, any proposed revision of a value of a statistical life.Declares that nothing in this Act: (1) expresses on behalf of Congress an endorsement of any use of value of statistical life analysis as a decisionmaking criterion, cost-benefit analysis, regulatory decisionmaking threshold, or single process of agency decisionmaking; (2) creates a duty to make or revise any standard under any other law; or (3) affects any substantive standard for promulgating regulations under any other law.</summary>
</bill>
