<bill session="112" type="s" number="1380" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HALT Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hinder the Administration's Legalization Temptation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to suspend until January 21, 2013, certain provisions of Federal immigration law, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2011-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2011-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2497"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2011--Introduced.
Hinder the Administration's Legalization Temptation Act or the HALT Act - Suspends until January 21, 2013, the Attorney General's (DOJ) authority regarding: (1) waiver of inadmissibility of aliens unlawfully present in the United States; (2) cancellation of removal and adjustment of status for certain non-permanent residents; (3) parole authority, except for parole entries for humanitarian, law enforcement, or security purposes; and (4) designation of a country for temporary protected status. Revises, until January 21, 2013, the definition of "unauthorized alien" (for purposes of the unauthorized employment of aliens) to eliminate the exclusion from such definition of an alien authorized to work by the Attorney General. Prohibits the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) from granting deferred action or extended voluntary departure to any alien until January 21, 2013, except for humanitarian, law enforcement, or security purposes. Suspends specified regulations until January 21, 2013. Revokes, as of the date of enactment of this Act, any immigration benefit granted during the period beginning on July 12, 2011, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act under any authority suspended by this Act with respect to: (1) parole authority, (2) the definition of an unauthorized alien, (3) deferred action or extended voluntary departure, or (4) such specified regulations.</summary>
</bill>
