<bill session="111" type="s" number="4037" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Security Screening Confidential Data Privacy Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to impose a criminal penalty for unauthorized recording or distribution of images produced using advanced imaging technology during screenings of individuals at airports and upon entry to Federal buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2010-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2010-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2010-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2010-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2010-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2010-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2010--Introduced.
Security Screening Confidential Data Privacy Act - Amends the federal criminal code to impose a fine and/or prison term of up to one year on any individual who: (1) photographs or otherwise records an image produced using advanced imaging technology during the screening of an individual at an airport or upon entry into any building owned or operated by the federal government without express authorization pursuant to a federal law or regulation;&#160;or (2) distributes such image to any individual who is not authorized pursuant to a federal law or regulation to receive it.&#160; Exempts: (1) individuals who record or distribute an image soley to be used in a criminal investigation or prosecution; and (2) journalists who publish an image&#160;in good faith that the image was not recorded or distributed in violation of such prohibition.</summary>
</bill>
