<bill session="109" type="h" number="5549" updated="2013-07-19T19:53:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Choice of Representation Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to remove certain limitations on attorney representation of claimants for veterans benefits in administrative proceedings before the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400279"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2006-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2694"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2006--Introduced.
Veterans' Choice of Representation Act of 2006 - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to prescribe: (1) qualifications and standards of conduct for agents and attorneys acting on behalf of veterans in claim proceedings before the Department of Veterans Affairs; and (2) restrictions on fees collected for such services. Adds to the list of reasons for which agents and attorneys may be suspended, including: (1) failure to conduct themselves with due regard for the non-adversarial nature of any proceeding; and (2) presenting frivolous claims, issues, or arguments. Repeals the current time period limitation for the hiring or paying of an agent or attorney. Revises the time period during which attorney fee agreements may be filed with the Board of Veterans' Appeals. Allows the Secretary to review such an agreement, and order a fee reduction if the Secretary finds the fee excessive or unreasonable.</summary>
</bill>
