<bill session="111" type="s" number="1177" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Confidence in Long-Term Care Insurance Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve consumer protections for purchasers of long-term care insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6046"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6046-6050" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5890"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2009--Introduced.
Confidence in Long-Term Care Insurance Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to request the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC) to conduct biennial reviews of the national and state-specific markets for long-term care (LTC) insurance policies. Directs the Secretary to request the NAIC to: (1) develop model language for marketing of long-term insurance policies that meets certain criteria; and (2) develop recommendations for enforcement of the model marketing disclosures and definitions. Amends the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 to authorize establishment of an Internet directory of information regarding LTC insurance ("LTC Insurance Compare") that shall include comparison tools to assist consumers in evaluating LTC insurance policies with different benefits and features. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to apply Medicaid partnership required model provisions to all tax-qualified LTC insurance contracts. Outlines a process for secretarial review of 2000 and 2006 model provisions as well as subsequent model provisions with respect to their application to tax-qualified LTC policies and Medicaid partnership policies. Amends the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 to require the Secretary to issue biennial reports to states and Congress on Medicaid LTC insurance partnerships and their impact. Outlines additional consumer protections for Medicaid partnerships. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on whether all LTC insurance policies sold after a certain date determined by the Secretary should provide annual compound inflation protection.</summary>
</bill>
