<bill session="111" type="h" number="4094" updated="2013-07-19T23:49:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drywall Victims Insurance Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit insurers from canceling or refusing to renew homeowners insurance policies because of the presence of certain types of drywall in the home.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400635"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2010-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2009--Introduced.
Drywall Victims Insurance Protection Act of 2009 - Declares it is unlawful for an insurer to cancel, or decline to renew, any coverage for homeowners' insurance for any single-family housing based on the presence, or possibility of presence, of any drywall that: (1) was imported from, or originated in, China at any time during calendar years 2004 through 2007; or (2) contains elevated levels of sulphur or strontium. Prohibits an insurer from issuing discriminatory terms in any renewal of homeowners' coverage based on the presence, or possibility of presence, in the structure of such drywall. Permits an insured adversely affected by a violation of this Act by an insurer to bring a civil action for relief against such insurer in federal or state court. Directs the court to allow a prevailing plaintiff reasonable attorneys' fee as part of the costs, including any expert fees.</summary>
</bill>
