<bill session="113" type="hj" number="91" updated="2013-11-02T06:48:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-10">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Honoring the families of fallen soldiers bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Defense Survivor Benefits Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Defense Survivor Benefits Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of Defense Survivor Benefits Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Department of Defense Survivor Benefits Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations for death gratuities and related survivor benefits for survivors of deceased military service members of the Department of Defense for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400142"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412502" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400646" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412453" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412584" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412546" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400439" joined="2013-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-09T12:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6431-6435" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-09T12:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Frelinghuysen moved to suspend the rules and pass the resolution.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6431" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-09T12:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 91.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-09T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-09T14:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6441-6442" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="538" datetime="2013-10-09T14:34:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 425 - 0 (Roll no. 538).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6431" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="216">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 216.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2013-10-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7368" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2013-10-10">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2013-10-10">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-44" type="public" datetime="2013-10-10" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-44.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3274"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3289"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="sj" number="24"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/2013--Public Law.
Department of Defense Survivor Benefits Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 - Makes appropriations, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for death gratuities and related benefits for survivors of deceased military service members of the Department of Defense (DOD) for FY2014, and for other purposes, such amounts as may be necessary, at a rate for operations as provided for FY2013 in the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2013 (division C of P.L. 113-6), for "Operation and Maintenance" and "Military Personnel" accounts for continuing the following projects and activities that are not otherwise specifically provided for in this joint resolution or the Pay Our Military Act (P.L. 113-39), and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available by the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2013: payment of death gratuities to certain survivors of deceased military service members, including for the death of members on active duty or inactive duty training, the death of members after discharge or release from duty or training, members and employees dying outside the United States while assigned to intelligence duties, and other eligible survivors; funeral and burial expenses; authorized funeral travel and travel related to the dignified transfer of remains and unit memorial services; and temporary continuation of a basic allowance of housing for certain dependents of members dying on active duty. Requires the rate of operations to be calculated to reflect the full amount of any reduction required in FY2013 pursuant to: (1) the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-6), and (2) the presidential sequestration order dated March 1, 2013, except as attributable to budget authority made available by the Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-2). Makes appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under this joint resolution available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment into law of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution, (2) enactment into law of the applicable appropriations Act for FY2014 without any provision for such project or activity, or (3) December 15, 2013. Requires implementation of this joint resolution so that only the most limited funding action be taken in order to provide for continuation of projects and activities. Expresses the sense of Congress that this joint resolution may also be referred to as the Honoring the Families of Fallen Soldiers Act.</summary>
</bill>
