<bill session="110" type="h" number="6474" updated="2013-07-19T22:00:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives to carry out a series of demonstration projects to promote the use of innovative technologies in reducing energy consumption and promoting energy efficiency and cost savings in the House of Representatives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400245"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2008-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 4 - 3.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25T20:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 110-890.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-25T20:30:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="575">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 575.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Capitol (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Congressional office buildings"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy consumption"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2008--Reported to House without amendment.
Authorizes the Chief Administrative Officer (CAO) of the House of Representatives to carry out a series of demonstration projects to promote the use of innovative technologies in reducing energy consumption and promoting energy efficiency and cost savings in the House of Representatives.Authorizes the CAO to enter into contracts with entities that have developed new methods of using energy more efficiently, generating electric power in a more sustainable manner, or improving the efficiency and lowering the costs of existing renewable power systems, consistent with regulations promulgated by the Committee on House Administration for CAO contracts.Requires the CAO, upon completion of each project, to report to the Committees on House Administration and Appropriations, including the CAO's analysis of the extent to which the project reduced energy consumption and promoted energy efficiency and cost savings.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
