<bill session="113" type="h" number="2296" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Taxpayer Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the impact aid program under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412475"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412505" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412418" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412584" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412583" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412449" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412515" joined="2013-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2378"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1108"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/2013--Introduced.
Local Taxpayer Relief Act - Amends the Impact Aid Improvement Act of 2012 to make permanent amendments that Act made to the Impact Aid program (which compensates local educational agencies [LEAs] for the financial burden of federal activities affecting their school districts) that: require the valuation of the federal property located within the boundaries of an LEA by calculating the valuation, for property tax purposes, of all property within the LEA's boundaries and then multiplying that value by the proportion of that property that is federal property; alter the formula for determining the foundation payments due LEAs for federal ownership of property when appropriations for a fiscal year are insufficient to provide them with full compensation; alter the formula for determining the payments due LEAs for eligible federally-connected children who are displaced from federal property or Indian lands due to housing renovation or rebuilding; and direct the Secretary of Education to complete Impact Aid payments to eligible LEAs within three fiscal years of their appropriation. Amends the Impact Aid program of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to alter the formula for determining the payments due LEAs for eligible federally-connected children. Includes not only children in average daily attendance but also those enrolled pursuant to a state open enrollment policy. Continues an LEA's eligibility for such payments while activities associated with military base closures and realignments or force structure changes or relocations are ongoing. Allows the calculation of such payments using current student counts instead of prior fiscal year data when LEAs experience a specified influx of new federally-connected students due to federal activities or the closure of an LEA that was receiving Impact Aid due to federally-connected children. Requires the Secretary to allow LEAs to count their federally-connected children using the date they register their students for the fiscal year for which their application is filed. Alters the formula for determining the construction payments due LEAs that are eligible for other Impact Aid payments. Divides 80% of the construction funds evenly between LEAs impacted by military dependent children and LEAs impacted by children residing on Indian lands, with the remainder reserved for emergency repair and modernization grants to LEAs serving Indian lands or experiencing a specified influx of new students due to federal activities. Alters the formula for determining whether a state's plan for equalizing assistance to its LEAs will except it from the prohibition on state aid to LEAs being affected by Impact Aid payments. Requires new LEAs applying for Impact Aid to have boundaries established by state law and the authority to tax or receive an imputed local tax. Reauthorizes appropriations for the Impact Aid program.</summary>
</bill>
