<bill session="111" type="h" number="4243" updated="2013-07-19T23:50:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Air and Water Investment Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit the issuance of tax-exempt bonds for air and water pollution control facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400355"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2009-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2010-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2906"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2009--Introduced.
Clean Air and Water Investment Act of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to include air and water pollution control facilities among the projects for which tax-exempt facility bonds may be issued. Defines such facilities as any property: (1) to be used to abate or control water or atmospheric pollution or contamination by removing, altering, disposing, or storing pollutants, contaminants, wastes, or heat; (2) which is either land or of a character subject to the allowance for depreciation; and (3) that a federal, state, or local agency has certified is designed for abating or controlling atmospheric or water pollution or for meeting local requirements for controlling such pollution. Provides that a water pollution control facility includes the necessary intercepting sewers, pumping, power, and other equipment, and their appurtenances. Makes this Act applicable to bonds issued after December 31, 2008.</summary>
</bill>
