<bill session="111" type="sr" number="405" updated="2013-07-20T00:19:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-02">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution reaffirming the centrality of freedom of expression and press freedom as cornerstones of United States foreign policy and United States efforts to promote individual rights, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412329"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2010-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-02-02" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S447-448" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S447-448" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S445-446" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2010--Passed Senate without amendment.
Reaffirms the centrality of the freedoms of expression and the press as cornerstones of U.S. foreign policy and U.S. efforts to promote individual rights. Expresses concern over official efforts in many countries to restrict speech and expression, including attempts to restrict Internet access. Welcomes the diplomatic initiative announced by Secretary of State Clinton to encourage Internet freedom globally. Condemns the cyber attacks allegedly launched from China against Google and other companies and calls on the government of China to review such cyber intrusions. Pays tribute to the professional and citizen journalists who persevere in their dedication to report in China. Urges companies to refuse to aid in the curtailment of free expression. Calls on the President and the Secretary to develop means by which the U.S. government can rapidly respond to threats against the freedoms of press and expression.</summary>
</bill>
