<bill session="109" type="h" number="112" updated="2013-07-19T19:05:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the videotaping of interrogations and other pertinent actions between a detainee or prisoner in the custody or under the effective control of the armed forces of the United States pursuant to an interrogation, or other pertinent interaction, for the purpose of gathering intelligence and a member of the armed forces of the United States, an intelligence operative of the United States, or a contractor of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2005-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2005-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2005-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1-15"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military and naval offenses"/>
    <term name="Military intelligence"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Punishment"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2005--Introduced.
Requires the President to take such actions as are necessary, in accordance with specified laws and treaties, to ensure the videotaping of interrogations and other intelligence-related interactions between detainees or prisoners under the effective control of the U.S. Armed Forces, and members of the U.S. Armed Forces, U.S. intelligence operatives, or contractors of the United States. Directs the President to provide for the appropriate classification of such videotapes. Requires such videotapes to be made available, under seal if appropriate, to both the prosecution and defense if material to any military or civilian criminal proceeding. Requires the President to take necessary actions to ensure immediate and unfettered access to detainees or prisoners in the custody or effective control of the U.S. Armed Forces by the following organizations: (1) International Federation of the International Committee of the Red Cross and the Red Crescent; (2) United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights; and (3) United Nations Special Rapporteur on Torture. Directs the Judge Advocate General to develop guidelines to ensure that the videotaping required by this Act is sufficiently expansive to prevent any abuse of detainees and prisoners and violations of specified laws and treaties.</summary>
</bill>
