<bill session="110" type="s" number="2859" updated="2013-07-19T22:46:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act Amendments of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 to clarify limits on disclosure of student health records, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412249"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="2008-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3030" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2008--Introduced.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act Amendments of 2008 - Amends the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 to declare that nothing in the Act prohibits a physician, psychiatrist, psychologist, or other healthcare professional or paraprofessional from consulting with or disclosing treatment records on a student who is 18 years old or older or who is attending a postsecondary educational institution to a healthcare professional or paraprofessional outside the educational institution in connection with the provision of treatment to the student. Prohibits deeming the release by an educational institution of education records or related personally identifiable information, in the good faith belief that such release is necessary to protect against a threat to the health or safety of the student or other persons, to be a failure to comply with the Act regardless of whether it is subsequently determined that the specified conditions for such release did not exist. Allows the release of education records to appropriate persons in an emergency if the knowledge of that information is necessary, according to the good faith belief of the educational institution or persons to whom the disclosure is made, to protect the health or safety of the student or other persons.</summary>
</bill>
