<bill session="110" type="s" number="2366" updated="2013-07-19T22:41:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAVE Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Secure America Through Verification and Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Border Law Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide immigration reform by securing America's borders, clarifying and enforcing existing laws, and enabling a practical verification program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2008-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="4088"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="2368"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Reconnaissance aircraft"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Vital statistics"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2007--Introduced.
Secure America Through Verification and Enforcement Act of 2007 or SAVE Act of 2007 - Sets forth border security and enforcement provisions, including provisions respecting: (1) increases in Border Patrol and investigative personnel; (2) recruitment of former military personnel; (3) use of Department of Defense (DOD) equipment; (4) infrastructure improvements; (5) aerial and other surveillance; (5) a national strategy to secure the borders; (6) emergency deployment of Border Patrol agents; and (7) expansion of the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism along the northern and southern borders. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act and specified maritime law sections to revise alien smuggling provisions. Sets forth provisions respecting border security on certain federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior. Border Law Enforcement Act - Authorizes a border relief grant program for a tribal, state, or local law enforcement agency in a county within 25 miles of the southern border of the United States. Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to make the basic employment eligibility confirmation pilot program permanent. Sets forth conditions for the mandatory use of the E-verify system. Requires: (1) employer/employee notification of social security number mismatches and multiple uses, and related information sharing with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS); and (2) establishment of electronic birth and death registration systems. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) penalize specified employers for failure to correct information returns; and (2) prohibit employers from deducting from gross income wages paid to unauthorized aliens, with an exception for an employer participating in the basic employment eligibility confirmation program. Increases criminal alien program (CAP) personnel. Establishes within DHS a rewards program to assist in the elimination of commercial operations to produce or sell fraudulent immigration-related documents and to assist in the investigation, prosecution, or disruption of commercial alien smuggling operations. Provides for: (1) increased alien detention facilities; (2) additional district court judgeships; and (3) a media campaign to inform the public of changes made by this Act including a multilingual media campaign explaining noncompliance penalties.</summary>
</bill>
