<bill session="113" type="h" number="1485" updated="2013-11-02T06:31:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to modify the phase-in increases in flood insurance premium rates for certain properties, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2013-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412449" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2013-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2013--Introduced.
Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to authorize the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to provide flood insurance to certain prospective insureds at rates less than certain statutory estimates. Increases by 12.5% each year the chargeable risk premium rates for flood insurance for business property and for residential property which is not the primary residence of an individual until the average risk premium rate for such properties is equal to the average of the risk premium rates for specified other properties. Increases by 12.5% each year the chargeable risk premium rates for flood insurance for primary residences purchased after the enactment of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (Biggert-Waters [enacted July 6, 2012]) as if such increase began on the date of such enactment, until the average risk premium rate for such primary residences is equal to the average of the risk premium rates for specified other properties. Requires the FEMA Administrator to adjust the chargeable risk premium rates for flood insurance, for properties subject to such 12.5% increase, as if the amendments made by this Act were enacted at the same time as Biggert-Waters.</summary>
</bill>
