<bill session="109" type="h" number="4989" updated="2013-07-19T19:48:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Electoral Fairness Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to clarify the treatment of provisional ballots cast in elections for Federal office, to ensure that polling places are adequately staffed and have sufficient equipment, to direct States to issue durable voter registration cards to each individual who registers to vote in elections for Federal office in the State, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election Assistance Commission"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Voting machines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2006--Introduced.
Electoral Fairness Act of 2006 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to revise requirements for: (1) treatment of provisional ballots cast at incorrect polling places; (2) minimum contents of provisional ballots; (3) treatment of voters who vote after closing of polling places; and (4) treatment of ballots after casting. Sets forth requirements for ensuring adequate staff and equipment at polling places. Applies certain election administration requirements to early voting sites. Provides for: (1) the availability of additional funds to enable states to meet requirements with respect to adequate staff and equipment at polling places; and (2) the issuance of durable voter registration cards. Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to prescribe notice and review requirements for removal of individuals from the official list of eligible voters by reason other than change of residence. Revises requirements for the contents and treatment of voter registration forms. Requires state or local election officials to ensure the availability of updated information for registered voters.</summary>
</bill>
