<bill session="112" type="h" number="5333" updated="2013-07-20T01:56:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Middle Class Tax Fairness Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make permanent the deduction of State and local general sales taxes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="445"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="476"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3903"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5727"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="24"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="80"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2059"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2230"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2252"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2012--Introduced.
Middle Class Tax Fairness Act of 2012 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to make permanent the taxpayer election to deduct state and local general sales taxes in lieu of state and local income taxes. Requires an individual taxpayer whose adjusted gross income exceeds $1 million to pay a minimum tax rate of 30% of the excess of the taxpayer's adjusted gross income over the taxpayer's modified charitable contribution deduction for the taxable year (tentative fair share tax). Establishes the amount of such tax as the excess (if any) of the tentative fair share tax over the excess of: (1) the sum of the taxpayer's regular tax liability, the alternative minimum tax (AMT) amount, and the payroll tax for the taxable year; over (2) certain tax credits. Provides for a phase-in of such tax. Requires an inflation adjustment to the $1 million income threshold for taxable years beginning after 2013. Requires any savings resulting from the enactment of&#160;this Act to be used for federal budget deficit reduction or reduction of the federal debt.</summary>
</bill>
