<bill session="109" type="h" number="5943" updated="2013-07-19T19:56:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fraud Accountability in Emergency Response Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse in emergency assistance programs administered by the Department of Homeland Security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400654"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400634" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2006-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Management, Integration, and Oversight.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM09" subcommittee="Management, Integration, and Oversight" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Alcohol"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Debit cards"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Pawnbroking"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2006--Introduced.
Fraud Accountability in Emergency Response Act of 2006 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), to ensure that: (1) all FEMA programs administering assistance develop and maintain proper internal management controls to prevent and detect waste, fraud, and abuse (waste); (2) application databases used by FEMA to collect information on eligible recipients record disbursements; (3) such tracking is designed to identify ineligible applications; and (4) such databases are integrated with disbursements and payment records. Requires the Director to: (1) establish and implement a system for recording and tracking benefits disbursed by FEMA; (2) ensure that debit cards used to disburse assistance are equipped with an electronic feature that prohibits their use for ineligible expenses; and (3) assess the role of independent private sector inspectors general. Authorizes the Director to enter into contracts for the delivery of necessary goods or services relating to the response to or recovery from emergencies, giving preference to small businesses. Requires the Secretary to: (1) ensure that any existing database for federal assistance programs administered by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) undergoes a review by DHS's Inspector General; (2) annually certify that internal controls are in place and operational before a database may be used to disburse assistance; (3) establish and maintain a database that contains information about small businesses for purposes of federal contracting relating to assistance activities conducted in response to and recovery from emergencies; and (4) develop and implement a training program on the prevention of waste and ways to identify potential waste. Requires a DHS component to consult the database before awarding federal contracts for disaster-related activity. Sets forth requirements regarding reports on expenditures and efforts to confirm the identity and eligibility of applicants for assistance. Establishes within the Inspector General's office the position of Deputy Inspector General for Response and Recovery.</summary>
</bill>
