<bill session="109" type="s" number="2446" updated="2013-07-19T20:34:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Fuels Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote the national security and stability of the economy of the United States by reducing the dependence of the United States on oil through the use of alternative fuels and new technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2006-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="6223"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Emissions trading"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy security"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Military vehicles"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Oils and fats"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2006--Introduced.
American Fuels Act of 2006 - Establishes in the Executive Office of the President the Office of Energy Security to oversee all federal energy security programs, including the coordination of efforts of federal agencies to assist the United States in achieving full energy independence. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide: (1) a tax credit for production of qualified flexible fuel motor vehicles, including allowance of the credit against the alternative minimum tax; and (2) an alternative fuel retail sales credit. Amends the Clean Air Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate regulations to ensure that diesel sold or introduced into commerce in the United States, on an annual average basis, contains the applicable volume of alternative diesel fuel. Requires such regulations to provide for the generation of an appropriate amount of credits by any person that refines, blends, or imports diesel that contains a quantity of alternative diesel fuel greater than prescribed quantities. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend the alcohol fuel mixture excise tax credit to cellulosic biomass ethanol. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to include within the term alternative fueled vehicle a medium or heavy duty hybrid vehicle. Sets a deadline by which: (1) any federal property with at least one fuel refueling station must include at least one alternative fuel refueling station; and (2) any alternative fuel refueling station on federally-owned property must permit full public access for the purpose of refueling using alternative fuel. Amends federal transportation law to require that any bus purchased with funds from the Mass Transit Account of the Highway Trust Fund to be a clean fuel bus. Requires the Secretary of Defense to implement a program to evaluate the commercial and technical viability of advanced technologies for the production of alternative transportation fuels having applications for the Department of Defense.</summary>
</bill>
