<bill session="110" type="h" number="3260" updated="2013-07-19T21:32:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to modify regulations to provide that certain Federal subsidies shall not be considered a grant made with respect to a building or its operation for purposes of the low-income housing tax credit.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mortgage interest rates"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2007--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to modify certain Treasury Regulations to provide that none of the following shall be considered a grant made with respect to a building or its operation for purposes of the required reduction of eligible basis by grants received under the low-income housing tax credit: (1) specified rental assistance under the Housing Act of 1949, Housing Act of 1959, and the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act; (2) loan guarantees for multifamily rental housing in rural area under the Housing Act of 1949; (3) periodic interest reduction payments on behalf of owner of rental or cooperative housing project for low-income families under the National Housing Act; (4) modernization, operating, and rental assistance under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996; (5) certain assistance under the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act for grantees following a current housing affordability strategy or an approved comprehensive homeless assistance plan; (6) tenant-based rental assistance under the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act; (7) assistance under the AIDS Housing Opportunity Act; (8) per diem payments for furnishing services to homeless veterans; (9) rent supplements under the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965; (10) rural housing voucher program assistance under the Housing Act of 1949; and (11) any other ongoing payment similar to any of these payments and designed to reduce cash flow needs from rent to enable the property to be rented to low-income tenants.</summary>
</bill>
