<bill session="109" type="s" number="973" updated="2013-07-19T20:21:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Abraham Lincoln National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Abraham Lincoln National Heritage Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2005-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4589-4590"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="1192"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governors"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lincoln Administration"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Office buildings"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Poetry"/>
    <term name="Presidential debates"/>
    <term name="Presidential libraries"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court justices"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2005--Introduced.
Abraham Lincoln National Heritage Area Act - Establishes the Abraham Lincoln National Heritage Area in Illinois. Designates the Looking for Lincoln Heritage Coalition as the management entity for the Area. Allows the Coalition, using funds made available under this Act, to prepare a management plan for the Area and reports, studies, interpretive exhibits and programs, historic preservation projects, and other activities recommended in the plan. Prohibits the Coalition from using Federal funds received under this Act to acquire real property. Directs the Coalition to submit to the Secretary of the Interior a management plan reviewed by participating units of government within the Area's boundaries which shall, among other things: (1) contain a comprehensive program for conservation, interpretation, funding, management, and development and historical, cultural, and natural resources and recreational and educational opportunities of the Area; and (2) include a business plan detailing the functions of the local coordinating entity and of activities included in recommendations contained in the plan. Requires the Secretary to approve or disapprove the proposed plan not later than 90 days after receiving it. Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical and financial assistance to the Coalition for the development and implementation of the management plan. Requires the Coalition to provide assistance and encouragement to State and local governments, private organizations, and persons to protect and promote the Area's resources and values.</summary>
</bill>
