<bill session="110" type="s" number="1290" updated="2013-07-19T22:31:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide additional discretion to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in contracting with State approving agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5583-5584"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S5584-5585" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/3/2007--Introduced.
Revises provisions concerning Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) use of state approving agencies (agencies) for approving courses of education for veterans under the Montgomery GI Bill veterans' educational assistance program. Authorizes (current law requires) the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to promote the development of veterans' apprenticeship and on-job training programs. Authorizes the Secretary to determine the criteria and contract conditions for reimbursing agencies for salary and travel costs incurred on behalf of the VA, including the condition that the agencies report annually to the Secretary and the congressional veterans' committees on resources expended and personnel qualification and performance standards. Limits the annual authorized amount for the VA for such expenses.Requires the Secretary to establish performance measures to assess the effectiveness of agencies in: (1) the services for which they are reimbursed; and (2) coordinating with other entities to reduce overlap and improve efficiency in approval activities.Requires the Secretary to establish standards of approval for accredited and nonaccredited courses offered by an educational institution, based on specified measures. Authorizes an agency, in approving courses for which such standards have been met, to rely upon determinations made by other entities, including the Departments of Labor and Education. Allows approval to be revoked by the Secretary or the agency, under conditions established by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
