<bill session="111" type="s" number="3904" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">High Plains Groundwater Resource Conservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to further continued economic viability in the communities on the High Plains by promoting sustainable groundwater management of the Ogallala Aquifer.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300013"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
High Plains Groundwater Resource Conservation Act - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture, for each of FY2011-FY2020, to enter into contracts with producers in the High Plains Aquifer states (Colorado, Kansas, Nebraska, New Mexico, Oklahoma, South Dakota, Texas, and Wyoming) through a High Plains Aquifer Groundwater Conservation Incentives Program, aimed at achieving significant per-acre savings of groundwater resources of the High Plains Aquifer. Directs the Secretary to ensure that producers on land drawing water from that Aquifer throughout the High Plains region have an opportunity to participate in the Program. Requires producers in areas experiencing significant aquifer level declines to be given priority. Provides for incentive payments for a producer on land drawing water from the Aquifer who agrees not to irrigate all or part of the land and to transfer the producer's water rights for the nonirrigated land to the applicable High Plains Aquifer state.</summary>
</bill>
