<bill session="110" type="h" number="6754" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">White Mountain Apache Tribe Rural Water System Loan Authorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to provide a loan to the White Mountain Apache Tribe for use in planning, engineering, and designing a certain water system project.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400310"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3128"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2008--Introduced.
White Mountain Apache Tribe Rural Water System Loan Authorization Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to provide a loan to the White Mountain Apache Tribe to carry out planning, engineering, and design of the Miner Flat Project (defined as the White Mountain Apache Rural Water System) in Arizona.Requires the zero-interest, 10-year loan to be repaid with funds from the Lower Colorado River Development Fund.Directs the Secretary to offer to enter into a cooperative agreement with the Tribe for the planning, engineering, and design of the Project, which shall be in accordance with all federal environmental laws and subject to the requirements of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act.</summary>
</bill>
