<bill session="112" type="s" number="438" updated="2013-07-20T02:20:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Heart Disease Education, Analysis, Research, and Treatment for Women Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HEART for Women Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve women's health by prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of heart disease, stroke, and other cardiovascular diseases in women.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2012-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2011-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2011-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2011-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3526"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2011--Introduced.
Heart Disease Education, Analysis, Research, and Treatment for Women Act or the HEART for Women Act - Directs the Comptroller General to report on whether the presentation of clinical study safety and effectiveness data by sex, age, and racial subgroups complies with Food and Drug Administration (FDA) requirements. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to submit a response to such report, including a corrective action plan as needed. Requires the Director of the Office of Women's Health of FDA to report on the compliance of clinical studies of women's health with such FDA requirements, including requirements regarding: (1) the adequacy of representation of females, racial and ethnic minorities, and adults of all ages in approved clinical studies; and (2) the extent to which a summary of product safety and effectiveness data disaggregated by sex, age, and racial subgroup is available to the public. Requires the Director of the Office of Minority Health of FDA to submit a report that includes such information with respect to clinical studies of minority health. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary to report on the quality of, and access to, care for women with heart disease, stroke, and other cardiovascular diseases and to include recommendations for eliminating disparities in, and improving the treatment of, heart disease, stroke, and other cardiovascular diseases in women. Reauthorizes a program to award grants for preventive heath services and referrals for medical treatment for women through entities that are screening women for breast or cervical cancer. Requires the Secretary to study the impact of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act on such services and make recommendations for improvement.</summary>
</bill>
