<bill session="112" type="h" number="4023" updated="2013-07-20T01:44:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Telehealth and Telemedicine Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the use of teleconsultation, teleretinal imaging, telemedicine, and telehealth coordination services for the provision of health care to veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412497"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2012-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2012--Introduced.
Veterans' Telehealth and Telemedicine Improvement Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a program to increase the use of: (1) teleconsultation, telemedicine, telehealth, and home telehealth by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA); and (2) teleretinal imaging in each Veterans Integrated Services Network. Directs the Secretary to: (1) require each VA facility involved in the training of medical residents to work with each university concerned to develop an elective rotation in telemedicine for such residents, and (2) provide VA health care professionals with education and training in the use of telemedicine to provide care for veterans in rural areas. Requires the Secretary to modify the Veterans Equitable Resource Allocation system to: (1) provide incentives for the use of teleconsultation, teleretinal imaging, telemedicine, and telehealth coordination services; and (2) require the inclusion of all telemedicine visits in the calculation of facility workload. Authorizes the Secretary to waive the imposition or collection of copayments for teleconsultation, telemedicine, teleretinal imaging, telehealth, and home telehealth visits of veterans.</summary>
</bill>
