<bill session="112" type="s" number="1407" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Air Ambulance Medicare Accreditation and Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish accreditation requirements for suppliers and providers of air ambulance services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2011-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2011--Introduced.
Air Ambulance Medicare Accreditation and Accountability Act - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to condition Medicare payment for air ambulance services upon: (1) provision by the supplier or service provider for appropriate medical oversight by a physician, and (2) accreditation of the air ambulance as level III or higher. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) establish a process for accrediting air ambulances according to three specified levels of accreditation, from lowest to highest; (2) consider certain factors in designating accreditation organizations; (3) establish criteria for use by an accreditation organization to evaluate an air ambulance; and (4) establish certain requirements for the collection of related data. Prohibits reimbursement for air ambulance services under a state plan under SSA title XVII (Medicaid) unless the state develops licensing and regulatory requirements for such services that comply with federal guidelines. Directs the Secretary to establish a revised air ambulance rate structure under the Medicare fee schedule. Requires sole community air ambulance services originating in a rural area to be reimbursed at a higher rate than for services by a non-sole community air ambulance. Requires the Secretary to reduce the update for ambulance services for the failure of suppliers and providers to submit certain quality data to the Secretary . Authorizes the Secretary to arrange with the Institute of Medicine of the National Academies to study ground critical care transport.</summary>
</bill>
