<bill session="109" type="h" number="2956" updated="2013-07-19T19:30:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Accutane Safety and Risk Management Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of certain restrictions with respect to drugs containing isotretinoin (including the drug marketed as Accutane).</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mental depression"/>
    <term name="Nervous system"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Skin diseases"/>
    <term name="Suicide"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2005--Introduced.
Accutane Safety and Risk Management Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, to withdraw approval within 30 days for the sale of drugs that contain isotretinoin as an active ingredient, including Accutane. Allows the Secretary to approve subsequent supplemental applications for such drugs subject to certain restrictions, including safety reporting. Requires that distribution of such subsequently approved drugs be limited, including by: (1) allowing distribution only directly from manufacturers to pharmacists; (2) requiring pharmacists to register, receive education on side effects, dispense only those prescriptions from physicians at certified treatment centers, and file a statement of compliance; (3) developing educational materials for patients, including monthly questionnaires for patients to monitor the development of adverse side effects; (4) requiring patients to register, receive counseling on the drug, sign a statement providing informed consent for treatment, and undergo appropriate tests; and (5) limiting prescriptions to a 30-day supply with no refills. Specifies conditions for a clinic to be certified as a treatment center for a drug containing isotretinoin, including requiring each practitioner to meet certain conditions, such as requirements for registration, an agreement to prescribe in accordance with this Act, and reporting of adverse events. Requires the Secretary to monitor the distribution of such drugs to determine whether the drug is being distributed in accordance with this Act. Specifies conditions under which the Secretary may approve a drug that contains isotretinoin as an active ingredient for a new use. Requires manufacturers and distributors of isotretinoin to report any information on adverse events associated with the drug to the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to conduct and support studies to explore the effects of isotretinoin on the central nervous system and behavior, including depression, suicide, and violent behavior.</summary>
</bill>
