<bill session="113" type="s" number="1358" updated="2013-11-02T07:03:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Seniors Fraud Prevention Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an advisory office within the Bureau of Consumer Protection of the Federal Trade Commission to prevent fraud targeting seniors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="1953"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2013--Introduced.
Seniors Fraud Prevention Act of 2013 - Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to establish an office within the Bureau of Consumer Protection to advise the FTC on the prevention of fraud targeting seniors and to assist the FTC in monitoring the market for mail, television, Internet, and telemarketing fraud including recorded message telephone calls (robocalls) targeting seniors. Requires the FTC, through such office, to: (1) disseminate to seniors and their families and caregivers information on the most common fraud schemes, including methods of reporting complaints either to the FTC's national toll-free telephone number or to the FTC's Consumer Sentinel Network, where complaints become immediately available to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), state attorneys general, and other appropriate law enforcement agencies; (2) provide, in response to a specific request about a particular entity or individual, publicly available information regarding the FTC's enforcement action; and (3) maintain a website as a resource for information on fraud targeting seniors. Directs the FTC to establish procedures through such office to: (1) log and acknowledge the receipt of complaints by individuals who believe they have been a victim of such fraud in the Consumer Sentinel Network and to make such complaints immediately available to federal, state, and local law enforcement authorities; and (2) provide individuals with information on such fraud as well as the most common schemes.</summary>
</bill>
