<bill session="109" type="h" number="681" updated="2013-07-19T19:10:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Mineral Leasing Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to issue separately, for the same area, a lease for tar sand and a lease for oil and gas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to issue separately, for the same area, a lease for tar sand and a lease for oil and gas. Declares that such a lease shall not be further subject to the Combined Hydrocarbon Leasing Act of 1981. Requires a lease for tar sand to be issued using the same bidding process, annual rental, and posting period as a lease issued for oil and gas. Sets the minimum acceptable bid for a tar sand lease at $2 per acre. Authorizes the Secretary, in order to promote any resource covered by a combined hydrocarbon lease, to waive, suspend, or alter any requirement that a permittee under a permit authorizing prospecting for tar sand must exercise due diligence.</summary>
</bill>
