<bill session="112" type="h" number="6169" updated="2013-07-20T02:03:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02T16:20:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-08-02T16:20:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pathway to Job Creation through a Simpler, Fairer Tax Code Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Pathway to Job Creation through a Simpler, Fairer Tax Code Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Pathway to Job Creation through a Simpler, Fairer Tax Code Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for expedited consideration of a bill providing for comprehensive tax reform.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412458" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412478" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400633" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2012-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412393" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412217" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412410" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412416" joined="2012-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-30T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Rules. H. Rept. 112-629.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-07-30T16:29:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="153">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 153.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T21:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 747 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6169 and H.R. 8. H.R. 6169 is accorded 3 hours of general debate and H.R. 8 is accorded 1 hour of general debate. For H.R. 6169, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in Part A of the report is in order and shall be debatable for 20 minutes. For H.R. 8, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in Part B is made in order and shall be debatable for 20 minutes. Section 3 provides that on any legislative day from August 3, 2012 through September 7, 2012: (a) the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved; (b) the Chair may adjourn the House to meet at a date and time within the limits of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution; and (c) bills and resolutions introduced shall be numbered, listed in the Congressional Record, and when printed shall bear the date of introduction, but may be referred at a later time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T12:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 747.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5658-5681" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5658-5659" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T12:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6169 and H.R. 8. H.R. 6169 is accorded 3 hours of general debate and H.R. 8 is accorded 1 hour of general debate. For H.R. 6169, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in Part A of the report is in order and shall be debatable for 20 minutes. For H.R. 8, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in Part B is made in order and shall be debatable for 20 minutes. Section 3 provides that on any legislative day from August 3, 2012 through September 7, 2012: (a) the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved; (b) the Chair may adjourn the House to meet at a date and time within the limits of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution; and (c) bills and resolutions introduced shall be numbered, listed in the Congressional Record, and when printed shall bear the date of introduction, but may be referred at a later time. Section 4 authorizes the Speaker to appoint Members to perform the duties of the Chair for the duration of the period addressed by section 3 as though under clause 8(a) of rule I. Section 5 of the resolution provides that each day during the period addressed by section 3 shall not constitute a calendar for purposes of section 7 of the War Powers Resolution. Section 6 of the resolution provides that each day during the period addressed by section 3 shall not constitute a legislative day for the purposes of clause 7 of rule XIII (resolutions of inquiry). Section 7 of the resolution provides that for each day during the period addressed by section 3 shall not constitute a calendar or legislative day for purposes of clause 7(c)(1) of rule XXII (motions to instruct conferees). Section 8 of the resolution authorizes the Speaker to entertain motions to suspend the rules on the legislative day of August 2, 2012. Section 9 of the resolution waives the requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII (requiring a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House) with respect to any resolution reported through the legislative day of August 2, 2012.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T12:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with three hours of debate on H.R. 6169.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 747, the House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Slaughter amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T15:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bishop (NY) moved to recommit with instructions to Ways and Means.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5678-5681" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5678" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T15:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bishop (NY) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to prohibit a tax reform measure considered under the expedited procedures provided by this bill from reducing, repealing, or otherwise eliminating deductions for mortgage interest or charitable contributions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T15:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5680" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 188 - 235 (Roll no. 551).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5680-5681" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-08-02T16:20:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="552" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 232 - 189 (Roll no. 552).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 747, the text of H.R. 6169, as passed by the House, is appended as new matter at the end of the engrossment of H.R. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02T17:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 747, H.R. 6169 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="747"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="747"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="hr" number="747"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="747"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="8"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="8"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6688"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Tax reform and tax simplification"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1475"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Passed House without amendment.
Pathway to Job Creation through a Simpler, Fairer Tax Code Act of 2012 - States that the purpose of this Act is to provide for the enactment of comprehensive tax reform in 2013 that: (1) protects taxpayers by creating a fairer, simpler, flatter tax code; (2) is comprehensive; (3) results in tax revenue consistent with historical norms; (4) spurs greater investment, innovation and job creation; and (5) makes American workers and businesses more competitive. Defines a "tax reform bill" for purposes of this Act as a bill to be introduced by the chair of the House Committee on Ways and Means not later than April 30, 2013, that is certified by the chair of the Joint Committee on Taxation as containing proposals to: (1) consolidate the 6 current individual income tax brackets into a maximum of 2 brackets (of 10% and not higher than 25%), (2) reduce the corporate income tax rate to not more than 25%, (3) repeal the alternative minimum tax (AMT), (4) broaden the tax base so that tax revenues comprise between 18% and 19% of Gross Domestic Product (GDP), and (5) reform the current system of foreign taxation. Provides for the expedited consideration of such bill in the House of Representatives and the Senate.</summary>
</bill>
