<bill session="112" type="sc" number="37" updated="2013-07-20T02:16:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A concurrent resolution setting forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2013, and setting forth the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2014 through 2022.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400408"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2012-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2259-2264" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-17">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Budget discharged pursuant to Section 300 of the Congressional Budget Act.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-04-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="356">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 356.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3183-3222" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 42 - 57. Record Vote Number: 99.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hc" number="112"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="18"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="19"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="20"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="21"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="39"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="40"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="41"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="42"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="44"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2012--Introduced.
Sets forth the congressional budget for the federal government for FY2013, including the appropriate budgetary levels for FY2014-FY2022. Lists recommended budgetary levels and amounts for FY2013-FY2022with respect to: (1) federal revenues, (2) new budget authority, (3) budget outlays, (4) deficits (on-budget), (5) public debt, and (6) debt held by the public. Lists the appropriate levels of new budget authority, outlays, and administrative expenses of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund (Social Security Trust Funds), U.S. Postal Service discretionary administrative expenses, and specified major functional categories for FY2013-FY2022. Authorizes the Chairman of the Senate Budget Committee to: (1) make a deficit-reduction reserve fund for legislation that eliminates or reduces improper payments; and (2) reduce the allocations of committees for any savings achieved by such eliminations or reductions, with the savings used to reduce the deficit. Makes it out of order to consider in the Senate any legislation that would cause the discretionary spending limits in this resolution to be exceeded (other than those allocated in this resolution to function 970 for war efforts overseas), except by a supermajority waiver. Specifies such discretionary spending limits in the Senate for FY2013-FY2022. Makes it out of order to consider in the Senate any legislation, except by a supermajority, that would require advanced appropriations other than for: (1) up to $28.5 billion in new budget authority in FY2013-FY2014 for programs, projects, activities, or accounts identified in the joint explanatory statement of managers accompanying this resolution; and (2) the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for the Medical Services, Medical Support and Compliance, and Medical Facilities accounts of the Veterans Health Administration. Sets forth requirements for the treatment of emergency legislation. Allows the Chairman to adjust the estimate of budgetary effects of legislation that: (1) amends or supersedes the system for updating physician payments under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, (2) amends the Estate and Gift Tax under the Internal Revenue Code, (3) extends the Alternative Minimum Tax (AMT) relief for individuals, and (4) extends middle-class tax cuts under the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 and the Jobs and Growth Tax Relief and Reconciliation Act of 2003. Permits the Chairman to make such adjustments only for points of order in specified legislation relating to: (1) pay-as-you-go, and (2) long- and short-term deficits. Requires the joint explanatory statement accompanying the conference report on any budget resolution in the Senate to include in its committee allocations to the Senate Committee on Appropriations amounts for the discretionary administrative expenses of the Social Security Administration and of the Postal Service.</summary>
</bill>
