<bill session="110" type="h" number="5870" updated="2013-07-19T21:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Neighborhood Reclamation Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to make grants to assist local governments with vacant housing problems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400352"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2008-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Land banking"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/2008--Introduced.
Emergency Neighborhood Reclamation Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to make grants to eligible units of general local government for neighborhood reclamation. Specifies grant applicant eligibility requirements, including a comprehensive plan for the demolition of all vacant and abandoned housing and other structures within the local government's jurisdiction that will increase the stability of neighborhoods, or promote the rational utilization of land within that jurisdiction. Requires the use of such grant to fund: (1) the demolition of vacant and abandoned housing, and other vacant and abandoned structures, located in areas that are primarily residential in character; (2) the abatement, before demolition, of any health and safety hazards within such housing or structures, or on the site upon which such housing or other structures are located; and (3) the capping or removal, after demolition, of utility connections and public infrastructure, including street pavements and sewer lines, and the rehabilitation of a site for use as public open space, inclusion in a land bank, or for sale. Prohibits the use of funds made available under this Act to demolish public housing.</summary>
</bill>
