<bill session="110" type="sr" number="690" updated="2013-07-19T22:18:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-27">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate concerning the conflict between Russia and Georgia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-09-27" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10020-10021" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10020" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10009-10010" label="text of measure as introduced in Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armistices"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Georgia (Republic)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2008--Passed Senate without amendment.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the Russian Federation's disproportionate military response on the sovereign territory of Georgia, including the South Ossetian Autonomous Region and the Autonomous Republic of Abkhazia, is in violation of international law and commitments of the Russian Federation; (2) the United States recognizes significant common interests with the Russian Federation which can serve as the basis for improved long-term relations; (3) the Russian Federation should comply with the cease-fire agreement; (4) the Russian Federation and Georgia should refrain from the future use of force to resolve the status of Abkhazia and South Ossetia, and work with interested countries and international organizations to reach a political settlement; and (5) the United States should provide humanitarian and economic assistance to Georgia, continue to support democracy in Georgia, and work to support the free flow of energy to Europe and the operation of communication and trade routes.</summary>
</bill>
