<bill session="113" type="s" number="1375" updated="2013-11-02T07:03:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rebuilding Equity Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a portion of closing costs to be paid by the enterprises with respect to certain refinanced mortgage loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="3031"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2013--Introduced.
Rebuilding Equity Act of 2013 - Directs the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) (government sponsored enterprises or GSEs) to each establish a voluntary program for eligible borrowers under which the GSE shall pay $1,000 toward the closing costs associated with applying for and receiving the refinancing when the borrower agrees to refinance into a fully amoritizing loan with a term not longer than 20 years. Prohibits the amount of the closing costs that each GSE pays under the program during the 12 months following enactment of this Act from varying based on the term of the mortgage that the borrower agrees to refinance into. Requires the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, for each of the next two 12-month periods, to: (1) adjust the amount of the portion of the closing costs that each GSE will pay in accordance with specified requirements. Makes eligible for the program borrowers: (1) who qualify for the Home Affordable Refinance Program carried out by the GSEs, (2) whose subject property has a loan-to-value ratio of at least 105%, and (3) who refinances from a loan with an original 30-year term to a loan with a term of 20 years or less.</summary>
</bill>
