<bill session="112" type="h" number="6032" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Shiloh National Military Park Boundary Adjustment and Parker's Crossroads Battlefield Designation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the boundary of the Shiloh National Military Park located in Tennessee and Mississippi, to establish Parker's Crossroads Battlefield as an affiliated area of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2012--Introduced.
Shiloh National Military Park Boundary Adjustment and Parker's Crossroads Battlefield Designation Act - Modifies the boundary of Shiloh National Military Park to include the following areas identified on the map entitled "Shiloh National Military Park, Proposed Boundary Adjustment" and dated April 2012: (1) Fallen Timbers Battlefield, (2) Russell House Battlefield, and (3) Davis Bridge Battlefield. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire lands by donation, purchase from willing sellers, or exchange. Establishes Parker's Crossroads Battlefield in Tennessee, consisting of the area identified on the map entitled "Parker's Crossroads Battlefield, Proposed Boundary" and dated April 2012, as an affiliated area of the National Park System.</summary>
</bill>
