<bill session="113" type="h" number="1561" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to make improvements to support facilities for National Historic Sites operated by the National Park Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412406"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1071"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2013--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, through the National Park Service (NPS), to make improvements to a support facility, including a visitor center, for a National Historic Site administered by the NPS if such project: (1) is conducted within the agency's existing budget, (2) is subject to a 50% non-federal cost sharing requirement, and (3) is conducted for a unit of the NPS which has the authority to establish a support facility outside the park's boundary. Allows the NPS to operate and use all or part of a support facility, including a visitor center, for such a Site: (1) to carry out the duties associated with the administration and support of such Site, and (2) only in situations where there is an agreement between the Secretary and the commissioners of the county or parish in which the facility is located.</summary>
</bill>
