<bill session="110" type="s" number="1955" updated="2013-07-19T22:37:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reinforce First Responders and Emergency Employees Deployed Overseas in the Military Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reinforce FREEDOM Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to make grants to first responder agencies that have employees in the National Guard or Reserves on active duty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-08-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10804"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Ambulances"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Replacement workers"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2007--Introduced.
Reinforce First Responders and Emergency Employees Deployed Overseas in the Military Act of 2007 or the Reinforce FREEDOM Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to make a grant to a first responder agency (a law enforcement or fire agency of a state or local government or an ambulance service) an employee of which (or a significant portion of the voluntary staff of which) is: (1) a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces; and (2) on active duty or has received orders to begin active duty. Authorizes the use of grant funds for: (1) the salary of an individual hired to replace such employee or volunteer; (2) overtime expenses for an employee performing tasks that would have been performed by such employee or volunteer; and (3) the cost of equipment, maintenance, or other activities that a first responder agency was unable to acquire or perform because of the costs of replacing such employee or volunteer or the need for which was caused by such employee's or volunteer's deployment.</summary>
</bill>
