<bill session="112" type="h" number="6508" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">E-STOP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ensuring Shoppers Transparency in Online Pricing Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Federal Trade Commission to promulgate rules requiring an Internet merchant to disclose the use of a price-altering computer program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2012-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
Ensuring Shoppers Transparency in Online Pricing Act of 2012 or the E-STOP Act - Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate rules requiring an Internet merchant with annual gross revenue of more than $1 million to disclose to each consumer, prior to the final purchase of any good or service, the use of a price-altering computer program. Defines "price-altering computer program" as one that: (1) accesses a consumer's personal information, including information about the consumer's computer and browsing history; and (2) uses such information to alter the merchant's selling price of a good or service. Allows exemptions to accommodate the reasonable expectations of consumers concerning price changes. Deems a violation of a rule promulgated under this Act to be an unfair or deceptive act or practice under the Federal Trade Commission Act.</summary>
</bill>
