<bill session="113" type="s" number="1366" updated="2013-11-02T07:03:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Verifying Agency Conduct and Needs Through (VACANT) Inspectors General Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the appointment of Inspectors General, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2013--Introduced.
Verifying Agency Conduct and Needs Through (VACANT) Inspectors General Act - Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to: (1) require the President to fill a vacancy at the head of an Office of Inspector General at any agency or department defined as an establishment by such Act within 210 days after the declaration of such vacancy by the Council of Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency; and (2) require the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate, after considering recommendations from the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Council, to appoint an Inspector General to fill a vacancy the President fails to fill within such 210-day period. Establishes a similar procedure for filling a vacant Inspector General position at any agency defined as a designated agency by such Act.</summary>
</bill>
