<bill session="112" type="s" number="3346" updated="2013-07-20T02:45:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Las Vegas Valley Public Land and Tule Springs Fossil Beds National Monument Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for certain land conveyances in the State of Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2012-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4676-4677"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4677-4682" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="6072"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2012--Introduced.
Las Vegas Valley Public Land and Tule Springs Fossil Beds National Monument Act of 2012 - Establishes the Tule Springs Fossil Beds National Monument in Nevada. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to provide for interpretation, education, and scientific research on the Monument's paleontological resources. Instructs the Secretary to issue to a qualified electric utility a 400-foot right-of-way for the construction of high-voltage transmission facilities identified as the Renewable Energy Transmission Corridor. Establishes the Tule Springs Fossil Beds National Monument Advisory Council. Adds specified land to Red Rock Canyon National Conservation Area. Requires conveyance of land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) identified as the North Las Vegas Job Creation Zone to the city of North Las Vegas, Nevada, for use for nonresidential development. Permits North Las Vegas to retain a part of such land for public recreation or other public purposes. Amends the Clark County Conservation of Public Land and Natural Resources Act of 2002 to convey additional land to the Las Vegas Metropolitan Police Department for development of an access road and parking facilities. Permits the county to convey to a unit of local government or regional governmental entity land within the Airport Environs Overlay District if such land is used for a public purpose. Requires specified federal lands be conveyed for: (1) the Nevada System of Higher Education, (2) the Southern Nevada Supplemental Airport, and (3) an off-road vehicle recreation park. Releases the Sunrise Mountain Instant Study Area from further study for designation as wilderness. Designates: (1) an Economic Support Area in North Las Vegas, and (2) the Nellis Dunes Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area.</summary>
</bill>
