<bill session="111" type="h" number="6565" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Water Access and Equity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve efforts of the United States Government to ensure that developing countries have affordable and equitable access to safe water and sanitation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2010-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2010-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2010-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2010-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2010--Introduced.
Global Water Access and Equity Act - Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to establish within the Department of State a Coordinator of United States Government Diplomatic Initiatives to Provide Safe Water and Sanitation Globally, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Directs the Coordinator to: (1) be the Secretary of State's principal advisor on efforts to ensure that developing countries have affordable and equitable access to safe water and sanitation; and (2) monitor U.S. diplomatic policy and formulate ways in which such policy may be used to further the goal of ensuring that developing countries have access to safe water and sanitation, including the objectives expressed in the Senator Paul Simon Water for the Poor Act of 2005. Amends the Senator Paul Simon Water for the Poor Act of 2005 to establish within the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) a Bureau for Global Water Aid which shall be responsible for the oversight and coordination of all activities to provide safe water and sanitation to developing countries. Expresses the sense of Congress that U.S. policy should promote more efficient use of existing water supplies in developing countries, as well as the development of additional reliable water supplies.</summary>
</bill>
