<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1433" updated="2013-07-19T21:02:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-16T16:38:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-16T16:38:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 6899) to advance the national security interests of the United States by reducing its dependency on oil through renewable and clean, alternative fuel technologies while building a bridge to the future through expanded access to Federal oil and natural gas resources, revising the relationship between the oil and gas industry and the consumers who own those resources and deserve a fair return from the development of publicly owned oil and gas, ending tax subsidies for large oil and gas companies, and facilitating energy efficiencies in the building, housing, and transportation sectors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400378"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16T00:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-853, by Ms. Slaughter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16T00:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6899 with 3 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-09-16T00:01:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="265">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 265.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16T12:22:00-04:00">
      <text>By the direction of the Committee on Rules, Ms. Slaughter called up H.Res. 1433 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Cantor raised a point of order against the provisions of H.Res. 1433 because it violates the Congressional Budget Act. The Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be solved by the question of consideration of H.Res. 1433. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Will the House now consider the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 230 - 180 (Roll no. 593).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16T13:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8152-8157, H8157-8168" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16T13:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1433.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 1433, the Chair put the question on adoption of ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Slaughter demanded the yeas and nays, and further proceedings on the question of adoption were postponed until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8178-8179" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16T16:26:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 238 - 185 (Roll no. 595).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-09-16T16:38:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="596" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 229 - 194 (Roll no. 596).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8152" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16T16:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="110" type="h" number="6899"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2008--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 6899) to advance the national security interests of the United States by reducing its dependency on oil through renewable and clean, alternative fuel technologies while building a bridge to the future through expanded access to Federal oil and natural gas resources, revising the relationship between the oil and gas industry and the consumers who own those resources and deserve a fair return from the development of publicly owned oil and gas, ending tax subsidies for large oil and gas companies, and facilitating energy efficiencies in the building, housing, and transportation sectors.</summary>
</bill>
