<bill session="112" type="s" number="3636" updated="2013-07-20T02:48:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-11-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-11-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-11-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gift Card Consumer Protection Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide increased consumer protections for gift cards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2012-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2012-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-11-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6895-6896"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-11-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/26/2012--Introduced.
Gift Card Consumer Protection Act of 2012 - Amends the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to repeal the exclusion from, and so include within, the definitions of "general-use prepaid card," "gift certificate," and "store gift card" a loyalty, award, or promotional gift card (thus extending to the latter the same consumer protections). Repeals exceptions to the prohibitions against: (1) imposition of a dormancy fee, an inactivity fee, or a service fee in connection with a gift certificate, store gift card, or general-use prepaid card; and (2) the sale of gift cards with expiration dates. (Thereby renders such fees and expiration dates unlawful without exception.) Makes it unlawful for a person that has filed for federal bankruptcy protection to either sell, resell, issue, or reissue a gift certificate or store gift card. Amends federal bankruptcy law to declare that the filing of a petition in bankruptcy shall not operate as a stay against the presentation or redemption of a gift certificate or store gift card at full value. Requires the trustee in bankruptcy, if the debtor's business is authorized to be operated, unless the court orders otherwise, to: (1) honor at full value a gift certificate or store gift card issued by the debtor, and (2) treat the gift certificate or gift card the same as cash.</summary>
</bill>
