<bill session="111" type="h" number="3523" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Biofuel Engineering Training Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Energy to provide for the establishment of accreditation standards relating to biofuel engineering, to provide support for undergraduate and graduate degree programs that create the engineering skills necessary to support biofuel production, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412316"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2009-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2009--Introduced.
Biofuel Engineering Training Act - Directs the Secretary of Energy to award a grant to an appropriate standard-setting or other entity to: (1) develop appropriate standards for the accreditation of undergraduate and graduate biofuel engineering programs at institutions of higher education (IHEs); and (2) study the needs of the biofuel industry for engineering support. Requires the Secretary to award competitive grants to IHEs to establish Centers of Excellence for Biofuels Research and Training that: (1) integrate biofuels research, training, and instruction; (2) coordinate the broad range of disciplines relevant to biofuels engineering; and (3) work with companies that are commercializing biofuels technology, and local communities spurring economic development and job creation in the biofuels sector. Directs the Secretary to award portable graduate fellowships to students pursuing doctorates in biofuels engineering. Requires the fellowships, which are for up to three years of study, to provide recipients with an annual living stipend, and cover graduate tuition and incidental expenses. Requires federal agencies, including national laboratories, to make research facilities available to accredited biofuel engineering programs.</summary>
</bill>
