<bill session="113" type="h" number="890" updated="2013-11-02T06:26:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-13T17:42:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-03-13T17:42:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving Work Requirements for Welfare Programs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Preserving Work Requirements for Welfare Programs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Preserving the Welfare Work Requirement and TANF Extension Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit waivers relating to compliance with the work requirements for the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412388" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412226" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400626" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412393" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412408" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412410" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412428" joined="2013-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-03-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 14.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-03-11T10:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 113-13, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-11T10:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Education and the Workforce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-03-11T10:17:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="8">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 8.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12T18:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 107 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 890 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. An amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 113-3 shall be considered as adopted. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13T15:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 107 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 107.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1373-1384" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 890 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. An amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 113-3 shall be considered as adopted. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13T15:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 890.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1382" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Enyart moved to recommit with instructions to Ways and Means.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1382-1384" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1382" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions in the motion seek to add a section to provide that any State receiving TANF funding is required to provide assistance to specific groups named in the amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1383" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13T17:36:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 199 - 230 (Roll no. 67).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="68" datetime="2013-03-13T17:42:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 246 - 181 (Roll no. 68).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1373" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13T17:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="107"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h25"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/13/2013--Passed House amended.
Preserving the Welfare Work Requirement and TANF Extension Act of 2013 - Prohibits the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) from finalizing, implementing, enforcing, or otherwise taking any action to give effect to the Information Memorandum dated July 12, 2012 (Transmittal No. TANF-ACF-IM-2012-03), or to any administrative action relating to the same subject matter or that reflects the same or similar policies. Prohibits the Secretary also from authorizing, approving, modifying, or extending any experimental, pilot, or demonstration project under the Social Security Act (SSA) that: (1) waives compliance with mandatory work requirements of SSA title IV part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF), or (2) authorizes an expenditure not otherwise allowable under a state TANF program with respect to compliance with such work requirements. Rescinds and nullifies any waiver relating to the subject matter of the Information Memorandum granted before the enactment of this Act. Extends through December 31, 2013, in the manner authorized for FY2012, the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) Program under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (except for the Contingency Fund for State Welfare Programs), including the entitlement of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and American Samoa to matching TANF grants. Makes appropriations for TANF activities through calendar 2013.</summary>
</bill>
