<bill session="112" type="s" number="1179" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Advanced Programs Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote advanced placement and International Baccalaureate programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3693"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2011--Introduced.
Advanced Programs Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Education to allot grants to states, based on their share of low-income elementary and secondary school students, to cover part or all of the Advanced Placement (AP) or International Baccalaureate (IB) examination fee low-income students incur. Directs the Secretary to award competitive matching grants to states, local educational agencies (LEAs), or partnerships between a nonprofit organization and a state or LEA for activities that increase: (1) the number of qualified teachers at high-need schools who are teaching AP or IB courses; and (2) the number of students at high-need schools who enroll in, and pass the examination for, such courses. Gives priority, in awarding the competitive grants, to applicants that: (1) have a statewide or districtwide strategy for increasing the availability of AP or IB courses, and pre-AP or pre-IB courses, in high-need schools; (2) focus on increasing AP or IB courses in English, mathematics, and science; and (3) target schools with high concentrations of low-income students.</summary>
</bill>
