<bill session="111" type="s" number="564" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wartime Treatment Study Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish commissions to review the facts and circumstances surrounding injustices suffered by European Americans, European Latin Americans, and Jewish refugees during World War II.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2970-2971"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2971-2973" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="1425"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2009--Introduced.
Wartime Treatment Study Act - Establishes the Commission on Wartime Treatment of European Americans to review U.S. government wartime treatment (from September 1, 1939, through December 31, 1948) of European Americans and European Latin Americans. Requires the Commission to review: (1) government actions with respect to European Americans and European Latin Americans pursuant to United States laws and directives, including the Alien Enemies Acts, Presidential Proclamations 2526, 2527, 2655, 2662, 2685, Executive Orders 9066 and 9095, and related directives pursuant to these and other pertinent laws, proclamations, or executive orders; (2) registration requirements, travel and property restrictions, internment, and forced abandonment of property; (3) participation by European Americans in the U.S. Armed Forces; and (4) appropriate remedies, including public education programs and the creation of a comprehensive online database by the National Archives and Records Administration of documents related to the government's wartime treatment of European Americans and European Latin Americans during World War II. Establishes the Commission on Wartime Treatment of Jewish Refugees to review the U.S. government's refusal to allow entry into the United States of Jewish and other refugees fleeing persecution or genocide in Europe. Directs the Commission to include reviews of: (1) the rationale for such refusal, its perceived benefit, and its impact on refugees; and (2) federal refugee policy concerning those fleeing persecution or genocide.</summary>
</bill>
