<bill session="111" type="s" number="3354" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to redesignate the North Mississippi National Wildlife Refuges Complex as the Sam D. Hamilton North Mississippi National Wildlife Refuges Complex.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300023"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-08-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="519">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 519.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2010-08-05" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6978-6979" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6978-6979" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-08-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-09T19:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-09T20:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Passed Senate without amendment.
Redesignates the North Mississippi National Wildlife Refuges Complex, consisting of the Dahomey National Wildlife Refuge, Tallahatchie National Wildlife Refuge, Coldwater National Wildlife Refuge, and Bear Lake Unit as the Sam D. Hamilton North Mississippi National Wildlife Refuges Complex. Prohibits anything in this Act from preventing the Secretary of the Interior, in carrying out the mission of the National Wildlife Refuge System, from: (1) making adjustments to the boundaries of the Complex; or (2) adding new land or parcels of the System to such Complex.</summary>
</bill>
