<bill session="113" type="h" number="1871" updated="2013-11-02T06:34:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Baseline Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Baseline Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to reform the budget baseline.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412438" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412478" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2013-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2013-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412540" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2013-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="2013-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Budget"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 15 - 10.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Budget"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Budget. H. Rept. 113-129.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-25T17:24:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="94">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 94.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2013--Reported to House amended.
Baseline Reform Act of 2013 - Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) to revise the formula for establishing the budget baseline. Revises the annual baseline, for any fiscal year, to mean a projection of current-year levels of new budget authority (as under current law), outlays (as under current law), or receipts (instead of revenues) and the surplus or deficit (as under current law) for the current year, the budget year, and the ensuing nine outyears based on laws enacted through the applicable date. Includes estimates for direct spending in the baseline calculation formula for the budget year and each outyear. Revises the formula for calculating the baseline for discretionary spending for the budget year and each outyear to eliminate adjustments for: (1) expiring multiyear subsidized housing contracts; (2) administrative expenses of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund, the Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund, the Unemployment Trust Fund, and the Railroad Retirement account; (3) offsets to federal employees' annual pay; and (4) certain inflators used to adjust budgetary resources in the Act. Requires the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to report to the congressional budget committees, on or before July 1 of each year, the Long-Term Budget Outlook for: (1) the fiscal year commencing on October 1 of that year, and (2) at least the ensuing 40 fiscal years.</summary>
</bill>
