<bill session="111" type="s" number="3054" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to establish efficiency standards for bottle-type water dispensers, commercial hot food holding cabinets, and portable electric spas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 111-402.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2010--Introduced.
Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to include bottle-type water dispensers and compartment bottle-type water dispensers, commercial hot food holding cabinets, and portable electric spas as "covered products" under the Energy Conservation Program for Consumer Products Other than Automobiles. Sets forth requirements concerning: (1) test procedures for such dispensers, cabinets, and spas; (2) standby energy consumption standards for dispensers; (3) idle energy rate standards for cabinets; and (4) normalized standby power rates standards for spas. Excludes from the general rule of preemption for energy conservation standards before federal standards become effective for products a state regulation that establishes efficiency standards for such dispensers, cabinets, and spas. Excludes from the general rule of preemption when federal standards become effective for products a regulation that establishes standards for such products and is adopted by the California Energy Commission by January 1, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
