<bill session="111" type="s" number="3751" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-10-08">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stem Cell Therapeutic and Research Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Stem Cell Therapeutic and Research Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Stem Cell Therapeutic and Research Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Stem Cell Therapeutic and Research Act of 2005.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2010-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2010-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2010-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2010-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2010-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6900-6901"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6901" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-09-23">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Harkin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="587">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 587.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2010-09-28" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7650-7653" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7650-7651" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T14:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T22:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pallone moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T22:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7186-7189" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T22:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3751.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T22:15:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Burgess objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-30T00:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7380" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-09-30T00:42:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/28/2010 H7186-7188" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-30T00:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-09-30">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-10-04">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-10-08">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-10-08" type="public" number="111-264">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-264.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="6081"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="6083"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cell biology and embryology"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2010--Public Law.
Stem Cell Therapeutic and Research Reauthorization Act of 2010 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Stem Cell Therapeutic and Research Act of 2005 to revise provisions related to the National Cord Blood Inventory (the Inventory), including to establish an inventory goal of at least 150,000 new units of cord blood to be made available under the C.W. Bill Young Cell Transplantation Program (the Program). (Currently, the number of units of cord blood is capped at 150,000). Revises application requirements for cord blood banks participating in the Inventory to require such banks to: (1) make assurances that cord blood units will be available for direct transplantation until the cord blood unit is released for transplantation for a first degree relative; (2) participate in the Program for a period of at least ten years beginning on the last date on which the recipient receives federal funds under a contract; (3) provide a plan to increase cord blood unit collections at collection sites that exist at the time of application, assist with the establishment of new collection sites, or contract with new collection sites; and (4) annually provide to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) a plan for, and demonstrate, ongoing measurable progress toward achieving self-sufficiency of cord blood unit collection and banking operations. Revises the requirements for a contract extension to make a qualified cord blood bank eligible for a five-year extension if the bank demonstrates a superior ability to satisfy the requirements of the contract and achieve the overall goals for which the contract was awarded. Redefines the term "first-degree relative" to exclude a parent. Authorizes appropriations for FY2011-FY2015 for the Inventory. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Program to support and expand studies and demonstration and outreach projects that focus on: (1) remote collection of cord blood units; and (2) novel approaches or incentives to encourage innovative technological advances that could be used to collect cord blood units. Defines "remote collection" to mean the collection of cord blood units at locations that do not have written contracts with cord blood banks for collection support. Requires the Secretary to: (1) set an annual goal of increasing collections of high quality cord blood units; (2) identify at least one demonstration or outreach project to replicate and expand nationwide, as appropriate; and (3) submit a plan for meeting such goal to the relevant congressional committees if no such project can be identified. Revises privacy requirements to protect the identity and privacy of patients and donors in accordance with federal and state law. Requires the Secretary to submit an interim report to Congress within 180 days of enactment of this Act describing: (1) the methods to distribute federal funds to cord blood banks; (2) how cord blood banks contract with collection sites for the collection of cord blood units; and (3) recommendations for improving the methods to distribute federal funds to encourage the efficient collection of high-quality and diverse cord blood units. Directs the Advisory Council on Blood Stem Cell Transplantation to submit recommendations to the Secretary with respect to remote collection of cord blood units. Authorizes appropriations for FY2011-FY2015 to carry out the Program. Directs the Comptroller General to submit to the relevant congressional committees and the Secretary a report reviewing studies, demonstration programs, and outreach efforts for the purpose of increasing cord blood unit donation and collection for the Inventory to ensure a high-quality and genetically diverse inventory of cord blood units.</summary>
</bill>
