<bill session="110" type="s" number="2127" updated="2013-07-19T22:39:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mine Disaster Family Assistance Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide assistance to families of miners involved in mining accidents.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12441"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2007--Introduced.
Mine Disaster Family Assistance Act of 2007 - Amends the MINER Act to require the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Mine Safety and Health, as soon as practicable after being notified of a mining accident involving a mine operator and resulting in a mine emergency response by the Mine Safety and Health Administration (MSHA), to: (1) designate and publicize the name and phone number of a director of a family support service as a point of contact within the federal government for the families of miners involved and as a liaison between the operator and the families; and (2) designate an independent nonprofit organization with primary responsibility for coordinating the emotional care and support of the miners' families.Sets forth responsibilities of the MSHA and the designated organization in such an accident.Prohibits: (1) impeding the ability of MSHA or the designated organization to carry out their responsibilities or the ability of families to have contact with one another; (2) unsolicited communications by attorneys or parties to litigation to injured individuals or their families concerning a potential action for personal injury or wrongful death before the 45th day following the accident date; and (3) preventing a designated organization from providing mental health and counseling services.Directs operators that are subject to the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 to submit to the Secretary of Labor a plan for addressing the needs of the families of miners involved in such accidents. Shields an operator from liability for damages (except for gross negligence or intentional misconduct) in any action brought in a federal or state court arising out of the operator's performance in preparing or providing a miner list pursuant to such plan.Requires the Secretary to establish a task force to develop guidelines and recommendations about responding to mining accidents.</summary>
</bill>
