<bill session="110" type="h" number="6346" updated="2013-07-19T21:59:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-24T18:17:00-04:00">PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-06-24T18:17:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Price Gouging Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect consumers from price-gouging of gasoline and other fuels, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-24T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Stupak moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-24T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5934-5940" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-24T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6346.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-24T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-24T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5964-5965" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="2008-06-24T18:17:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="448" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 276 - 146 (Roll no. 448).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5934-5935" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1252"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2008--Introduced.
Federal Price Gouging Prevention Act - Makes it unlawful, during a period proclaimed by the President as an energy emergency, to sell gasoline or any other petroleum distillate at a price that: (1) is unconscionably excessive; or (2) indicates the seller is taking unfair advantage of the circumstances of an emergency to increase prices unreasonably. Authorizes the President to issue an energy emergency proclamation of up to 30 days, with renewals allowed, and to cite the geographic area, gasoline or other petroleum distillate, and time period covered. Authorizes a proclamation to include a period of up to one week preceding a reasonably foreseeable emergency. Exempts from this Act a sale of gasoline or other petroleum distillate transaction on a futures market. Empowers the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and state attorneys general to enforce this Act and provides for civil and criminal penalties, limiting the criminal penalty to criminal actions brought by the Department of Justice (DOJ). Allows a state to bring a civil action to enforce this Act or to impose civil penalties. Requires deposit of fines and penalties collected under this Act in a separate Consumer Relief Trust Fund fund in the Treasury to provide assistance under the Low Income Home Energy Assistance (LIHEAP) Program. Declares that nothing in this Act preempts state law.</summary>
</bill>
