<bill session="110" type="s" number="3680" updated="2013-07-19T22:53:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Thorium Energy Independence and Security Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to provide for thorium fuel cycle nuclear power generation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2008-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-10-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10488"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-10-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in science"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2008--Introduced.
Thorium Energy Independence and Security Act of 2008 - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to direct the Secretary of Energy to establish, and provide funds to, an office for the regulation of thorium fuel cycle nuclear power generation in each of: (1) the Office of Nuclear Energy, Science and Technology (ONEST) of the Department of Energy; and (2) the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC). Directs the NRC Chairman to promulgate regulations for facilities and materials used in thorium fuel cycle nuclear power generation. Requires the heads of the two Offices to: (1) implement demonstration projects for thorium fuel cycle nuclear power generation at the Idaho National Engineering Laboratory; and (2) recommend to the Secretary methods of strengthening international partnerships to advance nuclear nonproliferation through thorium fuel cycle nuclear power generation, and of providing incentives to nuclear reactor operators to use proliferation-resistant, low-waste thorium fuels in lieu of other fuels.</summary>
</bill>
