<bill session="110" type="h" number="6190" updated="2013-07-19T21:57:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Iraqi Police Service Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restore to the Department of State responsibility over the Police Training Teams being used to provide advisory support, training and development, and equipment for the Iraqi Police Service, to require the Department of State to provide the majority of members for the Police Training Teams, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400396"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-04">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-04">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/2008--Introduced.
Iraqi Police Service Improvement Act of 2008 - Directs: (1) the Secretary of State to assume responsibility from the Department of Defense (DOD) over the Police Training Teams being used in Iraq to provide advisory support, training and development, and equipment for the Iraqi Police Service; (2) the Secretary to ensure that a majority of the members of each Police Training Team consists of qualified civilian advisors, including Department of State employees and contractor employees; and (3) the Secretary and the Secretary of Defense to submit to Congress a statement of understanding on command structure, including the responsibilities of members of the Police Training Teams. States that: (1) in addition to members of the Armed Forces serving on Police Training Teams the Secretary of Defense, at the request of the Secretary, shall make DOD equipment available for the Police Training Teams; and (2) the Armed Forces shall continue to provide security for Police Training Teams.</summary>
</bill>
