<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1746" updated="2013-07-19T23:11:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-08T16:17:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-08T16:17:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing and supporting the efforts of Welcome Back Veterans to augment the services provided by the Departments of Defense and Veterans' Affairs in providing timely and world-class care for veterans and members of the Armed Forces suffering from PTSD and related psychiatric disorders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-01">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-01">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T11:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Donnelly (IN) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T11:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8102-8104" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T11:05:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1746.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T11:15:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Donnelly (IN) objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T16:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8151-8152" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-12-08T16:17:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="621" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 409 - 0 (Roll no. 621).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8102" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T16:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2010--Passed House amended.
Recognizes and supports the efforts of Welcome Back Veterans to augment the services provided by the Departments of Defense (DOD) and Veterans Affairs (VA) in providing timely and world-class care for veterans and members of the Armed Forces suffering from post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) and related psychiatric disorders. Encourages the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish innovative public-private partnerships for the treatment and research of PTSD in teaching hospitals across the country.</summary>
</bill>
