<bill session="112" type="h" number="2507" updated="2013-07-20T01:32:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transportation Security Administration Employee Freedom Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To exclude employees of the Transportation Security Administration from the collective bargaining rights of Federal employees and provide employment rights and an employee engagement mechanism for passenger and property screeners.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412426"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412427" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412481" joined="2011-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412280" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2011-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2011-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2011-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM" subcommittee="Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1353"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2011--Introduced.
Transportation Security Administration Employee Freedom Act of 2011 - Excludes officers and employees of Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) from the right of federal employees to bargain collectively. Subjects also to such exclusion the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) personnel management system as it applies to TSA employees. Amends the Aviation and Transportation Security Act to provide that, notwithstanding the authority of the TSA Administrator to fix the terms and conditions of employment of TSA screeners, nothing shall prohibit such an employee from joining a labor organization. Authorizes screeners to: (1) appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board adverse actions brought against them which are finalized after enactment of the FAA Air Transportation Modernization and Safety Improvement Act, and (2) seek judicial review of any resulting Board orders or decisions. Requires the FAA Administrator to provide to TSA screeners with a collaborative, integrated employee engagement mechanism to address workplace issues. Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2003 to apply certain whistleblower protections to DHS employees.</summary>
</bill>
