<bill session="110" type="s" number="1761" updated="2013-07-19T22:35:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safety and Accountability in Construction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Transportation to contract with an independent engineer to review the construction methods of certain Federal highway projects, to require States to submit a project management plan for each highway project financed with Federal funds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Cost overruns"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Tunnels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2007--Introduced.
Safety and Accountability in Construction Act - Requires state transportation departments to submit project management plans for federal-aid highway projects to the Secretary of Transportation for approval. Authorizes the Secretary to contract with a qualified independent engineer to provide independent safety reviews of federally-financed highway projects if certain determinations are made. Requires the Secretary to establish a national tunnel inspection program (including national standards for the inspection of such tunnels). Authorizes states to obligate apportioned surface transportation program funds for: (1) the construction and repair of tunnels; and (2) tunnel safety inspections.</summary>
</bill>
