<bill session="110" type="h" number="6075" updated="2013-07-19T21:56:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Guard and Reserve Mental Health Access Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand and improve mental health care and reintegration programs for members of the National Guard and Reserve, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2008-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400642" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2008-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2939"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Brain"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Head injuries"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="Psychologists"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2008--Introduced.
National Guard and Reserve Mental Health Access Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of Defense to: (1) provide for the implementation of the Yellow Ribbon Reintegration Program for members of the National Guard and reserves and their families required by section 582 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 by not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act; and (2) report to the congressional defense committees on that Program's implementation. Directs the Secretary to carry out a joint psychological health program to: (1) increase access to and the provision of psychological health care and related services for members of the National Guard following their deployment, and their families; (2) improve coordination among DOD components in the provision of such care during members' transition from active duty to civilian life; and (3) coordinate and oversee DOD efforts to assist members of the National Guard with mental illness and members with traumatic brain injury post-deployment. Requires the Chief of the National Guard Bureau to establish the National Guard Psychological Health Council. Directs the Secretaries of Defense and Veterans Affairs to jointly carry out: (1) one or more pilot programs on the provision of mental health services to members of the National Guard and reserves, both before and after deployment, through telemental health technologies; and (2) an outreach program intended to reduce the stigma, among members of the National Guard and reserves returning from deployment, and their families, associated with seeking and obtaining mental health services. Requires the Secretary, as part of the Yellow Ribbon Reintegration Program, to assign community outreach coordinators to assist members of the National Guard and reserves returning from deployment.</summary>
</bill>
