<bill session="112" type="h" number="5683" updated="2013-07-20T01:59:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Job Corps Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the President to establish the Veterans' Job Corps as a means of providing gainful employment to unemployed veterans and widows of veterans through the performance of useful public works, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412192" joined="2012-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2012--Introduced.
Veterans' Job Corps Act - Authorizes the President to establish and operate a Veterans' Job Corps to employ veterans and veterans' widows or widowers who are otherwise unemployed in the construction, maintenance, and carrying on of public works in connection with: (1) the forestation of U.S. or state lands; (2) the prevention of forest fires, floods, and soil erosion; (3) public safety; (4) plant pest and disease control; and (5) the construction, maintenance, or repair of paths, trails, and fire-lanes in National Park System units and other public lands. Directs the President to employ individuals in the Corps in the following order of preference: (1) unemployed veterans, and (2) widows or widowers who are eligible for unemployment compensation immediately before employment in the Corps. Authorizes the President to provide individuals employed in the Corps with housing, necessary subsistence, clothing, medical attendance and hospitalization, a cash allowance, and transportation to and from the places of employment. Prohibits the employment in the Corps of an individual convicted of a felony or a veteran who was discharged from the Armed Forces under dishonorable conditions.</summary>
</bill>
