<bill session="113" type="hj" number="73" updated="2013-11-02T06:48:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-02T18:49:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-02T18:49:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Research for lifesaving cures bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Institutes of Health Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">National Institutes of Health Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations for the National Institutes of Health for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400221"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 370 Reported to House. The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 70, H.J. Res. 71, H.J. Res. 72, H.J. Res. 73, and H.R. 3230. The resolution provides for 30 minutes of debate on each measure and provides for one motion to recommit each measure. The resolution also provides that it shall be in order at any time through the calendar day of October 6, 2013, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T16:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 370.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6139-6146" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T16:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 70, H.J. Res. 71, H.J. Res. 72, H.J. Res. 73, and H.R. 3230. The resolution provides for 30 minutes of debate on each measure and provides for one motion to recommit each measure. The resolution also provides that it shall be in order at any time through the calendar day of October 6, 2013, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T16:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 73.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T17:08:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.J. Res. 73, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Kingston demanded the yeas and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the resolution until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T18:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6155-6156" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="514" datetime="2013-10-02T18:49:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 254 - 171 (Roll no. 514).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6139" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T18:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read the first time pursuant to the order of Oct. 2, 2013.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 205 pursuant to the order of Oct. 2, 2013.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="370"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="370"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2013--Passed House without amendment.
National Institutes of Health Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 - Appropriates, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, and out of applicable corporate or other revenues, receipts, and funds, for the National Institutes of Health (NIH) for FY2014, and for other purposes, such amounts as may be necessary, at a rate for operations as provided in the Full-Year Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 (division F of P.L. 113-6), for continuing projects or activities (including the costs of direct loans and loan guarantees) not otherwise specifically provided for in this joint resolution, that were conducted in FY2013, and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available by such Act to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) for NIH under the heading "Department of Health and Human Services--National Institutes of Health." Requires the rate of operations for each account to be calculated to reflect reductions required in FY2013 pursuant to division G of such Act and the presidential sequestration order dated March 1, 2013, except as attributable to budget authority made available by the Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013. Requires appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this joint resolution, unless otherwise provided for in this joint resolution or in the applicable appropriations Act for FY2014, to remain available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) the enactment of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution, (2) the enactment of the applicable appropriations Act for FY2014 without any provision for such project or activity, or (3) December 15, 2013. Requires expenditures made pursuant to this joint resolution to be charged to the applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization whenever a bill in which such applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization is contained is enacted into law. Requires only the most limited funding action of that permitted in this joint resolution to be taken in order to provide for continuation of projects and activities. Authorizes amounts made available for civilian personnel compensation and benefits in each agency to be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to avoid furloughs in such agencies, consistent with the applicable appropriations Act for FY2013, except that such authority shall not be used until after the agency has taken all necessary actions to reduce or defer non-personnel-related administrative expenses. Expresses the sense of Congress that this joint resolution may also be referred to as the Research for Lifesaving Cures Act.</summary>
</bill>
