<bill session="109" type="h" number="1758" updated="2013-07-19T19:19:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Open Air Drug Market Penalty Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to provide penalties for open air drug markets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2005--Introduced.
Open Air Drug Market Penalty Act of 2005 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to impose an additional five years' imprisonment for knowingly committing a Federal offense, of which an element is the distribution of a controlled substance and for which the maximum term of imprisonment equals or exceeds five years, within 500 feet of the place where such an offense was committed within the preceding 48 hours. Prohibits: (1) the court from placing on probation or suspending the sentence of anyone convicted for such a violation; and (2) the term of imprisonment imposed from running concurrently with any other term of imprisonment.</summary>
</bill>
