<bill session="109" type="h" number="2235" updated="2013-07-19T19:24:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Uniform Food Safety Labeling Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to safeguard public health and provide to consumers food that is safe, unadulterated, and honestly presented.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Beverages"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Dairy products"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Farm produce"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food prices"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foodborne diseases"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Frozen food"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grading (Agricultural products)"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Jews"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Natural foods"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Shellfish"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2005--Introduced.
National Uniform Food Safety Labeling Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to deem food to be misbranded unless the label: (1) for raw or partially cooked eggs, fish, milk, dairy products, shellfish, or unpasteurized juice discloses the increased risk associated with eating such food in raw or partially cooked form and the risk to children, the elderly, pregnant women, and persons with weakened immune systems of experiencing foodborne illnesses from eating such food; (2) for frozen fish or shellfish prominently discloses that the product has been frozen unless it was smoked, cured, cooked, or commercially sterilized prior to being frozen; (3) for raw eggs discloses the increased risk associated with eating raw eggs for children, the elderly, pregnant women, or persons with weakened immune systems; (4) for perishable agricultural commodities or derivatives contains the country of origin; (5) contains the date upon which it should no longer be sold because of diminution of quality, nutrient availability, or safety; (6) bears the word "natural" only if the food contains no artificial or synthetic ingredient added after harvesting and has not undergone other than minimal processing; (7) does not falsely represent that food has been prepared in accordance with orthodox Jewish religious standards; (8) includes the unit price and the total price of the food in accordance with this Act; and (9) bears a grade where grading is customary within the industry.</summary>
</bill>
