<bill session="111" type="sr" number="660" updated="2013-07-20T00:22:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-28">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing support for a public diplomacy program promoting advancements in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics made by or in partnership with the people of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412329"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2010-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-09-28" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7666-7669" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7669" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7637-7638" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2010--Passed Senate without amendment.
Commends individuals and institutions that participate in and support advancements in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM), especially through international partnerships. Supports the Science Envoy Program as representative of the commitment of the United States to collaborate with other countries to promote the advancement of science and technology. Encourages the Secretary of State to establish a public diplomacy program to: (1) establish exhibits that illustrate cooperation between institutions and the people of the United States and institutions and people of the host country; (2) create fora for host country individuals to discuss their work; and (3) encourage future STEM cooperation with students around the world.</summary>
</bill>
