<bill session="112" type="h" number="2017" updated="2013-07-20T01:27:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2012</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Disaster Assistance Recoupment Fairness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Continuing Appropriations Act, 2012</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Continuing Appropriations Act, 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2012, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An Act making continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2012, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400004"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26T19:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-91, by Mr. Aderholt.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-05-26T19:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="50">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 50.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-05-31T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 287 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2017 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI are waived except for section 536. The resolution authorizes the Chair to accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T15:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 287 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 287.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3832-3867" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3837, H3844, H3851-3852" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3856, H3857, H3857-3858, H3858-3860" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3861-3862, H3879, H3881, H3882" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3882, H3883-3884" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3884-3885, H3886-3888" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3890" label="text of Title VI as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3890" label="text of Title VII as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2017 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI are waived except for section 536. The resolution authorizes the Chair to accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 287 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T15:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable David Dreier to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T15:35:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2017.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 287, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on pro forma amendments to H.R. 2017.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the LaTourette amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the LaTourette amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Aderholt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T16:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Cicilline amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cicilline amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Aderholt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T16:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Royce amendment number 2 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Royce amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Royce demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T17:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson Lee(TX) amendment number 12 under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Broun(GA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Poe(TX) amendment number 8 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Poe(TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Poe(TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T17:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Norton amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Poe(TX) amendment number 7 under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T17:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T18:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T18:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Cuellar amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cuellar amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cuellar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which were debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Aderholt moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2017 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T18:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3855-3867" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T18:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King(IA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King(IA) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T19:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Barrow amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T19:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Richardson amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Richardson amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T19:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Clarke(MI) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T19:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Clarke(MI) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T20:22:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Clarke(MI) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Clarke (MI) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T20:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Heck amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T20:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Heck amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T20:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Richardson amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T20:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Honda amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T21:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Sessions amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T21:18:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sessions amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Dicks demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T21:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Lummis amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T21:45:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Carter amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Price (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T21:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Richmond amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T21:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Carter amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:05:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Carter amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Price (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Poe amendment no. 9 under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Poe amendment no. 10 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Richmond amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Poe amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Price (NC) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:32:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Price (NC) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Price (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Scalise amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Sherman amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:45:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sherman amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sherman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Gosar amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:55:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Price(NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Altmire amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T22:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Scalise amendment under the five-minute rule. A point of order was reserved, but was subsequently removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T23:12:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Scalise amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Dicks demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T23:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Engel amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T23:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King (IA) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T23:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King (IA) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T23:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King (IA) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T23:48:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the King (IA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. King (IA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T23:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Cravaack amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T23:53:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cravaack amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cravaack demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T23:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Amash amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T23:57:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amash amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Amash demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01T23:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Amash amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T00:01:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amash amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Price (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T00:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Amash amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T00:08:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amash amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Price (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T00:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Rokita amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T00:19:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rokita amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rokita demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T00:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Rokita amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T00:27:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rokita amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rokita demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T00:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Aderholt moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T00:28:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T00:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2017 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3928-3936" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T12:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Baldwin amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T12:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Speier amendment no. 19 under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Speier amendment no. 18 under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T12:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Debate - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T12:53:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Aderholt moved to that the Committee now rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to that the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T13:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2017 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3939-3945" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Cole (OK) amendment No. 42 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cole (OK) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cole (OK) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Gohmert amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T14:45:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gohmert amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gohmert demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T14:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Issa amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T15:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Mica amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mica amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Mica demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Aderholt moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2017 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3945-3964" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T16:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Polis(CO) amendment number 23 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis(CO) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Polis(CO) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T16:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Eshoo amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on the question of adoption of amendments which were debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Aderholt moved for the Committee of the Whole to rise and report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to rise and report Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2017.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3961" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bishop (NY) moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3961-3962" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3962" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T18:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House with an amendment to increase grants for Transportation Security and Counterterrorism through offsets from the Department of Homeland Security's National Bio and Agro-Defense Facility.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3962" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T18:52:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 187 - 234 (Roll no. 408).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-06-02T18:58:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="409" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 231 - 188 (Roll no. 409).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02T18:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-07">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 112-74.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-09-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="156">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 156.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-09-26">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5977-5987" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5977-5987" label="text of amendment in nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-26">
      <text>The committee reported substitute was withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5987" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2011-09-26" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/3/2011 S6055-6056" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-09-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-29T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Culberson asked unanimous consent that the House agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6463-6465" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2011-09-29T11:05:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6463-6465" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-09-29T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2011-09-29">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2011-09-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2011-09-30" type="public" number="112-33">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-33.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="287"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hj" number="66"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2608"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5855"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3216"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Export-Import Bank of the United States"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h349"/>
    <amendment number="h350"/>
    <amendment number="h351"/>
    <amendment number="h352"/>
    <amendment number="h353"/>
    <amendment number="h354"/>
    <amendment number="h355"/>
    <amendment number="h356"/>
    <amendment number="h357"/>
    <amendment number="h358"/>
    <amendment number="h359"/>
    <amendment number="h360"/>
    <amendment number="h361"/>
    <amendment number="h362"/>
    <amendment number="h363"/>
    <amendment number="h364"/>
    <amendment number="h365"/>
    <amendment number="h366"/>
    <amendment number="h367"/>
    <amendment number="h368"/>
    <amendment number="h369"/>
    <amendment number="h370"/>
    <amendment number="h371"/>
    <amendment number="h372"/>
    <amendment number="h373"/>
    <amendment number="h374"/>
    <amendment number="h375"/>
    <amendment number="h376"/>
    <amendment number="h377"/>
    <amendment number="h378"/>
    <amendment number="h379"/>
    <amendment number="h380"/>
    <amendment number="h381"/>
    <amendment number="h382"/>
    <amendment number="h383"/>
    <amendment number="h384"/>
    <amendment number="h385"/>
    <amendment number="h386"/>
    <amendment number="h387"/>
    <amendment number="h388"/>
    <amendment number="h389"/>
    <amendment number="h390"/>
    <amendment number="h391"/>
    <amendment number="h392"/>
    <amendment number="h393"/>
    <amendment number="h394"/>
    <amendment number="h395"/>
    <amendment number="h396"/>
    <amendment number="h397"/>
    <amendment number="h398"/>
    <amendment number="h399"/>
    <amendment number="h400"/>
    <amendment number="h401"/>
    <amendment number="h402"/>
    <amendment number="h403"/>
    <amendment number="h404"/>
    <amendment number="h405"/>
    <amendment number="h406"/>
    <amendment number="h407"/>
    <amendment number="h408"/>
    <amendment number="s666"/>
    <amendment number="s667"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/30/2011--Public Law.
Continuing Appropriations Act, 2012 - Makes continuing appropriations for FY2012. (Sec. 101) Makes appropriations for continuing operations, projects, or activities which were conducted in FY2011 and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available in: (1) the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2011 (division A of Public Law 112-10); and (2) the Full-Year Continuing Appropriations Act, 2011 (division B of Public Law 112-10). Reduces the rate for operations by 1.503%. (Sec. 102) Prohibits the use of appropriations, funds, or authority granted under this Act for the Department of Defense (DOD) for: (1) new production of items not funded for production in FY2011 or prior years; (2) the increase in production rates above those sustained with FY2011 funds; or (3) the initiation, resumption, or continuation of any project, activity, operation, or organization for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were not available during FY2011. Bars the use of DOD appropriations, funds, or authority granted under this Act to initiate multi-year procurements utilizing advance procurement funding for economic order quantity procurement unless specifically appropriated later. (Sec. 104) Prohibits the use of appropriations, funds, or authority granted by this Act to initiate or resume any project or activity for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were not available during FY2011. (Sec. 106) Provides funding under this Act until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this Act; (2) enactment of the applicable appropriations Act for FY2012 without any provision for such project or activity; or (3) October 4, 2011. (Sec. 111) Continues through October 4, 2011, certain activities for entitlements and other mandatory payments whose budget authority was provided in FY2011 appropriations Acts, and for activities under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008. Declares that, notwithstanding such date, funds shall be available and obligations for mandatory payments due on or about the first day of any month after October 2011 but within 30 days after October 4, 2011. (Sec. 112) Authorizes apportionment of amounts made available under this Act for federal civilian personnel compensation and benefits up to the rate for operations necessary to avoid furloughs within a department or agency. Prohibits the use of such authority until after the department or agency has taken all necessary actions to reduce or defer non-personnel-related administrative expenses. (Sec. 114) Designates specified funds for Overseas Contingency Operations/Global War on Terrorism, but only if the President subsequently makes such a designation and notifies Congress. Exempts from such requirement amounts for the Department of Justice (DOJ), Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) for salaries and expenses. (Sec. 115) Requires discretionary amounts appropriated for FY2012 provided in advance by appropriations Acts to be available in the amounts provided in such Acts, reduced by 1.503%. (Sec. 116) Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to use through October 4, 2011, certain amounts for operations and activities of the Office of Security Cooperation in Iraq and security assistance teams. (Sec. 117) Makes certain funds available for Overseas Contingency Operations at a rate for operations permitted by the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2012 as passed by the House of Representatives on July 8, 2011. (Sec. 118) Continues through October 4, 2011, DOD authority to pay monetary rewards for the provision to U.S. government personnel of information or nonlethal assistance beneficial to an operation, activity, or force protection for U.S. Armed Forces. (Sec. 119) Continues through October 4, 2011, DOD authority to use acquisition and cross-servicing agreements to lend certain military equipment to foreign forces in Iraq and Afghanistan for personnel protection and survivability purposes. (Sec. 120) Provides amounts at a specified rate for operations for the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board for salaries and expenses. (Sec. 121) Authorizes the District of Columbia to expend local funds for programs and activities, subject to specified conditions. (Sec. 122) Provides amounts at a specified rate for operations for necessary expenses of the Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board to carry out its functions under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009. (Sec. 123) Continues through October 4, 2011, the authority of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to carry out: (1) the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Program, (2) the Small Business Technology Transfer Program, and (3) the Commercialization Pilot Program. (Sec. 124) Extends through October 4, 2011, the requirement that the U.S. Postal Service pay $5.5 billion into the Postal Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund. (Sec. 125) Provides amounts at a specified rate for operations to the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) for disaster relief. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to provide a full accounting of disaster relief funding requirements for FY2012 and FY2013, including specified estimates. (Sec. 126) Authorizes the obligation of any DHS funds made available pursuant to this Act at a rate for operations necessary to sustain essential security activities. (Sec. 127) Continues through October 4, 2011, U.S. Secret Service authority to use proceeds derived from undercover criminal investigations for such operations. (Sec. 128) Continues through October 4, 2011, DHS authority to carry out basic, applied, and advanced research and development projects. (Sec. 129) Continues through October 4, 2011, DHS issued interim final regulations establishing risk-based performance standards. (Sec. 130) Continues through October 4, 2011, the authority of the Administrator of FEMA to issue notes or other obligations to the Secretary of the Treasury to carry out the flood insurance program. (Sec. 131) Continues through October 4, 2011, the authorities of Service First (a partnership authority among the Bureau of Land Management [BLM], the Forest Service, the National Park Service, and the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service). (Sec. 132) Increases appropriations for salaries and expenses in the Mine Safety and Health Administration of the Department of Labor. (Sec. 134) Provides amounts at a specified rate for operations for the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission for salaries and expenses. (Sec. 135) Continues through October 4, 2011 the authority of the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) with respect to: (1) autism spectrum disorder and other developmental disabilities; and (2) autism education, early detection, and intervention. Continues through such date the Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee. (Sec. 136) Eliminates certain FY2011 appropriations for military construction for the Army, the Air Force, and defense-wide. (Sec. 137) Extends through October 4, 2011, the authority of the Export-Import Bank of the United States to provide financing for the export of nonlethal articles or services meant primarily for civilian purposes. (Sec. 138) Continues through October 4, 2011, the Commission on International Religious Freedom. (Sec. 139) Limits to a specified rate of operations any commitments to guarantee loans incurred under the General and Special Risk Insurance Funds authorized under the National Housing Act. (Sec. 140) Approves the renewal of certain import restrictions contained in the Burmese Freedom and Democracy Act of 2003, and deems this Act a renewal resolution under such Act.</summary>
</bill>
