<bill session="109" type="s" number="137" updated="2013-07-19T20:14:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Federal Contractor Safeguard Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to modify the contract consolidation requirements in the Small Business Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S351-353"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S353-355" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2005--Introduced.
Small Business Federal Contractor Safeguard Act of 2005 - Amends the Small Business Act to prohibit an official of a military department, Defense Agency, or the Department of Defense Field Activity, or the head of any other Federal agency from executing an acquisition strategy that includes a consolidation of contract requirements with a total value above specified amounts unless the senior procurement executive first: (1) conducts market research; (2) identifies any alternative contracting approaches that would involve less consolidation; and (3) determines that the consolidation is necessary and justified. Defines "consolidation of defense requirements" as the use of a solicitation to obtain offers for a single contract to satisfy two or more requirements for goods or services that have previously been provided under separate contracts for a smaller cost or are capable of being so provided. Requires each procurement employee to communicate to their subordinates the importance of achieving small business goals and include the success of such an employee in small business utilization as an annual performance evaluation factor. Requires small business subcontracting plans to include a certification that the offeror or bidder will acquire articles or services from small businesses in the amount used in preparing the bid or proposal. Requires the Small Business Administration (SBA) to share subcontracting compliance review data with Federal contracting officers and to update a national centralized Government-wide database with such information. Requires annual reports from the Associate Administrator of Business Development to the small business committees on the effectiveness of the BusinessLINC program.</summary>
</bill>
