<bill session="112" type="hr" number="487" updated="2013-07-20T01:07:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-08T11:04:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-12-08T11:04:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1633) to establish a temporary prohibition against revising any national ambient air quality standard applicable to coarse particulate matter, to limit Federal regulation of nuisance dust in areas in which such dust is regulated under State, tribal, or local law, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412410"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-07T17:44:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-317, by Mr. Webster.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-07T17:44:00-05:00">
      <text>The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill; proivdes that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Energy and Commerce shall be considered as original text for the purpose of amendment and shall be considered as read. Further it waives all points of order against the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute. The resolution makes in order only those amendments printed in the report. Each amendment may be offered only by a Member designated in this report, shall be considred as read, shall be debatable for the time specified in this report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the House or Committee of the Whole.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-12-07T17:44:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="96">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 96.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08T09:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8267-8271" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08T09:15:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 487.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08T09:50:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 487, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Polis (CO) demanded the yeas and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08T10:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8271-8272" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08T10:58:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 173 (Roll no. 902).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8271-8272" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-12-08T11:04:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="903" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 249 - 161 (Roll no. 903).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8267" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08T11:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="1633"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/7/2011--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1633) to establish a temporary prohibition against revising any national ambient air quality standard applicable to coarse particulate matter, to limit Federal regulation of nuisance dust in areas in which such dust is regulated under State, tribal, or local law.</summary>
</bill>
