<bill session="110" type="s" number="1423" updated="2013-07-19T22:32:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Kansas Disaster Tax Relief Assistance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to extend tax relief to the residents and businesses of an area with respect to which a major disaster has been declared by the President under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (FEMA-1699-DR) by reason of severe storms and tornados beginning on May 4, 2007, and determined by the President to warrant individual or public assistance from the Federal Government under such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2935"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3444"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3444"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1532"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Tornadoes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1193"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/17/2007--Introduced.
Kansas Disaster Tax Relief Assistance Act - Extends to businesses and individuals in certain Kansas counties declared by the President as major disaster areas under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (FEMA-1699-DR) by reason of severe storms and tornados beginning on May 4, 2007 (qualifying area) provisions of the Internal Revenue Code allowing: (1) suspension of certain limitations on personal casualty losses; (2) an extension of the period for replacing damaged property without recognizing gain; (3) an employee retention tax credit for affected businesses through 2007; (4) 50% bonus depreciation for affected businesses; (5) increased expensing of small business assets; (6) expensing of demolition and cleanup costs; (7) extended net operating loss carryback periods for losses attributable to storms and tornadoes and for public utility property disaster losses; (8) relaxed income verification requirements for tenants in low-income rental projects; and (9) penalty-free withdrawals and loans from individual retirement accounts and other tax-exempt pension plans. Directs the Secretary of Education to carry out a program of student loan repayment for college graduates residing or employed in a qualifying area.Amends the Internal Revenue Code with respect to individuals in a qualifying area to allow: (1) a tax credit for the lesser of 10% or $5,000 of the purchase price of a principal residence; (2) a capital loss deduction for the sale or exchange of a principal residence; and (3) the establishment of tax-exempt homestead accounts for the payment of education, business, medical, and other expenses.Allows: (1) business-related tax credits for investment in certain buildings and small businesses in rural areas; and (2) accelerated deprecation of investment property in rural areas.</summary>
</bill>
