<bill session="113" type="s" number="825" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeless Veterans Prevention Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the provision of services for homeless veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3036"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3037-3038" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2150"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2485"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1058"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2013--Introduced.
Homeless Veterans Prevention Act of 2013 - Requires public or private nonprofit entities that receive grants under the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) comprehensive service programs for homeless veterans to agree to meet the physical, privacy, safety, and security needs of such veterans. Increases the per diem payment for transitional housing assistance for homeless veterans who are placed in housing that will become permanent upon the termination of such assistance to a maximum of 150% of the per diem rate authorized for veterans receiving domiciliary care in state homes. Allows services for which a homeless veteran receives a grant under the comprehensive service programs to include furnishing care for a dependent. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) to: (1) assess and measure the capacity of programs for which entities receive grants or per diem payments to assist homeless veterans, and (2) use such information to ensure that such programs effectively serve the needs of such veterans. Repeals a required annual VA report on activities under such programs. Repeals the September 30, 2013, sunset on the authority of the Secretary and the Secretary of Labor to carry out a program of referral and counseling for veterans who are at risk of homelessness and are transitioning from certain institutions, including penal institutions. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into partnerships with public or private entities to provide legal services to homeless veterans and veterans at risk of homelessness. Revises VA authority to provide dental care to veterans receiving certain other assistance through the VA to include those veterans receiving assistance under the United States Housing Act of 1937. Extends permanently the VA comprehensive service programs for homeless veterans. Extends temporarily various VA authorities and programs affecting homeless veterans.</summary>
</bill>
