<bill session="111" type="h" number="6552" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Single Food Safety Agency Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Food Safety Administration to protect the public health by preventing food-borne illness, ensuring the safety of food, improving research on contaminants leading to food-borne illness, and improving security of food from intentional contamination, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-17">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-17">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/17/2010--Introduced.
Single Food Safety Agency Act of 2010 - Establishes the Food Safety Administration as an independent agency within the executive branch.&#160; Requires the Administrator to: (1) administer and enforce food safety laws; (2) serve as a representative to international food safety bodies and discussions; and&#160; (3) oversee federal food safety efforts.&#160; Transfers all federal food safety duties to the Administration. Requires the Administrator to: (1)&#160; administer a national food safety program to protect public health, and (2) ensure that persons who produce or process food comply with federal laws and regulations to prevent or minimize food safety hazards related to their products. Establishes civil penalties for violations of food safety laws.&#160; Escalates civil and criminal penalties for knowingly violating food safety laws. Requires the President to submit a reorganization plan for the transfer of agencies, personnel, assets, and obligations to the Administration.</summary>
</bill>
