<bill session="112" type="h" number="2986" updated="2013-07-20T01:36:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Partners Neighborhood Preservation Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand the Officer Next Door and Teacher Next Door initiatives of the Department of Housing and Urban Development to include fire fighters and rescue personnel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="379"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3649"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2011--Introduced.
Community Partners Neighborhood Preservation Act of 2011 - Amends the National Housing Act to provide: (1) a 50% discount for teachers and public safety officers purchasing certain eligible asset properties for use as their primary residence during FY2012-FY2022, and (2) a $100 downpayment on any related insured mortgage. Authorizes such sales directly to a qualifying individual or to a unit of local government or a nonprofit organization for resale to such individual. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) should consult with the heads of other federal agencies that own or hold properties appropriate for use as housing to determine the possibility and effectiveness of including such properties in programs that make housing available for law enforcement officers, teachers, or fire fighters. Makes a public safety officer or teacher eligible to purchase any property owned or held by the Secretary pursuant to: (1) foreclosure of any HUD-insured mortgage; or (2) assignment of the mortgage, deed in lieu of foreclosure, conveyance of title, or any other acquisition of the property or mortgage in connection with the payment of insurance benefits by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to revise the Good Neighbor Next Door Initiative to provide that the subordinate mortgage on the property of a mortgagor who purchased it under the Initiative shall be released in any case in which the mortgagor loses his or her employment position as a law enforcement officer, teacher, firefighter, or emergency medical technician as a result of any reductions in force or other reason other than dismissal for cause. Directs the Secretary of HUD, in making any real estate owned by HUD available for purchase, to provide a preference for purchase by public safety officers and teachers.</summary>
</bill>
