<bill session="112" type="s" number="1215" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lowell National Historical Park Land Exchange Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the exchange of land located in the Lowell National Historical Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2012-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-401.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2240"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2011--Introduced.
Lowell National Historical Park Land Exchange Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to exchange any federal land or interest within the boundaries of Lowell National Historical Park in Massachusetts for any non-federal land or interest owned by the state of Massachusetts, the city of Lowell, or the University of Massachusetts Building Authority. Requires, if facilities or infrastructure required for the management and operation of the Park are located on the federal land to be exchanged and the value of the federal and non-federal land is not of equal value, the value shall be equalized by the making of a cash equalization payment to the Secretary. Requires any such payments received by the Secretary to be credited to a special account in the Treasury and made available for the replacement of such facilities and infrastructure. Bars the Secretary from being required to equalize the value of the federal and non-federal land if the non-federal land exceeds the value of the federal land. Requires loans made by the Lowell Historic Preservation Commission to the Lowell Development and Financial Corporation to enable the Corporation to provide low interest loans for the preservation, restoration, or development of certain property in the Park or Lowell Historic Preservation District because of its national historic or cultural significance to have a maturity of 60 years (under current law, 35 years).</summary>
</bill>
