<bill session="111" type="s" number="3070" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Florida National Forest Land Adjustment Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to release Federal reversionary interests retained on certain lands acquired in the State of Florida under the Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act, to authorize the interchange of National Forest System land and State land in Florida, to authorize an additional conveyance under the Florida National Forest Land Management Act of 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412380" joined="2010-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3954"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2010--Introduced.
Florida National Forest Land Adjustment Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to release, convey, and quitclaim to the state of Florida, without monetary consideration, all interest of the United States in and to those lands within or adjacent to the Blackwater River and Withlacoochee State Forests that were conveyed to the state under the authority of the Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act or under any other law authorizing conveyance subject to restrictions or reversionary interests retained by the United States. Requires the state to cover or reimburse the Secretary for reasonable costs incurred to make the conveyances. Bars the Secretary from seeking reimbursement for administrative overhead costs. Requires the state to agree: (1) that all net proceeds from any sale, exchange, or other disposition of the real property subject to deed restrictions be used by the state for the acquisition of lands or interests within or adjacent to units of Florida's forest and park systems; (2) to address and resolve boundary encroachments for the affected state forests; and (3) to indemnify and hold the United States harmless with regard to any boundary disputes related to any released parcel. Provides for an interchange of certain state lands and National Forest System lands in the Ocala and Apalachicola National Forests in Florida. Authorizes the Secretary to convey by sale or exchange tract W-1979 within Leon County, Florida.</summary>
</bill>
