<bill session="112" type="s" number="906" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">No Taxpayer Funding for Abortion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit taxpayer funded abortions and to provide for conscience protections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2011-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2011-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2011-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2011-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2011-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2011-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1232"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1484"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1488"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2011--Introduced.
No Taxpayer Funding for Abortion Act - Prohibits the expenditure of funds authorized or appropriated by federal law or funds in any trust fund to which funds are authorized or appropriated by federal law (federal funds) for any abortion. Prohibits federal funds from being used for any health benefits coverage that includes coverage of abortion. (Currently, federal funds cannot be used for abortion services and plans receiving federal funds must keep federal funds segregated from any funds for abortion services.) Prohibits the inclusion of abortion in any health care service furnished by a federal or District of Columbia health care facility or by any physician or other individual employed by the federal government or the District. Excludes from such prohibitions an abortion if: (1) the pregnancy is the result of rape or incest; or (2) the woman suffers from a physical disorder, injury, or illness, including a life-endangering physical condition caused by or arising from the pregnancy itself, that would place her in danger of death unless an abortion is performed, as certified by a physician. Makes such prohibitions applicable to District of Columbia funds. Codifies the prohibition against a federal agency or program or any state or local government that receives federal financial assistance from subjecting any individual or health care entity to discrimination on the basis that the health care entity does not provide, pay for, provide coverage of, or refer for abortions. Creates a cause of action for any violations of such provisions. Gives federal courts jurisdiction to prevent and redress actual or threatened violations of such provisions by issuing any form of legal or equitable relief, including an injunction or order preventing the disbursement of all or a portion of federal financial assistance until the prohibited conduct has ceased. Gives standing to institute an action to affected health care entities and the Attorney General. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to designate the Director of the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to receive, investigate, and refer to the appropriate federal agency complaints alleging a violation of such provisions. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to disqualify, for purposes of the tax deduction for medical expenses, any amounts paid for an abortion. Excludes from the definition of "qualified health plan" after December 31, 2013, for purposes of the refundable tax credit for premium assistance for such plans, any plan that includes coverage for abortion. Excludes from the definitions of "qualified health plan" and "health insurance coverage," for purposes of the tax credit for small employer health insurance expenses, any health plan or benefit that includes coverage for abortions. Includes any reimbursements or distributions to pay for an abortion in the gross income of participants in flexible spending arrangements under a tax-exempt cafeteria plan, Archer Medical Savings Accounts (MSAs), and health savings accounts (HSAs). Exempts from the application of such tax provisions: (1) abortions for pregnancies resulting from rape or incest or in cases where a woman suffers from a physical disorder, injury, or illness that would, as certified by a physician, endanger her life if an abortion were not performed; and (2) the treatment of any infection, injury, disease, or disorder that was caused by or exacerbated by the performance of an abortion.</summary>
</bill>
