<bill session="109" type="s" number="2065" updated="2013-07-19T20:31:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Occupational Safety Partnership Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to further improve the safety and health of working environments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="2005-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13370-13371"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13371-13374" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and employment"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Professional education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2005--Introduced.
Occupational Safety Partnership Act - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSHA) to direct the Secretary of Labor to establish a program that qualifies individuals to provide consultation services to help employers identify and correct workplace safety and health hazards. Exempts from civil penalties for two years (with a possible two-year renewal) employers who receive certificates of compliance from qualified consultants. Authorizes employers to establish alcohol and substance abuse testing programs in accordance with federal guidelines. Directs the Secretary to provide for: (1) employer cooperative agreements for comprehensive safety and health management systems; (2) an employer voluntary program, with increased small business participation, for excellence in technical and managerial protection of employees from occupational hazards; (3) state cooperative agreements for state consultation services for employers; and (4) a three-state pilot program for expedited consultation services for small businesses. Requires federal personnel responsible for enforcing OSHA to: (1) meet specified eligibility requirements; and (2) if they carry out inspections or investigations, receive professional education and training at least every five years. Authorizes the Secretary to develop and implement at least one training and educational exchange program with a specialty trade in the construction industry for specified activities relating to OSHA Rules.</summary>
</bill>
