<bill session="110" type="s" number="3396" updated="2013-07-19T22:51:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Independent Drug Education and Outreach Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide grants or contracts for prescription drug education and outreach for healthcare providers and their parents.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7952"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="6752"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Nonprescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2008--Introduced.
Independent Drug Education and Outreach Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, to award grants or contracts for: (1) the development and production of educational materials concerning the evidence available on the relative safety, effectiveness, and cost of prescription drugs, nonprescription drugs, and nondrug interventions for treating selected conditions, to be distributed and presented to health care providers who prescribe such drugs and their patients; and (2) the development and implementation of a program to appropriately train and deploy health professionals to distribute such materials to, and otherwise educate, physicians and other drug prescribers concerning such drugs and interventions. Requires that grantees receive no support from any entity that manufactures products used to treat the medical conditions discussed.</summary>
</bill>
