<bill session="109" type="s" number="1744" updated="2013-07-19T20:28:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Price Gouging Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit price gouging relating to gasoline and diesel fuels in areas affected by major disasters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S10300-10301" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1640"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2005--Introduced.
Price Gouging Act of 2005 - Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to direct the Federal Trade Commission to: (1) consult with certain senior law enforcement officials following the declaration of a major disaster by the President in order to determine whether any supplier is charging unconscionably excessive prices for gasoline or diesel fuel in the affected area; (2) establish a toll-free hotline to receive consumer reports of price gouging in the affected area; and (3) establish a program to develop and distribute public informational materials in English and Spanish to assist residents of the affected area in detecting and avoiding price gouging. Prohibits unconscionably excessive prices for any gasoline or diesel fuel in an affected area during the 180-day period after the date on which a major disaster is declared by the President. Subjects violations of this Act to specified civil and criminal penalties. Authorizes victims and state Attorneys General to bring a civil action against violators of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
