<bill session="113" type="h" number="2903" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Collegiate Athletics Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NCAA Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide increased accountability of nonprofit athletic associations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400648"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412565" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412569" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2013-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
National Collegiate Athletics Accountability Act or the NCAA Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require schools that have an intercollegiate athletic program and are participating in title IV programs to abstain from membership in a nonprofit athletic association unless the association: requires annual baseline concussion testing of student athletes on the active roster of teams participating in contact/collision or limited-contact/impact sports before they participate in any contact drills or activities; holds remedies for violations of its policies in abeyance until the schools and student athletes subject to those remedies have been afforded certain due process procedures; requires athletically-related student aid provided to student athletes who play contact/collision sports to be guaranteed for the duration of their attendance at the school, up to four years, and irrevocable for reasons related to skill or injury; and does not prevent schools from paying stipends to student athletes. Makes title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 inapplicable to any activity carried out by an institution of higher education to guarantee the continuance of student aid for student athletes in compliance with such membership requirements. (Title IX prohibits discrimination on the basis of sex or visual impairment under any education program that receives federal funds.)</summary>
</bill>
