<bill session="111" type="h" number="5456" updated="2013-07-20T00:01:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Farm-to-School Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to award competitive grants to assist eligible entities in implementing or expanding farm-to-school programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412304" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400328" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2010-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4710"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/28/2010--Introduced.
National Farm-to-School Act of 2010 - Expresses the sense of Congress regarding the benefits of farm-to-school programs and the federal role in furthering such programs. Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to require the Secretary of Agriculture to provide competitive matching grants and technical assistance to schools, local educational agencies (LEAs), institutions of higher education, and certain governmental and nongovernmental entities to implement or expand farm-to-school programs. Authorizes such grants to come in the form of implementation grants, training and technical assistance grants, or planning grants. Defines farm-to-school programs as those that connect schools and small- and medium-sized agricultural operations to: (1) serve locally produced, healthy foods in school cafeterias; (2) improve student nutrition; (3) provide agriculture, health, and nutrition education opportunities to students; and (4) support local and regional agriculture and the growth of rural communities. Directs the Secretary to prepare, and provide Congress with, a list identifying all the programs of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) that with little or no modification can be used to facilitate the participation of small- and medium-sized agricultural operations in farm-to-school programs. Declares that the value-added agricultural product market development grant program may be accessed by small- and medium-sized agricultural operations and their associations to support farm-to-school programs. Directs the Secretary, through the USDA Economic Research Service, to conduct a nationwide assessment of, and report to Congress on, the economic impact of farm-to-school programs on small- and medium-sized agricultural operations and rural communities. Requires the Secretary to establish an Internet-based forum for sharing and exchanging information on farm-to-school programs nationwide.</summary>
</bill>
