<bill session="112" type="h" number="638" updated="2013-07-20T01:15:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STAY PUT Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Suspending Travel After Years of Pleasure trips on Unwitting Taxpayers Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To impose a moratorium on the use of appropriated funds for official travel outside of the United States by Members, officers, and employees of the House of Representatives until the Comptroller General issues a report on the costs of such travel and makes recommendations regarding appropriate restrictions and reporting requirements on such travel.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400207"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2011-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="282"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2011--Introduced.
Suspending Travel After Years of Pleasure Trips on Unwitting Taxpayers Act of 2011 or STAY PUT Act of 2011 - Prohibits the use of appropriated funds, including official funds of the House of Representatives or funds available under any federal law, rule, or regulation, to pay for official travel outside of the United States by any Member, officer, or employee of the House, until the Comptroller General studies and reports to the Speaker of the House and the Secretaries of Defense (DOD) and of State on the use of certain appropriated funds for such travel and recommendations for appropriate restrictions on, and reporting requirements applicable to, such travel which will promote transparency and cost savings. Exempts from the prohibition and requirements of this Act any travel: (1) to a military installation or to a theater of operations of the Armed Forces; and (2) by Members and employees of the Committee on Foreign Affairs or the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, if the travel is for official committee business.</summary>
</bill>
