<bill session="111" type="h" number="6320" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Export Support Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the support, training, education, and compliance assistance regarding export licensing requirements provided to small businesses and medium-sized businesses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412193"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Small Business Export Support Act of 2010 - Amends the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to require the Secretary of Commerce to assign export licensing compliance specialists to at least 20 United States and Foreign Commercial Service district offices to provide small and medium-sized businesses with support, training, education, and compliance assistance regarding export licensing, including arms export licensing, requirements. Directs the Secretary to review and report to the President annually on the level of staffing at each such district office in order to determine the level that will enable it to serve such businesses effectively. Requires each of the Secretaries of Commerce, of Defense (DOD), of State, and of the Treasury, as well as the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), to designate an export licensing coordinator who exercises significant decisionmaking authority in the respective department or agency. Requires the coordinator to devise, encourage, and coordinate department or agency activities providing small and medium-sized businesses with export licensing assistance under this Act. Establishes in the Department of Commerce an Interagency Task Force on Export Control Assistance and Relief for Small and Medium-Sized Businesses to report annually to Congress its recommendations for improving such assistance.</summary>
</bill>
