<bill session="111" type="sr" number="616" updated="2013-07-20T00:21:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the United States civil-military partnership in Iraq, under the current leadership of General Raymond Odierno and Ambassador Christopher Hill, has refined and sustained an effective counterinsurgency and counterterrorism strategy that has enabled significant improvements in the security, governance, and rule of law throughout Iraq, and that these leaders should be commended for their integrity, resourcefulness, commitment, and sacrifice.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6908-6909" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the U.S. counterinsurgency and counterterrorism strategies have successfully enabled the Iraqi government to reach major milestones in security, governance, and rule of law and have set the conditions for reducing U.S. combat units in Iraq and changing their mission to advising and assisting Iraqi Security Forces; (2) United States Forces-Iraq was instrumental in effecting the recruitment, training, retention, and employment of approximately 700,000 Iraqi Security Forces who have assumed and maintained the lead for security operations within Iraq; and (3) U.S. commanders, their troops, and their civilian partners should be commended for their ingenuity, resourcefulness, courage, commitment, sacrifice, dedication, and service.</summary>
</bill>
