<bill session="111" type="h" number="1853" updated="2013-07-19T23:28:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior with respect to the C.C. Cragin Dam and Reservoir, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412286"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1080"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/2009--Introduced.
Withdraws specified land located in Coconino and Gila Counties, Arizona (covered land), from all forms of: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials. Grants the Secretary of the Interior exclusive jurisdiction with respect to covered land to manage each reclamation project carried out on such land in accordance with the Arizona Water Settlements Act. Requires that Secretary and the Salt River Project Agricultural Improvement and Power District to ensure the compliance of each activity carried out at the C.C. Craigin Dam and Reservoir with applicable federal law. Authorizes that Secretary to contract with the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, to carry out specified management activities on covered land that does not conflict with, or adversely affect, the operation, maintenance, or repair of the Dam, including the management of recreation, wildland fire activities, public conduct and law enforcement, and cultural and other resources. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, to carry out the operation, maintenance, and repair of the Dam, to authorize employees of the Department of the Interior and the District to use certain roads under Forest Service jurisdiction. Prohibits requiring any such individual from applying for or possessing a permit, license, or other similar document as a condition for authorization to use any such road. Requires the Department and the District to comply with applicable federal law.</summary>
</bill>
