<bill session="110" type="h" number="6053" updated="2013-07-19T21:56:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Price Stability Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to focus on price stability in establishing monetary policy to ensure the stable, long-term purchasing power of the currency, to repeal the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400351"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400662" joined="2008-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2008-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-14">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-14">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-14">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6042"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Open market operations"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Standard of living"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2008--Introduced.
Price Stability Act of 2008 - Declares it is US policy that the principal economic responsibilities of the Government are to establish both long-term economic growth and increases in living standards, maintain free markets, low taxes, respect for private property, and the stable, long-term purchasing power of US currency. Declares that the promotion of price stability should be the primary long-term goal of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. Amends the Federal Reserve Act to revise the mandate of the Board and the Federal Open Market Committee to require them to: (1) establish a numerical definition of the term "price stability"; and (2) maintain a monetary policy that promotes long-term price stability. Requires the Board to consult with, and report to, Congress semi-annually about Board and Committee objectives and plans to achieve and maintain price stability. Repeals the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978.</summary>
</bill>
