<bill session="111" type="sj" number="33" updated="2013-07-20T00:16:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A joint resolution to provide for the reconsideration and revision of the proposed constitution of the United States Virgin Islands to correct provisions inconsistent with the Constitution and Federal law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2010-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2010-06-17" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5138-5140" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5139-5140" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-06-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22T14:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22T18:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Christensen moved to suspend the rules and pass the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4925-4927" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S.J. Res. 33.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-06-29T13:20:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4925" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T13:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-06-30" type="public" number="111-194">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-194.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2010--Public Law.
Expresses the sense of Congress that Congress: (1) recognizes the commitment and efforts of the Fifth Constitutional Convention of the U.S. Virgin Islands to develop a proposed constitution; and (2) urges the Fifth Constitutional Convention of the U.S. Virgin Islands to reconvene to reconsider and revise the proposed constitution in response to the views of the executive branch of the federal government. Provides that if a convention reconvenes and revises the proposed constitution the convention shall resubmit the revised proposed constitution simultaneously to the Governor of the Virgin Islands and the President. Directs the President, within 60 calendar days after the date of receipt of the revised proposed constitution, to: (1) notify the convention, the Governor, and Congress of the President's comments on the revised proposed constitution; and (2) publish the comments in the Federal Register.</summary>
</bill>
