<bill session="113" type="s" number="53" updated="2013-11-02T06:52:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Disease Cluster Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to award grants to individuals that may be affected by a reported disease cluster.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2013-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/2013--Introduced.
Community Disease Cluster Assistance Act - Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), to award grants to any individual or group of individuals that may be affected by a reported community-based disease cluster. Requires such grants to be used to obtain technical assistance in interpreting information regarding: (1) investigating such reported disease clusters associated with hazardous chemicals, (2) the potential hazardous chemicals associated with a reported disease cluster, (3) providing individuals or groups with community-based tools to educate them about the mitigation of hazardous chemicals associated with reported disease clusters, or (4) other scientific and technical issues related to reported disease clusters.</summary>
</bill>
