<bill session="113" type="h" number="1533" updated="2013-11-02T06:31:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Regulatory Public Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an Office of Public Advocate within the Department of Justice to provide services and guidance to citizens in dealing with concerns involving the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/2013--Introduced.
Energy Regulatory Public Protection Act - Establishes within the Department of Justice (DOJ) an Office of Public Advocate to represent the interests of members of the general public affected by regulatory matters before the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC), other FERC-related matters before other federal regulatory agencies, or any court of competent jurisdiction. Makes it the duty of the Office to: (1) receive and assess comments from all interested parties with respect to project applications before FERC; (2) submit such comments to FERC, together with findings and recommendations, regarding the outcome, terms, and conditions of an application for approval; (3) review and assess applicant compliance with FERC orders; (4) seek full compliance with an order through the FERC or a court, if the applicant fails to comply and such noncompliance is harmful to the health, safety, and welfare of affected parties; and (5) undertake appeal of any FERC order it deems harmful to the heath, safety, or welfare of affected parties.</summary>
</bill>
