<bill session="113" type="h" number="1577" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">McLelland-Hasse Line of Duty Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect prosecutors, judges, law enforcement officers, and their families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2013-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2029"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="698"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/16/2013--Introduced.
McLelland-Hasse Line of Duty Act - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to: (1) require the use of grant funds under the community-oriented policing services program to train and provide security details for prosecutors and judges, including their immediate families, involved in cases that raise substantial concerns of retaliation or intimidation through violent acts; and (2) allow grants under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program to fund prosecutorial and judicial security details and programs. Amends the federal criminal code to make it unlawful to: (1) kill, or attempt or conspire to kill, a U.S. judge, a federal law enforcement officer, or a federally funded public safety officer engaged in official duties or a former U.S. judge, federal law enforcement officer, or federal funded public safety officer on account of past performance of official duties; or (2) travel in interstate commerce to avoid prosecution for such crimes. Expands criminal penalties for assaulting or interfering with law enforcement officers and employees. Permits judges, prosecutors, and law enforcement officials to carry firearms in federal facilities where such possession is otherwise authorized by law. Limits damages and costs in legal actions against a judicial officer by an individual injured during the commission of a felony or a crime of violence. Requires the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to ensure that each federal penal or correctional institution provides a secure firearms storage area for use by all employees who are authorized to carry a firearm.</summary>
</bill>
