<bill session="113" type="h" number="2911" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wireless Microphone Users Interference Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Federal Communications Commission to expand eligibility for part 74 licenses to certain wireless microphone users, to establish safe haven channels for wireless microphones, and to authorize access by owners and operators of wireless microphones to the TV bands databases for the purpose of protecting wireless microphone operations from interference.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400350"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2013-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2013-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
Wireless Microphone Users Interference Protection Act of 2013 - Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to expand eligibility for specified licenses authorizing the operation of low power auxiliary stations to the owners of, and operators of events and performances at: amusement parks, arenas, convention centers, educational facilities, houses of worship, lodging facilities, museums, outdoor venues, recording studios, and theaters. Requires the FCC to: (1) expand scope of service and permissible transmission regulations to include the use of wireless microphones in rehearsals and live or recorded events and performances by such licensees, and (2) establish two safe haven channels for exclusive use by wireless microphone users. Directs the FCC to authorize owners and operators of wireless microphones to have access to TV bands databases to protect wireless microphone operations from interference. (The purpose of the TV bands database is to provide unlicensed Television Band Devices [TVBDs] with the available TV channels at the TVBD's location and to register fixed TVBDs and other locations protected from interference that are not otherwise recorded in FCC licensing databases.) Permits restaurants, as well as the persons and entities made eligible for licenses by this Act, to be registered in such databases as sites where wireless microphone operations shall be protected from interference.</summary>
</bill>
