<bill session="111" type="h" number="4935" updated="2013-07-19T23:56:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PAL Extension Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To allow regional directors of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to extend temporarily the Provisional Accredited Levee period if a good faith effort to upgrade a levee to the accredited level is being made.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400405"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2010-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/2010--Introduced.
PAL Extension Act - Authorizes a regional director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to extend the Provisional Accredited Levee (PAL) period for up to 24 months from the date of the expiration of the original 24-month PAL period upon determining that the community, levee owner, or individual responsible for upgrading the levee has applied for a waiver and is making a good faith effort to complete the upgrade to the accredited level. Defines "good faith" to mean the responsible party provides evidence to the regional director that it: (1) has adequate funds available to upgrade the levee; and (2) has a contract with a qualified private contractor or an appropriate federal agency to verify the levee's certification. Requires FEMA to suspend any mapping activities in the area surrounding the levee during any extension period granted.</summary>
</bill>
