<bill session="110" type="s" number="316" updated="2013-07-19T22:23:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit brand name drug companies from compensating generic drug companies to delay the entry of a generic drug into the market.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2007-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-01-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S679"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S679-680" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-17">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-15">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Approved for reporting without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-02-27">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-02-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="59">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 59.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Antitrust, Competition Policy and Consumer Rights. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSJU01" subcommittee="Antitrust, Competition Policy and Consumer Rights" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1432"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Generic drugs"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Patent infringement"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act - Amends the Clayton Act to make it unlawful for a person, in connection with the sale of a drug product, to be a party to any agreement resolving or settling a patent infringement claim in which: (1) an abbreviated new drug (generic) application filer receives anything of value; and (2) such filer agrees not to research, develop, manufacture, market, or sell the generic product for any period. Excludes a resolution or settlement that includes no more than the right to market the generic product prior to the expiration of the patent. Amends the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 to set forth additional filing requirements related to agreements between a brand name drug company and a generic drug applicant. Requires the Chief Executive Officer or the company official responsible for negotiating any agreement to file a certification that materials filed with respect to such agreements: (1) are complete, final, and exclusive; (2) include any ancillary agreements that are contingent upon, provide a contingent condition for, or are otherwise related to, the agreement; and (3) include written descriptions of any relevant oral agreements, representations, commitments, or promises between the parties that have not been reduced to writing. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide that forfeiture of the 180-day exclusivity period for the marketing of a generic drug occurs if there is a final decision of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) or the court that an agreement has violated this Act. Requires the FTC to study the prevalence of anticompetitive agreements in the pharmaceutical industry and their impact. Requires the Attorney General or FTC to consider whether any additional enforcement action is necessary. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
