<bill session="109" type="h" number="5756" updated="2013-07-19T19:55:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Colorado Emergency Wildfire and Insect Infestations Response Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide additional authority to the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to implement hazardous fuel reduction projects in the State of Colorado in response to dangerous fuel levels and insect infestations in forested Federal land in Colorado, to extend the maximum duration of stewardship contracts carried out in Colorado, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the credit for electricity produced from biomass, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400020"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2006-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Resources, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Dairy, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2006--Introduced.
Colorado Emergency Wildfire and Insect Infestations Response Act of 2006 - Amends the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to prohibit the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior, for an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project that is proposed to be conducted on federal land in Colorado, from being required to study, develop, or describe any alternative to the proposed agency action in the environmental assessment or environmental impact statement. Amends the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 to permit longer terms for agreements and contracts for stewardship contracting projects in Colorado. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to expand the Fuels for Schools program to include Colorado. Authorizes such Secretary to make grants in a specified amount each fiscal year to carry out such program in Colorado. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend the placed in service date for the renewable electricity production credit for electricity produced by facilities using open-loop biomass to January 1, 2010. Makes electricity produced and sold from such facilities eligible for the full credit rate.</summary>
</bill>
