<bill session="111" type="hr" number="805" updated="2013-07-19T23:03:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Raising a question of the privileges of the House.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400068"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07T13:26:00-04:00">
      <text>QUESTION OF THE PRIVILEGES OF THE HOUSE - Mr. Carter rose to a question of the privileges of the House and offered a resolution. The Chair directed the Clerk to report the resolution. Upon examination of the resolution, the Chair determined that the resolution did constitute a question of the privileges of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07T13:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10540-10544" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H10542-10543" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07T13:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crowley moved to refer to Standards of Official Conduct.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07T13:27:00-04:00">
      <text>MOTION TO REFER PRIVILEGED RESOLUTION - Mr. Crowley moved to refer the privileged resolution to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct and the Chair recognized Mr. Crowley under the 1 hour rule. Subsequently, Mr. Crowley moved the previous question on the motion to refer and by voice vote, the Chair announced that the ayes prevailed. Mr. Carter demanded a recorded vote on ordering the previous question on the motion to refer.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07T13:45:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question on the motion to refer Agreed to by recorded vote: 243 - 156, 19 Present (Roll no. 758).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10543-10544" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07T13:53:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to refer Agreed to by recorded vote: 246 - 153, 19 Present (Roll No. 759).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/2009--Introduced.
Removes Representative Rangel as chairman of the Committee on Ways and Means pending completion of the investigation into his affairs by the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</summary>
</bill>
