<bill session="111" type="s" number="1930" updated="2013-07-20T00:41:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homebuyer Tax Credit Oversight and Accountability Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to enhance the administration of, and reduce fraud related to, the first-time homebuyer tax credit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3901"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/26/2009--Introduced.
Homebuyer Tax Credit Oversight and Accountability Act of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the first-time homebuyer tax credit, to: (1) deny such credit to taxpayers under the age of 18; (2) require taxpayers claiming such credit to attach to their returns a properly executed copy of the settlement statement used to purchase their residence and a certified statement of their eligibility for such credit from the real estate broker, settlement agent, or mortgage lender; and (3) prohibit a credit for residences acquired from a spouse. Requires the Commissioner of Internal Revenue to investigate, prosecute, and provide quarterly reports on instances of fraud related to the first-time homebuyer tax credit. Requires tax return preparers to file tax returns electronically unless they reasonably expect to file 100 or fewer individual income returns in a calendar year.</summary>
</bill>
