<bill session="113" type="h" number="1210" updated="2013-11-02T06:29:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mass Transit Intelligence Prioritization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to prioritize the assignment of officers and analysts to certain State and urban area fusion centers to enhance the security of mass transit systems.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412559" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412466" joined="2013-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM05" subcommittee="Counteterrorism and Intelligence" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2013--Introduced.
Mass Transit Intelligence Prioritization Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to make it a priority to assign DHS officers and intelligence analysts, including from the Transportation Security Administration (TSA), to participating state and urban area fusion centers located in high-risk jurisdictions with mass transit systems to enhance security of such systems by assisting law enforcement authorities in identifying, investigating, and otherwise interdicting persons, weapons, and contraband that pose a threat to homeland security. Makes it a primary responsibility of such officers and analysts to create mass transit intelligence products that: (1) assist law enforcement agencies in deploying their resources most efficiently to help detect and interdict terrorists, weapons of mass destruction, and contraband at U.S. mass transit systems; (2) promote more consistent and timely dissemination of mass transit security-relevant information among jurisdictions with such systems; and (3) enhance DHS's situational awareness with respect to the threat of terrorist acts at or involving U.S. mass transit systems.</summary>
</bill>
