<bill session="113" type="h" number="1412" updated="2013-11-02T06:30:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Job Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Improving Job Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Improving Job Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve and increase the availability of on-job training and apprenticeship programs carried out by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to extend certain expiring authorities affecting veterans and their families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 113-64.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-17T14:18:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="39">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 39.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-21T12:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-21T12:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2813-2815" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-21T12:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1412.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-21T12:48:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-21T14:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2830" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="164" datetime="2013-05-21T14:59:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 416 - 0 (Roll no. 164).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2813-2814" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-05-21T14:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-23">
      <text>Senate Committee on Veterans' Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6686-6687" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2013-09-23" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-09-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-27T09:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5888-5890" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-27T09:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on agreeing to the Senate amendments to H.R. 1412.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-27T09:20:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-27T10:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5894" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="pingpong" roll="491" datetime="2013-09-27T10:22:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 402 - 0 (Roll no. 491).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5888-5889" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-09-27T10:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2013-09-28">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2013-09-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-37" type="public" datetime="2013-09-30" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-37.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1216"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1964"/>
    <amendment number="s1965"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/30/2013--Public Law.
Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2013 - (Sec. 2) Authorizes specified appropriations for the period October 1-December 31, 2013, to pay a monthly assistance allowance to a veteran with a disability invited by the United States Olympic Committee (USOC) to compete for a slot on, or selected for, the Paralympic Team for any month in which the veteran is training or competing in any event sanctioned by the USOC, or who is residing at a USOC, training center. Extends for the same period the authorization for grants to USOC for an integrated adaptive sports program for disabled veterans and disabled members of the Armed Forces. Applies the same grant authorization, in the same manner and to the same degree as to the USOC, to: (1) the American Samoa National Olympic Committee, (2) the Guam National Olympic Committee, (3) the Comite Olimpico de Puerto Rico, and (4) appropriate entities representing the interests of the Northern Mariana Islands and the United States Virgin Islands. Extends through FY2014 a veteran's liability for copayments of $10 for every day the veteran receives hospital care and of $5 for every day he or she receives nursing home care. Extends through FY2014 the right of the United States to recover or collect from a third party reasonable charges for care or services for a non-service-connected disability of a veteran with a service-connected disability who is entitled to care (or payment of the expenses of care) under a health-plan contract. Extends through FY2014 the authority of the Secretary of Labor for homeless veterans reintegration programs, and of the same Secretary and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to contract for referral and counseling services for veterans at risk of homelessness who are transitioning from certain institutions. Extends through FY2015 the authorization of appropriations for comprehensive service programs for homeless veterans. Extends through FY2014 the availability of funds for: (1) financial assistance for supportive services for very low-income veteran families in permanent housing, and (2) the grant program for homeless veterans with special needs. Extends through FY2014 specially adapted housing assistance for a disabled veteran whose permanent and total service-connected disability causes difficulty with ambulating. Limits to 30 applications during FY2014 approval of such assistance for any such disabled veterans who served in the Armed Forces on or after September 11, 2001. Extends through FY2014 the authority to calculate, for liquidation purposes, the net value of real property securing a defaulted guaranteed housing or small business loan to a veteran. Amends the Caregivers and Veterans Omnibus Health Services Act of 2010 to extend through FY2014 the pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of providing assistance to veterans receiving regular or intensive mental health services and other intensive health care services in order to obtain child care while receiving such services. (Sec. 3) Amends part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) of title IV (Temporary Assistance to Needy families) (TANF) of the Social Security Act to revive for a specified 180-day period the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to furnish the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) with VA information for comparison with information in the National Directory of New Hires about individuals applying for or receiving needs-based veterans pension benefits, parents' dependency and indemnity compensation, veterans health care services, or compensation based on 100% unemployability. Authorizes for the same 180-day period the authority of the VA Secretary to terminate, deny, suspend, or reduce any of such veterans benefits or services, with respect to an applicant or recipient under age 65, by reason of information obtained from the HHS Secretary, but only if the VA Secretary takes appropriate steps to verify independently information relating to the individual's employment and employment income. (Sec. 4) Makes this Act effective on October 1, 2013, except for the authorization of appropriations for monthly assistance for disabled veterans invited to compete for a slot on, or selected for, the Paralympic Team, which shall be effective September 30, 2013. Deems ratified any VA actions undertaken before enactment of this Act under the authorities extended by this Act, if this Act is not enacted on or before September 30, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
