<bill session="109" type="h" number="2572" updated="2013-07-19T19:26:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reservist Health Care Continuity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require that employers of members of the National Guard and Reserve who are called to active duty continue to offer health care coverage for dependents of such members, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2005--Introduced.
Reservist Health Care Continuity Act - Requires employers to continue health care coverage for National Guard and reserve personnel called to active duty (and their dependents) for the lesser of: (1) an 18-month period or the day after the person fails to return to such employment, in the case of an employer with 20 or fewer employees; or (2) the period of such absence or the day after the person fails to return to such employment, in the case of an employer with more than 20 employees. Requires the Secretary of Defense to reimburse employers for the employer share of any premiums for such health care coverage for each month during such military service.</summary>
</bill>
