<bill session="111" type="h" number="4732" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Compassionate Access Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to create a new conditional approval system for drugs, biological products, and devices that is responsive to the needs of seriously ill patients, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400423"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2010-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2010-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2010-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2010-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2010--Introduced.
Compassionate Access Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to permit an investigational drug, biological product, or device to be made available for expanded access under a treatment investigational new drug application or treatment investigational device exemption if specified Compassionate Investigational Access requirements are met. Gives immunity to the manufacturer, distributor, administrator, sponsor, or physician from suit or liability relating to products approved under this Act. Establishes a procedure for accelerated approval of an investigational drug, biological product, or device that is reasonably likely to predict clinical benefit to a patient suffering from a serious or life-threatening condition. Requires the Secretary to establish: (1) the Accelerated Approval Advisory Committee; (2) a new program to expand access to investigational treatments for individuals with serious or life threatening conditions and diseases; and (3) a demonstration project under the Medicare program to pay for drugs, biological, products, and devices approved under this Act. Requires the Secretary to consider the clinical judgment and risks to the patient from the disease or condition in evaluating the safety and effectiveness of drugs, biological products, and devices that treat serious or life-threatening diseases or conditions, including the evaluation of nonstatistical information.Requires any committee evaluating investigational drugs, devices, or biological product applications to have at least two patient representatives as voting members.</summary>
</bill>
