<bill session="111" type="h" number="5847" updated="2013-07-20T00:05:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Child Protection Training Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to establish grant programs for the development and implementation of model undergraduate and graduate curricula on child abuse and neglect at institutions of higher education throughout the United States and to assist States in developing forensic interview training programs, to establish regional training centers and other resources for State and local child protection professionals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412214"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2010-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3437"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2010--Introduced.
National Child Protection Training Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to enter into an agreement with the National Child Protection Training Center to establish and sustain Regional Training Centers in the midwestern, northeastern, southern, and western regions of this country. Requires the Regional Training Centers to: (1) provide child protection professionals in the field with low-cost, high-quality training, technical assistance, and publications; (2) provide child protection professionals with ongoing training and assistance in developing evidence-based community prevention programs; (3) develop model undergraduate and graduate curricula on child maltreatment and, upon the Secretary's approval, disseminate them to institutions of higher education (IHEs); and (4) assist states in developing and maintaining forensic interview training programs. Directs the National Child Protection Training Center to award grants to state and local governments and other nonprofit entities to: (1) assist state and local child protection professionals in developing statewide forensic interview training programs; or (2) expand forensic interview training programs to provide for additional, advanced forensic interview training courses. Directs the National Child Protection Training Center to award grants to state and local governments and other nonprofit entities to assist IHEs in implementing or expanding model undergraduate or graduate curricula on child abuse and neglect.</summary>
</bill>
