<bill session="112" type="s" number="3505" updated="2013-07-20T02:47:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Afghanistan Contractor Accountability Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure the efficient use of taxpayer dollars in construction-related contracts for reconstruction efforts in Afghanistan by requiring reporting to Congress by Federal agencies that refuse to implement, or only partially concur with, SIGAR recommendations to seek reimbursement for failure by a contractor or subcontractor to successfully complete a contract due to poor contractor performance, cost overruns, or other reasons.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
Afghanistan Contractor Accountability Act of 2012 - Requires the head of an executive agency that fails to respond to a covered final audit report issued by the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, or that responds with a non-concur or partial concur response,&#160;to report to&#160;Congress with an explanation&#160;of the failure to respond or the non-concur or partial concur response.&#160; Defines "covered final audit report" as a final audit report issued by the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction that includes a recommendation for an executive agency to seek reimbursement for failure by a contractor or subcontractor to successfully complete a construction contract due to poor contractor performance, cost-overruns, or other reasons that would, if implemented, result in at least $500,000 in savings.</summary>
</bill>
