<bill session="112" type="s" number="1390" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tax Lien Simplification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to simplify, modernize, and improve public notice of and access to tax lien information by providing for a national, Internet accessible, filing system for Federal tax liens, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4722-4724"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2011--Introduced.
Tax Lien Simplification Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise procedures for the filing of federal tax liens. Direct the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) establish and maintain a federal tax lien registry, in lieu of filing tax liens in local jurisdictions, which would be accessible to and searchable by the public through the Internet at no cost; (2) take appropriate steps to secure and prevent tampering with the data recorded in the registry; and (3) review the information in the registry to determine whether information in the registry should be excluded or protected from public viewing. Establishes the priority of a federal tax lien based upon the date and time of the filing of a notice of lien in the federal tax lien registry. Reduces the period for releasing satisfied or unenforceable tax liens from 30 to 20 days.</summary>
</bill>
