<bill session="112" type="s" number="330" updated="2013-07-20T02:19:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Recall Protection Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit the sale of any product to a consumer that is subject to a recall, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2011--Introduced.
Consumer Recall Protection Act of 2011 - Prohibits a person from selling to consumers any covered product that is subject to a recall. Exempts from such prohibition the sale of a covered product that was subject to a recall because of a defect in such product if: (1) such defect was remedied prior to such sale; and (2) the seller of such product notifies such consumer of such recall, defect, and remedy. Defines a "covered product" to include a motor vehicle or replacement equipment, food, drugs, devices, cosmetics, a biological product, a consumer product, a meat or meat food product, a poultry or poultry product, and an egg or egg product. Defines "recall" for each type of covered product. Treats a violation of such prohibition as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice described under the Federal Trade Commission Act. Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to establish, maintain, and make available to the public a searchable list of covered products that are subject to a recall.</summary>
</bill>
