<bill session="113" type="h" number="601" updated="2013-11-02T06:24:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Permanent Repeal of Oil Subsidies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Deficit Reduction Through Fair Oil Royalties Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">End Big Oil Tax Subsidies Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">No Free Inspections for Oil Companies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">United States Exploration on Idle Tracts Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">USE IT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish an annual production incentive fee with respect to Federal onshore and offshore lands that are subject to a lease for production of oil or natural gas under which production is not occurring, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412546" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2013-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="609"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2956"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2013--Introduced.
Permanent Repeal of Oil Subsidies Act - United States Exploration on Idle Tracts Act or USE IT Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) issue regulations establishing a graduated annual production incentive fee governing federal onshore and offshore lands subject to an oil or natural gas production lease but for which such production is not occurring, and (2) deposit the prescribed fee assessment into the general fund of the Treasury. Deficit Reduction Through Fair Oil Royalties Act - Prohibits the Secretary from issuing new oil or natural gas production leases in the Gulf of Mexico under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) to a person that does not renegotiate its existing leases in order to require royalty payments if oil and natural gas prices are greater than or equal to specified price thresholds. Authorizes the Secretary, in the case of multiple lessees, to implement a separate agreement modifying payment responsibilities (including such price thresholds) with any lessee that owns a lease share. Prescribes analogous requirements for lease transfers. Requires rentals or royalties received by the United States to be deposited in the Treasury for federal budget deficit reduction or, if there is no federal budget deficit, for reducing the federal debt. Directs the Secretary to agree to a lessee's request to amend any lease issued for any Central and Western Gulf of Mexico tract in the period of January 1, 1996, through November 28, 2000, to incorporate price thresholds applicable to royalty suspension requirements that are equal to or less than the price thresholds specified under OCSLA. No Free Inspections for Oil Companies Act - Amends the OCSLA to direct the Secretary to establish and collect nonrefundable facility inspection fees from operators of Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) facilities. Establishes in the Treasury the Ocean Energy Enforcement Fund as depository for such fees. Requires amounts collected by the Secretary to be credited as offsetting collections and to be made available for expenditure only for implementing inspections of OCS facilities (including mobile offshore drilling units) and for administration of the inspection program.</summary>
</bill>
