<bill session="113" type="s" number="1231" updated="2013-11-02T07:02:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Duplication Elimination Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Pay-As-You-Go-Act of 2010 to create an expedited procedure to enact recommendations of the Government Accountability Office for consolidation and elimination to reduce duplication.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412391"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2013-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="2506"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3218"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2013--Introduced.
Duplication Elimination Act of 2013 - Requires the President, within 90 days after publication of the annual Government Accountability Office (GAO) report on duplication, consolidation, and elimination of duplicative government programs, to send Congress a proposed joint resolution accompanied by a special message specifying: any recommendations outlined in the GAO report that are excluded from the proposed joint resolution; in detail why they were excluded; and the outlined GAO recommendations included in the proposed joint resolution. Limits the proposed joint resolution to one that: (1) makes legislative changes needed to carry out the recommendations contained in the GAO report for a year that the President did not exclude, and (2) requires that any savings attributable to the legislative changes be transferred to the General Fund of the Treasury and be used to reduce the deficit. Sets forth procedures for expedited congressional consideration of the proposed joint resolution.</summary>
</bill>
