<bill session="113" type="h" number="1945" updated="2013-11-02T06:35:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fostering Resilience to Terrorism Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend the Terrorism Risk Insurance Program of the Department of the Treasury for 10 years, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400402"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412502" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412532" joined="2013-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412559" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2013-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM08" subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="508"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2146"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2013--Introduced.
Fostering Resilience to Terrorism Act of 2013 - Amends the Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002 to revise the definition of an "act of terrorism" to mean any act that is certified as meeting the specified criteria for such an act by the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), in concurrence with the Secretary of the Treasury (currently, by the Secretary of the Treasury in concurrence with the Secretary of State). Extends the Terrorism Insurance Program until December 31, 2024 (under current law the Program expires on December 31, 2014). Requires reports in 2017, 2020, and 2030 on the findings of the President's Working Group on Financial Markets pursuant to an ongoing analysis regarding the long-term availability and affordability of insurance for terrorism risk. Directs the DHS Secretary to: (1) provide to insureds under the Program, through the Secretary of the Treasury, timely homeland security information, including terrorism risk information, at the appropriate classification level and information on best practices to foster resilience to a terrorist act; and (2) conduct research to determine the extent to which such insureds, particularly insureds in critical infrastructure sectors, incorporate such best practices information into their business operations.</summary>
</bill>
