<bill session="109" type="s" number="3537" updated="2013-07-19T20:44:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Mental Health Emergency Preparedness Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a national center for public mental health emergency preparedness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6157"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6157-6159" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2006--Introduced.
Public Mental Health Emergency Preparedness Act of 2006 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish the National Center for Public Mental Health Emergency Preparedness to address mental health concerns and coordinate and implement the development and delivery of mental health services in the event of bioterrorism or other public health emergency. Requires the Director of the Center to: (1) develop a mechanism to appoint a panel of experts for the Center; (2) convene a Training Curricula Working Group to review and approve training curricula for emergency health professionals; (3) develop a mechanism through which individuals trained through approved curricula return to their communities to recruit and train others and provide expertise to state and local government agencies; (4) coordinate the use of existing emergency registries established to track medical and mental health volunteers for use by the Secretary, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Governor of each state to recruit and deploy trained emergency health professionals; (5) establish and maintain a central clearinghouse of educational materials, guidelines, information, strategies, resources, and research on public mental health emergency preparedness and service delivery; (6) convene a Clearinghouse Working Group; (7) organize an annual national forum to address public mental health emergency preparedness and service delivery; and (8) convene an Assessment Working Group to evaluate the effectiveness of the Center's efforts and those across the federal government in building the nation's public mental health emergency preparedness and service delivery capacity.</summary>
</bill>
