<bill session="109" type="h" number="5511" updated="2013-07-19T19:53:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Enforcement of Foreign Judgments Amendment of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 28, United States Code, to ensure that the validity of foreign judgments against United States citizens is adjudicated in Federal courts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International claims"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2006--Introduced.
The Fair Enforcement of Foreign Judgments Amendment of 2006 - Amends the federal judicial code to grant the district court original and exclusive jurisdiction of any action to enforce a foreign judgment exceeding $75,000 (exclusive of interest and costs) against a citizen of the United States, where: (1) any plantiff is a citizen of a state different from any defendant; (2) any plaintiff is a foreign state or a citizen or subject of a foreign state and any defendant is a citizen of a state; or (3) any plaintiff is a citizen of a state and any defendant is a foreign state or a citizen or subject or a foreign state. Permits removal of such an action to a district court without regard to whether any defendant is a citizen of the state in which the action is brought. Allows such a removal by any defendant without the consent of all defendants.</summary>
</bill>
