<bill session="113" type="h" number="1947" updated="2013-11-02T06:35:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-20T13:55:00-04:00">FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-20T13:55:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Farm bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Agriculture Reform and Risk Management Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Reducing Regulatory Burdens Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the reform and continuation of agricultural and other programs of the Department of Agriculture through fiscal year 2018, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2013-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 36 - 10.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-29T17:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on 113-92, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-29">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs for a period ending not later than June 7, 2013 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(i) of rule X..</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-29">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than June 7, 2013 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(l) of rule X..</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07T11:46:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Foreign Affairs Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 10, 2013.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07T11:46:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 10, 2013.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-10T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Affairs discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-10T18:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 113-92, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-10T18:43:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="73">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 73.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12T15:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Agriculture, H. Rept. 113-92, Part III.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T19:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 266 Reported to House. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 1947 and provides for consideration of H.R. 1797 with one hour of debate and one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 266 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 266.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3721-3730" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 1947 and provides for consideration of H.R. 1797 with one hour of debate and one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 266 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Candice S. Miller to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1947.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1947 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T00:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 271 Reported to House. Resolution provides for consideration of amendments to H.R. 1947</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 271 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3787-3926" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Lucas asked unanimous consent that during further consideration of H.R. 1947 pursuant to H. Res. 271, amendment 55 printed in Part B of House Report 113-117 may be considered out of sequence. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T14:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McGovern Part B amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McGovern amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gibbs Part B amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271 and a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Herrera Beutler Part B amendment No. 55.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T15:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Foxx Part B amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T15:55:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Foxx amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Foxx demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T15:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ellison Part B amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T16:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Broun(GA) Part B amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T16:10:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Broun (GA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Broun (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Enyart Part B amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves (GA) Part B amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer Part B amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T16:29:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Blumenauer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T16:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer Part B amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T16:41:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Blumenauer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ben Ray Lujan Part B amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gardner Part B amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fortenberry Part B amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T17:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kaptur Part B amendment No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T17:08:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kaptur amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Kaptur demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T17:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Royce Part B amendment No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Royce amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Engel demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Chabot Part B amendment No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T17:45:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Chabot amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Chabot demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T17:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Titus Part B amendment No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brooks(Al) Part B amendment No. 18.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Brooks (AL) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Brooks (AL) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Castor Part B Amendment No. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grimm Part B amendment No. 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T19:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hudson Part B amendment No. 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conaway Part B amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T19:34:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Conaway amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Conaway demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T19:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Butterfield Part B amendment No. 25.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T19:42:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Butterfield amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Butterfield demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T19:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Marino Part B amendment No. 26.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T19:54:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Marino amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes prevailed. Mr. David Scott demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T19:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Chabot Part B amendment No. 27.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Black Part B amendment No. 28.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T20:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kaptur Part B amendment No. 29.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schweikert Part B amendment No. 30.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T20:21:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Schweikert amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes prevailed. Ms. Fudge demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T20:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tierney Part B amendment No. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T20:27:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tierney amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes prevailed. Mr. Tierney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T20:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Costa Part B amendment No. 33.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T20:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gingrey Part B amendment No. 34.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T20:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Palazzo Part B amendment No. 36.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T20:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis Part B amendment No. 37.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T21:05:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. King (IA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T21:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garamendi Part B amendment No. 38.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T21:15:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garamendi amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garamendi demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T21:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis Part B amendment No. 39.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T21:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Marino Part B amendment No. 41.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T21:30:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Marino amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Marino demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T21:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McClintock Part B amendment No. 43.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T21:41:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McClintock amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. McClintock demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T21:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gibson Part B amendment No. 44.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T21:55:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gibson amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gibson demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T21:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walorski Part B amendment No. 45.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T22:05:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Walorski amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Walorski demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T22:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Courtney Part B amendment No. 46.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T22:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Courtney amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Courtney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T22:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Kind Part B amendment No. 47.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T22:38:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kind amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Kind demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T22:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Carney Part B amendment No. 48.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T22:45:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Carney amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Carney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T22:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Radel Part B amendment No. 49.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T22:56:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Radel amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Radel demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T22:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Commitee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walberg Part B amendment No. 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T23:07:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Walberg amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Walberg demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T23:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Lucas Part B amendments en bloc.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T23:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Benishek Part B amendment No. 51.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T23:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bachus Part B amendment No. 52.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T23:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wittman Part B amendment No. 54.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T23:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crawford Part B amendment No. 56.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T23:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crawford Part B amendment No. 57.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T23:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Foxx Part B amendment No. 58.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T23:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lucas moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T23:51:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19T23:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1947 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T09:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3933-3968" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T09:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T09:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Pitts amendment No. 98.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T09:54:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pitts amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Pitts demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T09:54:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T11:20:00-04:00">
      <text>VACATING PROCEEDINGS - Mr. Conaway asked unanimous consent to withdraw the request for a recorded vote on amendment No. 23 to the end that the amendment stand rejected in accordance with the previous voice vote thereon. Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3947" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T11:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Goodlatte amendment No. 99.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T11:49:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Goodlatte amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Goodlatte demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T11:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fortenberry amendment No. 100.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Fortenberry amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Fortenberry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Huelskamp amendment No. 101.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T12:12:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Huelskamp amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Huelskamp demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T12:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 271, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Southerland amendment No. 102.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T12:29:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Southerland amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Southerland demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T13:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1947.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3965" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/19/2013 H3787-3850" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T13:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Brownley (CA) moved to recommit with instructions to Agriculture.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3965-3967" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3965-3966" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brownley (CA) motion to recommit with instructions to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to protect homeowners from the devastating effects of wildfires by authorizing such sums as necessary for the Secretary for wildfire suppression, personnel, and equipment. The Motion would also create jobs and support small businesses by: (1) increasing water, waste disposal, and wastewater facility grants by $10 million per year (up from $30 million to $40 million) and extending the program for 5 years; and (2) increasing rural business opportunity grants by $5 million per year (up from $15 million to $20 million) and extending the program for 5 years. Lastly, the Motion would restore the $8 million cut (funding the program at $35 million instead of $27 million in the base bill) to the emergency and imminent community water assistance</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T13:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3967" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T13:42:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 188 - 232 (Roll no. 285).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="286" datetime="2013-06-20T13:55:00-04:00" where="h" result="fail" state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Failed by recorded vote: 195 - 234 (Roll no. 286).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="266"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="271"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="228"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="686"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="935"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="979"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1287"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1298"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1589"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1606"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1607"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1611"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1720"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1894"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1929"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2401"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2642"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2642"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2776"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="463"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="677"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="801"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="956"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Chesapeake Bay"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Delta Regional Authority"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="General agriculture matters"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h176"/>
    <amendment number="h177"/>
    <amendment number="h178"/>
    <amendment number="h179"/>
    <amendment number="h180"/>
    <amendment number="h181"/>
    <amendment number="h182"/>
    <amendment number="h183"/>
    <amendment number="h184"/>
    <amendment number="h185"/>
    <amendment number="h186"/>
    <amendment number="h187"/>
    <amendment number="h188"/>
    <amendment number="h189"/>
    <amendment number="h190"/>
    <amendment number="h191"/>
    <amendment number="h192"/>
    <amendment number="h193"/>
    <amendment number="h194"/>
    <amendment number="h195"/>
    <amendment number="h196"/>
    <amendment number="h197"/>
    <amendment number="h198"/>
    <amendment number="h199"/>
    <amendment number="h200"/>
    <amendment number="h201"/>
    <amendment number="h202"/>
    <amendment number="h203"/>
    <amendment number="h204"/>
    <amendment number="h205"/>
    <amendment number="h206"/>
    <amendment number="h207"/>
    <amendment number="h208"/>
    <amendment number="h209"/>
    <amendment number="h210"/>
    <amendment number="h211"/>
    <amendment number="h212"/>
    <amendment number="h213"/>
    <amendment number="h214"/>
    <amendment number="h215"/>
    <amendment number="h216"/>
    <amendment number="h217"/>
    <amendment number="h218"/>
    <amendment number="h219"/>
    <amendment number="h220"/>
    <amendment number="h221"/>
    <amendment number="h222"/>
    <amendment number="h223"/>
    <amendment number="h224"/>
    <amendment number="h225"/>
    <amendment number="h226"/>
    <amendment number="h227"/>
    <amendment number="h228"/>
    <amendment number="h229"/>
    <amendment number="h230"/>
    <amendment number="h231"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/13/2013--Introduced.
Federal Agriculture Reform and and Risk Management Act of 2013 - Title I: Commodities - Subtitle A: Repeals and Reforms - Repeals, but continues for crop year 2013: (1) direct payments, (2) countercyclical payments, and (3) the average crop revenue election program (ACRE). Provides for crop years 2014-2018 either: (1) price loss coverage if a covered commodity's effective price is less than its reference price; or (2) alternative revenue loss coverage, as a permanent one-time election, if a covered commodity's county revenue is less than the county revenue loss coverage trigger. Subtitle B: Marketing Loans - Authorizes: (1) nonrecourse marketing assistance loans through crop year 2018, (2) loan deficiency payments through crop year 2018, (3) payments in lieu of loan deficiency payments for grazed acreage through crop year 2018, (4) programs for upland cotton and extra long staple cotton, (5) assistance for peanuts, and (6) recourse loans for high moisture feed grains and seed cotton through crop year 2018. Subtitle C: Sugar - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to make nonrecourse loans to processors of domestically grown sugarcane and domestically grown sugar beets through crop year 2018. Directs the Secretary to make sugarcane and sugar beet quantity estimates through crop year 2018 for: (1) human consumption, (2) carryover stocks, (3) carry-in stocks, (4) domestic processing, and (5) imports. Subtitle D: Dairy - Establishes a dairy production margin protection program under which participating dairy operations are paid: (1) basic production margin protection program payments when production margins are less than threshold levels, and (2) supplemental production margin protection program payments if purchased by a participating dairy operation. Provides for program retroactivity. Establishes a dairy market stabilization program to assist in balancing the supply of milk with demand when participating dairy operations are experiencing low or negative operating margins. Terminates the production margin protection and stabilization programs on December 31, 2018. Repeals: (1) the dairy products price support program, (2) the milk income loss contract program, and (3) the dairy export incentive program. Extends: (1) the dairy indemnity program, (2) the dairy forward pricing program, and (3) the dairy promotion and research program. Makes the provisions of this subtitle effective on October 1, 2013. Subtitle E: Supplemental Agricultural Disaster Assistance Programs - Provides livestock indemnity payments through FY2018 to eligible producers on farms that have incurred excess livestock death losses due to: (1) attacks by animals reintroduced into the wild by the federal government or protected by federal law, or (2) adverse weather. Provides compensation through FY2018 to eligible livestock producers for grazing losses caused by drought or fire. Provides emergency assistance through FY2018 to eligible producers of livestock, honey bees, and farm-raised fish to aid in the reduction of losses due to disease or adverse weather. Provides assistance through FY2018 to eligible orchardists and nursery tree growers that planted trees for commercial purposes but lost the trees as a result of a natural disaster, and to eligible orchardists and nursery tree growers that have a production history for commercial purposes on planted or existing trees but lost the trees as a result of a natural disaster. Subtitle F: Administration - Directs the Secretary to use Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) funds, facilities, and authorities to carry out this title. Suspends permanent price support authority under the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 and the Agricultural Act of 1949 for covered commodities, cotton, and sugar through crop year 2018, and for milk through December 31, 2017. Revises specified payment limitation provisions. Prohibits a person or legal entity from receiving specified agricultural benefits during a crop, fiscal, or program year if the average adjusted gross income of such person or entity exceeds $950,000. Extends specified direct reimbursement payments for geographically disadvantaged farmers and ranchers through FY2018. Directs the Secretary to preclude the issuance of agricultural payments to, and on behalf of, deceased individuals that were not eligible for payments. Makes $100 million available to the Farm Service Agency to carry out this title. Title II: Conservation - Subtitle A: Conservation Reserve Program - Extends the conservation reserve program (CRP) and the farmable wetland program through FY2018. Sets forth maximum CRP acreage enrollments for FY2014- FY2018. Subtitle B: Conservation Stewardship Program - Revises, and extends through FY2018, the conservation stewardship program. Limits aggregate payments to a person or entity to $200,000 during FY2013-FY2017. Subtitle C: Environmental Quality Incentives Program - Extends the environmental quality incentives program through FY2018. Requires that 60% of FY2014-FY2018 program funds be used for livestock production practices, and that 5% of such funds be used for wildlife habitat practices. Provides payments for wildlife habitat development. Applies program limitations to the period FY2014-FY2018. Subtitle D: Agricultural Conservation Easement Program - Establishes the agricultural conservation easement program for the conservation of eligible land and natural resources through easements or other interests in land. (Combines the purposes and coordinates the functions of the wetlands reserve program, the grassland reserve program, and the farmland protection program.) Sets forth agricultural land and wetland easement provisions. Makes the provisions of this subtitle effective on October 1, 2013. Subtitle E: Regional Conservation Partnership Program - Establishes a regional conservation partnership program to: (1) accomplish purposes similar to the agricultural water enhancement program, the Chesapeake Bay watershed program, the cooperative conservation partnership initiative, and the Great Lakes basin program; (2) further the conservation use of natural resources on a regional or watershed scale; and (3) encourage partners to cooperate with producers in meeting or avoiding the need for regulatory requirements related to production on eligible land and implementing projects that affect multiple agricultural or nonindustrial private forest operations on a local, state, or regional basis. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into a partnership agreement for up to 5 years, with a one-time extension for up to 12 months. Provides program funding for FY2014-FY2018. Makes the provisions of this subtitle effective on October 1, 2013. Subtitle F: Other Conservation Programs - Authorizes appropriations through FY2018 for: (1) the conservation of private grazing land program, (2) the grass roots source water protection program, (3) the voluntary public access and habitat incentive program, and (4) the small watershed rehabilitation program. Subtitle G: Funding and Administration - Authorizes the use of Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) funds through FY2018 for: (1) the conservation reserve program, including specified amounts for transferring contract land from retiring owners and operators to beginning and disadvantaged farmers and ranchers; (2) the agricultural conservation easement program; (3) the conservation security program; (4) the conservation stewardship program; and (5) the environmental quality incentives program. Makes such provisions effective on October 1, 2013. Subtitle H: Repeal of Superseded Program Authorities and Transitional Provisions; Technical Amendments - Repeals: (1) the conservation enhancement program, (2) the emergency forestry conservation reserve program, (3) the wetlands reserve program, (4) the farmland protection program, (5) the grassland reserve program, (6) the agricultural water enhancement program, (7) the wildlife habitat incentive program, (8) the Great Lakes Basin program, (9) the Chesapeake Bay watershed program, (10) the cooperative conservation partnership initiative, and (11) the environmental easement program. Title III: Trade - Subtitle A: Food for Peace Act - Extends specified programs and authorizations of appropriations under the Food for Peace Act through FY2018. Subtitle B: Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 - Extends through FY2018: (1) export credit guarantee programs, (2) the market access program, and (3) the foreign market cooperator program. Subtitle C: Other Agricultural Trade Laws - Extends through FY2018: (1) the food for progress program, (2) the Bill Emerson humanitarian trust, (3) the McGovern-Dole international food for education and child nutrition program, (4) technical assistance for specialty crops, and (5) the Global Crop Diversity Trust. Authorizes the Secretary to establish the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Foreign Agricultural Services. Title IV: Nutrition - Subtitle A: Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program - Extends the supplemental nutrition assistance program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program) through FY2018. Revises program provisions, including provisions regarding: (1) participant eligibility, (2) retail stores, (3) services to the elderly and disabled, (4) utility allowances, (5) lottery or gambling ineligibility, (6) food assistance security, (7) mobile transactions, (8) restaurant meals, (9) data exchange standardization, (10) employment and training programs, (11) exclusion of medical marijuana from the excess medical expense deduction, (12) limitations on fund use to Puerto Rico, (13) funding for retailer trafficking, (14) nutrition education, and (15) the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands. Extends through FY2018: (1) the food distribution program on Indian reservations, and (2) commodity purchases for emergency food assistance. Subtitle B: Commodity Distribution Programs - Extends through FY2018: (1) the commodity distribution program, (2) the commodity supplemental food program, and (3) the distribution of surplus commodities to special nutrition projects program. Subtitle C: Miscellaneous - Extends funding for the senior farmers' market nutrition program through FY2018. Repeals the nutrition information and awareness pilot program. Establishes a pilot grant program for the purchase of fresh fruit and vegetables. Title V: Credit - Subtitle A: Farm Ownership Loans - Allows: (1) additional legal entities to qualify for farm ownership loans, and (2) other acceptable experiences to qualify for the three-year farming eligibility requirement for direct loans. Authorizes appropriations through FY2018 for the conservation loan and loan guarantee program. Increases maximum down payment loan program amounts. Subtitle B: Operating Loans - Allows additional legal entities to qualify for farm operating loans. Authorizes the Secretary to waive the personal liability of a youth borrower if a loan default was due to circumstances beyond the borrower's control. Authorizes a micro loan program for direct or guaranteed loans (maximum micro loan of $35,000 with a total micro loan indebtedness of $70,000 per borrower). Subtitle C: Emergency Loans - Allows additional legal entities to qualify for emergency loans. Subtitle D: Administrative Provisions - Extends the beginning farmer and rancher individual development accounts pilot program through FY2018. Subtitle E: State Agricultural Mediation Programs - Extends state agricultural mediation programs through FY2018. Subtitle F: Loans to Purchasers of Highly Fractionated Land - Amends the loan and loan guarantee program for Indian tribes and tribal corporations to purchase highly fractioned land within the reservation to permit loans to intermediaries to establish revolving loan funds for such purchases. Title VI: Rural Development - Subtitle A: Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act - Extends through FY2018: (1) water, waste disposal, and wastewater facility grants; (2) rural business opportunity grants; (3) funding for the federal share of developing tribal college or university essential community facilities; (4) emergency and imminent community water assistance grants; (5) grants to nonprofit organizations for water well system servicing for low- and moderate income households; (6) rural cooperative development grants; (7) loans to enterprises that process, store, and market locally or regionally produced agricultural food products; (8) the intermediary relending program to finance rural business facilities and community development projects; (9) grants for the federal share of acquiring radio transmitters to increase rural coverage by the weather radio broadcast system of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA); (10) the rural micro enterprise assistance program; (11) the Delta Regional Authority; (12) the Northern Great Plains Regional Authority; and (13) the rural business investment program. Authorizes appropriations for the rural water and wastewater circuit rider program. Subtitle B: Rural Electrification Act of 1936 - Extends through FY2018: (1) guarantee authority for rural electrification or telephone bonds and notes, (2) expansion of 911 access, and (3) loan guarantees for rural broadband telecommunications infrastructure. Gives loan priority to applicants that offer to provide broadband service to the greatest proportion of households that had no incumbent service provider. Subtitle C: Miscellaneous - Extends through FY2018	: (1) the distance learning and telemedicine program, (2) value-added agricultural producer grants, and (3) the agriculture innovation center demonstration program. Title VII: Research, Extension, and Related Matters - Subtitle A: National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 - Extends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board until September 30, 2018. Establishes a veterinary services grant program. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes appropriations through FY2018 for: (1) agricultural and food policy research centers. Repeals: (1) the human nutrition intervention and health promotion research program, (2) appropriations for research on national or regional problems, (3) the pilot research program to combine medical and agricultural research, (4) research equipment grants, and (5) the national and regional animal health and disease research program. Extends through FY2018: (1) grants and fellowships for food and agricultural sciences education, (2) the nutrition education program, (3) animal heath and disease research programs, (4) grants to upgrade agricultural and food sciences facilities at 1890 land-grant colleges and at land grant colleges in insular areas, (5) grants for Hispanic-serving institutions, (6) grants for international agricultural science and education, (7) assistance for extension programs, (8) assistance for university agricultural research, (9) assistance for supplemental and alternative crops, (10) aquaculture assistance programs, (11) rangeland research programs, and (12) biosecurity planning. Establishes a grant program for training Hispanic agricultural workers and youth in the food and agricultural sciences. Authorizes appropriations through FY2018 for distance education and resident instruction at insular-area institutions of higher education. Requires the recipient of a competitive grant that involves applied research or extension and that is commodity- or state-specific to provide matching funds or in-kind contributions. Authorizes appropriations through FY2018 to carry out this subtitle. Subtitle B: Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 - Extends through FY2018 programs and assistance under the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977. Repeals: (1) the national agricultural weather information system, (2) the agricultural genome initiative, (3) the electronic commerce extension program, (4) the nutrient management research and extension initiative, and (5) the agricultural bioenergy feedstock and energy efficiency research and extension initiative. Extends through FY2018: (1) integrated management systems, (2) Extension Service agent training, (3) sustainable agriculture technology, (4) organic agriculture research, (5) farm business management, (6) assistive technology for farmers with disabilities, (7) the national rural information center clearinghouse, (8) high-priority research and extension initiatives, and (9) the genetics resources program. Subtitle C: Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 - Extends through FY2018: (1) integrated management systems programs; (2) research regarding diseases of wheat, triticale, and barley caused by Fusarium graminearum or by Tilletia indica; (3) grants for youth organizations; (4) the specialty crop research initiative; (5) the food animal residue avoidance database program; and (6) the Office of Pest Management Policy. Repeals: (1) the program to improve the viability of small and medium dairy, livestock, and poultry operations; (2) Johne's (livestock) disease control program; and (3) the national swine research center. Subtitle D: Other Laws - Extends through FY2018 programs and assistance under: (1) the Critical Agricultural Materials Act, (2) the Research Facilities Act, (3) the Renewable Resources Extension Act of 1978, and (4) the National Aquaculture Act of 1980. Revises "1994 Institutions" (Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994) provisions. Extends the beginning farmer and rancher development program through FY2018. Makes beginning farmers and ranchers who are veterans eligible for program set-asides. Extends coverage under the McIntire-Stennis Cooperative Forestry Act to the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands. Subtitle E: Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 - Extends through FY2018: (1) the Agricultural Biosecurity Communication Center, (2) research and development of agricultural countermeasures, (3) training for agricultural biosecurity planning and response for food science professionals and veterinarians, and (4) the agricultural biosecurity grant program. Extends the period prohibiting federal land and facilities at El Reno, Oklahoma, from being declared to be surplus federal property or otherwise be conveyed. Revises budget submission and funding provisions. Extends through FY2018: (1) the natural products research program, and (2) the sun grant program. Repeals: (1) the antibiotic-resistant bacteria research grant program, (2) the farm and ranch stress assistance network, (3) the seed distribution program, and (4) the rural transportation research program. Subtitle F: Miscellaneous Provisions - Authorizes the Secretary to negotiate concession agreements at the National Arboretum with nonprofit organizations that support the Arboretum. Authorizes a non-federal entity to construct, at no cost to the government, a facility for use by the Agricultural Research Service on land owned by the Agricultural Research Service and managed by the Secretary. (Directs the Secretary to accept the completed facility as a gift.) Title VIII: Forestry - Subtitle A: Repeal of Certain Forestry Programs - Repeals: (1) the forest land enhancement program, (2) the watershed forestry assistance program, (3) the Hispanic-serving institution agricultural land leadership program, and (4) the tribal watershed forestry assistance program. Subtitle B: Reauthorization of Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 Programs - Extends the forest legacy program and the community forest and open space conservation program through FY2018. Subtitle C: Reauthorization of Other Forestry-Related Laws - Extends the rural revitalization technologies program and the Office of International Forestry through FY2018. Subtitle D: National Forest Critical Area Response - Directs the Secretary to designate critical areas within the National Forest System to address: (1) deteriorating forest health conditions due to insect infestation, drought, disease, or storm damage; and (2) the future risk of insect infestations or disease outbreaks through preventative treatments. Allows the use of expedited environmental, administrative, and judicial procedures to be used for such areas. Subtitle E: Miscellaneous Provisions - Directs the Secretary to revise the forest inventory strategic plan. Title IX: Energy - Extends through FY2018: (1) the biobased marketing program, (2) biorefinery assistance, (3) the bioenergy program for advanced biofuels, (4) the biodiesel fuel education program, (5) the repowering assistance program to reduce or eliminate biorefinery fossil fuel use, (6) the rural energy for America program, (7) biomass research and development, (8) the feedstock flexibility program for bioenergy producers, (9) the biomass crop assistance program, and (10) the community wood energy program. Title X: Horticulture - Extends through FY2018: (1) the specialty crop market news program, (2) the farmers market and local food promotion program, (3) organic production and market initiatives, (4) food safety initiatives, and (5) specialty crop block grants. Repeals the specialty crop movement-to-market program. Sets forth investigatory and enforcement provisions under the Organic Foods Production Act of 1990. Exempts the bulk bin shipment of apples to Canada from specified Apple Export Act requirements. Subjects imported olive oil to U.S. grade, size, and quality controls. Repeals the coordinated plant management program and establishes the national clean plant network for diagnostic and pathogen elimination services to: (1) produce clean propagative plant material, and (2) maintain blocks of pathogen-tested plant material in sites throughout the United States. Makes funding available through FY2018. Reducing Regulatory Burdens Act of 2013 - Prohibits, with specified exceptions, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) or a state from requiring a permit under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act for a discharge from a point source into navigable waters of a pesticide authorized for sale, distribution, or use under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act. Title XI: Crop Insurance - Makes available to crop producers a supplemental coverage option (based on area yield and loss) to cover part of a crop insurance policy deductible. Triggers such option only if area losses exceed 10% of normal levels. Provides for: (1) 65% premium coverage by the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation (FCIC), and (2) coverage to begin no later than crop year 2014. Makes permanent the pilot program under which FCIC pays a portion of the premiums for insurance plans or policies for which the insurable unit is defined as a whole farm or enterprise unit. Makes separate enterprise units available for irrigated and non-irrigated acreages of crops beginning with crop year 2014. Revises the adjustment in actual production history used to establish insurable yields. Requires FCIC to: (1) review any policy or pilot program to carry out research and development for new crop insurance policies, and submit it to the Board of Directors if it will likely result in a marketable policy and improved coverage; and (2) make an additional annual reimbursement through reinsurance year 2015 to insurance companies selling specialty crop policies. Provides crop insurance premiums at 50 percentage points less than the otherwise applicable subsidy for the first four crop years of planting on native sod acreage in the Prairie Pothole National Priority Area. Defines "beginning farmer or rancher" as a farmer or rancher who has not actively operated and managed a farm or ranch with a bona fide insurable interest in a crop or livestock as an owner-operator, landlord, tenant, or sharecropper for more than five crop years. Requires FCIC, beginning not later than the 2014 upland cotton crop, to make available to producers of maximum eligible acres of upland cotton an additional policy (the Stacked Income Protection Plan). States that Plan coverage shall be in addition to all other coverages available to upland cotton producers. Requires FCIC and the Risk Management Agency, beginning with the 2014 crop, to make available a revenue crop insurance program for peanuts based on a price equal to the Rotterdam price index for peanuts, as adjusted to reflect the farmer stock price of peanuts in the United States. Directs the Secretary to: (1) maintain and upgrade FCIC information management systems used in the administration and enforcement of this title, (2) implement an acreage reporting streamlining initiative to permit producers to report acreage and other information directly to USDA. Requires FCIC to: (1) contract for research and development for insuring producers of freshwater-reared catfish against reduction in the margin between market value and selected production costs; (2) contract to determine the feasibility of insuring commercial poultry production against business disruptions caused by integrator bankruptcy, and for a study to determine the feasibility of insuring poultry producers for a catastrophic event; (3) contract for research and development of insuring biomass and sweet sorghum grown to produce feedstocks for renewable biofuel, renewable electricity, or biobased products; (4) contract for a feasibility study of insuring swine producers for a catastrophic event; and (5) develop a whole farm risk management insurance plan (with liability of up to $1 million). Title XII: Miscellaneous - Subtitle A: Livestock - Extends through FY2018: (1) the national aquatic animal health plan, (2) the trichinae certification program, and (3) the National Sheep Industry Improvement Center. Directs the Secretary, through the Office of the Chief Economist, to conduct an economic analysis of the USDA's proposed rule "Mandatory Country of Origin Labeling of Beef, Pork, Lamb, Chicken, Goat Meat, Wild and Farm-raised Fish and Shellfish, Perishable Agricultural Commodities, Peanuts, Pecans, Ginseng and Macadamia Nuts." Directs the Secretary to enter into contracts, grants, and cooperative agreements with eligible laboratories to: (1) enhance USDA's capability to detect and respond to animal health threats and to support the protection of public health, the environment, and the agricultural economy; (2) coordinate enhancement of national veterinary diagnostic laboratory capabilities; and (3) provide for standardized laboratory biosafety and biosecurity levels. Authorizes appropriations through FY2018. Subtitle B: Socially Disadvantaged Producers and Limited Resource Producers - Provides funding through FY2018 for: (1) outreach and assistance to socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers (including veteran farmers and ranchers in the program), and (2) the Office of Advocacy and Outreach. Subtitle C: Other Miscellaneous Provisions - Provides funding through FY2018 for grants to improve the supply, stability, safety, and training of the agricultural labor force. Establishes: (1) an Office of Tribal Relations within the Office of the Secretary; and (2) a USDA position of Military Veterans Agricultural Liaison to provide information to returning military veterans on beginning farmer training, agricultural vocational and rehabilitation programs. Provides coverages based on individual yields (other than for value-loss crops) under the noninsured crop disaster assistance program equivalent to: (1) catastrophic risk protection, or (2) specified additional coverage. Reduces the premium for additional coverage by 50% for limited resource, beginning, and socially disadvantaged farmers. Requires each federal agency to have guidelines in effect for ensuring the quality of scientific information by January 1, 2014.</summary>
</bill>
