<bill session="110" type="s" number="2471" updated="2013-07-19T22:42:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">USERRA Enforcement Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the enforcement of the Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act of 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-12-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15463-15464"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2007--Introduced.
USERRA Enforcement Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends provisions concerning uniformed services members' employment or reemployment rights or benefits to: (1) require complainants to be notified of their rights within five days after receipt of the complaint by the Secretary of Labor; (2) require investigation and resolution of complaints to be completed no later than 90 days after receipt of the complaint; and (3) impose a 15-day deadline on referral to the Attorney General or to the Office of Special Counsel of an unsuccessful effort to resolve a complaint against a state or private employer or a federal executive agency, respectively. Requires the Attorney General or the Special Counsel, as appropriate, to make a decision and provide notification concerning representation of a complainant within 45 days of a referral.Modifies requirements for annual case reporting by the Secretary to include data of the National Committee for Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve and data concerning those with disabilities.Requires the Comptroller General to make quarterly reports on claims processing.Requires the Secretary to ensure that: (1) report information is categorized in a uniform way; and (2) the Secretary and the Secretaries of Defense and Veterans Affairs, the Attorney General, and the Special Counsel each have electronic access to case files reviewed under the uniformed services employment and reemployment rights provisions.</summary>
</bill>
