<bill session="111" type="h" number="4206" updated="2013-07-19T23:50:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Haiti Reforestation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to provide assistance to the Government of Haiti to end within 5 years the deforestation in Haiti and restore within 30 years the extent of tropical forest cover in existence in Haiti in 1990, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1183"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2009--Introduced.
Haiti Reforestation Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to offer to enter into agreements with the government of Haiti to provide financial assistance, technology transfers, or capacity building assistance to reduce deforestation and increase reforestation in Haiti. Directs the Secretary to establish a grant program to carry out such activities. Amends the the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to: (1) direct the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to invite the government of Haiti to submit a list of areas in which tropical forests are seriously degraded or threatened; and (2) authorize USAID to make grants to nongovernmental organizations to purchase discounted commercial debt of the government of Haiti in exchange for government commitments to restore identified forests or to develop plans for their sustainable use.</summary>
</bill>
