<bill session="110" type="s" number="918" updated="2013-07-19T22:28:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Railroad Safety Accountability and Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize appropriations for activities under the Federal railroad safety laws for fiscal years 2008 through 2011, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="1516"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1516"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Radio"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad equipment"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2007--Introduced.
Federal Railroad Safety Accountability and Improvement Act - Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2011 for the railroad safety program, including a safety risk reduction program to be implemented as part of such program. Eliminates the authority of the Secretary of Transportation (or state Secretary) to prescribe investigative and surveillance activities to enforce rail safety regulations and orders.Prohibits public disclosure of railroad safety risk reduction program records.Requires railroad carriers and states to report to the Secretary, and update periodically, unreported highway-rail (including non-vehicular pathway-rail) grade crossings and public highway-rail (including non-vehicular public pathway) grade crossings within the United States.Urges the development of new technology to prevent loss of life and injuries at highway-rail grade crossings.Sets forth requirements: (1) prohibiting the judicial review of railroad safety regulations or orders on the ground that they impact security; (2) authorizing the Secretary to waive compliance of such regulations and orders if there is an emergency event, it is in the public interest, and consistent with railroad safety; (3) authorizing the Secretary to monitor railroad radio communications to prevent rail accidents, or as part of an accident investigation; (4) authorizing the Secretary to prohibit individuals who have violated hazardous material transportation safety laws from performing safety-sensitive functions in the railroad industry until specified conditions are met; (5) repealing and reserving codified federal hours of service laws, requiring the conversion of such laws to regulations, and authorizing the Secretary to amend such regulations to prevent and mitigate fatigue in individuals performing safety-critical train related duties; (6) establishing maximum number of hours a train employee may be on duty; and (7) authorizing the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration and designated employees access to criminal history records of railroad employees.</summary>
</bill>
