<bill session="113" type="h" number="3237" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GARDS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Guard Appropriation Restoration During Shutdown Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Pay Our Military Act to provide funds for the operations of the National Guard.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412392"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3210"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3232"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2013--Introduced.
Guard Appropriation Restoration During Shutdown Act or the GARDS Act - Amends the Pay Our Military Act (P.L. 113-39) to make FY2014 continuing appropriations for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for FY2014 are not in effect to provide for: (1) members of the National Guard who perform inactive-duty training or other service for which members would otherwise be entitled to pay and allowances (under such Act only members of the Armed Forces, including reserve components, who perform active service); and (2) civilian personnel of the National Guard, including military technicians (dual status), without regard to any determination by the Secretary of Defense (DOD) or the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) that such personnel are providing support to members of the Armed Forces performing active service. Makes appropriations for FY2014, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for FY2014 are not in effect, such sums as are necessary to provide for the operation and maintenance of the National Guard, including necessary sums to prevent any interruption or delay in the performance by the National Guard of domestic disaster relief and recovery operations.</summary>
</bill>
