<bill session="113" type="h" number="2040" updated="2013-11-02T06:36:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Financial Aid Simplification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To simplify the process for determining the need and eligibility of students for financial assistance under the Higher Education Act of 1965, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412239"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/2013--Introduced.
Student Financial Aid Simplification Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to determine students' need and eligibility for title IV assistance, unless they qualify for the simplified needs test or expect no family contribution, by using tax return information regarding those students or their parents that this Act authorizes the Secretary of Education to obtain from the Internal Revenue Service (IRS). Requires those students to submit to the Secretary certain supplementary information not available from the IRS. Requires the Secretary to provide institutions of higher education and states with that tax return information, without charge, for the purposes of processing loan applications and determining need and eligibility for institutional and state financial aid. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to disclose tax return information to the Department of Education regarding taxpayers or their dependents whose need and eligibility for assistance under title IV of the HEA is based in whole or part on their income or their parents' income.</summary>
</bill>
