<bill session="111" type="h" number="5167" updated="2013-07-19T23:58:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">School Meals Stigma Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to reduce stigma associated with unpaid meal fees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412215"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2010--Introduced.
School Meals Stigma Reduction Act - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to allow local educational agencies (LEAs) to revise previously submitted meal claims to approve children retroactively for up to 90 days for free or reduced price meals under the school lunch program. Requires children who are eligible for free meals under the school lunch or breakfast programs to be provided the meal that is provided on any given day, regardless of unpaid fees. Requires children who are eligible for reduced price meals under the school lunch or breakfast programs to be provided the meal that is provided on any given day, as long as the child pays the reduced-price meal fee that day, regardless of unpaid fees. Directs LEAs that wish to implement a substitute meal policy for children with unpaid school meal fees to ensure that it doesn't stigmatize the children. Requires LEAs to directly certify children who owe at least a week of meal fees as eligible for free meals or provide their households with the materials and encouragement to apply for such meals. Prohibits LEAs attempting to collect unpaid school meal fees from a household from taking any action directed at the household's child or using a debt collector.</summary>
</bill>
