<bill session="110" type="s" number="1999" updated="2013-07-19T22:37:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the establishment of a Center of Excellence in Prevention, Diagnosis, Mitigation, Treatment, and Rehabilitation of Military Eye Injuries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3558"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Brain"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Eye care"/>
    <term name="Eye diseases"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Head injuries"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Surgery"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2007--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) to establish within the Department of Defense (DOD) the Center of Excellence in Prevention, Diagnosis, Mitigation, Treatment, and Rehabilitation of Military Eye Injuries to: (1) develop, implement, and oversee a registry for tracking the diagnosis, treatment, and follow-up for each case of eye injury incurred by a member of the Armed Forces in combat that requires surgery or other operative intervention; and (2) ensure the electronic exchange of registry information with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs. Requires the Secretary to: (1) include in the registry records of members who incurred eye injuries in combat in Operations Iraqi Freedom or Enduring Freedom before the registry's establishment; and (2) report to Congress on the Center's establishment. Directs the Secretary and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to conduct a cooperative study on neuro-optometric screening and diagnosis of members with traumatic brain injury (TBI) by military medical treatment facilities and VA medical centers for purposes of vision screening, diagnosis, rehabilitative management, and vision research on visual dysfunction related to TBI.</summary>
</bill>
