<bill session="113" type="h" number="599" updated="2013-11-02T06:24:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Arms Sale Responsibility Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the transfer of defense articles and defense services to the governments of foreign countries that are engaging in gross violations of internationally-recognized human rights, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2013-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="479"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2013--Introduced.
Arms Sale Responsibility Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress that it should be U.S. policy to adhere to a policy of restraint in transferring conventional arms if evidence exists of substantial risk that such arms will be used to commit or facilitate serious violations of international human rights law or international humanitarian law. Urges the President, in negotiating any conventional arms control agreement, to: (1) encourage the national control list of each party to an agreement to cover all types of weaponry, munitions, armaments and related material used for potentially lethal force in military and law enforcement operations; (2) assess each application or proposal to export or internationally transfer arms on a case-by-case basis; (3) deny an arms transfer authorization if there is a substantial risk that the arms will be used to commit or facilitate violations of international human rights law or international humanitarian law; (4) require import and transit state authorizations and certified end use assurances before issuing an export license or authorization for any international transfer of conventional arms; and (6) require each party to an agreement to establish a legal framework for lawful brokering and shipping activities relating to conventional arms transfers. Prohibits, with certain exemptions, the transfer of defense articles or defense services to the government of a foreign country under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 or the Arms Export Control Act unless the President certifies to Congress that such government is not: (1) engaging in gross violations of internationally-recognized human rights, and (2) identified by the Secretary of State as having governmental armed forces or government supported armed groups that recruit or use child soldiers.</summary>
</bill>
