<bill session="111" type="h" number="3658" updated="2013-07-19T23:45:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical corrections to subtitle A of title VII of the Consolidated Natural Resources Act of 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412312"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3770"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2009--Introduced.
Prohibits, subject to an existing provision, an alien who on May 8, 2008, was a resident of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands (CNMI) from being removed from the United States on the grounds of illegal presence in the CNMI prior to the date that is five years after the transition program effective date if such alien is lawfully present in the CNMI on such date and is: (1) a permanent resident of the CNMI; (2) an immediate relative of a citizen; or (3) the parent of a citizen who was under 21 years old. Makes such an alien parent eligible for a special nonimmigrant visa. Specifies conditions for such visa, including the requirement that the parent reside in the CNMI. Makes an alien who, as of May 8, 2008, was subject to CNMI immigration regulations eligible for a special nonimmigrant visa. Provides that such visa shall: (1) grant the alien all the privileges of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence except that the alien must reside in the CNMI; and (2) be valid until the earlier of the date on which the alien adjusts to permanent resident status or the date on which the alien ceases to reside in the CNMI. Makes an alien who, as of May 8, 2008, was subject to CNMI immigration regulations eligible for adjustment to permanent resident status if such alien applies for adjustment between January 1, 2014-November 28, 2014. Extends the effective date of the CNMI visitor entry program for 180 days. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to administer the program during such 180-day period consistent with CNMI provisions governing the program that were in effect prior to the commencement of such period. Amends the Consolidated Natural Resources Act of 2008 to: (1) direct the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of DHS to reduce the fees for family-based immigration benefit applications and petitions collected from CNMI residents who had immediate relative status pursuant to CNMI immigration laws as of May 8, 2008; and (2) waive related sponsor income requirements.</summary>
</bill>
