<bill session="112" type="s" number="901" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Making Public Lands Public Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to ensure that amounts are made available for projects to provide recreational public access, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1997"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2011--Introduced.
Making Public Lands Public Access Act - Amends the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to ensure, from amounts requested for the Land and Water Conservation Fund per fiscal year, that not less than the greater of 1.5% of the requested amounts or $10 million be made available for certain projects identified on an annual priority list to be developed pursuant to this Act. Requires projects identified on such a list to secure, through rights-of-way or the acquisition of lands or interests from willing sellers, recreational public access to existing federal public lands that have significantly restricted access to hunting, fishing, and other recreational purposes.</summary>
</bill>
