<bill session="111" type="h" number="2405" updated="2013-07-19T23:33:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Richard Helm Veterans' Access to Local Health Care Options and Resources Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide veterans enrolled in the health system of the Department of Veterans Affairs the option of receiving covered health services through facilities other than those of the Department.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400234"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2009-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2009--Introduced.
Richard Helm Veterans' Access to Local Health Care Options and Resources Act - Allows a veteran enrolled in the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) annual patient enrollment system to elect to receive covered health services through a non-VA facility. (Under current law, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may contract for such services when VA facilities are not capable of furnishing economic hospital care or medical services because of geographical inaccessibility or are not capable of furnishing the care or services required.) Directs the Secretary to authorize such services pursuant to a contract with such facility. Authorizes the Secretary to furnish to veterans through a VA health care facility drugs and medicines ordered on prescription of a duly licensed private physician under contract with the VA.</summary>
</bill>
