<bill session="112" type="h" number="3605" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Online Freedom Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent United States businesses from cooperating with repressive governments in transforming the Internet into a tool of censorship and surveillance, to fulfill the responsibility of the United States Government to promote freedom of expression on the Internet, to restore public confidence in the integrity of United States businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2012-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2011-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2249-2250"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-03-27">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-10-19">
      <text>Committee on Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe. Joint hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="JCSE" name="Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe (Helsinki Commission)" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2011--Introduced.
Global Online Freedom Act of 2011 - Makes it U.S. policy to: (1) promote the freedom to seek, receive, and impart information and ideas through any media; (2) use all appropriate instruments of U.S. influence to support the free flow of information without interference or discrimination; and (3) deter U.S. businesses from cooperating with Internet-restricting countries in effecting online censorship. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the President should seek international agreements to protect Internet freedom; and (2) some U.S. businesses, in assisting foreign governments to restrict online access to U.S.-supported websites and government reports and to identify individual Internet users, are working contrary to U.S. foreign policy interests. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to require assessments of electronic information freedom in each foreign country. Directs the Secretary of State to annually designate Internet-restricting countries. Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require each Internet communications services company that operates in an Internet-restricting country to include in its annual report information relating to: (1) human rights due diligence, (2) policies pertaining to the collection of personally identifiable information, and (3) restrictions on Internet search engines or content hosting services. Amends the Export Administration Act of 1979, as continued in effect under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, to direct the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) establish a list of goods and technology that would assist a foreign government in acquiring the capability to carry out censorship, surveillance, or any other related activity through means of telecommunications, including the Internet; and (2) prohibit the export of listed goods or technology to a government end user in any Internet-restricting country.</summary>
</bill>
