<bill session="109" type="h" number="1982" updated="2013-07-19T19:21:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Welcome Home G.I. Bill Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles 10 and 38, United States Code, to increase benefits for members of the Armed Forces who, after September 11, 2001, serve on active duty outside the United States or its territories or possessions as part of a contingency operation (including a humanitarian operation, peacekeeping operation, or similar operation) or a combat operation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400120"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2005-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1028"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1019"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2005--Introduced.
Welcome Home G.I. Bill Act of 2005 - Increases and extends the duration of basic educational assistance for individuals who serve at least six consecutive months (with exceptions from the six consecutive months requirement due to medical, hardship, or involuntary separation ) on active duty outside the United States as part of a combat or contingency operation (including a humanitarian or peacekeeping operation) beginning on September 11, 2001, and ending five years after enactment of this Act. Permits assistance use for student loan repayment. Provides for refund of educational contributions made under the Montgomery G.I. Bill program. Increases and extends the duration of educational assistance for reserve component members called or ordered to active service in response to a war or national emergency who perform active duty service for 180 consecutive days before the five-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act. Permits assistance use for student loan repayment. Provides $5,000 for a residential purchase downpayment for a veteran who: (1) performs active duty service outside the United States as part of a combat or contingency operation (including a humanitarian or peacekeeping operation) for at least six consecutive months (or a lesser time period for an individual with a service-connected disability) after September 11, 2001; and (2) has not previously obtained a veterans' guaranteed or insured housing loan. Makes such benefit available for five years from the date eligible service is completed. Amends the the Internal Revenue Code to exclude such housing benefit from gross income. Provides transitional health care benefits during the five-year period after separation from active duty for an individual who is not covered under an employer-provided or a spouse's employer-provided group health plan who: (1) serves in the active military, naval, or air service; (2) after September 11, 2001, is deployed outside the United States as part of a combat or contingency operation (including a humanitarian or peacekeeping operation) for at least six consecutive months (or a lesser time period for an individual with a service-connected disability); and (3) is discharged or released under conditions other than dishonorable. Revises predeployment and postdeployment medical exam provisions.</summary>
</bill>
