<bill session="113" type="hr" number="361" updated="2013-11-02T06:18:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-28T13:45:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-09-28T13:45:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules, and relating to consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 2642) to provide for the reform and continuation of agricultural and other programs of the Department of Agriculture through fiscal year 2018, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-26T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-231, by Mr. Sessions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-26T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution waives clause 6(a) of rule XIII against resolutions reported from the Rules Committee relating to: 1) A measure making continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2014. 2) A measure relating to the public debt limit. The resolution also provides that the House concurs in the Senate amendment to H.R. 2642 with an amendment consisting of the text of H.R. 2642, as passed by the House, modified by the insertion of a new title IV consisting of the text of H.R. 3102, as passed by the House.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-26T19:10:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="56">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 56.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28T12:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5938-5946" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28T12:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 361.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5945" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="493" datetime="2013-09-28T13:45:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 191 (Roll no. 493).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5938" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28T13:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2642"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2642"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2013--Reported to House without amendment.
Waives a specified requirement of Rule XIII (Calendar and Committee Reports) to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to any resolution reported through the legislative day of September 30, 2013, relating to measures making continuing FY2014 appropriations or to the public debt limit. Concurs in the Senate amendment to H.R. 2642 (agricultural and other programs of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) through FY2018) with an amendment substituting the text of H.R. 2642, as passed by the House, modified by the insertion of the text of H.R. 3102, as passed by the House.</summary>
</bill>
