<bill session="109" type="hr" number="437" updated="2013-07-19T18:58:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-15T17:05:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-15T17:05:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Select Bipartisan Committee to Investigate the Preparation for and Response to Hurricane Katrina.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Rules"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-09-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 9 - 4.</text>
      <committee name="House Rules"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14T21:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Rules. H. Rept. 109-220, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14T21:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on House Administration discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-09-14T21:16:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="84">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 84.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14T21:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 439 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 437 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 439 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 439.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8022-8031" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 437 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 439, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 437.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8031" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the resolution, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Dreier objected to the voice vote based upon the absence of a quorum and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of H. Res. 437 until later in the legislative day. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15T16:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8056-8057" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-09-15T17:05:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="475" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 188 (Roll no. 475).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8022" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15T17:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="439"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
    <term name="State-local relations"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2005--Passed House without amendment.
Establishes the Select Bipartisan Committee to Investigate the Preparation for and Response to Hurricane Katrina to conduct a full investigation, study, and report to the House on: (1) the development, coordination, and execution by local, state, and federal authorities of emergency response plans and other activities in preparation for Hurricane Katrina; and (2) the actual local, state, and federal government response to the Hurricane. Directs the chairman of the select committee to consult with the chairman of a Senate committee conducting a parallel investigation and study about meeting jointly to receive testimony, the scheduling of hearings or issuance of subpoenas, and joint staff interviews of key witnesses.</summary>
</bill>
