<bill session="111" type="h" number="4063" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To grant the Congressional Gold Medal to the members of the messman and steward branches of United States Navy, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard that served during World War II.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412263"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2009-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2009-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2010-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-07">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-07">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/7/2009--Introduced.
Directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate to award a single Congressional gold medal in honor of the steward and messman branches of the Navy, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard that served during World War II in recognition of their personal sacrifice and service to their country. Requires, after presentation, that the medal be given to the Smithsonian Institution. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal, depositing receipts in the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</summary>
</bill>
