<bill session="109" type="s" number="1114" updated="2013-07-19T20:23:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Professional Athletes Drug Testing bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Sports Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish minimum drug testing standards for major professional sports leagues.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2005-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5855"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-525.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2516"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2565"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Baseball"/>
    <term name="Basketball"/>
    <term name="Boxing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="College sports"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Designer drugs"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and athletes"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Football"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hockey"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Steroids"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2005--Introduced.
Clean Sports Act of 2005 - Prohibits a major professional league from arranging, promoting, organizing, or producing a professional game without meeting the requirements established by this Act for testing for the use of prohibited substances by professional athletes and for public disclosure of the names of athletes who test positive. Requires a suspension of an athlete for a minimum of two years for the first violation and a lifetime ban for the second violation. Allows a league to impose a lesser penalty if the athlete: (1) establishes that he did not know or suspect, and could not reasonably have known or suspected even with the exercise of utmost caution, that he had used the prohibited substance; or (2) provides substantial assistance to the league in identifying violations of the league's drug testing policy by other athletes or by any personnel working with or treating athletes. Authorizes the Director of National Control Policy to modify standards for a league under exceptional circumstances or for good cause with limitations. Require the Director to include additional professional sporting leagues or colleges if such additions would prevent the use of such substances by high school, college, or professional athletes. Treats violations of this Act as unfair or deceptive acts or practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act. Requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to study the use of performance-enhancing substances by college athletes. Requires the Director to establish a commission on high school and college athletics.</summary>
</bill>
