<bill session="109" type="h" number="785" updated="2013-07-19T19:11:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cargo Theft Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To coordinate cargo theft crime data collection and to amend title 18, United States Code, to make improvements relating to cargo theft prevention, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400328" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2005-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1854"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Containerization"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2005--Introduced.
Cargo Theft Prevention Act - Directs the Attorney General to issue regulations to: (1) permit the reporting of cargo theft to the Attorney General by a carrier, facility, or cargo owner promptly after its discovery, to include information on the shipment's origin and destination, the commodities stolen, and the time and location of the theft; (2) create a database to contain the reports and integrate them with non-criminal justice and intelligence data; (3) prescribe procedures for database access by government agencies and privacy protection; and (4) share the results and analysis with appropriate agencies. Requires Federal agencies with significant regulatory or law enforcement responsibilities over cargo theft, as designated by the Attorney General, to modify their databases to ensure the collection and retrievability of data relating to crime and terrorism and related activities affecting cargo transportation. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) establish an outreach program to work with State and local law enforcement officials to harmonize the reporting of data on cargo theft; and (2) disseminate cargo theft information to appropriate law enforcement officials. Limits disclosure of reports and data under the Freedom of Information Act. Expands the scope of prohibitions against: (1) interstate or foreign shipments by carrier to include trailers and air cargo containers; and (2) the transportation and sale of stolen vehicles to include vessels.</summary>
</bill>
