<bill session="113" type="h" number="2438" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Designating Requirements On Notification of Executive-ordered Strikes Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DRONES Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require an adequate process in preplanned lethal operations that deliberately target citizens of the United States or citizens of strategic treaty allies of the United States, to limit the use of cluster munitions generally, including when likely to unintentionally harm such citizens, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2013-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Intelligence (Permanent Select), and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="881"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="419"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2013--Introduced.
Designating Requirements On Notification of Executive-ordered Strikes Act of 2013 or the DRONES Act - Prohibits a federal department or agency or the Armed Forces from deliberately targeting a citizen of the United States or of a strategic treaty ally in a pre-planned lethal operation unless such operation is planned and executed pursuant to a written determination signed personally by the President: (1) confirming the status of the targeted citizen as an enemy combatant, and (2) authorizing the deliberate lethal targeting based on an articulated need for the use of lethal force. Requires the President, within 30 days after making such a determination, to submit a report to specified congressional committees: (1) certifying that the timing and details of the operation were approved personally by the President, and (2) detailing the information used to determine that the targeted citizen is an enemy combatant and the reasons why lethal force was necessary. Prohibits this Act from being construed to authorize such lethal targeting of&#160;such a citizen inside any location under U.S. jurisdiction. Prohibits the President, the head of any federal agency, or a general officer or flag officer of the Armed Forces from authorizing the use of cluster munitions: (1) unless the sub-munitions of such munitions, after arming, will not result in more than 1% unexploded ordnance across the range of intended operational environments and the policy applicable to the use of such munitions requires that they will only be used against clearly defined military targets and will not be used in locations where civilian noncombatants are known to be present or in areas normally inhabited by civilian noncombatants; or (2) if such use is reasonably likely to unintentionally harm any citizen of the United States or of a strategic treaty ally (i.e., when any such citizen is known to be within a two-mile radius of the area to be targeted). Authorizes the President to waive such limitations where vital to protect U.S. security. Requires congressional notification of such waiver. Directs the President, following the use of cluster munitions, to submit a plan for cleaning up any such munitions and sub-munitions that fail to explode. Prohibits such officials from providing cluster munitions to a foreign nation, agency or armed force unless: (1) such munitions will be used in a combined military operation with the United States, and (2) the use of such munitions complies with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
