<bill session="112" type="h" number="3851" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Advocate Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act with respect to Offices of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2012-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412486" joined="2012-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412423" joined="2012-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412424" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412413" joined="2012-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 11 - 7.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21T15:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 112-721, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21T15:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Oversight and Government discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-12-21T15:45:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="524">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 524.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3442"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3572"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2012--Introduced.
Small Business Advocate Act of 2012 - Amends the Small Business Act (the Act) to require the Director of the Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization (established in each federal agency having procurement powers) to be compensated at least at the GS-15 rate and allows such position to be compensated at up to a Senior Executive Service level. Includes as additional duties of each Director: (1) reviewing and advising on decisions to convert an activity performed by a small business to an activity performed by a federal employee; (2) providing advice and comments on acquisition strategies, market research, and justifications related to small business; (3) providing training to small businesses and contract specialists; (4) carrying out exclusively the duties enumerated under the Act and, while Director, not holding any other title, position, or responsibility, except as necessary to carry out such duties; and (5) reporting annually to the congressional small business committees on the provision of small business and contract specialist training. Amends the Federal Acquisition Streamlining Act of 1994 to require the Small Business Procurement Advisory Council to: (1) conduct reviews of each Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization to determine compliance with Small Business Administration (SBA) requirements, (2) identify best practices for maximizing small business utilization in federal contracting, and (3) report annually to the small business committees on such reviews and best practices.</summary>
</bill>
