<bill session="111" type="s" number="2790" updated="2013-07-20T00:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pandemic Protection for Workers, Families, and Businesses Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to allow Americans to receive paid sick time so that they can address their own health needs, and the health needs of their families, related to a contagious illness.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2009-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="4092"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2009--Introduced.
Pandemic Protection for Workers, Families, and Businesses Act - Requires certain covered employers to provide annually to each of their covered: (1) full-time employees at least seven days of paid sick time, and specified employment benefits; and (2) part-time employees the same employment benefits and a number of days or hours of paid sick time, determined under a specified pro rata formula. Allows the covered employee to use such sick time for an absence: (1) resulting from a medical condition involving symptoms of a contagious illness (including influenza-like illnesses such as the 2009 H1N1 virus), the need to obtain medical diagnosis or care, or to obtain preventive care for such illness; (2) due to determination by a health authority or a health care provider that the employee's presence on the job, after exposure to a contagious illness, would jeopardize the health of others; (3) to care for a child experiencing such symptoms; or (4) to care for a child due to determination by a health authority or a health care provider that the child's presence in the community, after exposure to a contagious illness, would jeopardize the health of others. Permits use of sick leave if the covered employee's place of business is closed due to a contagious illness or his or her need to care for a child whose school or child care or early childhood program has been closed for such reason. Specifies prohibited acts by an employer, and penalties for violations.</summary>
</bill>
