<bill session="110" type="h" number="6877" updated="2013-07-19T22:03:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Greenhouse Gas Registry Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the creation of a Federal greenhouse gas registry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2008-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fluorocarbons"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2008--Introduced.
Greenhouse Gas Registry Act - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) determine the quantity of each greenhouse gas that makes the same contribution to global warming as one metric ton of carbon dioxide; and (2) designate as a greenhouse gas any directly emitted anthropogenic gas that is included in the Inventory of the United States Greenhouse Gases and Sinks, one metric ton of which makes the same or greater contribution to global warming as one metric ton of carbon dioxide. Directs each covered entity to report to the Administrator its greenhouse gas emissions for the prior calendar year.Directs the Administrator to issue regulations establishing a federal greenhouse gas registry. Specifies that such regulations shall: (1) ensure accuracy and reliability of data submitted; (2) take into account best practices for measuring greenhouse gas emissions and the latest scientific research; (3) require that submitted data are monitored using monitoring systems for fuel use, fuel flow, or emissions, wherever feasible; (4) require annual reporting on the emission of greenhouse gases; (5) establish consistent policies for calculating carbon content and greenhouse gas emissions for each type of fossil fuel reported; (6) provide for immediate public dissemination of data reported, with certain exceptions; and (7) take into account the work done by the Climate Registry and other mandatory state or multistate authorized programs and explain the major differences in approach between the system established under the regulations and the respective registries or programs. Provides that nothing in this Act preempts any state or regional greenhouse gas registry efforts.Authorizes the Administrator to bring a civil action against any entity that fails to comply with the requirements of this Act. Sets forth civil penalties for violations.</summary>
</bill>
