<bill session="109" type="hr" number="224" updated="2013-07-19T18:56:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-27T13:15:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-04-27T13:15:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the expenses of certain committees of the House of Representatives in the One Hundred Ninth Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400293"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-04-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-04-26T19:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 109-54.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-04-26T19:51:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="25">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 25.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-04-27T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ney moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-27T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2573-2576" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-27T12:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 224.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-04-27T13:15:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2573" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-04-27T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="House Administration"/>
    <term name="House Agriculture"/>
    <term name="House Armed Services"/>
    <term name="House Budget"/>
    <term name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <term name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <term name="House Financial Services"/>
    <term name="House Government Reform"/>
    <term name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="House Intelligence"/>
    <term name="House International Relations"/>
    <term name="House Judiciary"/>
    <term name="House Resources"/>
    <term name="House Rules"/>
    <term name="House Science"/>
    <term name="House Small Business"/>
    <term name="House Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <term name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2005--Passed House amended.
Makes amounts available for expenses, including staff salaries, of the following committees of the House of Representatives in the 109th Congress: (1) Agriculture; (2) Armed Services; (3) Budget; (4) Education and the Workforce; (5) Energy and Commerce; (6) Financial Services; (7) Government Reform; (8) Homeland Security; (9) House Administration; (10) Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence; (11) International Relations; (12) Judiciary; (13) Resources; (14) Rules; (15) Science; (16) Small Business; (17) Standards of Official Conduct; (18) Transportation and Infrastructure; (19) Veterans' Affairs; and (20) Ways and Means. Sets forth first and second session limitations on such amounts. Prohibits such amounts from being used by a committee for the production of material for a mass mailing unless: (1) the mailing is of a press release to the communications media, a notice of the schedule of a hearing or markup of the committee (limited to specified content), a committee document printed pursuant to Federal public printing and documents requirements, or a request for the views of the public or the views of other authorities of government essential to the conduct of the study, investigation, or oversight of matters within the jurisdiction and related functions assigned to the committee under rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives;(2) before mailing, the chairman or ranking minority member of the committee (as the case may be) submits a sample of the material to the House Commission on Congressional Mailing Standards and the Commission determines that: (1) the mailing is ordinary and necessary to the conduct of the normal and regular business of the committee and is in compliance with Federal postal law requirements, if mailed by a Member of the House; (2) it would not be prohibited under such law, if mailed by such a Member; and (3) the aggregate amount that will be spent in franking costs by the committee for mass mailings during the session involved, after taking into account the franking costs of such mass mailing, will not exceed $5,000.</summary>
</bill>
