<bill session="112" type="s" number="3707" updated="2013-07-20T02:48:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Utility Employee Background Check Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize utilities to obtain national criminal history background checks of certain employees in sensitive positions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2012--Introduced.
Utility Employee Background Check Act of 2012 - Requires the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to establish procedures for regional entities or users, owners, or operators of the bulk-power system under the Federal Power Act, owners and operators of a facility licensed pursuant to and covered by the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, and owners and operators of a chemical facility subject to the Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Standards to obtain national criminal history background checks, including a search of the Interstate Identification Index of the National Crime Information Centers, for employees who have access to the most sensitive areas of operation. Authorizes the Director to collect fees for such checks. Amends the Federal Power Act to direct the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to order the Electric Reliability Organization to submit a proposed reliability standard that would require each such regional entity or user, owner, or operator of the bulk-power system to obtain a background check for every such employee. Amends the Atomic Energy Act to direct the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to require each such licensed facility to obtain a background check for every such employee. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to require each such chemical facility to obtain a background check for every such employee.</summary>
</bill>
