<bill session="112" type="h" number="2789" updated="2013-07-20T01:34:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prevention of Wasteful and Unneeded Coins Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 31, United States Code, to suspend the issuance of $1 coins for a 15-year period, or until excess stockpiles are exhausted, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412430"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412395" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412482" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2011-10-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic Monetary Policy and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Presidential administrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2011--Introduced.
Prevention of Wasteful and Unneeded Coins Act of 2011 - Amends federal law governing coins and currency to prohibit, for a 15-year period, the issuance of $1 dollar coins honoring each of the Presidents of the United States. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to resume issuance of such coins if the demand for $1 coins exceeds the number of them held in reserve. Prohibits the Secretary from issuing any $1 coins if it would result in an excess stockpile of $1 coins not in circulation. Repeals the requirement that the number of $1 coins minted and issued in a year with the Sacagawea design on the obverse be at least 20% of the total of such coins. Repeals the requirement that, during an introductory period, all institutions that want to are able to obtain unmixed supplies of each newly-issued design of $1 coins minted under the President $1 and the First Spouse bullion coin programs.</summary>
</bill>
