<bill session="112" type="h" number="4212" updated="2013-07-20T01:46:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Contaminated Drywall Safety Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Drywall Safety Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Drywall Safety Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Drywall Safety Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate drywall manufactured in China a banned hazardous product, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To prevent the introduction into commerce of unsafe drywall, to ensure the manufacturer of drywall is readily identifiable, to ensure that problematic drywall removed from homes is not reused, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412483"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400038" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412196" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412485" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2012-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412415" joined="2012-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2012-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412413" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2012-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2012-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T20:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Bono Mack moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T20:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6134-6137" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T20:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4212.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-09-19T20:49:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6134-6135" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T20:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T20:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8377-8378" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2012-12-21" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-12-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-30T17:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Terry moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7448-7450" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-30T17:14:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 4212.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-30T17:27:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Ms. Hochul objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-01T19:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7530-7531" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2013-01-01T19:14:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="657" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 378 - 37 (Roll no. 657).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/30/2012 H7448-7449" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-01-01T19:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2013-01-14">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2013-01-14" type="public" number="112-266">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-266.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA18" subcommittee="Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3432"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>1/14/2013--Public Law.
Drywall Safety Act of 2012 - (Sec. 2) Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Commerce should insist that: (1) the government of China, which has ownership interests in the companies that manufactured and exported problematic drywall to the United States, facilitate a meeting between the companies and U.S. government representatives about remedying affected homeowners; and (2) such companies comply with any related U.S. court decisions. (Sec. 3) Requires certain gypsum board labeling standards of ASTM International (formerly known as the American Society for Testing and Materials), as in effect on the day before the enactment of this Act, to be treated as a rule promulgated by the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC). Provides procedures for: (1) ASTM International to notify the CPSC of any subsequent revision of such standards; and (2) the revised standards to become effective unless the CPSC, within a specified period, determines that the revisions do not adequately identify gypsum board by manufacturer and month and year of manufacture. (Sec. 4) Requires the CPSC to promulgate a final rule concerning drywall manufactured or imported for domestic use that limits sulfur content to a level not associated with elevated rates of corrosion in the home. Provides exceptions, and means of enforcement as a rule, if the CPSC determines that a voluntary standard (developed by a specified Subcommittee on Specifications and Test Methods for Gypsum Products of ASTM International) is adequate to permit identification and publishes the determination in the Federal Register. Provides procedures for revision of such voluntary standards. Allows the CPSC, at any time subsequent to publication of such a rule, to initiate a rulemaking to modify the sulfur content limit or include a provision relating only to drywall composition or characteristics that the CPSC determines is reasonably necessary to protect public health or safety. (Sec. 5) Directs the CPSC to revise its "Remediation Guidance for Homes with Corrosion from Problem Drywall" to specify that problematic drywall removed pursuant to the guidance should not be reused or used as a component in production of new drywall.</summary>
</bill>
