<bill session="111" type="h" number="5407" updated="2013-07-20T00:01:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Program Reform Commission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Program Reform Commission to review and identify unnecessary Federal programs and make recommendations for termination, modification, or retention of such programs, and to express the sense of the Congress that the Congress should promptly consider legislation that would make the changes in law necessary to implement the recommendations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400379"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2010--Introduced.
Program Reform Commission Act - Establishes within the legislative branch an independent Program Reform Commission to: (1) identify federal programs that are no longer necessary or that merit modification; and (2) report to Congress with recommendations for termination, modification, or retention of such programs. Requires the head of each federal department or agency to include in budget documents submitted for FY2012 a list of programs that it determines are no longer necessary, together with a detailed description of each program in question and recommendations for appropriate action. Directs the Commission to conduct public hearings regarding, and to review, the termination, modification, or retention of all such programs. Expresses the sense of Congress that, following submission of the Commission's report, the House of Representatives and the Senate should promptly consider legislation to implement the Commission's recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
