<bill session="113" type="s" number="28" updated="2013-11-02T06:52:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Y Mountain Access Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Upper Y Mountain Trail and Y Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the conveyance of a small parcel of National Forest System land in the Uinta-Wasatch-Cache National Forest in Utah to Brigham Young University, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2013-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2013-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-28.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Wyden with amendments and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 113-92.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="170">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 170.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="253"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="253"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/2013--Reported to Senate amended.
Upper Y Mountain Trail and Y Conveyance Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), upon request by Brigham Young University, to convey an approximately 80-acre parcel of National Forest System land in the Uinta-Wasatch-Cache National Forest in Utah. Requires the University to pay to the Secretary the fair market value of such land. Requires such consideration to be deposited in the general Treasury fund to reduce the federal deficit. Directs the University, after the conveyance, to: (1) continue allowing the same reasonable public access to the trailhead, and the part of the Y Mountain Trail already owned by the University, as has been historically allowed; and (2) allow such access to the part of the Trail and the "Y" symbol located on the conveyed land. Requires that the exact acreage and legal description of the land to be conveyed be determined by a survey that is satisfactory to the Secretary. Requires the University to pay the costs of the survey and appraisal and any administrative analyses required by law.</summary>
</bill>
