<bill session="110" type="h" number="3242" updated="2013-07-19T21:32:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening America's Innovation and Competitiveness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 and the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve the ability of the United States to be competitive in a global economy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400659"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2007-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2007--Introduced.
Strengthening America's Innovation and Competitiveness Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) and public or private entities to recruit and train individuals outside of the elementary and secondary education system who have expertise in core academic subjects, particularly mathematics, science, and critical foreign languages, to serve as adjunct secondary school teachers of such subjects. Revises the Advanced Placement Incentive grant program to: (1) require nonprofit grantees to partner with educational agencies; (2) give priority to applicants that increase mathematics, science, or critical foreign language programs or target rural schools; and (3) require grantees to cover two-thirds of program costs and provide salary incentives for AP mathematics, science, or critical foreign language teachers. Establishes Math Now programs awarding competitive grants to states, high-need LEAs, and rural educational service agencies to improve mathematics instruction for students in elementary and middle schools. Replaces the Robert C. Byrd Honors Scholarship program with the Robert C. Byrd Mathematics and Science Honors Scholarship program awarding funds to a private nonprofit organization to administer, through a public-private partnership, such program for postsecondary and graduate students who commit to five consecutive years of service in a science, engineering, or mathematics field. Authorizes the Secretary to cover the student loan interest obligations of mathematics, science, or engineering professionals and elementary and secondary school teachers who make such an obligation. Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary to award grants to institutions of higher education to establish, in partnership with LEAs, articulated programs of critical-need foreign language studies enabling successful students to advance from elementary school through college and achieve superior proficiency in such languages. Expresses the sense of the Congress that female students should be encouraged to participate in this Act's grant programs.</summary>
</bill>
