<bill session="109" type="h" number="4983" updated="2013-07-19T19:48:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">First Step to Redeployment Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To recognize the exemplary service of the National Guard in Iraq and to direct the President to begin the redeployment of United States military forces from Iraq, starting with National Guard units.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E397"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military civic action"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military withdrawal"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2006--Introduced.
First Step to Redeployment Act of 2006 - Expresses appreciation to members of the National Guard (Guard) and all other members of the Armed Forces for their service and commends their achievements and sacrifices, and the sacrifices of their families. Declares that there is no more capable soldier than the citizen-soldiers of the Guard. Reaffirms the critical role of the Guard in defending the United States, carrying out combat missions, responding to domestic emergencies and disasters, and securing the homeland. Recognizes the importance of the Guard in ensuring a connection between the military and local communities. Opposes any attempt to reduce the role of the Guard within the Total Force concept of the Armed Forces. Directs the President to begin the redeployment of U.S. Armed Forces from Iraq, starting with the orderly redeployment of Guard units.</summary>
</bill>
