<bill session="111" type="h" number="3457" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Credit Card Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to provide coverage under such Act for credit cards issued to small businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400177" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2009-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412298" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2009-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400302" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412304" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412313" joined="2009-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2009-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2009--Introduced.
Small Business Credit Card Act of 2009 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to cover any qualified small business as a consumer with respect to a credit card account under an open end credit plan (thereby extending credit card protections under such Act to small businesses). Defines "qualified small business" under the Act as any business concern having 50 or fewer employees, whether or not: (1) the credit card account is in the name of an individual or a business entity; and (2) any credit transaction involving such account is for business or personal purposes. Permits a qualified small business to elect to opt out of coverage by the Act. Exempts from coverage by the Act any credit transaction in which the total amount financed exceeds $50,000 (currently $25,000). Requires certain creditor disclosures before opening any account under an open end consumer credit plan for a qualified small business. Prohibits a creditor from: (1) discriminating against any business concern having 50 or fewer employees in connection with any credit card account under an open end credit plan; or (2) requiring any qualified small business to make an opt-out election as a condition for opening a credit card account, or for providing more advantageous terms for such an account.</summary>
</bill>
