<bill session="110" type="h" number="7081" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-10-08">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To approve the United States-India Agreement for Cooperation on Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400229" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2008-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T18:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Berman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T18:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10088-10103" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T18:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7081.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T19:40:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10223" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-09-27T16:44:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="662" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 298 - 117, 1 Present (Roll no. 662).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/26/2008 H10088-10090" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T16:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-01">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10191-10198, S10199-10208, S10290-10291" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2008-10-01" how="roll" result="pass" roll="211" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate, having achieved the required 60 votes in the affirmative, pursuant to the order of September 30, 2008, without amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 86 - 13. Record Vote Number: 211.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2008-10-01">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2008-10-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2008-10-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2008-10-08">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2008-10-08" type="public" number="110-369">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 110-369.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="7039"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="7061"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3548"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear exports"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Reactor fuel reprocessing"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5683"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/8/2008--Public Law.
United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act - (Sec. 2) Defines specified terms. Title I: Approval of United States-India Agreement for Cooperation on Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy - (Sec. 101) Approves the United States-India Agreement for Cooperation on Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy (Agreement), subject to the provisions of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, the Henry J. Hyde United States-India Peaceful Atomic Energy Cooperation Act of 2006, and other applicable U.S. law. (Sec. 102) Declares that it is the understanding of the United States that the provisions of the Agreement have the meanings conveyed in the authoritative representations provided by the President and his representatives to the Congress and its committees prior to September 20, 2008. Declares it to be congressional policy that: (1) in the event that nuclear transfers to India are suspended or terminated it is U.S. policy to prevent the transfer to India of nuclear equipment, materials, or technology from other participating governments in the Nuclear Suppliers Group (NSG) or from any other source; and (2) any nuclear power reactor fuel reserve provided to India for use in safeguarded civilian nuclear facilities should be commensurate with reasonable reactor operating requirements. States that before exchanging specified diplomatic notes the President shall certify to Congress that entry into force and implementation of the Agreement pursuant to its terms is consistent with the obligation of the United States under the Treaty on the Nonproliferation of Nuclear Weapons (Nuclear Nonproliferation Treaty) not to assist, encourage, or induce India to manufacture or otherwise acquire nuclear weapons or other nuclear explosive devices. (Sec. 103) Urges the government of India to sign and adhere to an Additional Protocol with the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA). (Sec. 104) States that licenses may be issued by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) for transfers pursuant to the Agreement only after the President certifies to Congress that: (1) the Agreement Between the Government of India and the International Atomic Energy Agency for the Application of Safeguards to Civilian Nuclear Facilities has entered into force; and (2) the government of India has filed a declaration of facilities that is not materially inconsistent with the facilities and schedule of the separation plan presented in the national parliament of India. (Sec. 105) Amends the Henry J. Hyde United States-India Peaceful Atomic Energy Cooperation Act of 2006 to revise related congressional reporting requirements. Title II: Strengthening United States Nonproliferation Law Relating to Peaceful Nuclear Cooperation - (Sec. 201) States that no subsequent arrangement concerning reprocessing arrangements and procedures shall take effect until: (1) the President reports to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations (Committees) respecting the reasons for such arrangement and a certification that third-party reprocessing arrangements with India will be conducted under similar arrangements; and (2) a period of 30 days of continuous session has elapsed after such report's transmittal. States that a subsequent agreement shall not become effective if during such 30-day period Congress enacts a joint resolution of disapproval. (Sec. 202) Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to direct the President to inform the Committees of any negotiations relating to a new or amended agreement for peaceful nuclear cooperation. (Sec. 203) Requires that Congress enact a joint resolution to override a presidential determination permitting the export of nuclear materials, equipment, or technology to a country to which such export is otherwise prohibited. (Current law provides for a concurrent resolution of disapproval.) (Sec. 204) Directs the President to: (1) certify to the Committees that it is U.S. policy to work with members of the Nuclear Suppliers Group (NSG) to restrict transfers of equipment and technology related to the enrichment of uranium and reprocessing of spent nuclear fuel; (2) seek to achieve within NSG or with NSG participating governments the adoption of principles and exchanges of information to assure peaceful use and accounting of byproduct material; and (3) report every six months to the Committees until such purposes have been achieved. (Sec. 205) Makes conforming amendments with respect to related congressional actions under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954.</summary>
</bill>
