<bill session="113" type="s" number="847" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Polar Bear Conservation and Fairness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to allow the importation of polar bear trophies taken in sport hunts in Canada before the date on which the polar bear was determined to be a threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300030"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2013-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1818"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3197"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1335"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2013--Introduced.
Polar Bear Conservation and Fairness Act of 2013 - Amends the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to direct the Secretary of the Interior to issue a permit for the importation of any polar bear part (other than an internal organ) from a polar bear taken in a sport hunt in Canada to any person: (1) who submits proof that the polar bear was legally harvested before February 18, 1997 (current law); or (2) who has submitted, with an application submitted before May 15, 2008, proof that the bear was legally harvested before such date from a polar bear population from which a sport-hunted trophy could be imported before such date. (Polar bears were listed as a threatened species by the Department of the Interior on May 14, 2008.)</summary>
</bill>
