<bill session="112" type="s" number="1304" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fisheries Fee Fairness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make funds available to reimburse certain fishermen for legal fees and costs incurred in connection with improper fines and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2011-07-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4234-4235"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2610"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2011--Introduced.
Fisheries Fee Fairness Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce, using sums received as fines, penalties, and forfeitures of property for violations of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act or other fishery resource laws enforced by the Secretary, to reimburse certain legal fees and costs to a person applying for reimbursement that: (1) the Secretary directed to be remitted a fisheries enforcement penalty in the Secretarial Decision Memorandum issued by the Secretary on May 17, 2011, entitled Decisions regarding Certain NOAA Fisheries Enforcement Cases Based on Special Master Swartwood's Report and Recommendations; or (2) received a Notice of Violation and Assessment for a fisheries enforcement penalty issued on or after March 17, 1994, that was settled or otherwise resolved prior to February 3, 2010, paid a civil penalty, submitted a complaint seeking remittance prior to May 7, 2011, and was directed by the Secretary to receive at least a portion of such remittance. Directs the Secretary to make a final determination on whether to provide a reimbursement within 90 days after receiving such an application. Prohibits providing more than $200,000 to such a person for appropriate legal fees and costs.</summary>
</bill>
