<bill session="112" type="s" number="1307" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-11-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Commerce to convey real property, including improvements, of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in Ketchikan, Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-11-02">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-11-14">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller without amendment. With written report No. 112-239.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-11-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="547">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 547.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2641"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/14/2012--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to convey to a nonfederal entity specified real property, including improvements, located at 1010 Stedman Street in Ketchikan, Alaska, under the administrative jurisdiction of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), provided that the United States receive consideration of at least fair market value of the property or rights conveyed. Specifies acceptable forms of property, cash, and in-kind consideration. Directs the Secretary to determine fair market value based on a highest- and best-use appraisal in conformance with the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Professional Appraisal Practice. Directs that any proceeds the United States receives as such consideration be available to the Secretary, subject to appropriation, for the acquisition, through lease or by purchase of real property, and associated design and construction of a new port facility in the Ketchikan Gateway Borough, Alaska, that is under the administrative jurisdiction of the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere. Requires the exact acreage and legal description of any property so conveyed to be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to bear the cost of such survey. Permits the Secretary, as appropriate to protect the interest of the United States, to: (1) exchange all or any portion of the real property, and (2) require additional terms and conditions with any such conveyance.</summary>
</bill>
