<bill session="109" type="s" number="1949" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cooperative Proliferation Detection, Interdiction Assistance, and Conventional Threat Reduction Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Conventional Arms Disarmament Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Cooperative Proliferation Detection and Interdiction Assistance Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for coordination of proliferation interdiction activities and conventional arms disarmament, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2005-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12130-12132"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-09">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-880.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2566"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conventional weapons"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Guided missiles"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Land mines"/>
    <term name="Maritime law"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Minesweeping"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Surface-to-air missiles"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/2005--Introduced.
Cooperative Proliferation Detection, Interdiction Assistance, and Conventional Threat Reduction Act of 2005 - Cooperative Proliferation Detection and Interdiction Assistance Act of 2005 - Authorizes the President to establish a program to provide proliferation detection and interdiction assistance to friendly foreign countries and requires that at least 25% of the amount made available for nonproliferation, anti-terrorism, demining and related programs and activities for FY2006 shall be made available to establish such program. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the President, in order to promote cooperation regarding the interdiction of weapons of mass destruction and related materials and delivery systems, to conclude agreements (including reciprocal maritime agreements) with other countries to prevent the transportation of such items to states and non-state actors of proliferation concern. Establishes within the Department of State an Office of Proliferation Detection and Interdiction Assistance Coordination. Provides that activities authorized to be carried out under the Nonproliferation and Disarmament Fund in the independent states of the former Soviet Union may also be carried out in other countries and with respect to international organizations when such activities are in the U.S. national interest. States that the President should ensure that, when in the national security interest of the United States, at least 25% of military assistance furnished will enhance the capabilities of friendly foreign countries to detect or interdict the illicit trafficking of weapons of mass destruction, related materials, and means of delivery and dual-use items of proliferation concern. Conventional Arms Disarmament Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Secretary of State to carry out an accelerated global program to secure or eliminate stocks of man-portable air defense systems (MANPADS), other conventional weapons, and tactical missile systems, as well as related equipment and facilities that pose a proliferation threat. Redesignates the (Department of State) Office of Weapons Removal and Abatement as the Office of Conventional Arms Threat Reduction.</summary>
</bill>
