<bill session="112" type="h" number="924" updated="2013-07-20T01:18:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Jobs for Veterans Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to establish a Veterans Business Center program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412281"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2011--Introduced.
Jobs for Veterans Act of 2011 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish within the SBA a Veterans Business Center program (program), headed by a Director, to provide entrepreneurial training and counseling to veterans. Authorizes the Director to make grants to each entity designated as a veterans business center. Requires each center to use such funds on veteran entrepreneurial development, counseling of veteran-owned small businesses through one-on-one instruction and classes, and providing government procurement assistance to veterans. Targets populations where veterans and veterans of Operations Iraqi Freedom. Enduring Freedom, or New Dawn exceed the national median. Requires the Director to establish, with respect to veteran-owned small businesses, grant programs for: (1) access to capital; (2) procurement assistance; and (3) service-disabled veteran-owned small businesses. Authorizes the Director to carry out, every two years, a veterans entrepreneurial development summit. Requires: (1) an annual report from the Administrator on appointments made to, and activities of, the interagency task force on veteran-owned small businesses; and (2) a study by the Comptroller General of the effects of this Act on small businesses owned and controlled by veterans.</summary>
</bill>
