<bill session="109" type="s" number="566" updated="2013-07-19T20:18:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Dual Eligible Prescription Drug Coverage Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to continue State coverage of medicaid prescription drug coverage to medicare dual eligible beneficiaries for 6 months while still allowing the medicare part D benefit to be implemented as scheduled.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2005-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2005-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2270-2271"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2271-2272" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="1144"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Drug utilization"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2005--Introduced.
Medicare Dual Eligible Prescription Drug Coverage Act of 2005 - Provides that, for prescriptions filled between January 1 and June 30, 2006, requirements for the coordination of prescription drug benefits with Medicare as primary payor for dual eligible individuals under the new prescription drug benefit program (PDP) under Medicare part E (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) shall not apply. Requires a State to continue to provide Medicaid medical assistance with respect to prescription drugs as if such coordination requirements had not been enacted. Declares that no State or the District of Columbia shall be required to pay (reimburse) the Secretary of Health and Human Services for Medicaid prescription drug costs for dual eligible individuals (Medicaid clawback payments) for any month before July 1, 2006. Earmarks specified amounts for education and outreach to dual eligibles regarding prescription drug coverage and monitoring of their transition to prescription drug coverage under Medicare. Requires a PDP sponsor and an MA organization offering an MA-PD plan to submit to the Secretary appropriate information regarding the drug utilization of enrollees in such plans who are full-benefit dual eligible individuals. Directs the Secretary to collect data on the drug utilization of full-benefit dual eligible individuals and share it with the States and District of Columbia in as close to a real-time basis as possible. Directs the Comptroller General of the United States to study and report to Congress on the clawback formula.</summary>
</bill>
