<bill session="111" type="sr" number="386" updated="2013-07-20T00:19:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-22">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution condemning the Government of Iran for restricting and suppressing freedom of the press, freedom of speech, freedom of expression, and freedom of assembly, and for its human rights abuses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412329"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2009-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2009-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2009-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2009-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2009-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2009-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2009-12-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-12-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13792-13793" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S13793" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S13790-13791" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/22/2009--Passed Senate without amendment.
Supports the right of the people of Iran to peacefully express their voices despite repression. Condemns: (1) the human rights abuses and suppression of freedom committed by the government of Iran against Iranian citizens; (2) online censorship, monitoring, intimidation, and harassment conducted by the government of Iran, including threats against citizens of Iran and Iranian-Americans living in the United States; and (3) the government of Iran for violating the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights. Welcomes the the Department of State decision to support the free flow of information to Iranian citizens by recommending that the Department of the Treasury's Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) issue a general license that would authorize downloads of free mass market software to Iran. Urges implementation of the Victims of Iranian Censorship Act.</summary>
</bill>
