<bill session="111" type="h" number="4708" updated="2013-07-19T23:54:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reinstatement of Personal Responsibility for Immigrants Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles XIX and XXI of the Social Security Act to require citizenship and immigration verification of eligibility under Medicaid and the State Children's Health Insurance Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400405"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2010-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2010-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2010--Introduced.
Reinstatement of Personal Responsibility for Immigrants Act of 2010 - Amends titles XIX (Medicaid) and XXI (Children's Health Insurance Program) (CHIP) of the Social Security Act to repeal the authority of states to elect to provide medical assistance to children and pregnant women who are lawfully residing in the United States, notwithstanding the mandatory five-year delay for general coverage of legal immigrants. Requires CHIP to participate in the state income and eligibility verification system (SAVE program). Requires application under Medicaid and CHIP of the citizenship verification procedures that applied before enactment of the Children's Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2009 (CHIPRA). Rescinds unobligated amounts under CHIPRA for the alternative state process for verification of declaration of citizenship or nationality for purposes of eligibility for Medicaid and CHIP.</summary>
</bill>
