<bill session="110" type="s" number="3534" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vision Preservation Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the expansion of Federal programs to prevent and manage vision loss, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2008-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9210-9211"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9211-9212" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3750"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Eye care"/>
    <term name="Eye diseases"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Occupational therapy"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2008--Introduced.
Vision Preservation Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), and the National Institutes of Health (NIH), to expand and intensify programs to increase awareness of vision problems. Directs the Secretary to expand and intensify: (1) activities to establish a solid scientific base of knowledge on the prevention, control, and rehabilitation of vision problems and related disabilities; (2) research within CDC on the prevention and management of vision loss; and (3) programs targeted to prevent vision loss, treat eye and vision conditions, and rehabilitate people of all ages who are blind or partially sighted in underserved and minority communities.Amends title V (Maternal and Child Health Services) of the Social Security Act to authorize appropriations to enable the Secretary to introduce core performance measures on eye health by incorporating vision screening and examination standards into state programs.Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to eligible institutions of higher education or nonprofit organizations for vision rehabilitation professional development.</summary>
</bill>
