<bill session="111" type="s" number="1293" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhancing Child Health with Automatic School Meal Enrollment Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to improve automatic enrollment procedures for the national school lunch and school breakfast programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6811"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6811-6812" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2009--Introduced.
Enhancing Child Health with Automatic School Meal Enrollment Act of 2009 - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to make performance awards to states that demonstrate outstanding performance or show substantial improvement in directly certifying children whose families are eligible for supplemental nutrition assistance under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 as eligible for free meals under the school lunch and breakfast programs. (Direct certification eliminates the need for such families to submit applications for participation in the school lunch and breakfast programs.) Requires each state that directly certifies less than 95% of their children who are eligible for direct certification to implement a direct certification improvement plan that is approved by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary of Education to report to Congress on how statewide databases used to track compliance with the requirements of the school improvement program under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 can be used for the purposes of direct certification.</summary>
</bill>
