<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1640" updated="2013-07-19T23:10:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-23T13:08:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-09-23T13:08:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 5297) to create the Small Business Lending Fund Program to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to make capital investments in eligible institutions in order to increase the availability of credit for small businesses, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax incentives for small business job creation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412307"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22T18:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-621, by Ms. Pingree (ME).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22T18:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Upon the adoption of the resolution, it shall be in order to take from the Speaker's table H.R. 5297, with the Senate amendment thereto, and to consider in the House a motion to concur in the Senate amendment. The motion shall be debatable for one hour, equally divided and controlled. The previous question on the motion shall be considered as ordered. The resolution provides suspension authority through the legislative day of October 1, 2010. The resolution waives the 2/3 requirement for same day consideration through the legislative day of October 1, 2010.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-09-22T18:58:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="239">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 239.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23T10:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6886-6891" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23T10:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1640.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23T11:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1640, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lincoln Diaz-Balart demanded the yeas and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23T12:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6902-6903" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23T12:59:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 230 - 181 (Roll no. 535).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-09-23T13:08:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="536" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 186 (Roll no. 536).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6886" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23T13:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5297"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2010--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 5297) to create the Small Business Lending Fund Program to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to make capital investments in eligible institutions in order to increase the availability of credit for small businesses, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax incentives for small business job creation.</summary>
</bill>
