<bill session="112" type="s" number="1845" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STORAGE 2011 Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Storage Technology for Renewable and Green Energy Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for an energy investment credit for energy storage property connected to the grid, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2011-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2012-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7371"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7371-7372" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4096"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/2011--Introduced.
Storage Technology for Renewable and Green Energy Act of 2011 or the STORAGE 2011 Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow, through 2020, a 20% energy tax credit for investment in energy storage property that is directly connected to the electrical grid (i.e., a system of generators, transmission lines, and distribution facilities) and that is designed to receive. store, and convert energy to electricity, deliver it for sale, or use such energy to provide improved reliability or economic benefits to the grid; (2) make such property eligible for new clean renewable energy bond financing; (3) allow a 30% energy tax credit for investment in energy storage property used at the site of energy storage; and (4) allow a 30% nonbusiness energy property tax credit for the installation of energy storage equipment in a principal residence.</summary>
</bill>
