<bill session="111" type="h" number="3108" updated="2013-07-19T23:40:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medication Therapy Management Benefits Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to promote medication therapy management under the Medicare part D prescription drug program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400345"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400026" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412206" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400280" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2010-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2010-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3543"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2009--Introduced.
Medication Therapy Management Benefits Act of 2009 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require that the medication therapy management (MTM) services prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsors offer to targeted beneficiaries include: (1) an annual comprehensive medication review furnished person-to-person by a licensed pharmacist; (2) at least quarterly targeted medication reviews, also furnished person-to-person by a licensed pharmacist; and (3) followup interventions, person-to-person or through other interactive means, on a schedule and frequency recommended by the prescriber or a licensed pharmacist. Increases the number of diseases and conditions for which beneficiaries may be targeted for MTM services. Requires a PDP sponsor to identify a process, subject to approval by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), that allows pharmacists or other qualified providers to identify enrollees for MTM interventions where such individuals are not targeted beneficiaries or are not otherwise offered MTM services. Requires any MTM program to offer both comprehensive and targeted medication reviews to individuals dually eligible for both Medicare and Medicaid (under SSA title XIX), regardless of whether they are MTM-targeted beneficiaries. Requires a PDP sponsor to offer any willing pharmacy in its network the ability to provide MTM services. Requires the PDP sponsor to reimburse pharmacists and other entities furnishing MTM services based on the resources used and the time required to provide such services. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish measures and standards for data collection by PDP sponsors to evaluate performance of pharmacies and other entities in furnishing MTM services; and (2) support the continued development and refinement of performance measures. Provides pharmacies and other entities that furnish MTM services with additional incentive payments based on their performance in meeting quality measures established under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
