<bill session="111" type="h" number="2181" updated="2013-07-19T23:31:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mortgage Assistance Information and Scam Prevention Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require servicers of mortgages on single family homes to provide notice to mortgagors of possible eligibility for Federal mortgage assistance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412318"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2009-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2009--Introduced.
Mortgage Assistance Information and Scam Prevention Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to require that each covered mortgage servicer provide periodic notice to each mortgagor under a first mortgage on residential real property designed principally for occupancy of one to four families. Requires such a notice to: (1) notify the mortgagor of possible eligibility for federal or federally related homeowner assistance; (2) identify specific programs of HUD, the Rural Housing Service of the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), the Department of the Treasury, the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), the Federal Home Loan Banks, and any other federal or federally related entities that provide mortgage relief, mortgage refinancing, loan modification, mortgage foreclosure mitigation, homeowner stability or affordability, or other homeowner assistance; and (3) explain how to obtain further information regarding such programs.</summary>
</bill>
