<bill session="110" type="s" number="844" updated="2013-07-19T22:27:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Unaccompanied Alien Child Protection Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the protection of unaccompanied alien children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2007-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3004-3005"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3005-3010" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Age"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Children's rights"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diet"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Group homes"/>
    <term name="Guardian and ward"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigrant education"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal aid"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mexicans"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Right of asylum"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2007--Introduced.
Unaccompanied Alien Child Protection Act of 2007 - Addresses the care and custody of unaccompanied alien children (children), defined as children under the age of 18 with no lawful immigration status and no parent or legal guardian in the United States who is available to provide care and physical custody. Directs immigration officers who find such children at U.S. land borders or ports of entry to permit them to withdraw their applications for admission and return to their country of nationality or last habitual residence. States that such children shall have the right to consult with a consular officer prior to repatriation and with the Office of Refugee Resettlement (the Office) at the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). Gives the Office jurisdiction over the care and custody of all unaccompanied alien children except: (1) the Department of Justice (DOJ) shall have responsibility for those imprisoned for a federal crime or in DOJ custody pending prosecution; and (2) the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall have responsibility for those who threaten national security. Requires federal departments or agencies to transfer such children in their custody to the Office. Specifies the order of preference for placing released children, including custody rights of parents and legal guardians. Requires the Office to protect such children from smugglers and traffickers. Prohibits the placement of such children in adult detention facilities or in facilities housing delinquent children unless they exhibit violent or criminal behavior. Specifies the preference order for such children's placement. Requires the Office and and DHS to: (1) promulgate detention standards; and (2) develop procedures to prohibit the unreasonable use of restraints, solitary confinement, or pat or strip searches. Expresses the sense of Congress that the U.S. government should ensure that it does not repatriate children into settings that would threaten their life and safety. Requires the Office to develop procedures for determining the age of aliens in DHS or Office custody. Authorizes the Director of the Office to appoint qualified and duly trained child advocates for such children. Requires the Director to: (1) provide professional training for such child advocates; and (2) implement a pilot program for their appointment. States that the Director should ensure that such children in Office or DHS custody, except those being repatriated to a contiguous country, have immigration counsel. Requires the Executive Office for Immigration Review (EOIR) to develop and implement model guidelines for the legal representation of alien children in immigration proceedings. Bars such children in Office custody from consenting to immigration actions, including voluntary departure, unless first afforded an opportunity to consult with counsel. Makes such child advocate and counsel provisions applicable to all such children in federal custody on, before, or after the effective date of this Act. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to revise special immigrant juvenile visa provisions. Requires an alien to be 18 years or younger and present in the United States on the date of visa application. (Provides a transition rule for aliens who applied for such visa before enactment of this Act and were between the ages of 19-21 at the time of application.) Authorizes waiver of certain grounds of inadmissibility. Commends the Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) for its issuance of the 1998 Guidelines for Children's Asylum Claims and encourages implementation of such guidelines by INS and its successor. Calls upon EOIR to adopt such guidelines in its handling of children's asylum claims. Requires such children apprehended by DHS, except those subject to contiguous country rules, to be placed in removal proceedings. Exempts such children from certain bars to asylum. Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (HSA) to make the Director responsible for: (1) placement suitability assessments for such children; and (2) ensuring that minimum standards of care are met for residential alternatives to detention. States that the amendments to HSA made by this Act shall be effective as if enacted as part of HSA.</summary>
</bill>
