<bill session="110" type="s" number="2236" updated="2013-07-19T22:40:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preexisting Condition Exclusion Patient Protection Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide additional limitations on preexisting condition exclusions in group health plans and health insurance coverage in the group and individual markets.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13450-13451"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13451" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="2833"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/25/2007--Introduced.
Preexisting Condition Exclusion Patient Protection Act of 2007 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code to allow a group health plan to impose a preexisting condition exclusion only if: (1) such exclusion relates to a condition for which medical advice, diagnosis, care, or treatment was recommended or received within the 30-day period ending on the enrollment date; and (2) such exclusion extends not more than three months, or nine months for a late enrollee, after the enrollment date.Applies such requirement to coverage offered in the individual market. Allows an issuer of individual health insurance coverage to impose a preexisting condition exclusion for a period of not more than three months under certain circumstances.Revises provisions that prohibit health insurance issuers that offer health insurance coverage in the individual market from declining to offer coverage or imposing any preexisting condition exclusion on coverage to an eligible individual to remove eligibility requirements that require an individual to have: (1) elected COBRA continuation coverage, if it was offered; and (2) exhausted such continuation coverage, if elected.</summary>
</bill>
