<bill session="112" type="h" number="4247" updated="2013-07-20T01:46:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cell Phone Theft Prevention Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit mobile service providers from providing service on mobile electronic devices that have been reported stolen and to require such providers to give consumers the ability to remotely delete data from mobile electronic devices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2012-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2012--Introduced.
Cell Phone Theft Prevention Act of 2012 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit a provider of commercial mobile or commercial mobile data service from providing service on a mobile electronic device reported to such provider as stolen by: (1) the person who holds the service account, if such person submits a copy of a report made to a law enforcement agency regarding the theft; or (2) another provider of commercial mobile or commercial mobile data service required by this Act to inform all other providers of a device reported stolen and of any information necessary for identification of the device. Defines "mobile electronic device" as a personal electronic device on which commercial mobile or commercial mobile data service is provided, excluding devices: (1) for which the consumer purchases service by paying in advance for a specified amount of calling or data usage, or (2) with respect to which the consumer does not have a direct relationship with the provider. Directs providers to make available to account holders the capability of deleting, from a remote location, all information that was placed on such a device after its manufacture. Prohibits a person from manufacturing in or importing into the United States for sale or resale to the public a mobile electronic device unless it is: (1) equipped with a unique identifier that allows a provider to identify such device, and (2) configured to enable a provider to make available the remote deletion capability required by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
