<bill session="110" type="hc" number="339" updated="2013-07-19T22:11:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress regarding the necessity to improve public awareness in the United States among older individuals and their families and caregivers about the impending Digital Television Transition through the establishment of a Federal interagency taskforce between the Federal Communications Commission, the Administration on Aging, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, and the outside advice of appropriate members of the aging network and industry groups.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400616"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against the elderly"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2008--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) shall enter into a partnership with the Administration on Aging and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to create a comprehensive public education campaign for older individuals and aging support networks to ensure that older individuals receive uninterrupted television service during the transition to digital television and to mitigate related fraud targeting older individuals.</summary>
</bill>
