<bill session="109" type="sc" number="82" updated="2013-07-19T20:13:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A concurrent resolution to establish a procedure for the appointment of independent Congressional Ethics Office to investigate ethics violations in the Senate and the House of Representatives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1552"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1551-1552" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2006--Introduced.
Establishes in the legislative branch the Congressional Ethics Office, headed by a Congressional Ethics Officer, which shall: (1) make informal preliminary inquiries in response to requests for reviews of allegations of improper conduct or a violation of law or House or Senate regulations; (2) report to the Members of Congress and the Department of Justice any finding of probable cause that a violation of ethics rules has occurred; (3) if warranted, conduct full investigations of such allegations; (4) report on investigations to the Senate Select Committee on Ethics or the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct; and (5) report to Congress on ethics complaints, ethics investigations, and recommendations for changes to ethics regulations. Requires a request for review to be accompanied by a sworn statement of facts. Authorizes the Officer to refer false statements to the Attorney General for prosecution. Sets penalties for knowingly filing or encouraging another to file a false complaint. Bans filings close to an election.</summary>
</bill>
