<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1218" updated="2013-07-19T21:01:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-22T12:18:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-05-22T12:18:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5658) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2009 for military activities of the Department of Defense, to prescribe military personnel strengths for fiscal year 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400065"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-05-21T21:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-666, by Mr. Cardoza.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-21T21:51:00-04:00">
      <text>No further general debate shall be in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committeee on Armed Services now printed in the bill. All points of order against the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute are waived except those arising under clause 10 of rule XXI. In the engrossment of H.R. 5658, the Clerk shall add the text of H.R. 6048 as passed by the House as new matter at the end of H.R. 5658. It shall be in order at any time through the legislative day of Thursday, May 22, 2008, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules relating to any measure pertaining to agricultural programs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-05-21T21:51:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="226">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 226.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T10:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4457-4468" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T10:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1218.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T12:10:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 192 (Roll no. 350).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4467-4468" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-05-22T12:18:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="351" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 223 - 197 (Roll no. 351).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4457" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T12:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="110" type="h" number="5658"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2008--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5658) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2009 for military activities of the Department of Defense, to prescribe military personnel strengths for fiscal year 2009.</summary>
</bill>
