<bill session="113" type="h" number="1021" updated="2013-11-02T06:27:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Land Acquisition to cut National Debt Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LAND Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that there shall be no net increase in the acres of certain Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management, the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, or the Forest Service unless the Federal budget is balanced for the year in which the land would be purchased.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412461"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/2013--Introduced.
Land Acquisition to cut National Debt Act or LAND Act - Bars the Secretary of the Interior from using federal funding to purchase land resulting in a net increase of land acreage being under the jurisdiction of the National Park Service (NPS), the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS), or the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) unless the federal budget is balanced for the year in which such land would be purchased. Makes such prohibition inapplicable to: (1) lands purchased with funding made available through the sale of Federal Migratory Bird Hunting and Conservation Stamps, and (2) easements acquired by the Secretary of the Interior to facilitate the management of federal lands. Bars the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) from using federal funding to purchase land resulting in a net increase of land acreage included in the National Forest System unless the federal budget is balanced for the year in which that land would be purchased. Makes such prohibition inapplicable to easements acquired by the USDA Secretary to facilitate the management of federal lands.</summary>
</bill>
