<bill session="111" type="h" number="2535" updated="2013-07-19T23:34:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Blueprint for Health Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a Blueprint for Health in order to create a comprehensive system of care incorporating medical homes to improve the delivery and affordability of health care through disease prevention, health promotion, and education about and better management of chronic conditions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412239"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2009--Introduced.
Blueprint for Health Act of 2009 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to create the Blueprint for Health program to provide a national infrastructure for disease prevention, health promotion, and education about, and better management of, chronic conditions. Sets forth elements to be included in the Blueprint, including: (1) a strategic plan for designing an integrated medical home model of care; (2) chronic management programs; (3) incentives for the prevention of chronic diseases, including investments in health and sustainable local and regional food systems; and (4) a plan for the assessment of current health information technology initiatives. Requires the Secretary to convene an executive committee to advise the Secretary on the creation and implementation of the Blueprint for Health. Requires the Blueprint for Health to promote the effective, efficient, national use of health care information technology initiatives. Directs the Secretary to commission an assessment that examines the implementation of the health information technology provisions of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009. Requires the Secretary to recommend to Congress legislation to implement the Blueprint for Health, including the establishment of programs designed to enhance primary care, promote multidisciplinary care coordination, prevent disease, improve quality, contain costs, more effectively manage chronic illness, and promote good health and prevention initiatives.</summary>
</bill>
