<bill session="113" type="h" number="2286" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maximizing Optimal Maternity Services for the 21st Century</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MOMS for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote optimal maternity outcomes by making evidence-based maternity care a national priority, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400347"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/2013--Introduced.
Maximizing Optimal Maternity Services for the 21st Century or the MOMS for the 21st Century Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Office on Women's Health to: (1) establish the Interagency Coordinating Committee on the Promotion of Optimal Maternity Outcomes, and (2) develop and implement a consumer education campaign to promote understanding and acceptance of evidence-based maternity practices and models of care for optimal maternity outcomes among women of childbearing ages and their families. Requires the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality to make publicly available and update an online bibliographic database identifying systematic reviews, including an explanation of the level and quality of evidence, for the care of childbearing women and newborns. Requires the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration to: (1) designate maternity care health professional shortage areas under the National Health Service Corps program, and (2) award planning and implementation grants to address workforce disparities for such professionals. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to support the establishment of two additional Centers for Excellence on Optimal Maternity Outcomes to conduct research to improve maternity outcomes. Requires the Secretary to convene an Interprofessional Maternity Provider Education Commission to discuss and make recommendations for: (1) a consensus standard physiologic maternity care curriculum that takes into account the core competencies for basic midwifery practice and the educational objectives for physicians practicing in obstetrics and gynecology, (2) suggestions for multidisciplinary use of the consensus physiologic curriculum, (3) strategies to integrate and coordinate education across maternity care disciplines, and (4) pilot demonstrations of interprofessional educational models. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to cover services provided by a supervised student midwife or an intern or resident-in-training under a teaching program under certain circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
