<bill session="109" type="s" number="460" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening America's Armed Forces and Military Family Bill of Rights Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to expand and enhance benefits for members of the Armed Forces and their families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1720-1722"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Checkoff"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Group counseling"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Marines"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="Psychiatrists"/>
    <term name="Replacement workers"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/18/2005--Introduced.
Strengthening America's Armed Forces and Military Family Bill of Rights Act - Increases Army and Marine Corps end strengths for FY 2005 and thereafter. Makes members of the Selected Reserve and the Individual Ready Reserve eligible for either the Prime or Standard option of the TRICARE Program (a Department of Defense managed health care program), allowing for either self-coverage or self-and-family coverage. Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned to pay the applicable premium to continue in force any qualified health plan coverage for a reserve member (and his or her dependents) while the member is serving on active duty pursuant to a call or order issued during a war or national emergency declared by the President or Congress. Requires the continuation of COBRA coverage during such period. National Reservist Enterprise Transition and Sustainability Act of 2005 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish a program to provide business planning assistance to small businesses owned and operated by members of the National Guard and Reserve. Authorizes SBA: (1) loans to new veteran entrepreneurs; and (2) grant assistance for military reservists' small businesses. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a reserve component employment credit equal to the sum of the employment credit with respect to all qualified employees of the taxpayer and the self-employment credit of a qualified self-employed taxpayer. Disallows the credit for failure to comply with reserve member employment or reemployment rights, or when a reserve member is called or ordered to active duty for training. Authorizes a taxpayer to designate overpayments of income tax for payment into the the American Military Family Relief Fund (established herein), to be used to make distributions to individuals and family of members who serve or have served in the Armed Forces for needs not met by other laws or programs. Authorizes penalty-free withdrawals from retirement plans for individuals called or ordered to certain active duty. Increases the military death gratuity from $12,000 to $250,000. Continues for 365 (currently 180) days the basic allowance for housing for dependents of members who die while on active duty. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to employ at least one psychiatrist and a complimentary clinical team at each Department of Veterans Affairs medical center to provide post-traumatic stress disorder treatment for veterans of service in Afghanistan and Iraq and the War on Terrorism.</summary>
</bill>
