<bill session="110" type="s" number="3489" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to conduct a study on black carbon emissions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2008-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2008-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-09-17">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 110-489.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1060">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1060.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smoke"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to work with representatives of industry and environmental groups to conduct a study of black carbon emissions, which shall include: (1) an identification of the major sources of black carbon emissions in the United States and throughout the world, an estimate of the quantity of current and future emissions, and the net climate effects of the emissions from those sources; (2) an identification of the most effective and cost-effective control technologies, operations, or strategies for additional domestic and international reductions in black carbon reductions and the health benefits associated with additional reductions; and (3) recommendations regarding areas of focus for additional research for technologies, operations, and strategies with the highest potential to reduce black carbon emissions, government actions to encourage or require additional black carbon emission reductions, and the development of a climate-beneficial tropospheric ozone reduction strategy. Requires the Administrator to report to Congress on the study results within 180 days after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
