<bill session="109" type="h" number="3359" updated="2013-07-19T19:34:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical Malpractice and Insurance Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit frivolous medical malpractice lawsuits, to reform the medical malpractice insurance business in order to reduce the cost of medical malpractice insurance, to enhance patient access to medical care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2005-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2005-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2005-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2005-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="2005-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1540-1541"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contempt of court"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Gynecology"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Price fixing"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Surgeons"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2005--Introduced.
Medical Malpractice and Insurance Reform Act of 2005 - Sets forth provisions regulating medical malpractice lawsuits and insurance. Sets the statute of limitation at three years. Requires a complaint to include: (1) an affidavit from a qualified specialist of the reasonableness and merit of the action; and (2) a certificate of merit from the attorney or party attesting to the reasonableness of the action. Requires mediation that is provided by the state before a trial. Prohibits punitive damages awards except upon proof of gross negligence, reckless indifference to life, or intentional acts. Diverts 50 percent of such awards to the Secretary of Health and Human Services for patient safety activities. Requires each medical malpractice liability insurance company to reduce physicians' premiums with financial savings from this Act. Declares that the McCarran-Ferguson Act does not permit commercial insurers to engage in any form of price fixing, bid rigging, or market allocations in providing medical malpractice insurance. Requires the Secretary to establish an Internet site to allow health care providers to obtain quotes from licensed insurers. Requires states to have a policy that: (1) gives licensed health care professionals standing to challenge proposed medical malpractice rate insurance increases; and (2) prohibits insurers from increasing rates without substantial justification. Amends the Public Health Service Act to permit the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to award grants or contracts to geographic areas that have health care provider shortages due to the cost of maintaining malpractice insurance. Establishes: (1) the Independent Advisory Commission on Medical Malpractice Insurance to evaluate recent dramatic increases in medical malpractice insurance premiums and to make recommendations to avoid future dramatic increases; and (2) the Medical Malpractice Insurance Information Administration, which shall identify data necessary to evaluate the medical malpractice insurance market.</summary>
</bill>
