<bill session="110" type="s" number="381" updated="2013-07-19T22:23:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Latin Americans of Japanese Descent Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Latin Americans of Japanese Descent Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a fact-finding Commission to extend the study of a prior Commission to investigate and determine facts and circumstances surrounding the relocation, internment, and deportation to Axis countries of Latin Americans of Japanese descent from December 1941 through February 1948, and the impact of those actions by the United States, and to recommend appropriate remedies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2007-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2007-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1065-1066"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1066-1067" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman without amendment. With written report No. 110-452.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="950">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 950.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="662"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Concentration camps"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Japanese Americans"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Latin Americans"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Latin Americans of Japanese Descent Act - Establishes the Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Latin Americans of Japanese descent. Directs the Commission to: (1) extend the study of the Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians to investigate U.S. relocation, internment, and (in some cases) deportation to Axis countries of Latin Americans of Japanese descent held in U.S. custody from December 1941 through February 1948, including the review of relocation-related U.S. Armed Forces and Department of State directives; (2) recommend appropriate remedies to Congress based on preliminary findings by the original Commission and new discoveries; and (3) report to Congress. Sets forth Commission authorities and administrative and personnel provisions. Terminates the Commission 90 days after submission of its congressional report. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
