<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1311" updated="2013-07-19T23:07:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing support for the charitable collection and good samaritan distribution to uninsured, low-income Americans of Food and Drug Administration-approved, medically-appropriate, non-expired, non-narcotic prescription medications by non-profit organizations licensed to dispense such medications.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2010--Introduced.
Encourages pharmaceutical manufacturers, health care professionals, and institutions providing health care to make charitable donations of Food and Drug Administration (FDA)-approved, medically appropriate, non-expired, non-narcotic prescription medications to nonprofit organizations whose primary mission is to fill prescriptions for low-income Americans. Expresses support for exempting pharmaceutical companies from liability arising from the donation of medications in good faith to nonprofit organizations for distribution to needy individuals, assuming there is no gross negligence or intentional misconduct. Encourages the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to convene a working group to develop plans to facilitate the creation and operation of such nonprofit organizations.</summary>
</bill>
