<bill session="110" type="s" number="2286" updated="2013-07-19T22:40:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commission on Natural Catastrophe Risk Management and Insurance Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Commission on Natural Catastrophe Risk Management and Insurance Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">An original bill to establish a nonpartisan commission on natural catastrophe risk management and insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-01">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Dodd. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-11-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="462">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 462.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3644"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Casualty insurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Property insurance"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Commission on Natural Catastrophe Risk Management and Insurance Act of 2007 - Establishes the Commission on Natural Catastrophe Risk Management and Insurance to report to Congress on its findings and assessments regarding the risks posed to the United States by natural catastrophes, and means for mitigating those risks and paying for losses caused by such catastrophes. Requires the Commission to assess: (1) the condition of the property and casualty insurance and reinsurance markets prior to and in the aftermath of Hurricanes Katrina, Rita, and Wilma in 2005, and the four major hurricanes that struck the United States in 2004; (2) the current condition of, as well as the outlook for, the availability and affordability of insurance in all regions of the country; and (3) the current ability of states, communities, and individuals to mitigate their natural catastrophe risks, including the affordability and feasibility of such activities.Directs the Commission to report its findings and assessments to certain congressional committees on December 1, 2008.</summary>
</bill>
