<bill session="110" type="h" number="6167" updated="2013-07-19T21:57:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prevention and Deterrence of Crimes Against Children Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to strengthen penalties for child pornography offenses, child sex trafficking offenses, and other sexual offenses committed against children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400212"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2008-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3014"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Sex-oriented businesses"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2008--Introduced.
Prevention and Deterrence of Crimes Against Children Act of 2008 - Amends the federal criminal code to increase criminal penalties for offenses relating to the sexual exploitation of children and child pornography, transportation of minors for illicit sexual purposes, child sex trafficking and prostitution, and sex crimes against children resulting in death. Directs the Attorney General to notify the Secretaries of State and Homeland Security of individuals, including aliens, who are convicted of sex offenses against children. Requires the Secretary of State to deny passports for such individuals and authorizes the Secretary to revoke, restrict, or limit a passport issued to a convicted sex offender if the passport was used to transport a minor for illicit sexual purposes.Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to place aliens convicted of sex offenses in removal proceedings. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) render aliens who are convicted of sexual abuse of a minor inadmissible to the United States; and (2) subject aliens convicted of a sex crime against a minor to deportation.</summary>
</bill>
