<bill session="112" type="s" number="917" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Outer Continental Shelf Reform Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to reform the management of energy and mineral resources on the Outer Continental Shelf, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2785"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2785-2793" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2823-2824"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-51.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2566"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2011--Introduced.
Outer Continental Shelf Reform Act of 2011 - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to prescribe a program of structural reform for management of the Outer Continental Shelf, including establishing two bureaus to carry out leasing, permitting, and safety and environmental regulatory functions. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish: (1) an office to carry out the royalty and revenue management functions, and (2) an Outer Continental Shelf Safety and Environmental Advisory Board. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) recruit and directly appoint highly qualified critical technical personnel, upon a determination that there is a severe shortage of candidates or a critical hiring need for particular positions; and (2) approve reemployment of civilian retirees to carry out a critical functions under this Act. Directs the Secretary to: (1) prescribe and amend rules and regulations addressing operational safety and protection of the marine and coastal environment; (2) review bond and surety amounts every five years; (3) review royalty and rental rates; (4) review and report on the federal offshore oil and gas fiscal system; and (5) implement research and development to improve methodologies for characterizing resources of the Outer Continental Shelf and conditions affecting the ability to develop and use resources in a safe, sound, and environmentally responsible manner. Instructs the Secretary to develop and implement programs for: (1) analysis and dissemination of environmental and other resource data; (2) risk assessment to address technology and development issues associated with Outer Continental Shelf energy and mineral resource activities, including safety, environmental protection, and spill response; (3) review of alleged safety violations; and (4) the collection of a non-refundable inspection fee for deposit into the Ocean Energy Enforcement Fund (established under this Act). Cites conditions under which bids for a lease may be disqualified. Revises requirements governing explorations plans and drilling permits.</summary>
</bill>
