<bill session="112" type="s" number="3455" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Government Customer Service Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the establishment of customer service standards for Federal agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2012-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="538"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2012--Introduced.
Government Customer Service Improvement Act of 2012 - Directs the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to: (1) develop performance measures to determine whether federal agencies are providing high-quality, timely, customer service and improving delivery service, (2) develop customer service and service delivery standards for such agencies, and (3) include achievements in meeting such performance measures and standards in agency performance updates. Requires the head of each federal agency to designate an agency employee to be its service improvement officer, who shall issue guidelines to implement customer service standards and publish customer service contact information. Directs the OMB Deputy Director of Management to establish a two-year Service Improvement Unit Pilot Program to provide assistance to agencies that do not meet such customer service standards and performance measures. Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to: (1) report to Congress and the Comptroller General (GAO) on information submitted by each federal agency on its employees who are retiring, and (2) establish a timetable for the completion of its retirement systems modernization project.</summary>
</bill>
