<bill session="110" type="h" number="3296" updated="2013-07-19T21:32:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mortgage Broker Transparency and Accountability Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to establish transparency and accountability requirements for mortgage brokers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage banks"/>
    <term name="Mortgage interest rates"/>
    <term name="Property insurance"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2007--Introduced.
Mortgage Broker Transparency and Accountability Act of 2007 &#150; Amends the Truth in Lending Act to establish mandatory responsibilities, duties, and disclosures governing mortgage brokers. Deems any mortgage broker to have a statutory agency relationship with the consumer subject to all requirements under state or federal law. Sets forth disclosure requirements, including disclosure of: (1) the risks and benefits of each home mortgage loan product; (2) possible payment increases at the time of any resetting of rate; (3) the extent of any prepayment penalties and balloon payments; and (4) the consumer's responsibilities to pay taxes and insurance with respect to such product. Requires mortgage brokers to maintain a bond that inures, first, to the benefit of any consumer who has any claim against the mortgage broker under this Act. Prohibits: (1) mortgage brokers from steering a consumer to a higher-cost mortgage than one for which the consumer would otherwise qualify; and (2) waiver by a consumer of the requirements imposed upon a mortgage broker under this Act. Requires disclosure of specified affiliations on the part of persons involved in the home mortgage loan process.</summary>
</bill>
