<bill session="111" type="s" number="815" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to exempt surviving spouses of United States citizens from the numerical limitations described in section 201 of such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4369-4370"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4370" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to allow an alien widow of a U.S. citizen who was married for less than two years at the time of the citizen spouse's death who proves by a preponderance of the evidence that the marriage was entered into in good faith and not for the purpose of obtaining an immigration benefit to self-petition (within the required two years) for continued immediate relative status. Applies such provision to all applications and petitions pending on or after the date of enactment of this Act. Extends the petition filing deadline for two years after the date of enactment of this Act for an alien spouse if: (1) the U.S. citizen spouse died before the date of enactment of this Act; (2) the alien and the citizen spouse were married for less than two years at the time of the citizen spouse's death; and (3) the alien has not remarried.</summary>
</bill>
