<bill session="109" type="sr" number="370" updated="2013-07-19T20:10:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-08">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution honoring the sacrifice and courage of the 16 coal miners killed in various mine disasters in West Virginia, and recognizing the rescue crews for their outstanding efforts in the aftermath of the tragedies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2006-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-02-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S870-871" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S871" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S868-869" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="hc" number="331"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Industrial accidents"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2006--Passed Senate without amendment.
Recognizes Thomas Anderson, Alva Martin Bennett, Jim Bennett, Jerry Groves, George Hamner Jr., Terry Helms, David Lewis, Martin Toler, Fred Ware Jr., Jack Weaver, Jesse Jones, and Marshall Winans for their sacrifice in the Sago, West Virginia, coal mine. Recognizes Don Israel Bragg and Ellery "Elvis" Hatfield for their sacrifice in the Aracoma Alma, West Virginia, coal mine. Extends the deepest condolences of the Nation to the families of these men. Recognizes Edmund Vance and Paul Moss for their sacrifice in the Boone County, West Virginia, coal mines. Recognizes Randal McCloy for his stamina and courage that enabled him to survive in severe conditions for over 40 hours. Recognizes the rescue crews for their outstanding effort resulting in the safe rescue of Randal McCloy. Recognizes the many volunteers who provided support for the miners' families during the rescue operations.</summary>
</bill>
