<bill session="111" type="s" number="579" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Tobacco Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a comprehensive Federal tobacco product regulatory program, to create a Tobacco Regulatory Agency, to prevent use of tobacco products by youth, and to provide protections for adult tobacco product users through the regulation of the tobacco products manufacturing industry.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2009-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2009--Introduced.
Federal Tobacco Act of 2009 - Establishes the Tobacco Regulatory Agency within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), but not as part of the Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Sets forth criteria by which tobacco products are deemed adulterated or misbranded. Establishes limits on tobacco product advertising, promotion, and marketing related to youth, including: (1) prohibiting the use of any cartoon; (2) restricting the use of any human image; (3) prohibiting sponsorship of certain athletic events; and (4) limiting the sale of small packages of cigarettes. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to reduce federal substance abuse grants for states that: (1) do not have in effect a statute setting forth specific provisions to prevent the sale of tobacco products to minors; or (2) spend less than the recommended amount of tobacco settlement agreement funds on tobacco control programs. Prohibits the use of certain descriptors in the packaging and advertising of cigarettes. Requires an approved application under this Act for any reduced-exposure or reduced-risk claim. Directs the Administrator of the Agency to establish standards and procedures for ranking tobacco products and nicotine-containing products based on the relative risks of serious or chronic tobacco-related diseases and adverse health conditions. Requires tobacco product manufacturers to publicly disclose a list of the ingredients in each of their tobacco products. Establishes testing and reporting requirements for tobacco products to determine nicotine and tar yields. Sets forth provisions governing disclosures on tobacco product packaging. Directs the Administrator to assess an annual user fee on each tobacco product manufacturer.</summary>
</bill>
