<bill session="110" type="s" number="1169" updated="2013-07-19T22:30:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State-Based Health Care Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure the provision of high quality health care coverage for uninsured individuals through State health care coverage pilot projects that expand coverage and access and improve quality and efficiency in the health care system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2007-04-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5077-5079"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/19/2007--Introduced.
State-Based Health Care Reform Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a Health Care Coverage Task Force to: (1) approve state, local, or tribal applications for a health care coverage grant; (2) submit a legislative proposal concerning such approvals and recommendations on the level of funding required; and (3) establish minimum performance measures with respect to coverage, quality, and cost of state health care programs.Prohibits the Task Force from approving an application that: (1) proposes to adopt more restrictive criteria for eligibility determinations for any federal, state, or local health care program; or (2) would result in making individuals enrolled in federal health programs ineligible.Requires states seeking a matching grant to submit to the Task Force a state health care plan that: (1) designates the lead state entity that will be responsible for administering the program; (2) describes the benefits that will be provided to all covered individuals; (3) describes the number and percentage of currently uninsured individuals who will achieve coverage; (4) describes how the state will ensure that an increased number of individuals residing within the state will have expanded access to health care coverage; (5) includes provisions to improve the effectiveness and efficiency of health care in the state; and (6) complies with premium and cost sharing limitations.Sets forth procedures for congressional consideration of legislative proposals and recommendations.Authorizes appropriations for the grant program and specifies offsetting savings and fee provisions. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise requirements for the reduction in the Medicare part B premium subsidy based on income.</summary>
</bill>
