<bill session="113" type="s" number="1502" updated="2013-11-02T07:04:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Meat and Poultry Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to protect against foodborne illnesses, provide enhanced notification of recalled meat, poultry, eggs, and related food products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2013--Introduced.
Safe Meat and Poultry Act of 2013 - Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act, the Poultry Products Inspection Act, and the Egg Products Inspection Act (the Acts) to include in the definition of "adulterated" a product bearing or containing a pathogen or contaminant associated with serious illness or death. Amends the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 to: (1) define specified food safety terms, and (2) set forth civil penalties for food safety law violations. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to: (1) identify significant foodborne disease pathogens, (2) determine levels of food product contamination, (3) establish public health goals to reduce foodborne illness, (4) prescribe pathogen reduction performance standards and implement a sampling program to determine food establishment compliance, (5) establish an accredited meat and meat food product testing program, and (6) implement adulterated food tracing protocols. Requires certain food establishments to sample for the presence of identified pathogens at any production or processing point. Permits banning food imports from countries refusing inspections by the Secretary. Sets forth notice and recall provisions. Requires the Secretary to: (1) maintain an active surveillance system of food, food products, and epidemiological evidence; (2) assess the frequency and sources of food-caused human illness; (3) establish guidelines for a system to take and analyze food samples; (4) establish a national public education program on food safety; and (5) conduct specified research concerning food safety. Establishes penalties under the Acts for the introduction into commerce of unsafe or misbranded products of up to $100,000, 20 years' imprisonment, or both. Requires a study of worker safety in the meat packing and poultry processing industry, including the relationship between line speed and worker safety.</summary>
</bill>
