<bill session="112" type="h" number="2388" updated="2013-07-20T01:31:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Access to Timely Information Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the submission of information by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400279"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR08" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2011--Introduced.
Access to Timely Information Act - Deems the submission of information by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of either the House of Representatives or the Senate in response to a request by the chairman or ranking member (or designee) of such Committees or of a subcommittee such Committees to be: (1) a covered disclosure of certain records maintained on individuals submitted without the written request or prior written consent of the individual to whom the record pertains; and (2) a permitted disclosure under regulations promulgated under specified provisions of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, including certain authorized oversight activities. Directs the Secretary, when responding to a request for information by such a member other than a chairman, to also submit such information to the relevant House or Senate Committee chairman.</summary>
</bill>
