<bill session="112" type="h" number="6224" updated="2013-07-20T02:03:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Providing Assistance with the Paperwork from Excessive Regulations Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 44 of the United States Code, to provide for the suspension of fines under certain circumstances for first-time paperwork violations by small entities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412417"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-26">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-26">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1770"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="128"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2012--Introduced.
Providing Assistance with the Paperwork from Excessive Regulations Act of 2012 - Amends the Paperwork Reduction Act to direct agency heads not to impose a civil fine for a first-time paperwork violation by a small business concern unless: (1) there is potential for serious harm to the public interest; (2) the detection of criminal activity would be impaired; (3) the violation is a violation of an internal revenue law or a law concerning the assessment or collection of any tax, debt, revenue, or receipt; (4) the small business concern fails to correct such violation within six months after receiving notice of the violation; or (5) the violation presents a danger to the public health or safety. Permits an agency to determine that a fine should not be imposed for a violation that presents a danger to public health or safety if the violation is corrected within five days after receipt by the small business concern of notification of the violation in writing. Makes this Act inapplicable to any violation by a small business concern of a requirement regarding the collection of information by an agency if the small business concern previously violated any requirement regarding the collection of information by that agency.</summary>
</bill>
