<bill session="112" type="s" number="3253" updated="2013-07-20T02:44:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">EXCEL Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Expanding Access to Capital for Entrepreneurial Leaders Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to enhance the Small Business Investment Company Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2012-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3638-3639"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3442"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3572"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2012--Introduced.
Expanding Access to Capital for Entrepreneurial Leaders Act or EXCEL Act - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to authorize the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to guarantee the payment of up to $4 billion per fiscal year for debentures or participating securities issued by small business investment companies (SBICs) to encourage the formation and growth of small businesses. Increases the maximum amount of outstanding leverage for two or more commonly-controlled SBICs. Authorizes annual inflationary adjustments of such limits. Directs the Administrator to make publicly available on the SBA website specified fiscal and related information with respect to each SBIC. Allows SBIC licensing fees to be used by the SBA for SBIC program needs other than the costs of licensing examinations. Expresses the sense of Congress that SBICs would benefit from partnerships with community banks and other lenders, and that the Administrator should: (1) increase outreach to such banks and lenders for investment in SBICs; (2) use the Internet to publicize which SBICs are soliciting and making investments in small businesses; (3) partner with governors, mayors, states, and municipalities to increase outreach by SBICs to underserved and rural areas; and (4) revise and update the SBIC program webpage to make it more prominent and user-friendly.</summary>
</bill>
