<bill session="112" type="s" number="840" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Canadian Trash Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish customs user fees for commercial trucks transporting foreign municipal solid waste, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2011-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-18">
      <text>Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-18">
      <text>Rereferred to Senate Committee on Finance by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Re-Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2011--Introduced.
Stop Canadian Trash Act - Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to require the Secretary of the Treasury to charge and collect a $500 fee for the provision of customs services for the arrival of a truck that&#160;is transporting foreign municipal solid waste. Defines "municipal solid waste" to mean waste materials discarded for disposal by households or that were generated by commercial, institutional, municipal, or industrial sources, excluding certain hazardous waste, separated recyclable materials, waste being used solely as feedstock for alternative energy production, segregated medical waste, and solid waste generated incident to the provision of service in interstate, intrastate, foreign, or overseas air transportation. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to require each importer of foreign municipal solid waste to provide, with respect to each truck carrying such waste into U.S. customs territory, the cubic feet, specific type, and content of such waste. Establishes a civil penalty for each failure to provide or falsification of information required by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
