<bill session="113" type="s" number="715" updated="2013-11-02T06:58:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Authorized Rural Water Projects Completion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to use designated funding to pay for construction of authorized rural water projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-32.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2013--Introduced.
Authorized Rural Water Projects Completion Act - Establishes in the Treasury a Reclamation Rural Water Construction Fund, into which the Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit for each of FY2014-FY2030 a specified amount of revenues that would otherwise be deposited in the reclamation fund established by the Reclamation Act of 1902. Authorizes the Secretary to use amounts from the Fund to complete construction of rural water projects that were authorized to be carried out on or before this Act's enactment or for which: (1) a feasibility study has been submitted to the Secretary by September 30, 2012, pursuant to the Rural Water Supply Act of 2006 that recommends construction, (2) an Act of Congress enacted after this Act's enactment has authorized construction. Prohibits the Secretary from using amounts from the Fund to pay for project operation and maintenance costs. Prohibits the Secretary from expending amounts from the Fund until the date on which the Secretary develops: (1) programmatic goals that would enable the completion of construction of the authorized rural water projects as expeditiously as possible and that reflect the goals and priorities identified in the laws authorizing the projects and the goals of the Reclamation Rural Water Supply Act; and (2) funding prioritization criteria that takes into account specified information, including an evaluation of the need for potable water supplies in the affected rural and tribal communities, the completion status of a project, and the financial needs of the affected communities. Terminates the Fund on September 30, 2035.</summary>
</bill>
