<bill session="111" type="h" number="2795" updated="2013-07-19T23:36:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Roadmap Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Roadmap to End Global Hunger and Promote Food Security Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To address global hunger and improve food security through the development and implementation of a comprehensive governmentwide global hunger reduction strategy, the establishment of the White House Office on Global Hunger and Food Security, and the creation of the Permanent Joint Select Committee on Hunger, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400263"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2009-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2817"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2009--Introduced.
Roadmap to End Global Hunger and Promote Food Security Act of 2009 or the Roadmap Act of 2009 - Declares that it shall be U.S. policy to reduce global hunger, advance nutrition, increase food security, and ensure that relevant federal policies and programs: (1) provide emergency response and direct support to vulnerable populations in times of need; (2) increase resilience to and reduce, limit, or mitigate the impact of shocks on vulnerable populations; (3) increase and build the capacity of people and governments to sustainably feed themselves; (4) ensure adequate access to the required calories and nutrients needed to live healthy lives; (5) strengthen the ability of small-scale farmers to sustain and increase their production and livelihoods; and (6) incorporate sustainable and environmentally sound agricultural methods and practices. Establishes in the Executive Office of the President a White House Office on Global Hunger and Food Security. Directs the President to appoint, as head of such Office, a Coordinator on Global Hunger and Food Security to implement a comprehensive government-wide strategy to address global hunger and food security and to ensure that the strategy: (1) contributes to achieving the Millennium Development Goal of reducing global hunger by half not later than 2015 and to advancing the United Nations Comprehensive Framework for Action with respect to global hunger and food security; and (2) is integrated into any review or development of a federal strategy for global development. Requires: (1) the Office to work with all relevant federal departments and agencies; (2) the Coordinator to establish, schedule, and administer a high-level, government-wide global hunger and food security meeting each week; and (3) the Comptroller General to submit to Congress biennial reports evaluating the design, implementation, and federal coordination of the strategy. Establishes a Permanent Joint Select Committee on Hunger. Expresses the sense of Congress that no less than $50.36 billion should be made available for FY2010-FY2014 for federal programs addressing global hunger and food security.</summary>
</bill>
