<bill session="111" type="h" number="2800" updated="2013-07-19T23:37:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Imported Food Safety Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to improve the safety of imported food, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400052"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2009--Introduced.
Imported Food Safety Improvement Act of 2009 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to refuse admission into the United States of any food (or any type of food) from a country, growing area, producer, manufacturer, or shipper if the Secretary determines that such food: (1) has been associated with repeated and separate outbreaks of foodborne disease or has been repeatedly determined to be adulterated; (2) presents a reasonable probability of causing significant adverse health consequences or death; and (3) is likely, without systemic intervention or changes, to cause disease or be adulterated again. Directs the Secretary to rescind such a determination if it is no longer justified because of remedial action or other circumstances. Sets forth procedures for review of such determinations.Authorizes the Secretary to make an emergency determination to refuse admission to food that has been strongly associated with a single outbreak of foodborne disease that has caused serious adverse health consequences or death. Requires that any refusal to admit food under this Act be done in a manner consistent with bilateral, regional, and multilateral trade agreements. Provides that nothing in this Act shall be interpreted to diminish the authority of the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (FDA) to ensure the safety of food.</summary>
</bill>
