<bill session="110" type="h" number="6583" updated="2013-07-19T22:01:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tribal Law and Order Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Indian Law Enforcement Reform Act, the Indian Tribal Justice Act, the Indian Tribal Justice Technical and Legal Assistance Act of 2000, and the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to improve the prosecution of, and response to, crimes in Indian country, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400443"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2008-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, Energy and Commerce, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3320"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2008--Introduced.
Tribal Law and Order Act of 2008 - Amends the Indian Law Enforcement Reform Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to submit to Congress a long-term plan to address incarceration in Indian country. Authorizes each U.S. Attorney serving a district that includes Indian country to appoint Special Assistant U.S. Attorneys to prosecute crimes in Indian country when the crime rate, or the rate at which criminal offenses are declined to be prosecuted, exceeds the national average. Establishes in the Department of Justice's (DOJ) criminal division an Office of Indian Country Crime.Requires the United States to maintain concurrent jurisdiction to prosecute serious crimes in Indian country under specified circumstances. Authorizes the Attorney General to provide assistance to state, tribal, and local governments that enter into cooperative agreements to improve law enforcement effectiveness and reduce crime in and around Indian country.Directs the Attorney General to ensure that tribal law enforcement officials that meet applicable requirements have access to national crime information databases. Establishes: (1) the Indian Law and Order Commission to conduct a comprehensive study of law enforcement and criminal justice in tribal communities and recommend improvements to justice systems at the tribal, federal, and state levels; and (2) within the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), an Office of Indian Alcohol and Substance Abuse.Provides for: (1) the tracking of crimes committed in Indian country and grants to improve tribal data collection systems; (2) training in interviewing victims of domestic and sexual violence and collecting, preserving, and presenting evidence to prosecutors; (3) the development of victim services and victim advocate training programs; and (4) the development of standardized sexual assault policies and protocol.</summary>
</bill>
