<bill session="110" type="h" number="6767" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Target Practice and Marksmanship Training Support Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate the establishment of additional or expanded public target ranges in certain States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1660"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2008--Introduced.
Target Practice and Marksmanship Training Support Act - Amends the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act to limit the federal share of the cost of acquiring land for, or construction or expansion of, public target ranges in eligible states to 90% of such cost. Defines "eligible state" to mean a state that, since the most recent decennial census, has experienced: (1) at least a 2% growth in population; and (2) a reduction in the acreage of federal lands in such state where target practice and marksmanship training are permitted. Specifies that amounts made available and apportioned for grants that are provided to eligible states under the firearm and bow hunter education and safety program for acquiring land for, or construction or expansion of, public target ranges shall remain available until they are expended. Permits not more than 10% of the amounts apportioned to an eligible state under the Act for such state's wildlife conservation and restoration program to be used for acquiring land for, or construction or expansion of, public target ranges or for assisting a federal land-management agency with environmental remediation or other steps needed to allow for public target ranges on federal lands.</summary>
</bill>
