<bill session="112" type="s" number="973" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Endowment for the Oceans Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to create the National Endowment for the Oceans to promote the protection and conservation of the United States ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes ecosystems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2011-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2011-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2941-2942"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2011--Introduced.
National Endowment for the Oceans Act - Establishes in the Treasury the National Endowment for the Oceans which shall fund grants for programs to restore, protect, maintain, or understand living marine resources and their habitats, and ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources, including baseline scientific research, ocean observing, and other programs in coordination with federal and state agencies. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to make grants for such purposes. Requires state matching funds for specified projects. States that programs funded in Great Lakes states shall also seek to attain the goals embodied in the Great Lakes Restoration Initiative Plan, the Great Lakes Regional Collaboration Strategy, the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement, or other collaborative planning efforts of the Great Lakes Region. Directs the Secretary to make grants to: (1) coastal states or affected Indian tribes, and (2) regional planning bodies to create and implement regional strategic plans. Directs the Secretary to establish a National Endowment for the Oceans Council.</summary>
</bill>
