<bill session="111" type="h" number="4492" updated="2013-07-19T23:52:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Metropolitan Medical Response System Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to ensure continuation of the Metropolitan Medical Response System Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412250"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM12" subcommittee="Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4580"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4580"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/2010--Introduced.
Metropolitan Medical Response System Program Act of 2009 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to conduct a Metropolitan Medical Response System Program that shall assist state and local governments in preparing for and responding to public health and mass casualty incidents resulting from natural disasters, terrorist acts, and other man-made disasters. (Repeals provisions of the Post-Katrina Management Reform Act of 2006 regarding a Metropolitan Medical Response Program.)Authorizes the Secretary, through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), to make grants to state and local governments for such purposes. Authorizes the use of grant funds to support the integration of emergency management, health, and medical systems into a coordinated response to mass casualty incidents caused by any hazard.Sets forth eligibility requirements. Directs the Administrator to ensure that each jurisdiction that receives a grant, as a condition of receiving such grant, is actively coordinating its preparedness efforts with surrounding jurisdictions, with the official with primary responsibility for homeland security (other than the governor) of the government of the state in which the jurisdiction is located, and with emergency response providers from all relevant disciplines, to effectively enhance regional preparedness.Requires the Administrator: (1) in coordination with the Assistant Secretary, Office of Health Affairs, and a National Metropolitan Medical Response System Working Group, to issue performance measures that enable objective evaluation of the performance and effective use of funds provided in any jurisdiction; and (2) together with the Assistant Secretary and the Working Group, to conduct a review of the Program.</summary>
</bill>
