<bill session="109" type="h" number="117" updated="2013-07-19T19:05:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Higher Education Affordability and Fairness Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make higher education more affordable by providing a tax deduction for higher education expenses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2005-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2005-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E17"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="21st Century Competitiveness" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tuition tax credits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2005--Introduced.
Higher Education Affordability and Fairness Act of 2005 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the tax deduction for qualified higher education tuition and related expenses. Makes such tax deduction permanent. Increases adjusted gross income limits for purposes of determining the allowable amount of the Hope Scholarship tax credit. Directs the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct an annual study to examine whether the Federal income tax incentives to provide education assistance affect higher education tuition rates in order to identify if institutions of higher education are absorbing the intended savings by raising tuition rates. Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the maximum Pell Grant should be increased to $4,700 to pay approximately: (1) 20 percent of the tuition, fees, room and board, and other expenses of the average college; or (2) the tuition and fees of the average public college.</summary>
</bill>
