<bill session="111" type="h" number="2858" updated="2013-07-19T23:37:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Quality Improvement Organization Modernization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles XI and XVIII of the Social Security Act to modernize the quality improvement organization (QIO) program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2009-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2009--Introduced.
Medicare Quality Improvement Organization Modernization Act of 2009 - Amends title XI of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require utilization and quality control peer review organizations to offer quality improvement assistance to providers, practitioners, Medicare Advantage organizations under part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare), and prescription drug sponsors under part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of such title. Allows an organization to provide de-identified patient data to providers treating the same population of patients for the purpose of measuring and improving the safety, quality, and effectiveness of patient transitions from one service provider to another. Requires the organization to establish a Medicare quality accountability program. Adds a program administration component under part B (Peer Review) of SSA title XI. Directs the Secretary to ensure that Quality Improvement Organizations (QIOs) are provided maximum freedom in designing and applying intervention strategies for local quality improvement. Revises requirements for the quality improvement program, including use of evaluation and competition, quality improvement funding, and qualifications for QIOs. Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to require state medical assistance plans to provide for an alternative quality improvement program.</summary>
</bill>
