<bill session="112" type="hr" number="389" updated="2013-07-20T01:06:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing persons of African descent in Europe during the International Year for People of African Descent.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1508"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe and Eurasia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA14" subcommittee="Europe and Eurasia" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="26"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Hate crimes"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2011--Introduced.
Supports the goals of the International Year for People of African Descent. Reaffirms the importance of the full and equal participation of people of African descent around the world in all aspects of political, economic, social, and cultural life. Recognizes that as a result of their skin color and ancestry many Black Europeans have experienced injustices in the public and private sector. Urges: (1) European governments and members of civil society and the private sector, in consultation with Black European communities, to develop initiatives to combat racial discrimination and promote racial equality in Europe; and (2) the Secretary of State to provide support for such initiatives. Supports the adoption of a Joint Action Plan on Racial and Ethnic Equality and Inclusion between the European Union (EU) and United States and implementation of the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) Parliamentary Assembly 2011 Resolution on Strengthening Efforts to Combat Racism and Xenophobia and Foster Inclusion.</summary>
</bill>
