<bill session="109" type="h" number="5610" updated="2013-07-19T19:53:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Anti-Sex Offender Protection Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent sex offenders from using immigration laws to bring innocent, unsuspecting victims into the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400657" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2006-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marriage"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Wife abuse"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/2006--Introduced.
Foreign Anti-Sex Offender Protection Act of 2006 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to deny a family-based immigration petition by a U.S. petitioner for an alien spouse or child if: (1) the Secretary has confirmed that the petitioner is on the national sex offender registry for a conviction that individually resulted in incarceration for more than one year; (2) the petitioner has been given at least 90 days to rebut such information and has failed to do so; and (3) the Secretary finds that granting the petition would put a primary or derivative spouse or child beneficiary in grave danger of being sexually abused. Directs the Secretary to base such petitioner evaluation upon: (1) the nature of the relationship; (2) the nature of the sex offense; (3) rehabilitation; and (4) previous visa petitions. Directs the Secretary to provide the petitioner with a notice that states the reasons for the intended denial and provides the petitioner with at least 90 days to submit rebuttal evidence. Provides post-denial remedies through: (1) the Board of Immigration Appeals; and (2) a new petition filing based on additional evidence. States that where the Secretary has confirmed that the petitioner is listed on the national sex offender registry: (1) an interview with the alien spouse, and any alien sons or daughters, shall be required prior to removal of conditional permanent resident status; and (2) if there is abuse or harm by the petitioner the victim shall be offered appropriate assistance, including information on ways to remain in the United State that do not depend on continuing the qualifying marriage. Provides a hardship waiver in cases of sexual abuse of the alien spouse or child. Directs the Secretary to establish the Task Force to Rescue Immigrant Victims of American Sex Offenders.</summary>
</bill>
