<bill session="112" type="s" number="2145" updated="2013-07-20T02:35:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Playing Field Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permit the Secretary of the Treasury to issue prospective guidance clarifying the employment status of individuals for purposes of employment taxes and to prevent retroactive assessments with respect to such clarifications.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2012-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="4123"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5727"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6653"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2252"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2012--Introduced.
Fair Playing Field Act of 2012 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the classification of workers for employment tax purposes, to: (1) repeal the prohibition against issuance of regulations and guidance by the Secretary of the Treasury on workers' employment tax status (i.e., as an employee or as an independent contractor) enacted by the Revenue Act of 1978; (2) direct the Secretary to issue regulations and other guidance to clarify the proper employment status of workers for employment tax purposes; (3) prohibit a retroactive assessment of employment tax, except with respect to certain skilled workers, for tax periods after December 31, 1978, and before a specified reclassification date for worker misclassifications, unless the taxpayer had no reasonable basis for not treating a worker as an employee; (4) require taxpayers who hire independent contractors on a regular and ongoing basis to provide such contractors with notice of their federal tax obligations, the labor and employment law protections that do not apply to them, and their right to seek a status determination from the Internal Revenue Service (IRS); and (5) eliminate reduced penalty provisions for failure to withhold income taxes for taxpayers who lack a reasonable basis for treating a worker as other than an employee (i.e., as an independent contractor). Provides that for purposes of determining whether a registered representative of a securities broker-dealer is an employee for employment tax purposes, no weight shall be given to instructions from a service recipient which are imposed only in compliance with investor protection standards. Makes this rule applicable to services performed by a broker-dealer after December 31, 1997.</summary>
</bill>
