<bill session="113" type="h" number="414" updated="2013-11-02T06:22:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the continued lease or eventual conveyance of certain Federal land within the boundaries of Fort Wainwright Military Reservation in Fairbanks, Alaska.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E55"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/23/2013--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Army (the Secretary) to offer to extend, for one or more periods of 15 years, the current lease involving a parcel of Bureau of Land Management (BLM) land in Fairbanks, Alaska, that was withdrawn for military use and is administered as a part of Fort Wainwright Military Reservation and that contains a 400-home rental housing community (the covered land). Requires the Secretary, if the Secretary intends to offer any extension of the lease, to provide a written notice of such offer to the current lessee and the Secretary of the Interior before the lease expires. Authorizes the Secretary, upon the expiration of the lease, to convey the covered land, if the lease is not extended. Requires the concurrence of the Secretary of the Interior for such conveyance. Allows the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to waive such conveyance requirement if it is determined that the retention and military use of the covered land are in the national security interests of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
