<bill session="112" type="s" number="79" updated="2013-07-20T02:17:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Pregnant Women and Children From Hexavalent Chromium Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to protect the health of vulnerable individuals, including pregnant women, infants, and children, by requiring a health advisory and drinking water standard for hexavalent chromium.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4266"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2011--Introduced.
Protecting Pregnant Women and Children From Hexavalent Chromium Act of 2011 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) publish a health advisory for hexavalent chromium that is fully protective of the health of vulnerable individuals (including pregnant women, infants, and children), taking into consideration body weight, exposure patterns, and all routes of exposure; and (2) establish a national primary drinking water regulation for hexavalent chromium that is protective of vulnerable individuals and the maximum contaminant level of which is as close to the maximum contaminant level goal for hexavalent chromium, and as protective of vulnerable individuals, as is feasible.</summary>
</bill>
