<bill session="112" type="h" number="105" updated="2013-07-20T01:11:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Empowering Patients First Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Help Efficient, Accessible, Low-cost, Timely Healthcare (HEALTH) Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and related health-care provisions and to enact in its place incentives to encourage health insurance coverage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, Education and the Workforce, Natural Resources, House Administration, Ways and Means, the Judiciary, Rules, Appropriations, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Organization, Efficiency, and Financial Management     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO24" subcommittee="Government Organization, Efficiency, and Financial Management" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1050"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3000"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5652"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6299"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1099"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
Empowering Patients First Act - Repeals the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and&#160;the health care provisions of the Health Care and Education and Reconciliation Act of 2010, effective as of their enactment. Restores or revives provisions amended or repealed by&#160;such Act or such health care provisions. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for qualified health insurance costs to residents of a state that implements a high-risk pool, a reinsurance pool, or other risk-adjustment mechanism. Amends the Public Health Service Act to provide for the establishment and governance of individual membership associations (IMAs) to make available health benefits coverage to IMA members and their dependents. Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2011 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for establishment and governance of association health plans, which are group health plans whose sponsors are trade, industry, professional, chamber of commerce, or similar business associations and which meet certain ERISA certification requirements. Directs that the laws of the state designated by a health insurance issuer (primary state) shall apply to individual health insurance coverage offered by that issuer in the primary state and in any other state (secondary state), but only if the coverage and issuer comply with conditions of this Act. Amends title XXI (Children's Health Insurance) (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to: (1) require a state CHIP plan to specify how it will achieve coverage for 90% of targeted low-income children; and (2) prohibit CHIP payments for children with family income above 300% of the applicable poverty line. Help Efficient, Accessible, Low-cost, Timely Healthcare (HEALTH) Act of 2011 - Sets conditions for lawsuits arising from health care liability claims regarding health care goods or services or any medical product affecting interstate commerce. Establishes a statute of limitations and limits noneconomic and punitive damages. Permits a group health plan to vary premiums and cost-sharing by up to 50% of the benefits based on participation (or lack of participation) in a wellness program. Requires a health insurance issuer to provide claims information, on request, to a plan, plan sponsor, or plan administrator. Prohibits the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) from using comparative effectiveness research to deny coverage of an item or service under a federal health care program. Authorizes a state to establish a Health Plan and Provider Portal website to standardize information on health insurance plans available in the state. Revises the formula for determining rates in the fee schedule for Medicare physician payments. Sets forth provisions regarding students loans and loan repayment for health care professionals. Establishes discretionary spending limits for FY2011-FY2020 for new budget authority in the nondefense category.&#160; Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to reinstate budget provisions related to deficit reductions during a recession. Rescinds unobligated balances of certain discretionary appropriations made available under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009. Repeals other provisions of such Act, including provisions providing fiscal assistance to states and setting limits on executive compensation.</summary>
</bill>
