<bill session="112" type="h" number="3331" updated="2013-07-20T01:39:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FARE Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Accounting of Renewable Energy Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require an accounting for financial support made to promote the production or use of renewable energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2011-11-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-02">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-02">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1556"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/2/2011--Introduced.
Federal Accounting of Renewable Energy Act of 2011 or FARE Act of 2011 - Requires the head of each federal agency to submit to Congress an accounting for all FY2009-FY2011 financial support (including grants, loans, loan guarantees, and direct payments) made by the agency to promote the production or use of renewable energy. Directs the agencies to include in such accounting: (1) a list of the projects that directly led to the production or use of renewable energy; (2) the quantity of renewable energy or products on the market as a direct result of such support and the gross sales of the recipient company during a recent fiscal year; and (3) the total quantity of financial support, the number of jobs created, and the average cost to the recipient company of each full-time job created. Requires, for each project, a full accounting of: (1) the employment, sales, and revenue targets submitted by each recipient company before receiving support and a list of the companies that substantially failed to meet targets; (2) a list of all recipient companies that received support but are no longer in operation or have moved any portion of their operations to a location outside the United States; and (3) a list of all venture capital firms involved in submitting the proposal for awarded support. Directs the Inspector General of an agency that provided support to a company that is no longer in existence, or is unlikely to achieve substantially the purpose of the support, to conduct a preliminary investigation of the documents submitted by the company to determine whether fraud was committed in obtaining such support. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to prohibit the Secretary of Energy (DOE) from guaranteeing a project loan unless an independent review, paid for by the applicant, demonstrates the applicant's ability to repay such loan.</summary>
</bill>
