<bill session="111" type="s" number="2770" updated="2013-07-20T00:50:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Business Center Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to establish a Veterans Business Center program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1803"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2352"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/2009--Introduced.
Veterans Business Center Act of 2009 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish within the SBA a Veterans Business Center program (program), headed by a Director, to provide entrepreneurial training and counseling to veterans. Requires the Director to establish a program of grants to centers that will develop specialized programs to assist veteran-owned small businesses in securing capital and repairing damaged credit, counsel on how to improve financial presentations, facilitate access to financing, and assist unemployed veterans become entrepreneurs. Requires the Director to establish a program of grants to centers to: (1) assist veteran-owned small businesses to identify contracts that are suitable to such businesses; (2) prepare veteran-owned small businesses to be ready as subcontractors and prime contractors for contracts made available through the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, particularly with respect to the construction trades; and (3) provide veteran-owned small businesses technical assistance with respect to the federal procurement process. Requires the Director to establish a program of grants to centers to develop outreach programs for service-disabled veterans to promote self-employment opportunities and to train and assist such veterans with respect to developing business plans and securing business opportunities. Authorizes the Director to carry out a veterans entrepreneurial development summit. Requires an annual report from the Administrator to Congress on appointments made to, and activities of, the interagency task force on veteran-owned small businesses. Directs the Comptroller General to carry out a study of the effects of this Act on small businesses owned and controlled by veterans.</summary>
</bill>
