<bill session="112" type="h" number="1778" updated="2013-07-20T01:25:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Construction Quality Assurance Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assure quality and best value with respect to Federal construction projects by prohibiting the practice known as bid shopping.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2011-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E829-830"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform     .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO30" subcommittee="Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2011--Introduced.
Construction Quality Assurance Act of 2011 - Requires each solicitation by an executive agency for the procurement of construction in excess of $1 million to require each bidder to submit the name, business location, and nature of work of each subcontractor with whom such bidder will subcontract for work in excess of $100,000. Deems to be non-responsive, and prohibits consideration of, any bidder that fails to list such subcontractors. Prohibits a contractor from substituting another subcontractor for a listed subcontractor, permitting any subcontract to be voluntarily assigned or transferred, or subcontracting work for which the contractor listed itself, except with the consent of the contracting officer for good cause. Sets forth: (1) examples of good cause and procedures required for substitution requests; and (2) penalties for violations of substitution prohibitions, including suspension or debarment from federal contracts for multiple violations. Requires revisions to the Federal Acquisition Regulation to implement this Act.</summary>
</bill>
