<bill session="111" type="h" number="5469" updated="2013-07-20T00:01:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Service Members Permanent Change of Station Relief Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase the mileage reimbursement rate for members of the armed services during permanent change of station and to authorize the transportation of additional motor vehicles of members on change of permanent station to or from nonforeign areas outside the continental United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400659"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2010-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3150"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/28/2010--Introduced.
Service Members Permanent Change of Station Relief Act - Sets at the business standard mileage rate of the Internal Revenue Service the monetary allowance for a member of the Armed Forces for travel by privately owned vehicles in lieu of government transportation in the case of: (1) a change of permanent station; (2) travel to the first station upon call to active duty; and (3) travel from a last duty station upon separation from service. Sets the monetary allowance for authorized travel by a member's dependent at the rate per mile established by the Administrator of General Services instead of the actual expenses for such transportation. Revises requirements allowing the transport at government expense of one motor vehicle owned or leased by a member (or member's dependent) to the new station of the member who has been ordered to make a change of permanent station. Authorizes the transport at government expense of one additional motor vehicle of a member (or member's dependent) if: (1) the member is ordered to make a change of permanent station to or from a nonforeign area outside the continental United States and the member has at least one dependent of driving age who will use the motor vehicle; or (2) the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that a replacement for the transported motor vehicle is necessary for reasons beyond the member's control and is in the interest of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
