<bill session="112" type="h" number="5794" updated="2013-07-20T02:00:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Debt Collection Practices Clarification Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to exempt a debt collector from liability when leaving certain voice mail messages for a consumer with respect to a debt as long as the debt collector follows regulations prescribed by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection on the appropriate manner in which to leave such a message, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4101"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2012--Introduced.
Fair Debt Collection Practices Clarification Act of 2012 - Amends the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to revise the disclaimer of liability for any act done or omitted in good faith in conformity with any advisory opinion of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB). Exempts from liability, in addition, acts done or omitted in good faith in compliance with any rule, regulation, or interpretation of the CFPB, or in conformity with any interpretation or approval by a CFPB official or employee duly authorized to issue such interpretations or approvals. Permits a debt collector to leave messages for a consumer regarding the collection of a debt on the consumer's answering machine, voice messaging system, or similar device, including in an initial communication with the consumer, so long as the message complies with regulations prescribed by the CFPB to ensure the preservation of consumer privacy and other rights, including restrictions on communications with third parties. Prohibits a debt collector from initiating a legal action on a debt in an arbitration setting, or requiring the consumer to resolve by arbitration a collection-related dispute on the debt, unless the consumer has agreed in writing to resolution by arbitration after collections activities have been initiated and a legal action or dispute has arisen.</summary>
</bill>
