<bill session="109" type="sr" number="591" updated="2013-07-19T20:11:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution calling for the strengthening of the efforts of the United States to defeat the Taliban and terrorist networks in Afghanistan and to help Afghanistan develop long-term political stability and economic prosperity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S10748-10749" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Opium"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States must strengthen its commitment to establishing stability and peace in Afghanistan; (2) the United States, in partnership with the International Security Assistance Force (ISAF) and the government of Afghanistan, must increase its efforts to eradicate the Taliban, terrorist organizations, and criminal networks currently operating in Afghanistan; (3) the United States, in consultation with ISAF and the government of Afghanistan, should consider all options necessary to implement a comprehensive new program to eliminate opium production in Afghanistan; (4) the United States should work to hold the international community accountable for delivering on financial pledges made to support development and reconstruction efforts in Afghanistan; (5) the United States and the international community, in concert with the government of Afghanistan, should increase efforts to strengthen the legitimacy of the government of Afghanistan; (6) the United States should increase economic assistance for reconstruction, social and economic development, counternarcotics efforts, and democracy promotion in Afghanistan; (7) the President, through the Secretary of State, should develop a comprehensive interagency stabilization and reconstruction strategy in coordination with the international community and the government of Afghanistan; (8) the President, through the Secretary of Defense, should evaluate the impact that U.S. military operations in Iraq are having on U.S. government reconstruction and counterinsurgency efforts in Afghanistan; and (9) the President should present to Congress a status report on Afghanistan.</summary>
</bill>
