<bill session="109" type="h" number="4731" updated="2013-07-19T19:46:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Eliminate Warehousing of Consumer Internet Data Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require owners of Internet websites to destroy obsolete data containing personal information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E91"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2006--Introduced.
Eliminate Warehousing of Consumer Internet Data Act of 2006 - Requires an owner of an Internet website to destroy, within a reasonable time frame, any data containing personal information if the information: (1) is no longer necessary for the purpose for which it was collected or any other legitimate business purpose; or (2) there are no pending requests or orders for access to such information pursuant to a court order. Treats a violation of this Act as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under the Federal Trade Commission Act. Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act were incorporated into and made part of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
