<bill session="109" type="h" number="5040" updated="2013-07-19T19:48:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Death Penalty Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the law with respect to the death penalty, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400651"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homicide"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Juries"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mentally disabled"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Public defenders"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2006--Introduced.
Death Penalty Reform Act of 2006 - Amends the federal criminal code to modify substantive law and procedures relating to the death penalty. Adds certain crimes that result in death, including obstruction of justice, as aggravating factors in death penalty deliberations. Defines "mentally retarded" for death penalty purposes. Requires a defendant to give notice to the government of any mitigating factors, including mental retardation, which the defendant intends to present in a death penalty proceeding. Grants the government the right to an independent mental health examination of a defendant claiming mental retardation. Grants the Attorney General regulatory authority over the implementation of the death penalty. Repeals the prohibition against executing a person who is mentally retarded. Grants the government an unlimited right to rehearings of a finding of mental incapacity in death penalty cases. Requires a court in a death penalty case to: (1) assign a second attorney for the defendant when the government files a notice of intent to seek a sentence of death (currently, assignment is required upon indictment); and (2) permit the government to strike for cause jurors who oppose the death penalty. Modifies criteria relating to mitigating and aggravating factors in death penalty cases. Authorizes a court in the sentencing phase of a death penalty case to impanel a jury of less than 12 members upon a finding of good cause. Amends the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure to increase the number of alternative jurors and peremptory challenges to such jurors in criminal proceedings.</summary>
</bill>
