<bill session="112" type="h" number="6264" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">GSA Path to Privatization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize a pilot program for Federal agencies to enter into contracts with the private sector for property management, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2012-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2012--Introduced.
GSA Path to Privatization Act - Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to: (1) establish and conduct a pilot program to be known as the Federal Real Property Management Privatization Pilot Program to allow certain federal agencies to contract with the private sector to plan, acquire, manage, and dispose of leased federal property; (2) develop a management plan for such program; (3) issue guidance to federal agencies on participation in the program; and (4) issue a solicitation for contracts with the private sector for services under the program. Terminates the program 15 years after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
