<bill session="112" type="h" number="4361" updated="2013-07-20T01:47:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National High Performance Passenger Rail Transportation-Oriented Development Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote transportation-oriented development and encourage dedicated revenue sources for urban and regional rail corridor development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400318"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2012-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E520"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/16/2012--Introduced.
National High Performance Passenger Rail Transportation-Oriented Development Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to establish an initiative to promote passenger rail operations and transportation-oriented development by creating rail projects qualified for federal incentives for communities to encourage dedicated revenue sources for urban and regional rail corridor development. Amends the Railroad Revitalization and Regulatory Reform Act of 1976 to direct the Secretary to provide direct loans and loan guarantees for qualified rail projects. Authorizes the Secretary to make secured loans, loan guarantees, or lines of credit for such projects. Directs the Secretary to provide technical assistance to: (1) states to identify transportation-oriented development opportunities, (2) states and regions outside the Northeast Corridor to establish Regional Advisory Committees and identify stations and potential stations within the region to maximize development and commercial revenue generation to support financially the development of a high performance rail passenger corridor, and (3) states and entities along the Northeast Corridor to establish a Northeast Corridor Transportation-Oriented Development Working Group and identify Northeast Corridor stations and potential stations to maximize development and commercial revenue generation to support financially the creation of a true high-speed rail corridor in the Northeast Corridor.</summary>
</bill>
