<bill session="110" type="h" number="6830" updated="2013-07-19T22:03:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Forests, Healthy Planet Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to assist in the development and coordination of markets for biomass and carbon trading for private forest landowners, to assure sustainable forest practices in the use of biomass and carbon trading activity, and to enhance the relationship between Federal lands and private forest lands on a regional basis in the biomass and carbon trading markets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412225"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2008-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2008--Introduced.
Healthy Forests, Healthy Planet Act of 2008 - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to the National Forest System, and the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to other federal land, or both Secretaries acting jointly when a Carbon Cooperative Zone will include multiple types of federal land, to: (1) establish Carbon Cooperative Zones consisting of forested federal land and forested land in the same contiguous geographical area in private ownership or owned by a state or local government or Indian tribe; and (2) establish, for each Zone, a Carbon Cooperative and Partnership Council that is comprised of a Carbon Cooperative and a Carbon and Biomass Partnership. Declares the purpose of such Zones to be: (1) identification of viable biofuels and carbon storage market areas from forested land within a contiguous geographic area; (2) management of effects on forest ecosystems from potential activities that drive carbon storage and biofuels markets; (3) management of effects of potential leakage, permanence, and other market distortions in a carbon trading system; and (4) management of the forest carbon registry. Sets forth the duties of the Council, Cooperative, and Partnership, including requiring the Council to: (1) coordinate the land ownership plans of partnering entities in the corresponding Cooperative in order to sustain forest ecosystems in the Zone while developing the biomass and carbon storage markets of the Zone; (2) administer the Forest Carbon Registry for the Zone; and (3) establish the forest carbon baseline for the Zone and determine all credits due to partnering entities in the Cooperative.Establishes an Environmental Services Standards Board to develop consistent performance standards for quantifying carbon storage credits to facilitate the development of credit markets for conservation and land management activities that are forest based. Requires: (1) the Secretary of Agriculture to serve as the Board's chairperson; and (2) such Board to promulgate rules for tradable forest carbon credits and a forest carbon replacement reserve.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise provisions concerning credits for energy produced within such Zones and credits for forest biomass producers.Authorizes the Secretary concerned to make grants for small energy generation facilities where the output is expected to be used within a single Zone.Requires biomass production from federal lands to be generated through forest activities that enhance ecosystem services.</summary>
</bill>
