<bill session="109" type="s" number="3965" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Latina Health Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to address the serious health care access barriers, and consequently higher incidences of disease, for low-income, uninsured populations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10461"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10462" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Asthma"/>
    <term name="Birth control"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular diseases"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2006--Introduced.
Latina Health Access Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act (PHSA) to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants for programs and activities that provide health care services to uninsured and low-income individuals in medically underserved areas. Directs that grant funds be used to care for a full spectrum of preventable and treatable health care problems in a culturally and linguistically appropriate manner, including through: (1) family planning services and information; (2) prenatal and postnatal care; and (3) assistance and services with respect to asthma, cancer, HIV disease and AIDS, sexually transmitted diseases, mental health, diabetes, and heart disease. Requires the Secretary to reserve a portion of grants and assistance awarded under the PHSA for entities that represent medically underserved areas or populations with a large number of uninsured low-income individuals. Directs the Secretary to award grants to research institutions to: (1) conduct research on the health status of populations for which there is an absence of health data, such as the Latina population; and (2) work with organizations that focus on such populations on developing participatory community-based research methods. Requires the Secretary to: (1) provide outreach, education, and delivery of comprehensive health services to uninsured and low-income individuals in a culturally competent manner; and (2) carry out a health education program targeted specifically to such individuals through community centered informational forums, public service announcements, and media campaigns.</summary>
</bill>
