<bill session="112" type="s" number="3388" updated="2013-07-20T02:45:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sewage Overflow Community Right-to-Know Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to ensure that sewage treatment plants monitor for and report discharges of raw sewage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2012-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2012--Introduced.
Sewage Overflow Community Right-to-Know Act - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to require owners or operators of publicly owned treatment works to: (1) institute monitoring systems to provide timely alerts of sewer overflows, (2) notify the public not later than 24 hours after receiving knowledge of such overflows in areas where human health is potentially affected, (3) notify public health authorities and other affected entities immediately of an overflow that may imminently and substantially endanger human health, (4) report each overflow on discharge monitoring reports to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) or the state, and (5) annually report to the Administrator or the state on the total number of overflows in a calendar year. Makes specified exceptions to notification and reporting requirements for backups into single-family residences and for overflows that occur in the course of treatment works maintenance, respectively. Requires annual summary reports by states to the Administrator. Requires the Administrator to promulgate regulations, including to establish overflow assessment guidance and develop communications measures to provide notification under this Act. Makes the monitoring systems eligible for state water pollution control revolving fund assistance.</summary>
</bill>
