<bill session="112" type="h" number="6284" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Breath of Fresh Air Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a grant program for nebulizers in elementary and secondary schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1425"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
Breath of Fresh Air Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award matching grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to: (1) purchase nebulizers for use in their schools, and/or (2) train school personnel to use nebulizers. Requires LEA grant applicants to demonstrate that for each of their schools that are to use the nebulizers: (1) a full-time certified nurse is on staff; (2) trained personnel and other resources necessary for nebulizer use are in place; (3) emergency services personnel are notified of nebulizer locations; (4) nebulizers are integrated into the school's emergency response procedures; and (5) procedures are in place to notify parents of the availability of nebulizers, and inform them how to provide the school with their child's prescription asthma medication and authorization to use a nebulizer to assist their child. Gives grant priority to LEAs that: (1) serve areas where the prevalence of asthma is at least 10% higher than the national average; (2) do not already have at least one nebulizer in each of their schools; (3) serve schools that typically have a significant number of students, staff, and visitors present during the day; and (4) have not received funds under the Rural Access to Emergency Devices Act.</summary>
</bill>
