<bill session="111" type="h" number="1963" updated="2013-07-19T23:29:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to ensure that members of the Armed Forces who are being separated from active duty receive comprehensive employment assistance, job training assistance, and other transitional services, to require that such members receive a psychological evaluation in addition to the physical examination they receive as part of their separation from active duty, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2009-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2009-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412313" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
Modifies the requirement that the Secretary concerned provide preseparation counseling to members of the Armed Forces whose discharge or release from active duty is anticipated as of a specific date. Directs the Secretary concerned, including the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security, to require such members to receive, as part of their preseparation counseling, employment assistance, job training assistance, and other transitional services under a specified program established by the Secretary of Labor. Directs the Secretary concerned to require separating Armed Forces members to undergo a psychological evaluation (as well as a physical examination, as under current law).</summary>
</bill>
