<bill session="109" type="s" number="2617" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Retirees Health Care Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to limit increases in the costs to retired members of the Armed Forces of health care services under the TRICARE program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2006-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2006-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2006-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2006-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3388"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3388-3389" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/2006--Introduced.
Military Retirees Health Care Protection Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Department of Defense (DOD) and the nation have a committed obligation to provide health benefits to retired military personnel that exceeds the obligation of corporate employers to their employees; (2) DOD has many additional options to constrain the growth of health care spending in ways that do not disadvantage retirees, and should pursue such options rather than seeking large fee increases for retirees and their dependents; and (3) any percentage increase in health care fees, deductibles, or copayments for retirees and their families, and for members of the Selected Reserve currently serving on active duty and their families, should not exceed the percentage increase in military retired pay or basic pay, respectively. Limits to the previous percentage increase in retired or basic pay the authorized annual fee increase under: (1) the DOD pharmacy benefits program; and (2) certain premiums and other charges under the TRICARE program (a DOD managed health care program). Prohibits: (1) charges for DOD inpatient care from exceeding $535 per day; and (2) charging an enrollment fee under the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services (CHAMPUS).</summary>
</bill>
