<bill session="111" type="h" number="467" updated="2013-07-19T23:16:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Equitable Treatment of State and Local Governments Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To put State and local governments and other public entity or instrumentality established under State law in the same position they would have been in had the Secretary of the Treasury and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System provided emergency financial assistance to Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. by requiring the Secretary of the Treasury to purchase bonds issued by such financial institution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2009-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2009-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412192" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400620" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2009-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/13/2009--Introduced.
Equitable Treatment of State and Local Governments Act of 2009 - Amends the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA) to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to purchase at face value debt instruments issued by Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. which: (1) were held as of September 15, 2008, by any state or local government, or any other public entity or instrumentality established under state law; (2) have been held by such entity continuously since such date; and (3) are subject to bankruptcy proceedings filed on September 15, 2008, by Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. Declares that the Secretary: (1) shall be substituted as a creditor in any bankruptcy proceeding for any state or local government, or any other public entity or instrumentality established under state law from which the Secretary purchases a debt instrument; and (2) has the same standing in such proceedings with respect to other creditors as the state or local government or public entity for which the Secretary is substituted.</summary>
</bill>
