<bill session="109" type="s" number="129" updated="2013-07-19T20:14:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to provide for HOV facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300096"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S317"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S317-319" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Bicycles"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy security"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Liquefied petroleum gas"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Motorcycles"/>
    <term name="Natural gas vehicles"/>
    <term name="Speed limits"/>
    <term name="Toll roads"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Aid Highways program to require a State agency with jurisdiction over the operation of a HOV facility to establish the occupancy requirements of vehicles operating on the facility. Requires such agency to permit motorcycles and bicycles to use the HOV facility. Permits a State agency to restrict use of the HOV facility by motorcycles or bicycles (or both) if it certifies to the Secretary of Transportation that such use would create a safety hazard. Prescribes guidelines under which a State agency may permit use of an HOV facility by: (1) public transportation vehicles and high occupancy toll vehicles; (2) inherently low-emission vehicles and low emission and energy-efficient vehicles; and (3) advanced lean burn technology vehicles. Permits tolls to be charged on a HOV facility on the Interstate System. Requires a State agency that allows low-emission and energy-efficient vehicles to use a HOV facility to certify to the Secretary that it will establish: (1) a continuous monitoring, assessment, and reporting program regarding the impacts such vehicles may have on the operation of the facility and adjacent highways; and (2) an enforcement program that ensures the facility is operated in accordance with this Act. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection to issue a final rule establishing certification requirements for low emission and energy-efficient vehicles and for advanced lean burn technology vehicles.</summary>
</bill>
