<bill session="113" type="hj" number="71" updated="2013-11-02T06:48:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-02T16:19:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-02T16:19:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Provide local funding for the District of Columbia bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">District of Columbia Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations of local funds of the District of Columbia for fiscal year 2014.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400086"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crenshaw moved to suspend the rules and pass the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6077-6082" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6077" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 71.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T19:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6089-6090" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="507" datetime="2013-10-01T19:55:00-04:00" where="h" result="fail" suspension="1" state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the resolution Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 265 - 163 (Roll no. 507).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 370 Reported to House. The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 70, H.J. Res. 71, H.J. Res. 72, H.J. Res. 73, and H.R. 3230. The resolution provides for 30 minutes of debate on each measure and provides for one motion to recommit each measure. The resolution also provides that it shall be in order at any time through the calendar day of October 6, 2013, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T15:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 370.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6133-6138" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T15:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 70, H.J. Res. 71, H.J. Res. 72, H.J. Res. 73, and H.R. 3230. The resolution provides for 30 minutes of debate on each measure and provides for one motion to recommit each measure. The resolution also provides that it shall be in order at any time through the calendar day of October 6, 2013, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T15:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 71.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6138" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2013-10-02T16:19:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6133" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read the first time pursuant to the order of Oct. 2, 2013.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 204 pursuant to the order of Oct. 2, 2013.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="370"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="370"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2013--Passed House without amendment.
District of Columbia Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 - Allows the District of Columbia to expend local funds under the heading "District of Columbia Funds" for such programs and activities under title IV of H.R. 2786 (113th Congress), as reported by the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, at the rate set forth under "District of Columbia Funds--Summary of Expenses" as included in the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Request Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-127), as modified as of the date of the enactment of this joint resolution. Provides such appropriations under the authority and conditions as provided under the Full-Year Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 (division F of P.L. 113-6) and makes them available to the extent and in the manner that would be provided by such Act. Makes appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under this joint resolution available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment into law of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution, (2) enactment into law of the applicable appropriations Act for FY2014 without any provision for such project or activity, or (3) December 15, 2013. Makes appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under this joint resolution available without regard to the time limitations for submission and approval of apportionments, without waiver of any other provision of law governing the apportionment of funds. Expresses the sense of Congress that this joint resolution may also be referred to as the Provide Local Funding for the District of Columbia Act.</summary>
</bill>
