<bill session="113" type="h" number="1536" updated="2013-11-02T06:31:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding American Commerce and Agriculture Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Office of Agriculture Inspection within the Department of Homeland Security, which shall be headed by the Assistant Commissioner for Agriculture Inspection, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412498"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E437"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/2013--Introduced.
Safeguarding American Commerce and Agriculture Act of 2013 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish the Office of Agriculture Inspection within U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP), which shall be headed by an Assistant Commissioner. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), acting through the CBP Commissioner, to: (1) identify career paths for customs and border protection agriculture specialists; (2) provide such specialists the opportunity to acquire the education, training, and experience necessary to qualify for promotion; (3) develop a plan to recruit and retain qualified specialists; and (4) identify, and develop a plan to address, any deficiencies in equipment and other resources that are necessary at CBP agriculture inspection stations and facilities to enable such specialists to carry out their mission. Authorizes the DHS Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to establish an interagency rotation program. Directs the DHS Secretary to report to Congress regarding: (1) the implementation status of the action plans developed by the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service-U.S. Customs and Border Protection Joint Task Force on Improved Agriculture Inspection, and (2) any additional legal authority the Secretary determines is necessary to carry out the agriculture inspection mission of DHS.</summary>
</bill>
