<bill session="111" type="h" number="5875" updated="2013-07-20T00:05:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Border Security Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Emergency Border Security Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making emergency supplemental appropriations for border security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2010, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400657" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412188" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400281" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400302" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412316" joined="2010-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T20:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Price (NC) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T20:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6253-6257" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T20:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5875.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-07-28T20:43:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6253" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T20:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6838-6845" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2010-08-05" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>See also S. 3721.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23T16:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Senate amendment and accompanying papers returned to Senate pursuant to H.Res. 1653.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23">
      <text>Message received in the Senate: Returned to the Senate pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1653.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="1653"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6080"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3721"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4572"/>
    <amendment number="s4580"/>
    <amendment number="s4582"/>
    <amendment number="s4590"/>
    <amendment number="s4591"/>
    <amendment number="s4592"/>
    <amendment number="s4593"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Passed Senate amended.
Title I: Department of Homeland Security - Appropriates additional FY2010 amounts to remain available until September 30, 2011, to: (1) U.S. Customs and Border Protection for salaries and expenses related to staffing on the Southwest Border of the United States, construction of up to two Border Patrol forward operating bases along the Southwest Border, and border security fencing, infrastructure, and technology along the Southwest border; (2) U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement for salaries and expenses for law enforcement activities along the Southwest Border; and (3) Federal Law Enforcement Training Center training for new U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers and Border Patrol agents. Appropriates additional FY2010 amounts to remain available until September 30, 2012, for acquisition and deployment of unmanned aircraft systems. (Sec. 101) Rescinds from unobligated balances certain funds for U.S. Customs and Border Protection, border security fencing, infrastructure, and technology. Title II: Department of Justice - Appropriates additional FY2010 amounts to remain available until September 30, 2011, for Department of Justice (DOJ) law enforcement activities related to the Southwest Border. Title III: the Judiciary - Appropriates additional FY2010 amounts to remain available until September 30, 2011, for courts of appeals, district courts, and other judicial services. States that funding shall be available for transfer between Judiciary accounts to meet increased workload requirements resulting from immigration and other law enforcement initiatives. Title IV: General Provisions - (Sec. 401) Designates each amount made available under this Act as an emergency requirement and necessary to meet emergency needs. (Sec. 402) Increases, for the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on September 30, 2014: (1) the L visa (intracompany transfer) nonimmigrant application filing fee and fraud prevention and detection fee by $2,250 for applicants that employ 50 or more employees in the United States if more than 50% of the applicant's employees are L visa or H-1b visa (nonagricultural specialty worker) nonimmigrants; and (2) the H-1b visa application filing fee and fraud prevention and detection fee by $2,000 for applicants that employ 50 or more employees in the United States if more than 50% of the applicant's employees are H-1b or L visa nonimmigrants. Provides that during such period all amounts collected pursuant to such fee increases shall be deposited in the General Fund of the Treasury.</summary>
</bill>
