<bill session="113" type="s" number="787" updated="2013-11-02T06:58:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Integrity to our Government Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require agencies to set forth reasons for determining that a proposed regulatory action is significant.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300083"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="191"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="786"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/2013--Introduced.
Restoring Integrity to our Government Act - Prohibits a proposed significant regulatory action from being finalized unless it includes the reasons why the agency proposing it determined that it is a significant regulatory action. Defines "significant regulatory action" as any regulatory action likely to result in a regulation that may: (1) have an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more or adversely affect in a material way the economy, a sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, or state, local, or tribal governments or communities; (2) create a serious inconsistency or otherwise interfere with an action taken or planned by another agency; (3) materially alter the budgetary impact of entitlements, grants, user fees, or loan programs or the rights and obligation of recipients thereof; (4) add to the national debt; or (5) raise novel legal or policy issues arising out of legal mandates, the President's priorities, or the principles set forth in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
