<bill session="111" type="h" number="6134" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a 10 percent reduction in pay for Members of Congress; to make Federal civilian employees subject to a period of mandatory unpaid leave, and to reduce appropriations for salaries and expenses for offices of the legislative branch, during fiscal year 2011; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2010-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5927"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2010--Introduced.
Requires a 10% reduction in the annual rate of pay for Members of Congress. Requires the President by regulation to subject employees in the executive branch, during FY2011, to: (1) a total of two weeks of mandatory unpaid leave; or (2) the pro rata equivalent in the case of employees serving for less than the entire fiscal year. Requires the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, by regulation, to apply such requirements to employees in the judicial branch. Allows such regulations to make exceptions for: (1) national security reasons; (2) reasons relating to the public health or safety, including effective law enforcement; or (3) such other reasons as the President considers necessary or appropriate. Limits the aggregate amount which may be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for allowances and expenses (including salaries) of any legislative branch office, except the U.S. Capitol Police, to 96% of the aggregate amount appropriated or otherwise made available for FY2010 for such allowances and expenses.</summary>
</bill>
