<bill session="109" type="s" number="1566" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commodity Exchange Reauthorization Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Commodity Exchange Reauthorization Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">An original bill to reauthorize the Commodity Exchange Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300021"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-07-21">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Chambliss. With written report No. 109-119.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-07-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="191">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 191.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="4473"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4473"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4473"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Commodity exchanges"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Margins (Security trading)"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Commodity Exchange Reauthorization Act of 2005 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Commodity Exchange Act (CEA) to authorize the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) to bring anti-fraud actions in off-exchange principal-to-principal futures transactions. Provides that a person shall not be obligated, in connection with a covered futures transaction with another person, to disclose to such other person nonpublic information that may be material to the market price, rate, or level of such commodity or transaction except as necessary to make any statement not materially misleading. (Sec. 3) Increases specified civil and criminal penalties for violations of such Act. States that such provisions do not create new CFTC civil enforcement and administrative authority. (Sec. 4) Revises foreign exchange transaction authority to specify that CFTC jurisdiction extends to any agreement, contract, or transaction in foreign currency, and any person engaged in such transaction, that is offered to, or entered into: (1) with a person who is not an eligible contract participant; (2) on a leveraged, margined, or similarly financed basis; and (3) for purposes other than commercial or personal use, except that personal use shall include only those agreements, contracts, or transactions in which a person takes immediate ownership and possession of foreign currency. States that such jurisdiction shall not apply if the counterparty, or the person offering to be the counterparty, of the person that is not an eligible contract participant is: (1) a financial institution; (2) a specified broker or dealer registered under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934; (3) a specified futures commission merchant registered under CEA; (4) a specified insurance company or affiliate; (5) a financial holding company; or (6) an investment bank holding company. (Sec. 5) Authorizes appropriations through FY2010. (Sec. 6) Directs CFTC to maintain a liaison with the Department of Justice to coordinate civil and criminal investigations and prosecutions of CEA violations. (Sec. 7) Establishes a two-year portfolio margining pilot program for security futures products, which shall continue to function unless a required report finds that such program has resulted in undue risks to the financial integrity of the relevant contract markets or derivatives transaction execution facilities, or to their respective clearing systems, or has resulted in systemic risk to financial markets or undue risk to customers. (Sec. 8) Requires CFTC and the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to jointly promulgate a final rule to exclude from the definition of "narrow-based security index" indexes based on: (1) U.S. debt instruments; (2) other U.S. securities; (3) foreign equities; and (4) foreign debt instruments.</summary>
</bill>
