<bill session="113" type="h" number="1294" updated="2013-11-02T06:29:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Self-Sufficient Community Lands Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a program that will generate dependable economic activity for counties and local governments containing National Forest System land through a management-focused approach, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412419"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412549" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2013-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2013--Introduced.
Self-Sufficient Community Lands Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to establish the community forest demonstration area or areas of a state, consisting of National Forest System (NFS) land, at the request of a Board of Trustees appointed by a governor to manage such land in that state. Conditions establishment of an area upon: (1) inclusion of at least 200,000 acres of NFS land; (2) a state has a forest practices law or regulatory structure applicable to state or privately owned forest land; (3) agreement with the governor by the county in which the land is located requiring the county, in using revenues received from the area, to continue to meet obligations under applicable state law pursuant to the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 or other provisions concerning payment of receipts for the benefit of public schools and roads. Excludes from a community forest demonstration area land that is a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System or on which the removal of vegetation is specifically prohibited by federal law. Deems the administration and management of a community forest demonstration area, including implementing actions, not to be federal action and subject to federal laws only to the extent that they apply to the state administration and management of forest lands in which the community forest demonstration area is located.</summary>
</bill>
