<bill session="110" type="s" number="3131" updated="2013-07-19T22:48:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oil Speculation Control Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Commodity Exchange Act to ensure the application of speculation limits to speculators in energy markets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5629-5630"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5630-5631" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Commodity exchanges"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Swaps (Finance)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2008--Introduced.
Oil Speculation Control Act of 2008 - Amends the Commodity Exchange Act to define "institutional investor" as a long-term investor in financial markets (including pension funds, endowments, and foundations) that invests in energy commodities as an asset class in a portfolio of financial investments and does not take or make physical delivery of energy commodities on a frequent basis.Establishes in the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) an Office of the Inspector General.Directs the CFTC to carry out a review of the trading practices of index traders, swap dealers, and institutional investors in markets under the CFTC's jurisdiction to: (1) ensure that index trading is not adversely impacting the price discovery process; (2) determine whether different practices or regulations should be implemented; and (3) gather data for use in proposing regulations to limit the size and influence of the institutional investor positions in commodity markets.Directs the CFTC to exercise emergency authority to prevent institutional investors from increasing their positions in energy commodity futures and commodity future index funds.Defines: (1) "bona fide hedging transaction or position" as a transaction or position that represents a hedge against price risk exposure relating to physical transactions involving an energy commodity and (2) "speculator" as any institutional investor or investor of an investment fund that holds a position through an intermediary broker or dealer.Directs the CFTC to enforce speculation limits with respect to speculators in energy markets.Set forth recordkeeping and reporting requirements relating to large trader transactions and positions applicable to index traders, swaps dealers, and institutional investors in markets under the CFTC's jurisdiction.Requires the CFTC to promulgate regulations to establish separate classifications for index traders, swap dealers, and institutional investors to enforce recordkeeping and reporting requirements and to enforce position limits and position accountability levels with respect to energy commodities.Imposes certain institutional investor speculation limits with respect to energy commodities.</summary>
</bill>
