<bill session="111" type="h" number="4117" updated="2013-07-19T23:49:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Agricultural Adjustment Act to clarify that the delivery of milk to a handler under a Federal milk marketing order occurs when the raw milk is received at the producer's farm, and the producer may not be charged for transportation-related costs incurred by a handler after the raw milk leaves the farm, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412224"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412234" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412291" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2009-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG29" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act, reenacted with amendments by the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, to state that: (1) the delivery by a producer or association of producers of raw milk to a handler under a federal milk marketing order shall be deemed to occur when the raw milk is received at the producer's farm, whether directly by the handler or by a transportation agent acting on behalf of the handler; and (2) the producer may not be charged for transportation-related costs, including hauling fees, stop fees, and fuel surcharges, incurred by a handler or the transportation agent after the raw milk leaves the farm.</summary>
</bill>
