<bill session="113" type="s" number="863" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Back to School Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to repeal time limitations on the eligibility for use of educational assistance under All-Volunteer Force Educational Assistance Program, to improve veterans education outreach, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2013--Introduced.
Veterans Back to School Act of 2013 - Provides that an individual's entitlement to educational assistance under the all-volunteer force veterans' educational assistance program shall not end until 10 years after the individual begins using such benefit. (Under current law, there are several more stringent time limits on the use of such assistance.) Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA), under specified conditions, to fund offices of veterans affairs at eligible institutions of higher learning (institutions with at least 50 veteran-enrollees) for veterans' certification, outreach, recruitment, and special education programs. Limits payments to $15,000 per institution per fiscal year. Directs the Secretary to annually collect information about exemplary veterans educational outreach programs, and to disseminate such information to other institutions offering such programs.</summary>
</bill>
