<bill session="113" type="h" number="1926" updated="2013-11-02T06:35:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Trade Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To further enhance the promotion of exports of United States goods and services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412405" joined="2013-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSFA18" subcommittee="Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2013--Introduced.
State Trade Coordination Act - Amends the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to revise membership of the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee (TPCC) to include one or more presidential appointees representing state trade promotion agencies. Directs the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the TPCC and in coordination with representatives of state trade promotion agencies, to develop a plan to integrate resources and strategies of state trade promotion agencies into the overall federal trade promotion program. Directs the Secretary, acting through the head of the U.S. Commercial Service, to develop an annual federal-state export strategy for goods and services for each state that submits to the Secretary its export strategy for the upcoming year. Directs the Secretary, in coordination with representatives of state trade promotion agencies, to develop a framework to share export success information, and develop a coordinated set of reporting metrics. Revises the strategic plan for federal trade promotion efforts to include an annual survey and analysis of the overall effectiveness of federal-state coordination and export promotion goals, as well as best practices, recommendations to better assist small businesses, and other relevant matters.</summary>
</bill>
