<bill session="110" type="h" number="1904" updated="2013-07-19T21:20:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-10T14:55:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-07-10T14:55:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">New Mexico Water Planning Assistance Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">New Mexico Water Planning Assistance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide assistance to the State of New Mexico for the development of comprehensive State water plans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400434"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2007-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-10T14:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sarbanes moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-10T14:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7445-7446" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-10T14:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1904.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-07-10T14:55:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7445" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-07-10T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-07-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="267">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 267.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="255"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="255"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="255"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="255"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2007--Passed House without amendment.
New Mexico Water Planning Assistance Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, at the request of the governor of New Mexico and acting through the Bureau of Reclamation and the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), to: (1) provide to New Mexico technical assistance and grants for the development of comprehensive state water plans; (2) conduct water resources mapping in New Mexico; and (3) conduct a comprehensive study of groundwater resources in New Mexico to assess the quantity, quality, and interaction of groundwater and surface water resources. Lists types of technical assistance that may be provided, including acquisition of hydrologic data, expansion of groundwater monitoring networks, and coordination of federal water management planning efforts. Directs the Secretary to allocate specified funds: (1) to develop hydrologic models and acquire associated equipment for the New Mexico Rio Grande main stem sections and Rios Pueblo de Taos and Hondo, Rios Nambe, Pojoaque and Teseque, Rio Chama, and Lower Rio Grande tributaries; (2) to complete the hydrographic survey development of hydrologic models and acquire associated equipment for the San Juan River and tributaries and for Southwest New Mexico, including the Animas Basin, the Gila River, and tributaries; and (3) for statewide digital orthophotography mapping. Sets the non-federal share of the total cost of any activity carried out using a grant under this Act at 50%, which may be in the form of in-kind services as determined by the Secretary. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this Act 10 years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
