<bill session="111" type="sr" number="573" updated="2013-07-20T00:21:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution urging the development of a comprehensive strategy to ensure stability in Somalia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5544-5545" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-24">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="588">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 588.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-09-29" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7770-7771" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7770-7771" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Eritrea"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Somalia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Passed Senate amended.
Acknowledges the urgency of addressing the threats to U.S. national security in Somalia and the conditions that foster those threats. Reaffirms the Senate's commitment to stand with the people of Somalia who aspire to a future free of terrorism and violence through political reconciliation. Recognizes the important work being done by the African Union Mission in Somalia (AMISOM). Calls on: (1) the Transitional Federal Government in Somalia to cease any use of child soldiers and renew its commitment to political reconciliation; and (2) regional governments and parties, particularly the government of Eritrea, to play a productive role in helping to bring peace to Somalia. Welcomes the President's efforts to bring greater focus and resources toward the situation in Somalia. Urges the President to develop a comprehensive strategy to ensure that all U.S. humanitarian, diplomatic, political, and counterterrorism programs in Somalia and the wider Horn of Africa are coordinated toward the long-term goal of establishing stability, respect for human rights, and functional, inclusive governance in Somalia.</summary>
</bill>
