<bill session="110" type="s" number="3543" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Integrity in Offshore Energy Resources Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the administration of the Minerals Management Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9282-9283"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="7211"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2008--Introduced.
Integrity in Offshore Energy Resources Act of 2008 - Prohibits any employee of the Minerals Management Service of the Department of the Interior from: (1) knowingly accepting a gift from an entity engaged in the business of mineral mining or from being employed by such an entity while employed in the Service; and (2) accepting employment from an entity engaged in the business of mineral mining during the one-year period after termination of employment with the Service. Makes violations of such prohibitions a felony. Requires financial disclosure by employees of the Service in positions equivalent to GS-13 or higher. Suspends the authority of the Secretary of the Interior to carry out royalty-in-kind programs (payment of royalties from oil and gas leases in the form of production rather than cash) until the Secretary certifies that a comprehensive review of such programs has been conducted, implements an ethics training program for employees of the Minerals Management Service, and creates an ombudsman position to monitor the progress of the Service in carrying out reforms. Requires the Secretary to perform at least 550 audits in each fiscal year of oil and gas leases for which payment is made under a royalty-in-kind program. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to repeal the authority of the Secretary to pay salaries and other administrative costs related to a royalty-in kind program from royalty-in-kind sales revenues.</summary>
</bill>
