<bill session="111" type="s" number="2731" updated="2013-07-20T00:50:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Administration Disaster Recovery and Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve disaster assistance provided by the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11207-11210, S11212"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11210-11212" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/5/2009--Introduced.
Small Business Administration Disaster Recovery and Reform Act of 2009 - Amends the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to submit to the congressional small business committees recommendations for improvements to the Gulf Coast disaster loan refinancing program. Extends for 24 additional months the authorized loan assistance term for small businesses affected by Hurricanes Katrina or Rita and participating in the SBA small business and capital ownership development program. Allows the Administrator to declare a disaster with respect to small businesses that installed defective drywall manufactured in China, for purposes of qualification for SBA disaster loan assistance. Amends the Small Business Act to increase authorized assistance under the SBA's: (1) pioneer business recovery program (formerly the expedited disaster assistance loan program); and (2) disaster loan assistance program. Authorizes the Administrator to guarantee loans made under an approved state bridge loan program. Requires the Administrator to report on: (1) regional outreach on disaster assistance programs; (2) coordination of economic injury disaster declarations; and (3) coordination between SBA and Department of Agriculture (USDA) disaster programs. Directs the Administrator to ensure that disaster recovery needs unmet by federal and private sources are not overlooked by the SBA in determining duplication of benefits for disaster victims.</summary>
</bill>
