<bill session="111" type="h" number="5516" updated="2013-07-20T00:02:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Access to Appropriate Immunizations for Veterans Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for certain requirements relating to the immunization of veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1072"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2010--Introduced.
Access to Appropriate Immunizations for Veterans Act of 2010 - Includes within authorized preventive health services available to veterans through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) immunizations against infectious diseases, including each immunization on the recommended adult immunization schedule established by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices. Requires the inclusion, in an annual report from the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on VA preventive health services, of programs conducted to ensure that veterans have received each immunization on such immunization schedule at the appropriate time. Directs the Secretary to develop and implement quality measures and metrics to ensure that veterans receiving VA medical services receive each immunization at the time indicated on the schedule. Requires statistics related to such quality measures and metrics to be included in the annual report described above. Provides deadlines for the establishment and implementation of the measures and metrics.</summary>
</bill>
