<bill session="112" type="h" number="190" updated="2013-07-20T01:12:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting America's Workers Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to expand coverage under the Act, to increase protections for whistleblowers, to increase penalties for high gravity violations, to adjust penalties for inflation, to provide rights for victims or their family members, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400436"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2012-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2012-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2011-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412498" joined="2012-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2011-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2011-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2011-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2011-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2012-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2012-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2011-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="571"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="1166"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
Protecting America's Workers Act - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSHA) to expand its coverage to federal, state, and local government employees. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor, under specified conditions, to cede OSHA jurisdiction to another federal agency with respect to certain occupational standards or regulations for such agency's employees. Declares OSHA inapplicable to working conditions covered by the Federal Mine Safety and Heath Act of 1977. Increases protections for whistle blowers under OSHA. Prescribes requirements relating to: (1) the posting of employee rights, (2) employer reporting of employee work-related deaths or hospitalizations, (3) a prohibition against employers adopting or implementing policies or practices that discourage or discriminate against employee reporting of work-related injuries or illnesses, (4) a prohibition against the loss of wages or employee benefits due to an employee participating in a workplace inspection, (5) investigations of incidents resulting in death or the hospitalization of two or more employees which occur in a place of employment, and (6) a prohibition against the issuing, modifying, or settling of unclassified citations for occupational health and safety standard violations. Continues requirements relating to: (1) the rights of an employee (including a former employee or family member in lieu of an employee) who has sustained a work-related injury or illness that is the subject of an inspection or investigation; (2) an employer's right to contest citations and penalties; and (3) periods permitted for an employer to correct serious, willful, or repeated violations pending an employer's contest to a citation and procedures for stays of the time period for abatement of those violations. Increases civil and criminal penalties for certain OSHA violators. States that pre-final order interest on any penalties owed shall begin to accrue on the date a party contests a citation, at an interest rate calculated at the current underpayment rate. Prescribes requirements for the Secretary's evaluation of state occupational safety and health plans as well as workplace health hazard evaluations by the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH). Requires a state that has an approved plan for the development and enforcement of occupational safety and health standards to amend its plan to conform to the requirements of this Act within 12 months after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
