<bill session="110" type="s" number="1718" updated="2013-07-19T22:35:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Education Tuition Support Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">VETS Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to provide for reimbursement to servicemembers of tuition for programs of education interrupted by military service, for deferment of students loans and reduced interest rates for servicemembers during periods of military service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2007-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2910"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Students' rights"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2007--Introduced.
Veterans Education Tuition Support Act or VETS Act - Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to require an institution of higher education, in the case of a servicemember who because of military service discontinues a program of education at an institution that administers a federal financial aid program, to: (1) refund to the servicemember tuition and other fees paid for the portion of the program of education for which the servicemember did not receive academic credit because of such military service; and (2) provide the servicemember an opportunity to reenroll at the institution with the same educational and academic status that the servicemember had when the program was discontinued because of the military service. Requires a provider of a student loan with respect to such a servicemember: (1) if the servicemember reenrolls in the program of education (or a comparable program) within 13 months following the period of military service, to disregard the entire period that the education was discontinued in determining the date on which student loan repayment is to begin; or (2) if the servicemember does not reenroll, to not require loan repayment to begin before the later of the last day of such 13-month period or the date the repayment was otherwise required to begin. Prohibits a court from granting a creditor relief from the 6% limit on interest charged against student loan indebtedness.</summary>
</bill>
