<bill session="112" type="h" number="2211" updated="2013-07-20T01:29:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Great Teaching for Great Schools Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide for a system of professional learning to continuously improve educator effectiveness, student achievement, and overall school and system performance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2011-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2011--Introduced.
Great Teaching for Great Schools Act of 2011 - Amends title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to create a new part E (Building School and System Capacity for Effective Teaching). Directs the Secretary of Education to allot funds to states for subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to implement a comprehensive professional learning system in their schools that: (1) fosters collective responsibility for improved student performance; (2) comprises professional learning that primarily occurs several times or hours each week among established teams of teachers, principals, and other instructional staff; and (3) may be supported by activities such as courses, workshops, institutes, networks, and conferences. Requires states to give subgrant priority to LEAs that demonstrate the greatest need for such funds by reason of their serving: (1) a population of children 40% of whom are eligible for free and reduced price meals under the school lunch program; (2) a school identified, under title I of the ESEA, as needing corrective action; and (3) schools having an average graduation rate below 65%. Allows LEA subgrantees to use school improvement funds received under title I of the ESEA for professional learning activities under this Act, which are to be integrated and aligned with their state's school improvement efforts under title I. Requires LEA subgrantees to conduct formal evaluations of their professional learning systems.</summary>
</bill>
