<bill session="109" type="sr" number="342" updated="2013-07-19T20:09:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-21">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution recognizing the Republic of Croatia for its progress in strengthening democratic institutions, respect for human rights, and the rule of law and recommending the integration of Croatia into the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2005-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-12-21" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/22/2005 S14402-14403" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 12/22/2005 S14402-14403" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR 12/22/2005 S14334-14335" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="529"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Croatia"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2005--Passed Senate without amendment.
States that: (1) since the Republic of Croatia became an independent country, the government and people of Croatia have made significant progress in strengthening democratic institutions, respect for human rights, and the rule of law in Croatia; and (2) Croatia's membership in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) would contribute to stability in Southeast Europe; Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the government and people of Croatia should be commended for their progress on protecting minority rights in Croatia, progress toward achieving the political, economic, military, and other requirements of the NATO's Membership Action Plan, contribution to the International Security Assistance Force and the war against terrorism, and for their constructive participation in the Proliferation Security Initiative and in the United States-Adriatic Charter; (2) the government of Croatia should be commended for its cooperation with the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia which led to the apprehension and transfer of several individuals indicted for war crimes to the Tribunal; (3) the government of Croatia should continue its cooperation with the Tribunal; (4) the government of Croatia should continue and strengthen its role as a partner on nonproliferation and its support in the war against terrorism and in Iraq; (5) the government of Croatia should continue its efforts to implement defense reforms; (6) the United States should continue and increase its defense and security cooperation with the Croatia; and (7) upon complete satisfaction of NATO membership criteria, Croatia should be invited to be a full member of NATO at the earliest possible date.</summary>
</bill>
