<bill session="113" type="h" number="3107" updated="2013-11-02T06:45:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Security Cybersecurity Boots-on-the-Ground Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish cybersecurity occupation classifications, assess the cybersecurity workforce, develop a strategy to address identified gaps in the cybersecurity workforce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412221"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412559" joined="2013-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412466" joined="2013-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2013-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSHM08" subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2013--Introduced.
Homeland Security Cybersecurity Boots-on-the-Ground Act - Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to develop: occupation classifications for individuals performing activities in furtherance of the cybersecurity mission of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and to ensure that the such classifications may be used throughout DHS and are made available to other federal agencies; a workforce strategy that enhances the readiness, capacity, training, recruitment, and retention of the DHS cybersecurity workforce, including a multiphased recruitment plan and a 10-year projection of federal workforce needs; and a process to verify that employees of independent contractors who serve in DHS cybersecurity positions receive initial and recurrent information security and role-based security training commensurate with assigned responsibilities. Defines "cybersecurity mission" as threat and vulnerability reduction, deterrence, incident response, resiliency, and recovery activities to foster the security and stability of cyberspace. Directs the DHS Chief Human Capital Officer and Chief Information Officer to assess the readiness and capacity of DHS to meet such mission. Requires the Secretary to provide Congress with annual updates regarding such strategies, assessments, and training.</summary>
</bill>
