<bill session="112" type="h" number="979" updated="2013-07-20T01:18:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FEHBP Prescription Drug Integrity, Transparency, and Cost Savings Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 89 of title 5, United States Code, to ensure program integrity, transparency, and cost savings in the pricing and contracting of prescription drug benefits under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400249"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2011-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2011-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2011-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2011-03-09" withdrawn="2011-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2011--Introduced.
FEHBP Prescription Drug Integrity, Transparency, and Cost Savings Act - Prohibits the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) from entering a contract or approving a health benefits plan with a carrier that is a party to a pharmacy benefit manager (PBM) carrier arrangement to provide or administer prescription drug coverage under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program (FEHBP) unless the PBM and the carrier comply with the requirements for PBM carrier arrangements set forth by this Act. Directs OPM to terminate a contract or discontinue a plan that fails to comply with such requirements. Prohibits: (1) a PBM under a carrier arrangement from being under common corporate control with a prescription drug manufacturer or a retail pharmacy, and (2) OPM from permitting a carrier under common corporate control with a PBM to earn a profit from such control. Sets forth terms and requirements for PBM carrier arrangements under the FEHBP, including: (1) drug substitution restrictions, (2) PBM reimbursement of carriers, (3) sale by a PBM of utilization and claims data, (4) drug pricing and the basis for reimbursement, (5) PBM provision to plan enrollees of an explanation of benefits statement regarding prescription drugs, (6) nondiscriminatory contracts regarding required participation, (7) OPM access to PBM contract information, and (8) civil monetary penalties for making false statements or claims to the government.</summary>
</bill>
