<bill session="111" type="hr" number="520" updated="2013-07-19T23:00:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Impeaching Samuel B. Kent, judge of the United States District Court for the Southern District of Texas, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2009-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 29 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17T15:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 111-159.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-06-17T15:37:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="75">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 75.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7053-7067" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19T13:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 520.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19T15:03:00-04:00">
      <text>On agreeing to Article I of the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 389 - 0 (Roll no. 415).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7064-7065" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>On agreeing to Article II of the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 385 - 0 (Roll no. 416).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7065-7066" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>On agreeing to Article III of the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 381 - 0 (Roll no. 417).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7066" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19T15:21:00-04:00">
      <text>On agreeing to Article IV of the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 372 - 0, 1 Present (Roll no. 418).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7066-7067" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="431"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2009--Passed House without amendment.
Impeaches Samuel B. Kent, judge of the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of Texas, for high crimes and misdemeanors. Sets forth articles of impeachment. Declares that, incident to his position as a U.S. district court judge, Samuel B. Kent engaged in conduct with respect to employees associated with the court that is incompatible with the trust and confidence placed in him as a judge. Declares that Judge Kent, on one or more occasions, sexually assaulted Cathy McBroom and Donna Wilkerson by: (1) touching their private areas directly and through their clothing against their will; and (2) attempting to cause them to engage in sexual acts with him. Declares that Judge Kent corruptly obstructed, influenced, or impeded an official proceeding relating to Ms. McBroom's complaint, and made false statements to a Fifth Circuit Special Investigative Committee about his unwanted sexual contact with Ms. Wilkerson. States that Judge Kent was indicted and pled guilty and was sentenced to imprisonment for the felony of obstruction of justice on the basis of false statements made to the Committee. Declares that Judge Kent made material false and misleading statements about the nature and extent of his nonconsensual sexual contact with Ms. McBroom and Ms. Wilkerson to agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) on or about November 30, 2007, and to FBI agents and representatives of the Department of Justice on or about August 11, 2008. Declares that Judge Samuel B. Kent is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors and should be removed from office.</summary>
</bill>
