<bill session="111" type="h" number="6444" updated="2013-07-20T00:10:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">No Health Care Subsidies for Illegal Aliens Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to provide for appropriate procedures under such title for verification of citizenship status.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2010--Introduced.
No Health Care Subsidies for Illegal Aliens Act of 2010 - Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, with respect to procedures for determining eligibility for participation in a state health care insurance exchange (Exchange), to: (1) require an applicant for enrollment in a qualified health plan (enrollee)&#160;to appear in person at an Exchange and&#160;submit a sworn statement, under penalty of perjury, that the enrollee is a citizen or national of the United States or an eligible alien; (2) require enrollees to provide satisfactory documentary evidence of citizenship or nationality or satisfactory immigration status; (3) require Exchanges to verify citizenship or immigration status of enrollees based on satisfactory documentary evidence&#160;and (4) eliminate the authority of the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to modify the methods used by Exchanges to verify enrollee eligibility.</summary>
</bill>
