<bill session="111" type="s" number="991" updated="2013-07-20T00:32:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">English Language Unity Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to declare English as the official language of the United States, to establish a uniform English language rule for naturalization, and to avoid misconstructions of the English language texts of the laws of the United States, pursuant to Congress' powers to provide for the general welfare of the United States and to establish a rule of naturalization under article I, section 8, of the Constitution.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2009-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5239-5240"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5240-5241" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="997"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2009--Introduced.
English Language Unity Act of 2009 - Makes English the official language of the United States. Requires, subject to exceptions and rules of construction, that: (1) official functions of the United States be conducted in English; and (2) all naturalization ceremonies be conducted in English. Establishes a uniform English language rule for naturalization. Makes English language requirements and workplace policies, whether in the public or private sector, presumptively consistent with the laws of the United States. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to issue for public notice and comment a proposed rule for uniform testing of English language ability of candidates for naturalization based upon the principles that: (1) all citizens should be able to read and understand generally the English language text of the Declaration of Independence, the Constitution, and the laws of the United States; and (2) any exceptions to this standard should be limited to extraordinary circumstances, such as asylum.</summary>
</bill>
