<bill session="111" type="h" number="2728" updated="2013-07-19T23:36:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-30T16:13:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-07-30T16:13:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">William Orton Law Library Improvement and Modernization Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">William Orton Law Library Improvement and Modernization Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">William Orton Law Library Improvement and Modernization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide financial support for the operation of the law library of the Library of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400245"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2009-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19T13:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 111-170.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-06-19T13:45:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="86">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 86.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-28T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Lofgren, Zoe moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-28T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8936-8937" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-28T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2728.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-28T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Lungren, Daniel E. objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30T16:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9138-9139" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-07-30T16:13:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="678" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 383 - 44 (Roll no. 678).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/28/2009 H8936" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2009--Passed House amended.
William Orton Law Library Improvement and Modernization Act - Authorizes appropriations to the Library of Congress for the maintenance and administration of the operations of the Law Library of the Library of Congress, including the cataloguing of the collections of the Law Library. Directs the Law Library to electronically catalog and archive material in its collections in a nonproprietary and nondiscriminatory format. Requires the separation of the salaries and expenses of the Law Library from other salaries and expenses of the Library of Congress in the preparation of the annual budget for the Library of Congress. Establishes the William Orton Law Library Support Program to provide enhanced or special services and programs for the Law Library and otherwise support the mission of the Law Library. Allows the Librarian of Congress (the Librarian) to carry out the Program through agreements and partnerships with other government and private entities, including the American Association of Law Libraries and the American Bar Association (ABA). Permits the Library of Congress Trust Fund Board and the Librarian to accept private donations in support of the Program. Makes any accepted donations subject to disbursement by the Librarian only upon the recommendation of the Law Librarian, with an exception. Establishes in the Treasury a separate account for the Program. Limits the use of account funds only to the Law Librarian to carry out such Program. Authorizes annual appropriations to the Library of Congress for the deposit into such account of an amount equal to 40% of the amount of donations accepted by the Board in support of such Program, in addition to any other amounts authorized for the Law Library. Designates the Law Library as the "National Law Library."</summary>
</bill>
