<bill session="110" type="s" number="2009" updated="2013-07-19T22:38:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize additional funds for emergency repairs and reconstruction of the Interstate I-35 bridge located in Minneapolis, Minnesota, that collapsed on August 1, 2007, to waive the $100,000,000 limitation on emergency relief funds for those emergency repairs and reconstruction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3311"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1937"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2007--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to carry out a project for the repair and reconstruction of the Interstate I-35 bridge located in Minneapolis, Minnesota, that collapsed on August 1, 2007. Makes the federal share of the project cost 100%. Authorizes appropriations. Waives, for such project, the $100 million per state single-failure (or, single-disaster) highway-related total obligation limitation. Amends the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users to authorize the Secretary to: (1) use such single-failure (or, single-disaster) highway-related funds for the repair and reconstruction of the Interstate I-35 bridge in Minneapolis, Minnesota, that collapsed on August 1, 2007; and (2) use up to $5 million of such funds to reimburse the Minnesota state department of transportation for actual and necessary costs of maintenance and operation (less the amount of fares earned) for providing additional public transportation services and traveler information services as a substitute for highway traffic service following the collapse of the Interstate I-35 bridge in Minneapolis, Minnesota, on August 1, 2007, until highway traffic service is restored on such bridge. Makes the federal share of the project cost 100%.</summary>
</bill>
