<bill session="113" type="h" number="1190" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep America's Oil Here Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that the Secretary of the Interior may accept bids on any new oil and gas leases of Federal lands (including submerged lands) only from bidders certifying that all oil produced pursuant to such leases, and all refined petroleum products produced from such oil, shall be offered for sale only in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1191"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2013--Introduced.
Keep America's Oil Here Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to accept bids on any new oil and gas leases of federal lands (including submerged lands) only from bidders certifying that all crude oil produced under such leases, and all refined petroleum products made from such crude oil, shall be offered for sale only in the United States. Authorizes the President to waive such limited leasing authorization upon specified determinations, including that waiver is in the national interest because it will not lead to: (1) an increase in domestic consumption of crude oil obtained from countries hostile to U.S. interests or that have political and economic instability compromising energy supply security, (2) higher costs to oil refiners purchasing the crude oil than the refiners would have to pay in the absence of such a waiver, and (3) higher gasoline costs paid by consumers than they would have to pay in the absence of such a waiver. Declares this Act without force or effect 10 years after enactment of this Act. Instructs the Secretary of the Interior and the Comptroller General to report separately to Congress on the impact of this Act upon: (1) oil production on federal lands, (2) consumption of oil and refined petroleum products in the United States, and (3) prices and markets for oil and refined petroleum products in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
