<bill session="111" type="s" number="3446" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Nutrition Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to advance the health and wellbeing of schoolchildren in the United States through technical assistance, training, and support for healthy school foods, local wellness policies, and nutrition promotion and education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4547"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/2010--Introduced.
Child Nutrition Enhancement Act of 2010 - Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to replace the team nutrition network program with the wellness and nutrition network (TWNN) program: a nationwide, multidisciplinary program that promotes healthy eating and physical activity by children and is funded and overseen at the federal level, administered at the state level, and implemented at the local level. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to develop and carry out a comprehensive, integrated national strategy that coordinates federal, state, and local efforts to promote and support healthy eating, physical activity, and positive behavioral changes. Requires the Secretary to provide grants to states to: (1) establish a comprehensive, integrated, and coordinated wellness and nutrition network in their state; and (2) allocate funding to local educational agencies (LEAs) and other institutions providing services under the child nutrition programs to support child nutrition promotion and education. Requires LEAs and other institutions to use such funds to: (1) implement, assess, or strengthen a local wellness policy established under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act; (2) improve the nutritional quality of meals and snacks served through the child nutrition programs; (3) increase children's acceptance of nutritious meals and snacks; (4) implement federal, state, or other health guidelines; (5) provide children with regular physical activity; or (6) work with public and private organizations to promote and support healthy eating and physical activity.</summary>
</bill>
