<bill session="110" type="h" number="658" updated="2013-07-19T21:09:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-19T19:12:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-03-19T19:12:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Natural Resource Protection Cooperative Agreement Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Natural Resource Protection Cooperative Agreement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Natural Resource Protection Cooperative Agreement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements to protect natural resources of units of the National Park System through collaborative efforts on land inside and outside of units of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2007-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2007-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2007-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-19T14:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-19T14:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2631-2633" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-19T14:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 658.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-19T14:39:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-19T19:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2638-2639" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-03-19T19:12:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="158" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 390 - 10 (Roll no. 158).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2631-2632" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-03-19T19:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-105.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-06-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="235">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 235.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="241"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="241"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Natural Resource Protection Cooperative Agreement Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with state, local, or tribal governments, other federal agencies, other public entities, educational institutions, private nonprofit organizations, or participating private landowners for the purpose of protecting natural resources of units of the National Park System through collaborative efforts on land inside and outside of National Park System units. States that such an agreement shall provide clear and direct benefits to park natural resources and shall provide for: (1) the preservation, conservation, and restoration of coastal and riparian systems, watersheds, and wetlands; (2) preventing, controlling, or eradicating invasive exotic species that are within a unit of the National Park System or adjacent to such a unit; or (3) restoration of natural resources, including native wildlife habitat or ecosystems. Bars the Secretary from using any funds associated with such an agreement for the purposes of land acquisition, regulatory activity, or the development, maintenance, or operation of infrastructure, except for ancillary support facilities that the Secretary determines to be necessary for the completion of projects or activities identified in the agreement. Limits the funds available to carry out the provisions of this Act to programs and amounts specified in the statute for such use in the annual appropriation Act for the National Park Service.</summary>
</bill>
