<bill session="112" type="h" number="3604" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide for equitable allotment of lands to Alaska Native veterans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/7/2011--Introduced.
Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act - Amends provisions of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (ANCSA) that allow certain Alaska Native Vietnam veterans to file for allotments of up to two parcels of federal land totaling up to 160 acres. Eliminates the requirement that limits the allotments to lands that were vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved on the date when the person eligible for the allotment first used and occupied them. Allows allotments to be selected from vacant federal lands or lands that have been selected or conveyed to the state of Alaska or a Native Corporation, if the state or Corporation voluntarily relinquishes or conveys the land to the United States for allotment. Limits the prohibition against conveying allotments to: (1) lands in the right-of-way granted for the TransAlaska Pipeline, or (2) the inner or outer corridor of that right-of-way withdrawal. Limits the eligibility for allotments to veterans who served between August 5, 1964, and May 7, 1975. Allows an heir to apply for and receive the allotment. Allows a Native Corporation to select an equal amount of acres of appropriate federal land in Alaska to replace lands voluntarily relinquished or conveyed to the United States for allotment. Permits any person who made an allotment selection under ANCSA before this Act's enactment to withdraw it and reselect lands if those originally selected were not conveyed to that person before this Act's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
