<bill session="111" type="s" number="3401" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ACCESS ADAP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Addressing Cost Containment Measures To Ensure the Sustainability and Success of ADAP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the use of unobligated discretionary stimulus dollars to address AIDS Drug Assistance Program waiting lists and other cost containment measures impacting State ADAP programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412380" joined="2010-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="4006"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Drug and radiation therapy"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2010--Introduced.
Addressing Cost Containment Measures To Ensure the Sustainability and Success of ADAP Act or the ACCESS ADAP Act - Transfers funds from discretionary amounts appropriated under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act that remain unobligated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to be used in FY2010 to provide assistance in reducing AIDS Drug Assistance Program waiting lists and to address other cost containment measures that state AIDS Drug Assistance Programs implement after January 1, 2009. Requires amounts transferred under this Act to be used by states in a manner consistent with their state programs. Requires the Secretary, in allocating such funds, to: (1) give special consideration to the total scope and the basis of a state's needs, including the total number of patients on a waiting list, eligibility requirements, and other cost containment measures; and (2) ensure that funds be used only to provide treatments to individuals who were eligible to participate in the state program on the date of enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
