<bill session="111" type="h" number="6061" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Presidential Funding Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reform the system of public financing for Presidential elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3681"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission (FEC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
Presidential Funding Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to public financing of presidential election campaigns, to: (1) quadruple (from 1:1 to 4:1) the matching rate for contributions to primary election candidates or their authorized committees for contributions not exceeding $200 (currently, $250); (2) eliminate primary and general election spending limits on participating candidates; (3) increase the eligibility threshold for receiving matching payments from $5,000 to $25,000 in contributions from residents of each of at least 20 states; (4) limit the maximum campaign contribution by individuals to $1,000 for primaries (currently, $2,400); (5) allow an inflation adjustment for periods after 2012 for contribution limitations and matching payment amounts; (6) prohibit contributions raised by lobbyists or political action committees from qualifying for matching fund payments; (7) require candidates who accept public financing in primary elections to accept such financing in general elections; (8) change the starting date for payment of matching funds to primary candidates from January 1 of the election year to 6 months before the first presidential primary or caucus; (9) allow an equal payment to eligible candidates in a presidential election of $50 million with additional matching funds according to a specified formula; and (10) increase from $3 to $10 ($6 to $20 for joint returns) the tax checkoff for the Presidential Election Campaign Fund. Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to: (1) increase to $50 million the limit on coordinated spending by a national party and its presidential candidate; (2) prohibit political parties from spending unregulated funds (soft money) on their national conventions; (3) prohibit an authorized committee of a candidate from establishing a joint fundraising committee with a political committee other than the candidate's authorized committee; and (4) require presidential campaign committees to disclose information about bundled campaign contributions (i.e., a series of contributions exceeding specified threshold amounts)</summary>
</bill>
