<bill session="110" type="h" number="4042" updated="2013-07-19T21:39:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Farm, Small Business, and Home Tax Relief Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce the estate tax for periods before its termination in 2010 by increasing the unified credit, lowering the maximum estate tax rate, restoring the exclusion for family-owned business interests, excluding the value of the decedent's principal residence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2007-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412229" joined="2007-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family enterprises"/>
    <term name="Family farms"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Inheritance tax"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/2007--Introduced.
Family Farm, Small Business, and Home Tax Relief Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) accelerate from 2009 to 2008 the $3.5 million unified estate tax credit and adjust such credit amount for inflation in calendar years after 2008; (2) reduce the maximum estate tax rate from 49 to 43% in 2008; (3) restore and increase to $8 million the estate tax deduction for family-owned business interests and adjust such deduction amount for inflation after 2008; (4) accelerate from 2010 to 2008 the repeal of the tax on generation-skipping transfers; and (5) allow an exclusion, in calculating the gross estate for estate tax purposes, of the adjusted value of a decedent's principal residence, up to $2 million.</summary>
</bill>
