<bill session="112" type="s" number="2369" updated="2013-07-20T02:37:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">America Innovates Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the American Innovation Bank, to improve science and technology job training, to authorize grants for curriculum development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="4720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2012--Introduced.
America Innovates Act of 2012 - Establishes in the executive branch an independent agency called the American Innovation Bank. Directs the Bank to award competitive grants and loans to institutions of higher education, nonprofit research institutions, individual investigators, and private companies to develop new science and engineering discoveries into new companies, products, or jobs. Amends the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2010 to require the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to award competitive grants to: (1) Integrative Graduate Education and Research Traineeship program-funded institutions of higher education to support students who perform their graduate research in an industry setting, and (2) institutions of higher education to develop professional science masters programs. Prescribes certain training requirements for students who receive funding under an NSF graduate research fellowship, a National Institutes of Health (NIH) national research service award, or any federal program that provides funding to train graduate students for careers in scientific research and development.</summary>
</bill>
