<bill session="112" type="h" number="4345" updated="2013-07-20T01:47:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Domestic Fuels Protection Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide liability protection for claims based on the design, manufacture, sale, offer for sale, introduction into commerce, or use of certain fuels and fuel additives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400373"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400004" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2012-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2012-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2012-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412280" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2012-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2012-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2012-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2012-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2012-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2012-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412431" joined="2012-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2012-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="409888" joined="2012-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412217" joined="2012-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400392" joined="2012-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2012-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2264"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2012--Introduced.
Domestic Fuels Protection Act of 2012 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to provide that no person shall be liable under any federal, state, or local law, and no provider of financial assurance may deny payment for a claim, because an underground storage tank, underground storage tank system, or associated dispensing equipment at a stationary facility is not compatible with any fuel or fuel additive for use in a motor vehicle, nonroad vehicle, or engine if such tank or equipment has been determined to be compatible pursuant to the guidelines and regulations issued under this Act. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to issue regulations setting standards for determining whether underground storage tanks and systems and associated dispensing equipment are compatible with any fuel or fuel additive that is authorized and registered by the Administrator or by statute for use in a motor vehicle or engine or nonroad vehicle, engine, or equipment. Deems tanks, systems, and equipment that are listed by a nationally recognized testing laboratory as compatible with such a fuel or fuel additive as of the date of enactment of this Act to be compatible under such regulations. Amends the Clean Air Act to prohibit a person selling such fuel who complies with such regulations from being liable under any federal, state, or local law if: (1) a self-service purchaser introduces any such fuel into a vehicle, engine, or equipment for which the fuel has not been approved under such Act; or (2) the introduction of any such fuel voids the warranty of the manufacturer of such vehicles, engines, or equipment. Excludes from such protection: (1) a person who sells a transportation fuel and does not comply with the misfueling regulations adopted by the Administrator, and (2) a person who intentionally misfuels. Prohibits filing or maintaining in any U.S. or state court any civil action or proceeding against an entity engaged in the design, manufacture, sale, or distribution of any qualified product or of any motor vehicle, engine, or nonroad equipment for damages, abatement, restitution, fines, penalties, or other relief resulting from the introduction of any such product into a motor vehicle, engine, or nonroad equipment. Requires actions filed or pending upon enactment of this Act to be dismissed with prejudice. Defines a "qualified product" as any fuel or fuel additive that is registered under federal law or any transportation fuel or fuel additive that contains renewable fuel and that is designated for introduction into interstate commerce under federal law, any component thereof, or any blend stock. Prohibits a qualified productfrom being considered a defective product if it does not violate a control or prohibition with respect to any of its characteristics or components imposed by the Administrator under the Clean Air Act.</summary>
</bill>
