<bill session="110" type="s" number="454" updated="2013-07-19T22:24:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving Access to Higher Education Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide an increase in funding for Federal Pell Grants, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 in order to expand the deduction for interest paid on student loans, raise the contribution limits for Coverdell Education Savings Accounts, and make the exclusion for employer provided educational assistance permanent, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1430-1431"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2007--Introduced.
Improving Access to Higher Education Act of 2007 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to increase the maximum Pell Grant award to $5,100 for the 2007-2008 academic year. Raises the minimum Pell Grant award from $400 to $500. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to raise: (1) the maximum student loan interest deduction to $3,750; and (2) the modified adjusted gross income level where such deduction begins to be phased-out. Exempts from the sunset provisions of the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 (EGTRRA): (1) the elimination of the 60-month limit on the period of such deduction; and (2) the increase in the income limitation on such deduction. Increases the maximum annual contribution limit for Coverdell education savings accounts from $2,000 to $3,000, and makes such increase permanent. Repeals the EGTRRA sunset on the tax exclusion of employer-provided educational assistance.</summary>
</bill>
