<bill session="112" type="h" number="1378" updated="2013-07-20T01:22:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fighting for American Jobs Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit business enterprises that lay off a greater percentage of their United States workers than workers in other countries from receiving any Federal assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400417"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Organization, Efficiency, and Financial Management     .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO24" subcommittee="Government Organization, Efficiency, and Financial Management" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/5/2011--Introduced.
Fighting for American Jobs Act of 2011 - Directs each federal agency that provides contracts, grants, loans, or loan guarantees to businesses to require, as a condition of such assistance, that such businesses provide annually information on: (1) the number of employees employed in the United States and its territories and possessions and the number employed outside the United States, as well as wage information on U.S. employees; and (2) the percentage of the workforce that has been laid off or forced to resign during the preceding year. Prohibits, until the situation is corrected, subsequent federal assistance to businesses that lay off a greater percentage of workers in the United States and its territories and possessions than in other countries.</summary>
</bill>
