<bill session="111" type="hr" number="944" updated="2013-07-19T23:04:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-24T12:32:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-02-24T12:32:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives on religious minorities in Iraq.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives on the protection of members of vulnerable religious and ethnic minority communities in Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412264" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412273" joined="2009-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412285" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412297" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412296" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400280" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2009-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412332" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2880-2881"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23T14:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McMahon moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23T14:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H675-679" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23T14:39:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 944.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23T14:58:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. McMahon objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-24T12:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H770-771" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-02-24T12:32:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="62" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 415 - 3 (Roll no. 62).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 2/23/2010 H676" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-02-24T12:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-24T12:32:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="sr" number="322"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/24/2010--Passed House amended.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States remains deeply concerned about the plight of members of vulnerable religious and ethnic minority communities of Iraq; (2) the Secretary of State should develop and report to Congress on a comprehensive strategy to encourage the protection of the rights of such members; and (3) the U.S. government should urge the Iraqi government to enhance security at places of worship in Iraq, particularly where members of religious minority communities are known to be at risk. Urges the U.S. government to continue to work with the government of Iraq to integrate religious and ethnic minorities into the Iraqi government and the Iraqi Security Forces, with the goal of ensuring that members of such communities: (1) suffer no discrimination in recruitment, employment, or advancement; and (2) are initially assigned in reasonable numbers to their locations of origin. Urges the government of Iraq, with U.S. government assistance, to: (1) ensure that the upcoming national elections in Iraq are safe, fair, and free of intimidation and violence; and (2) permit and facilitate election monitoring by experts from local and international nongovernmental organizations, the international community, and the United Nations. Urges the U.S. government: (1) to encourage the Iraqi government to work with religious and ethnic minority communities to develop and implement effective measures to protect their rights and reverse their marginalization; (2) in providing assistance to Iraq, to continue to take into account the needs of religious and ethnic minority communities and expand efforts to work with local organizations that serve those communities; (3) to continue to fund capacity building programs for the Iraqi Ministry of Human Rights, the independent national Human Rights Commission, and the newly-created independent minorities committee; and (4) to strongly encourage the Iraqi government to direct the Iraqi Ministry of Human Rights to investigate, report on, and make recommendations to address abuses against, and the marginalization of, members of religious and ethnic minority communities in Iraq. Urges the Iraqi government, with the assistance of the U.S. government and international organizations, to help ensure that displaced Iraqis considering returning to Iraq have the information needed to make informed decisions.</summary>
</bill>
