<bill session="111" type="h" number="3730" updated="2013-07-19T23:45:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financial Education for Teachers and Students Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for financial literacy education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400204"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1339"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2009--Introduced.
Financial Education for Teachers and Students Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to award grants to states to: (1) integrate financial literacy education into their public middle and secondary schools; and (2) provide training to financial literacy teachers in such schools. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) for the provision of financial literacy training and assistance to parents and students. Encourages LEA grantees to partner with community organizations, financial institutions, or local businesses when implementing such program. Directs the Secretary and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to coordinate the activities funded under this Act with the activities carried out by any financial education research center operated by a Federal Reserve bank.</summary>
</bill>
