<bill session="112" type="sr" number="630" updated="2013-07-20T02:15:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-02">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-01-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution congratulating the Navy and the current and former officers and crew of the U.S.S. Enterprise (CVN 65) on completion of the 26th and final deployment of the vessel.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2013-01-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2013-01-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2013-01-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2013-01-02" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8668" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8668" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8666" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hc" number="143"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sc" number="65"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/2/2013--Passed Senate without amendment.
Congratulates the Navy and the many crews of the U.S.S. Enterprise (CVN 65) (Enterprise) on having provided the United States an incalculable service in international relations and engagement and in the prevention and winning of armed conflicts over the 51-year period of its service. Honors the service and memory of: (1) the 117 sailors who made the ultimate sacrifice for their country while serving onboard the Enterprise, including the 30 who were killed in action during the Vietnam War; and (2) the 22 Enterprise sailors who were held as prisoners of war during the Vietnam War, the 3 who died while in captivity, and the 3 still listed as missing-in-action. Congratulates the nearly 100,000 current and former sailors and thousands of current and former Marines who have served on the Enterprise and thanks them for their selfless sacrifice in service to the United States.</summary>
</bill>
