<bill session="112" type="sr" number="372" updated="2013-07-20T02:13:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution recognizing the importance of the United States-Egypt relationship, and urging the Government of Egypt to protect civil liberties and cease intimidation and prosecution of civil society workers and democracy activists, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2012-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S636-637" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-02-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-02-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-02-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="322">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 322.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2012--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Acknowledges the importance of the U.S.-Egyptian strategic partnership. Reiterates support for the Egyptian people during a difficult transition towards a more representative democratic government. Praises the work of U.S. democracy promotion organizations such as the National Democratic Institute, the International Republican Institute, Freedom House, and the International Center for Journalists. Calls upon Egypt to cease its intimidation and prosecution of civil society workers and democracy activists and to allow non-Egyptian civil society workers to voluntarily leave the country. Urges Egypt to protect civil liberties for all citizens and promote a vibrant civil society.</summary>
</bill>
