<bill session="109" type="sr" number="548" updated="2013-07-19T20:11:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-03">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the need for the United States and the international community to take certain actions with respect to the hostilities between Hezbollah and Israel.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2006-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2006-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2006-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2006-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2006-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2006-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8857-8858"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-08-03" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8878-8879" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8878-8879" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref=" CR S8857" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armistices"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hostages"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Logistics"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military withdrawal"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2006--Passed Senate without amendment.
Expresses the the sense of the Senate that: (1) the governments of Syria and Iran should end material and logistical support for Hezbollah and use their influence to disarm Hezbollah and release all kidnapped prisoners; (2) the U.S. government and the international community must work with the governments of Israel and Lebanon for a cessation in the hostilities between Hezbollah and Israel based on the return of Israeli soldiers held in Lebanon, the disarmament of Hezbollah, the removal of all Hezbollah forces from southern Lebanon and their replacement with army and security forces of the government of Lebanon, and an agreement to fully implement United Nations Security Council Resolution 1559; (3) the U.S. government and the international community must work with the governments of Israel and Lebanon to organize an international donors conference to ensure international resources for the reconstruction of Lebanon's civilian infrastructure; (4) the U.S. government and the international community must work with the governments of Israel and Lebanon to promote sustainable peace and security for Israel and Lebanon and the greater Middle East and to assist the government of Lebanon on its path to democracy; and (5) Lebanon's territorial integrity, sovereignty, unity, and political independence should be strongly supported.</summary>
</bill>
