<bill session="110" type="h" number="6872" updated="2013-07-19T22:03:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Presidential Historical Records Preservation Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 44, United States Code, to authorize grants for Presidential Centers of Historical Excellence.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2008-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1767"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3477"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Presidential administrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2008--Introduced.
Presidential Historical Records Preservation Act of 2008 - Authorizes appropriations for the National Historical Publications and Records Commission for FY2010.Requires the Commission to make grants to eligible entities on a competitive basis to promote the historical preservation of, and public access to, historical records and documents relating to any President who does not have a presidential archival depository currently managed and maintained by the federal government pursuant to the Presidential Libraries Act of 1955. Defines eligible entities as specified tax-exempt organizations or state or local governments.Prohibits the use of grants for the maintenance, operating costs, or construction of any facility to house the historical records or documents.Prohibits the Commission from approving a grant application unless an entity establishes that it meets certain requirements, including that it: (1) ensures the preservation of, and access to, such historical works and collections of historical sources at no charge to the public; (2) has educational programs that make the use of such documents part of the entity's mission; and (3) has raised funds from nonfederal sources in support of the entity's efforts to promote such preservation and access.</summary>
</bill>
