<bill session="113" type="sr" number="110" updated="2013-11-02T06:50:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Duplicative and Overlapping Government Programs Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to prevent the creation of duplicative and overlapping Federal programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2013-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2965" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2013--Introduced.
Preventing Duplicative and Overlapping Government Programs Resolution - Amends Rule XXVI (Committee Procedures) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to require the report accompanying each public bill or joint resolution reported by any committee to contain: (1) an analysis by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) to determine if the bill or joint resolution creates any new federal program, office, or initiative that would duplicate or overlap any existing federal entity with similar mission, purpose, goals, or activities, along with a listing of all such overlapping or duplication; and (2) an explanation provided by the committee as to why the creation of each new program, office, or initiative is necessary if a similar program, office, or initiative exists. Amends Rule XVII (References to Committees; Motions to Discharge; Reports of Committees; and Hearings Available) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to make it out of order in the Senate to consider such a measure unless the committee of jurisdiction has prepared and posted on its website an overlapping and duplicative program analysis and explanation for the legislation that contains the same CRS analysis and committee explanation. Permits waiver of this resolution.</summary>
</bill>
