<bill session="112" type="h" number="4084" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Restoring America's Commitment to Consumers Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to establish a national usury rate for consumer credit card accounts under open end consumer credit plans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2012-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2012-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2012--Introduced.
Restoring America's Commitment to Consumers Act of 2012 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to prohibit the annual percentage rate (APR) applicable to an extension of credit on a credit card account under an open end consumer credit plan from exceeding 16%. Includes in an APR any compensation fee (including a membership fee or an annual fee) for: (1) opening or maintaining the account; (2) granting an extension of credit; or (3) making available a line of credit. Authorizes the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Board) to make adjustments to the maximum APR limitation; but creates the presumption that any increase by the Board to the maximum limitation is not in the public interest unless severe economic conditions justify the increase. Prohibits construction of this Act as an endorsement by Congress of a 16% APR. Declares the intention of Congress that: (1) such maximum APR limitation should merely serve as a ceiling on consumer credit cards and few, if any, consumer credit card accounts would ever bear the maximum rate; and (2) consumer credit card issuers should strive to maintain APRs most advantageous to borrowers. Treats as an unfair or deceptive act or practice a credit card account which, as of February 8, 2012, bears an APR that is less than 16%, and subsequently increases it between February 8, 2012, and 60 days after enactment of this Act. Imposes a $15 cap upon certain credit card account fees, including fees (such as late fees, overdraft fees, or over-the-limit transaction fees) for borrower default or breach of any condition upon which credit was extended.</summary>
</bill>
