<bill session="109" type="s" number="628" updated="2013-07-19T20:18:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Promotion FIRST Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Promotion Funding Integrated Research, Synthesis, and Training Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for increased planning and funding for health promotion programs of the Department of Health and Human Services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="2005-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2743"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Health promotion"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Psychology"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2005--Introduced.
Health Promotion Funding Integrated Research, Synthesis, and Training Act or the Health Promotion FIRST Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop a plan for health promotion that includes coordinating the health promotion activities of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) and addressing how best to: (1) develop the basic and applied science of health promotion; (2) disseminate health promotion research; (3) support the health promotion community; and (4) modify or develop policies, structure, and legislation to integrate health promotion into all health professions and sectors of society. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), acting through the Office of Behavioral and Social Sciences Research, to: (1) develop a plan on how best to develop the basic science of health promotion through NIH agencies; and (2) conduct or support early research programs and research training regarding health promotion. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to develop a plan to establish a research agenda regarding health promotion for CDC. Requires the Director of the National Center for Chronic Disease Prevention and Health Promotion to award grants to develop Health Promotion Research Centers. Requires the Director of CDC to: (1) make an effort to attract grant applications from groups experienced in providing programs; (2) fund research to develop the applied science of health promotion for specified settings; and (3) develop a research agenda for workplace health promotion. Requires the Secretary to modify the application process for grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts awarded under this Act to attract the most qualified individuals and organizations, rather than those most experienced with the application process.</summary>
</bill>
