<bill session="113" type="h" number="2127" updated="2013-11-02T06:36:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from finalizing any rule imposing any standard of performance for carbon dioxide emissions from any existing or new source that is a fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating unit unless and until carbon capture and storage is found to be technologically and economically feasible.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412487"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412485" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Prohibits the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) from finalizing any rule imposing a standard of performance for carbon dioxide emissions from any existing or new source that is a fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating unit until: the Administrator determines that carbon capture and storage is the best system of emission reduction ; and carbon capture and storage is found to be technologically and economically feasible for such units in a report submitted by at least three of the following officials: the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, the Comptroller General, the Director of the National Energy Technology Laboratory, and the Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology. Prohibits the Administrator, in proposing or finalizing any such rule, from combining in the same category of stationary sources: (1) an electric utility steam generating unit that is constructed for supplying more than one-third of its potential electric output capacity and more than 25 megawatt net-electrical output to any utility power distribution system for sale, and (2) a combined cycle electric generating unit that is subject to standards of performance for stationary combustion turbines.</summary>
</bill>
