<bill session="113" type="s" number="1340" updated="2013-11-02T07:03:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cruise Passenger Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve passenger vessel security and safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2013-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2800"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2013--Introduced.
Cruise Passenger Protection Act - Amends federal shipping law to direct the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to develop standards for passenger vessel owners to provide passengers with a summary of key terms of passage contracts upfront and before they are binding. Requires such standards to include recommendations that ensure that the summary is conspicuous and unambiguous. Requires vessel owners, no later than 180 days after the standards are developed, to: (1) provide each passenger vessel with a summary meeting those standards, (2) include a link to each website the owner maintains for passengers to purchase or book passage on a passenger vessel, and (3) include the summary in promotional literature or advertising. Applies this Act to passenger vessels that: (1) carry at least 250 passengers, (2) have sleeping facilities for each passenger, (3) are on a voyage that embarks or disembarks passengers in the United States, (4) are not engaged in coastwise trade, and (5) are not federal- or state-owned. Directs the Secretary to establish a toll-free hotline and website for passenger complaints. Prescribes both civil and criminal penalties for persons who violate the requirements of this Act. Directs the Secretary to determine whether any of the enumerated rights in the international cruise line passenger bill of rights (adopted by the members of the Cruise Lines International Association) is enforceable under federal law. Directs the Secretary to establish an advisory committee for passenger vessel consumer protection. Revises passenger vessel security and safety requirements concerning: (1) log book entries and reporting of deaths, missing individuals, thefts, and other crimes; and (2) placement, access to records, and notice of video surveillance equipment to monitor crime. Directs the Secretary to: (1) designate a director of victim support services to act as primary point of contact within the federal government for vessel passengers who are victims of crime, (2) establish a 24-hour toll-free telephone number for crime victims to obtain support services, and (3) develop a summary of rights for victims of crime. Directs the Secretary to maintain on a website a statistical compilation of reported incidents of missing persons, crimes, and other information for vessel passengers. Directs the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, the Attorney General, and heads of other relevant federal agencies, to study the feasibility of having an individual on board each passenger vessel to provide victim support and related safety and security services. Requires the Administrator of the Maritime Administration (who, currently, is merely authorized) to certify organizations in the United States and abroad that offer the curriculum for training and certification of passenger vessel security personnel, crewmembers, and law enforcement officials on the appropriate methods for prevention, detection, evidence preservation, and reporting of crimes in international waters. Revises vessel design, equipment, construction, and retrofitting requirements. Requires the peep hole or other means of visual identification in the entry door of a passenger stateroom or crew cabin to provide an unobstructed view of the area outside the stateroom or crew cabin. Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to withhold or revoke the clearance of, and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to deny entry into the United States to, any vessel owner that: (1) commits an act or omission for which a penalty is imposed under this Act, or (2) fails to pay the penalty.</summary>
</bill>
