<bill session="109" type="s" number="4059" updated="2013-07-19T20:48:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Guarantee of Medical Accuracy in Sex Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit departments, agencies, and other instrumentalities of the Federal Government from providing assistance to an entity for the development of course material or the provision of instruction on human development and sexuality, if such material or instruction will include medically inaccurate information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-11-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11058-11059"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-11-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11059" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5598"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Ethics"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Sex education"/>
    <term name="Sexual abstinence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/2006--Introduced.
Guarantee of Medical Accuracy in Sex Education Act - Prohibits a federal agency from providing funds or assistance to an entity for the development of course material or the provision of instruction on human development and sexuality if such material or instruction will include medically inaccurate information. Directs such an agency to require a sufficient assurance that such material or instruction will not include medically inaccurate information. Defines "medically inaccurate information" as information related to medical, psychiatric, psychological, empirical, or statistical statements that is unsupported or contradicted by peer-reviewed research by leading medical, psychological, psychiatric, and public health organizations and agencies.</summary>
</bill>
