<bill session="112" type="h" number="6330" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protect Seniors Against Identity Theft and Fraud Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide for sentencing enhancements for certain identity theft offenses victimizing the elderly, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412497"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2012-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
Protect Seniors Against Identity Theft and Fraud Act of 2012 - Amends the federal criminal code to authorize an additional term of imprisonment of not more than 10 years for perpetrators of the following offenses, if they result in harm to a person who is 65 years old or older: (1) fraud and related activity in connection with access devices, computers, electronic mail, or identification documents, authentication features, and information; (2) frauds and swindles; (3) mail fraud-related activity involving the use of a fictitious name or address; (4) fraud by wire, radio, or television; (5) bank fraud; and (6) health care fraud. Amends the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to limit the liability of a consumer who is 65 years old or older for losses that the financial institution establishes would not have occurred but for the consumer's failure to report any loss or theft of a card or other means of access, to: (1) $50 if the consumer notifies the institution within 7 business days, or (2) no more than $250 if the consumer notifies the institution within 8 to 60 days.</summary>
</bill>
