<bill session="112" type="h" number="6630" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fort Hood Casualties Benefits Clarification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require that the members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense who were victims in the attack that occurred at Fort Hood, Texas, on November 5, 2009, and the family members of those victims be accorded the same treatment, benefits, and honors as were accorded the victims of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks on the United States and the family members of those victims.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400068"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-04">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-04">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2012--Introduced.
Fort Hood Casualties Benefits Clarification Act - Requires that members of the Armed Forces or civilian employees of the Department of Defense (DOD) who were killed or wounded in the attack that occurred at Fort Hood, Texas, on November 5, 2009, and their family members be accorded the same treatment, benefits, and honors as were accorded the victims and the families of victims of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks.</summary>
</bill>
