<bill session="111" type="h" number="6310" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Accountability for Defense Contractors Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restore accountability and Congressional oversight to the defense contracting process.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7217,  E1815"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3909"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Accountability for Defense Contractors Act - Amends the Act authorizing the making, amending, or modification of federal contracts in order to facilitate the national defense (P.L. 85-804) to direct the Secretary of Defense, if the Department of Defense (DOD) takes any action under the authority of such Act during any year, to report to Congress on all such actions taken by DOD during the preceding year. Requires additional report information with respect to an action taken that involves actual or potential costs to the United States in excess of $1 million. Prohibits a DOD contractor from being indemnified for: (1) government claims against the contractor; (2) a claim, loss, or damage caused by gross negligence, willful misconduct, or lack of good faith on the part of any of the contractor's principal officials; or (3) a claim, loss, or damage resulting from an unusually hazardous or nuclear risk not specified in the contract terms and discovered on the site where the contract is performed, or that reasonably should have been discovered there. Allows a DOD contract to provide for contractor indemnification as the Secretary determines necessary only if the contract complies with: (1) the congressional notification requirements of this Act; and (2) the prohibitions on indemnifications described above.</summary>
</bill>
