<bill session="112" type="s" number="1436" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transportation and Regional Infrastructure Project Bonds Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TRIP Bonds Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide $50,000,000,000 in new transportation infrastructure funding through bonding to empower States and local governments to complete significant infrastructure projects across all modes of transportation, including roads, bridges, rail and transit systems, ports, and inland waterways, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2011-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3736"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2011--Introduced.
Transportation and Regional Infrastructure Project Bonds Act of 2011 or TRIP Bonds Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an income tax credit for any TRIP bond issued by a state infrastructure bank as part of an issue, if 100% of the available project proceeds from such issue are to be used for expenditures incurred for one or more qualified projects. Requires proceeds from the sale of bonds issued under this Act to be held in a TRIP Bonds Trust Account. Defines "qualified project" as the capital improvements to any transportation infrastructure project (including roads, bridges, rail and transit systems, ports, and inland waterways) proposed and approved by a state infrastructure bank. Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to extend certain customs fees for the processing of merchandise entered into the United States through specified dates in 2048.</summary>
</bill>
