<bill session="109" type="h" number="3855" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Farm Relief Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To raise funds necessary to respond to Hurricane Katrina and future disasters by selling a portion of the lands administered by the Forest Service and the Department of the Interior, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400394"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400131" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="2005-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2005-09-21" withdrawn="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400305" joined="2005-09-21" withdrawn="2006-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Dairy, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2005--Introduced.
Directs: (1) the Secretary of Agriculture to select 15% of the lands included in the National Forest System and to convey the lands selected by public sale; and (2) the Secretary of the Interior to identify 15% of the lands managed by agencies of the Department of the Interior (excluding lands in units of the National Park System and lands held for an Indian tribe) and convey the lands identified by public sale. Instructs such Secretaries to: (1) place an emphasis on identifying lands in those states where the United States owns more than 15% of the total land area; and (2) complete the identification of federal lands under this Act and commence the sale of such lands by October 1, 2006. Requires all proceeds from the sale of federal lands under this Act (other than amounts retained to cover the administrative costs incurred solely to conduct the sales) to be deposited in the Disaster Response and Relief Fund established by this Act. Makes amounts in the Disaster Response and Relief Fund available only for appropriation to cover or defray the costs of responding to a natural disaster or terrorist attack in an area covered by a disaster declaration made by the President. Provides that, until such Secretaries comply with the duties imposed on them under this Act, an interest in land may not be acquired by the Forest Service or an agency of the Department of the Interior unless the acquisition of that land is specifically authorized by an Act of Congress enacted after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
