<bill session="113" type="h" number="727" updated="2013-11-02T06:25:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Stewardship and Fire Fuels Reductions Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management stewardship end result contracting authority, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412558" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2013--Introduced.
Forest Stewardship and Fire Fuels Reductions Act of 2013 - Amends the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 to extend, through FY2023, the authority of the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to enter into stewardship end result contracting projects with private persons or other public or private entities to perform services to achieve land management goals for national forests and public lands that meet local and rural community needs. Permits the land management goals of such a project to include restoration work, fire fuels reduction, and clearing of overgrowth on snowpack watersheds.</summary>
</bill>
