<bill session="109" type="s" number="1907" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Native American Small Business Development Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote the development of Native American small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2006-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2006-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2005-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2005-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2006-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2005-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2005-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2006-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2005-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2005-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/21/2005--Introduced.
Native American Small Business Development Act of 2005 - Amends the Small Business Act to establish within the Small Business Administration (SBA) the Office of Native American Affairs, headed by an Assistant Administrator, to implement SBA programs for the development of business enterprises by Native Americans (American Indians, Alaska Natives, and Native Hawaiians). Requires the Office to assist Native American entrepreneurs to: (1) start, operate, and grow small businesses; (2) develop management and technical skills; (3) seek federal procurement opportunities; (4) increase Native American employment opportunities; and (5) increase Native American access to capital markets. Requires the SBA to provide financial assistance to tribal governments, tribal colleges, Native Hawaiian organizations, and Alaska Native corporations to create Native American business centers. Requires each business center to conduct five-year projects for business education aid to such entities. Requires each assistance applicant to submit a five-year plan on proposed assistance and training activities. Establishes a four-year pilot program under which the SBA is authorized to award Native American development grants to provide culturally-tailored business development training and related services to Native Americans and Native American small businesses. Establishes a four-year pilot program under which the SBA shall award at least three American Indian Tribal Assistance Center grants to establish joint projects to provide culturally-tailored business development assistance to prospective and current owners of small businesses on or near tribal lands.</summary>
</bill>
