<bill session="113" type="h" number="3231" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Continuing Protection for Victims and Law Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making automatic continuing appropriations for law enforcement, crime prevention, and victim services programs of the Department of Justice in the event of a Government shutdown.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2013-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2013--Introduced.
Continuing Protection for Victims and Law Enforcement Act - Appropriates for FY2014, for any period during which a joint resolution or other Act making appropriations for commerce, justice, science, and related agencies is not in effect, such sums as may be necessary for continuing law enforcement, crime prevention, and victim services programs of the Department of Justice (DOJ) for which funds were made available in title II of the Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2013 (division B of P.L. 113-6), at a rate for operations as provided for by such Act (as reduced by the presidential sequestration order dated March 1, 2013). Makes appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under this Act available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this Act, (2) enactment of the applicable appropriations Act for FY2014 without any provision for such project or activity, or (3) December 15, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
