<bill session="113" type="sr" number="12" updated="2013-11-02T06:49:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-11">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing the third anniversary of the tragic earthquake in Haiti on January 12, 2010, honoring those who lost their lives in that earthquake, and expressing continued solidarity with the people of Haiti.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2013-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2013-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2013-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2013-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S291-292" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-02-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with an amendment and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-02-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="15">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2013-03-11" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1668-1669" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1668-1669" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2013--Passed Senate amended.
Mourns the loss of lives as a result of the earthquake in Haiti on January 12, 2010, and the subsequent cholera epidemic. Honors the sacrifice made by the government and civil society of Haiti, the U.S. government, the United Nations (U.N.), and the international community in their response to those affected by the calamity. Reaffirms the Senate's solidarity with the government and people of Haiti. Supports the long-term reconstruction efforts of the United States in full cooperation with the government of Haiti, its Office of the Secretary of State for the Integration of Persons with Disabilities, and Haitian civil society, and with private sector support. Urges the President and the international community to: (1) focus assistance on increasing the Haitian public sector's capacity to provide services; (2) involve civil society in Haiti and the Haitian diaspora at all stages of the post-earthquake response; (3) provide programs that protect and involve vulnerable populations; and (4) enhance the government of Haiti's ability to improve economic development, attract investment, pursue judicial reform, enhance the rule of law, reduce gender-based violence, improve water and sanitation systems, and reform land tenure policies. Welcomes evidence of progress in building a better future for Haiti, including: (1) agricultural yields improvements via the Feed the Future initiative, (2) opening the Caracol Industrial Park in northern Haiti, (3) economic opportunity programs for women and survivors of sexual violence and reintegration assistance programs for Haitian migrants, (4) reduction of the cholera mortality rate and provision of HIV and AIDS services, and (5) recruitment and provisioning of new Haitian National Police officers. Urges the President to: (1) continue reconstruction and development efforts coordinated with the government of Haiti, the Haitian diaspora, and appropriate international actors; (2) ensure close monitoring of U.S. aid programs; and (3) work with the Government of Haiti and private landowners to prevent the forced eviction of internally displaced people and communities and to provide sustainable housing solutions for the most vulnerable people in Haiti.</summary>
</bill>
