<bill session="109" type="s" number="500" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Identity Theft bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Information Protection and Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to regulate information brokers and protect individual rights with respect to personally identifiable information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="1080"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2005--Introduced.
Information Protection and Security Act - Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate regulations governing the conduct of information brokers and the protection of personally identifiable information held by such brokers. States that such regulations shall include rules: (1) requiring procedures for maximum data accuracy, confidentiality, user authentication and tracking, the prevention and detection of illegal or unauthorized activity, and mitigation of potential harm to individuals; (2) allowing individuals to obtain disclosure of such information pertaining to them held by an information broker, to be informed of each entity that procured such information, and to request and receive prompt correction of errors; and (3) prohibiting brokers from engaging in activity that fails to comply with FTC regulations. Requires violations of such regulations to be treated as unfair or deceptive acts or practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act. Authorizes States, after providing notice to the FTC and the Attorney General, to bring civil actions on behalf of State residents in Federal district court or any other court of competent jurisdiction to: (1) enjoin such acts or practices; (2) enforce compliance with FTC regulations; or (3) obtain damages, restitution, compensation, or other appropriate relief. Prohibits State actions during the pendency of criminal proceedings brought by the Attorney General or civil actions instituted by the FTC against the same defendant for violations of this Act. Establishes a private right of action for individuals injured by violations of regulations promulgated under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
