<bill session="111" type="h" number="2873" updated="2013-07-19T23:37:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-02T12:04:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-02T12:04:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhanced S.E.C. Enforcement Authority Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Enhanced S.E.C. Enforcement Authority Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide enhanced enforcement authority to the Securities and Exchange Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T11:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Kanjorski moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T11:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13404-13405" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T11:57:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2873.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-12-02T12:04:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13404" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T12:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/2/2009--Passed House amended.
Enhanced S.E.C. Enforcement Authority Act - Amends the Securities Act of 1933, the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, the Investment Company Act of 1940, and the Investment Company Act of 1940 to declare that, in any action or proceeding instituted under such Acts by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) in a U.S. district court for any judicial district, subpoenas issued by or on behalf of the court to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documents or tangible things (or both) may be served in any other district (thus granting the SEC nationwide service of process). States that such subpoenas may be served and enforced without application to the court or a showing of cause. Denies application to subpoenas so issued of the requirement of Rule 45 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure that, on timely motion, the issuing court quash or modify any subpoena that requires a person who is neither a party nor a party's officer to travel more than 100 miles from where that person resides, is employed, or regularly transacts business in person (except that the person may be commanded to attend a trial by traveling from any such place within the state where the trial is held).</summary>
</bill>
