<bill session="111" type="s" number="1596" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gold Hill-Wakamatsu Preservation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Gold Hill-Wakamatsu Preservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to acquire the Gold Hill Ranch in Coloma, California.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2010-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9004-9005"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-645.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-308.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="594">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 594.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="4108"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5653"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Gold Hill-Wakamatsu Preservation Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire the Gold Hill Ranch in Coloma, California, including any interest in the Ranch, by purchase from a willing seller with donated or appropriated funds, donation, or exchange. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into a cooperative agreement with public or nonprofit entities to interpret the history of the Wakamatsu Tea and Silk Farm Colony and related pioneer history associated with Japanese immigration to the area, including the history of traditional Japanese crops and farming practices and the contribution of those practices to the agricultural economy of California. Permits such agreement to include provisions for the development of a visitor center to further public education and interpretation of the Ranch. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
