<bill session="109" type="h" number="6250" updated="2013-07-19T19:59:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to recodify as part of that title the educational assistance programs for members of the reserve components.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2006-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Correspondence schools and courses"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Flight training"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2006--Introduced.
Recodifies under federal veterans' benefits provisions former federal armed forces provisions relating to educational assistance programs for members of the reserve components. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) (currently, the Secretaries of each military department) to establish and maintain a program of educational assistance to members of the Selected Reserve who agree to remain members of the Selected Reserve for at least six years. Increases monthly educational assistance benefit amounts. Includes under such recodification provisions concerning Selected Reserve educational assistance allowances for: (1) apprenticeships and on-the-job training; (2) correspondence courses; (3) tutorial assistance; (4) courses beyond the baccalaureate degree level; and (5) persons with skills or specialties for which there is a critical shortage. Extends the time limitation for the use of such entitlement to ten years after separation from the Selected Reserve (currently, ten years after the person first becomes entitled to such assistance). Requires the Secretary (currently, the Secretaries of each military department) to establish and maintain a program to provide educational assistance to members of the Ready Reserve. Extends the time limitation for the use of such entitlement to ten years after separation from the Ready Reserve.</summary>
</bill>
