<bill session="111" type="sr" number="322" updated="2013-07-20T00:19:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on religious minorities in Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2009-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2010-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10739-10740"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10738-10739" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6989-6990" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-08-05" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="hr" number="944"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4604"/>
    <amendment number="s4605"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Passed Senate amended.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States remains deeply concerned about the plight of vulnerable religious and ethnic minorities of Iraq; (2) the U.S. government and the United Nations Assistance Mission for Iraq (UNAMI) should urge the government of Iraq to enhance security at places of worship in Iraq; (3) the U.S. government should work with the government of Iraq to ensure that members of minorities suffer no employment discrimination in the Iraqi police and security forces; (4) the government of Iraq and the Kurdistan regional government should work towards a peaceful resolution of territorial disputes; (5) the U.S. government and UNAMI should urge the government of Iraq to implement provisions of the Constitution of Iraq that protect rights to freedom of thought and religion; (6) the government of Iraq should act to reverse the marginalization of religious minorities; (7) the U.S. government should fund capacity-building programs for the Iraqi Ministry of Human Rights and the independent national Human Rights Commission and should continue to help reconstitute the minorities committee; (8) the government of Iraq should direct the Iraqi Ministry of Human Rights to issue a public report on abuses against, and the marginalization of, minorities; and (9) the U.S. government should encourage the government of Iraq and the Kurdistan regional government to protect minorities, particularly those in the Nineveh Plain.</summary>
</bill>
