<bill session="113" type="s" number="999" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Responding to Urgent needs of Survivors of the Holocaust Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RUSH Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to provide social service agencies with the resources to provide services to meet the urgent needs of Holocaust survivors to age in place with dignity, comfort, security, and quality of life.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2064"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2013--Introduced.
Responding to Urgent Needs of Survivors of the Holocaust Act or RUSH Act - Amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 to include specifically within its purview older Americans who are Holocaust survivors. Authorizes the Administrator for Community Living to designate, within the Administration for Community Living of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), a person with specialized training, background, or experience with issues of Holocaust survivors to implement services for them. Requires a state nutrition project to: (1) ensure that project meals meet the dietary needs of program participants based on religious, cultural, or ethnic requirements; and (2) encourage individuals who distribute nutrition services to engage in conversation with homebound older individuals and to be aware of the warning signs of medical emergencies, injury, or abuse in order to reduce isolation and promote wellbeing. Amends the Older Americans Act Amendments of 2006 to require the study of nutrition projects to analyze the abilities of service providers to obtain viable contracts for special foods necessary to meet a religious requirement, required dietary need, or ethnic consideration. Authorizes the HHS Assistant Secretary for Aging to make grants to or contract with states, public agencies, private nonprofit agencies, institutions of higher education, and organizations, including tribal organizations, to support programs that provide transportation services and resources to older individuals with the greatest economic or social need.</summary>
</bill>
