<bill session="113" type="s" number="1506" updated="2013-11-02T07:04:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gulf Coast Oil Recovery Zone Tax Relief and Economic Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide tax relief for persons affected by the discharge of oil in connection with the explosion on, and sinking of, the mobile offshore drilling unit Deepwater Horizon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2013--Introduced.
Gulf Coast Oil Recovery Zone Tax Relief and Economic Recovery Act - Allows non-recognition, for income tax purposes, of proceeds or payments from insurance received in connection with the Gulf oil spill or any payment for damages attributable to the oil spill under the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 that are invested in a qualified recovery zone trade or business within five years after the later of an oil spill payment or the enactment of this Act. Defines: (1) "Gulf oil spill' as the discharge of oil by reason of the explosion on, and sinking of, the mobile offshore drilling unit Deepwater Horizon; (2) "recovery zone" as certain counties in Florida, Mississippi, and Alabama and specified parishes in Louisiana that were affected by the oil spill; and (3) "qualified recovery zone trade or business" as any commercial or charter fishing business or any hotel, lodging, recreation, entertainment operating in, or restaurant business located in, the recovery zone.</summary>
</bill>
