<bill session="112" type="h" number="6108" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce the pay of Members of Congress who miss votes because of campaigning for election to another office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2012--Introduced.
Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to reduce the rate of pay otherwise applicable to Members of Congress for any month, during a Congress, by the Member's missed vote percentage for the most recent month before such month if the individual missed votes because of campaigning for election to another office. Applies this requirement to a vote taken in the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union unless the Member of the House of Representatives did not engage in any campaign-related activity on the date of the vote. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer from the general fund of the Treasury to a specified mandatory account to reduce the public debt the difference between the aggregate amount expended for pay of Members of Congress for the fiscal year and the aggregate amount that would have been expended but for the reduction in pay.</summary>
</bill>
