<bill session="112" type="s" number="1102" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fairness for Struggling Students Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 11, United States Code, with respect to certain exceptions to discharge in bankruptcy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2012-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2011-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2012-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3436"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3436-3437" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Administrative Oversight and the Courts. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Oversight and the Courts" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
Fairness for Struggling Students Act of 2011 - Revises federal bankruptcy law with respect to the exemption from the exception to discharge in bankruptcy for certain educational loans if excepting such debt from discharge would impose an undue hardship on the debtor and debtor's dependents. Limits such exemption to the existing ones for: (1) an educational benefit overpayment or loan made, insured, or guaranteed by a governmental unit or made under any program funded in whole or in part by a governmental unit; and (2) an obligation to repay funds received from a governmental unit as an educational benefit, scholarship, or stipend. Repeals the current exemption for: (1) any loan made under any program funded in whole or in part by a governmental unit or nonprofit institution; and (2) any other qualified education loan incurred by an individual debtor on behalf of the taxpayer, the taxpayer's spouse, or any dependent, including indebtedness used to refinance a qualified education loan. (Thus makes both kinds of loans nondischargeable in bankruptcy.)</summary>
</bill>
