<bill session="112" type="h" number="6638" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">S.A.F.E. Compounded Drugs Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Supporting Access to Formulated and Effective Compounded Drugs Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to enhance the requirements for pharmacies that compound drug products.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2012-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2012--Introduced.
Supporting Access to Formulated and Effective Compounded Drugs Act of 2012 or S.A.F.E. Compounded Drugs Act of 2012 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FFDCA) with respect to the regulation of compounded drugs. Eliminates authority for compounding pharmacies to compound any drug product that is a copy of a commercially available drug. Establishes notification requirements before a patient is prescribed, dispensed, or administered a compounded drug, which must include providing the patient a document concerning the availability, safety, and production of such drugs. Requires a drug product compounded under the FFDCA to be clearly labeled as a &#8220;non-FDA approved compounded drug product.&#8221; Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish different labeling requirements for compounded drugs. Requires the Secretary to establish a process for pharmacies to register as compounding pharmacies. Exempts pharmacies that employ fewer than 20 full-time employees and perform traditional compounding of drug products for use in a single state. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a database of information on compounding pharmacies licensed in more than one state for oversight purposes, (2) establish minimum standards for the safe production of compounded drugs as well as for which drugs must meet those standards, and (3) conduct regional training for state agencies that regulate compounding pharmacies. Directs the Secretary to establish advisory committees on labeling of compounded drugs and on the database under this Act. Requires the Secretary to convene an Advisory Committee on Pharmacy Compounding as appropriate to consider issues related to the safety and availability of compounded drugs.</summary>
</bill>
