<bill session="111" type="h" number="4666" updated="2013-07-19T23:54:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cluster-Based Economy Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 to establish a grant program to support cluster-based economic development efforts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2010-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2010-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="826"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="826"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/23/2010--Introduced.
Cluster-Based Economy Enhancement Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Commerce to make block grants to a state or local government, an institution of higher education, or a nonprofit economic development organization to: (1) assess the potential for the development or enhancement of business clusters (geographic concentrations of business entities that are competing, complementary, or interdependent firms and industries, that do business with one another, and that have common needs for talent, technology, and infrastructure); (2) establish cluster development programs in specified regions of the United States; and (3) promote cluster development programs in such regions and support the staff who operate such programs. Permits a recipient of grant funds to use the funds to provide assistance for startup costs, worker training, relocation costs, planning, and other projects identified by the recipient that are consistent with the purposes of this Act. Limits: (1) the federal share of the cost of projects carried out using funds authorized by this Act to 50%; and (2) the portion of the non-federal share of project costs that may be provided through in-kind contributions to 50%.</summary>
</bill>
