<bill session="112" type="h" number="6712" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Elgin Stafford Mental Illness Information Disclosure Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Elgin's Law</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the disclosure to parents of information regarding mental illness treatment for their children under the age of 26.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/27/2012--Introduced.
Elgin Stafford Mental Illness Information Disclosure Act of 2012 or Elgin's Law - Requires a health care professional to disclose to a parent of a covered individual being treated for a mental illness any information regarding the mental illness and treatment which may be useful for the parent's appropriate involvement with the treatment. Excludes exceptional circumstances where parental involvement would be counter-productive to treatment. Makes such a disclosure permissible under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) as not requiring consent of the covered individual. Applies this Act to a minor child, an uninsured adult under age 26, or an adult under age 26 who is included as a dependent under the parent's health benefits coverage.</summary>
</bill>
