<bill session="111" type="s" number="1036" updated="2013-07-20T00:32:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Surface Transportation Policy and Planning Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to establish national purposes and goals for Federal surface transportation activities and programs and create a national surface transportation plan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2009--Introduced.
Federal Surface Transportation Policy and Planning Act of 2009 - Declares it is U.S. policy to develop a national surface transportation system that advances the national interest and defense, interstate and foreign commerce, the efficient and safe interstate mobility of people and goods, and the protection of the environment. Sets forth certain U.S. policy objectives and goals, including to: (1) reduce national per capita motor vehicle miles traveled annually; (2) reduce national surface transportation-generated carbon dioxide levels by 40% by 2030; (3) reduce national surface transportation (including passenger and freight) delays and congestion at U.S. points of entry; (4) increase the total usage of public transportation, intercity passenger rail services, and non-motorized transportation; and (5) ensure adequate transportation of domestic energy supplies. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) develop performance criteria and data collections systems to evaluate the effectiveness of federal surface transportation programs; (2) implement such programs to meet the policy, objectives, goals, and performance criteria established by this Act; and (3) develop and implement a National Surface Transportation Performance Plan. Authorizes the Secretary to amend the goals established under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
