<bill session="113" type="h" number="1799" updated="2013-11-02T06:34:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Arizona Sonoran Desert Heritage Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain public lands in the Sonoran Desert of the State of Arizona as national conservation areas and wilderness areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2013-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2013--Introduced.
Arizona Sonoran Desert Heritage Act of 2013 - Establishes the Belmont-Harquahala National Conservation Area and the Gila Bend National Conservation Area in Arizona. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to manage the Conservation Areas as: (1) components the National Landscape Conservation System, and (2) in a manner that conserves and enhances their resources and values. Designates specified wilderness and wilderness additions in Maricopa County, Arizona, as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Establishes the Sentinel Plain Special Management Area and the Rainbow Valley Special Management Area in Arizona. Requires the Secretary to develop separate comprehensive management plans for the long-term protection and management of such Areas. Requires the Secretary to provide for the protection of the Agua Caliente Road.</summary>
</bill>
