<bill session="110" type="s" number="1209" updated="2013-07-19T22:30:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Channel Islands National Park Management Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the continued administration of Santa Rosa Island, Channel Islands National Park, in accordance with the laws (including regulations) and policies of the National Park Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5095"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5095-5096" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-104.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2029"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2029"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Deer"/>
    <term name="Elk"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2007--Introduced.
Channel Islands National Park Management Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to manage Santa Rosa Island, Channel Islands National Park in California: (1) in accordance with the National Park Service Organic Act, title II of Public Law 96-199 (relating to the establishment of the Park), and any other laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System; and (2) in a manner that ensures that the natural, scenic, and cultural resources of Santa Rosa Island are protected, restored, and interpreted for the public and visitors to the Park are provided with a safe and enjoyable Park experience. Repeals a provision of the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 which requires the Secretary of the Interior to immediately cease the plan to exterminate deer and elk on Santa Rosa Island by helicopter.</summary>
</bill>
