<bill session="109" type="s" number="2786" updated="2013-07-19T20:37:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to permit access to databases maintained by the Federal Emergency Management Agency for purposes of complying with sex offender registry and notification laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4381"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2006--Introduced.
Amends the Privacy Act of 1974 to authorize the disclosure to government agencies of Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) records on assistance provided to individuals in connection with a major disaster or emergency for purposes of complying with a federal or state sex offender registry or notification law. Conditions receipt of federal funds by non-governmental organizations under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act on the organization providing assurances satisfactory to the President that it will disclose its records for the purpose of permitting a requesting jurisdiction to comply with a federal or state sex offender registry or notification law.</summary>
</bill>
