<bill session="109" type="s" number="2699" updated="2013-07-19T20:37:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Elimination of Neglected Diseases Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote the research and development of drugs related to neglected and tropical diseases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2006-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3900"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Antibiotics"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Malaria"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/2006--Introduced.
Elimination of Neglected Diseases Act of 2006 - Provides for the extension and restoration of the patent term for a certified tropical disease product: (1) that is used to treat neglected or tropical diseases such as HIV, malaria, tuberculosis, or other infectious disease that disproportionately affect poor and marginalized populations; and (2) the patent for which claims an approved new molecular entity standard review drug or the process of making such a drug or the drug's active ingredient. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, to: (1) designate as a new molecular entity standard review drug a drug that has a new molecular entity chemical type classification and standard review drug treatment potential classifications and is not a drug developed to treat serious or life-threatening diseases; and (2) maintain and annually update a classification list of serious and life-threatening diseases. Allows the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, to remove the designation of a drug as a new molecular entity standard review drug. Requires the Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) to study the effect of patent extension and restoration on the ability of pharmaceutical companies to develop and distribute tropical disease products for poor and marginalized populations.</summary>
</bill>
