<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1039" updated="2013-07-19T20:59:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-12">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Raising a question of the privileges of the House.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400036"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12T10:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1543-1544" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1544" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12T10:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McGovern moved to table the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12T11:22:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the measure Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 215 - 193 (Roll no. 125).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hr" number="895"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hr" number="1031"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional leadership"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Democratic Party"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2008--Introduced.
Declares that the House: (1) denounces any violations of House rules by Speaker Nancy Pelosi and other Members of the Democratic leadership in the strongest terms possible; (2) rejects the practices of holding votes open beyond a reasonable period of time for the sole purpose of circumventing the will of the House; and (3) directs the Speaker to take such steps as necessary to prevent any further abuse. Vacates the votes on ordering the previous question and adoption of House Resolution 1031 (adopting H.Res. 895). Directs the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to investigate and report to the House on: (1) violations of House rules by the Speaker and such Members; and (2) its findings and recommendations to the House, including a recommendation regarding the appropriate actions for the Speaker's activities. Directs the Select Committee to Investigate the Voting Irregularities of August 2, 2007, to investigate and include in the report its findings and resulting recommendations concerning the actions of the Speaker, the time the vote was held open and the changes in votes cast by members, resulting in passage of the previous question vote to H. Res. 1031 on March 11, 2008.</summary>
</bill>
