<bill session="110" type="s" number="2474" updated="2013-07-19T22:42:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Port of Entry Personnel and Infrastructure Funding Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide additional resources and funding to address inspection delays at United States ports of entry on the Southern border, open additional inspection lanes, hire more inspectors, and provide recruitment and retention incentives for United States customs and Border Protection officers who serve on the Northern and Southern borders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Police communication systems"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2007--Introduced.
Emergency Port of Entry Personnel and Infrastructure Funding Act of 2007 - Directs the U.S. Customs and Border Protection for FY2009-FY2012 to hire, train, and assign additional customs and border protection personnel (with an additional allotment for Texas) for the Northern and Southern U.S. borders. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) to ensure such personnel are equipped with secure two-way communication devices and that existing personnel and new hires receive law enforcement training. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) construct additional ports of entry along the Northern and Southern U.S. borders; and (2) determine the location for new U.S. ports of entry. Requires expansion of the vehicle, cargo, and pedestrian inspection lanes at Eagle Pass, Texas, and Laredo, Texas. Exempts the provisions of this Act from: (1) the Administrative Procedures Act and the Paperwork Reduction Act; and (2) federal competitive contracting and hiring requirements. Authorizes appropriations, including for continued implementation of: (1) the Secure Border Initiative, the Western Hemisphere Travel Initiative, and the US-VISIT program; and (2) the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism.</summary>
</bill>
