<bill session="111" type="s" number="3405" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Close Big Oil Tax Loopholes Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to eliminate oil and gas company preferences.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2010-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2010--Introduced.
Close Big Oil Tax Loopholes Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to deny to taxpayers with gross revenues in excess of $100 million in a taxable year (applicable large taxpayers): (1) the tax deduction for intangible drilling and development costs; (2) the tax deduction for qualified tertiary injectant expenses; (3) the exemption from restrictions on the deductibility of passive losses; (4) the percentage depletion allowance for oil and gas wells; and (5) the tax deduction for income attributable to domestic production of oil, natural gas, or primary products thereof. Requires applicable large taxpayers to amortize their geological and geophysical expenditures over a seven-year period. Imposes on producers of taxable crude oil or natural gas a 13% excise tax on the removal price of such oil and natural gas produced from lands on the Outer Continental Shelf in the Gulf of Mexico. Allows a nonrefundable credit against such tax for royalties paid under federal law with respect to the production of such crude oil and natural gas. Denies a foreign tax credit to any large integrated oil company that is subject to a levy of a foreign country or possession of the United States and receives an economic benefit from such country or possession (dual capacity taxpayer) if such country or possession does not impose a generally applicable income tax.</summary>
</bill>
