<bill session="111" type="s" number="213" updated="2013-07-20T00:25:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Airline Passenger Bill of Rights Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to ensure air passengers have access to necessary services while on a grounded air carrier, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2009-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2009-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S314-315"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="624"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="624"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/12/2009--Introduced.
Airline Passenger Bill of Rights Act of 2009 - Requires each air carrier and airport operator to submit for approval by the Secretary of Transportation a proposed contingency plan meeting minimum standards established by the Secretary. Requires an air carrier to provide passengers on a departure- or arrival-delayed grounded aircraft with: (1) adequate food, water, restrooms, ventilation, and medical services; as well as (2) a time frame under which passengers may deplane a delayed aircraft after three hours, except in specified circumstances. Requires an airport operator plan to describe: (1) how passengers will be deplaned following a long tarmac delay; and (2) how facilities will be shared and gates made available to aircraft that experience such delays. Authorizes the Secretary to assess a civil penalty against air carriers and airport operators that fail to submit, obtain approval of, or adhere to a contingency plan. Requires public access to such plans. Directs the Secretary to establish a consumer hotline telephone number for air passenger complaints.</summary>
</bill>
