<bill session="111" type="s" number="3549" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the effective date of the gift card provisions of the Credit Card Accountability Responsibility and Disclosure Act of 2009.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2010-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2010-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5502"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2010--Introduced.
Amends the Credit Card Accountability Responsibility and Disclosure Act of 2009 to state that, in the case of a gift certificate, store gift card, or general-use prepaid card produced before April 1, 2010, the effective date of the certain disclosure requirements under the Electronic Funds Transfer Act pertaining to fees shall be delayed until January 31, 2011. Requires the issuer of such a certificate or card, as a condition of such delayed effective date, to: (1) comply with a specified prohibition against and certain requirements for the imposition of any dormancy, inactivity, or service fees; (2) consider any such certificate or card for which funds expire to have no expiration date with respect to the underlying funds; (3) replace, at consumer request, any such certificate or card that has funds remaining at no cost to the consumer; and (4) comply with certain consumer rights disclosure requirements.</summary>
</bill>
