<bill session="112" type="s" number="1488" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hyde Amendment Codification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit the expenditure of Federal funds for abortion, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="397"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="906"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1484"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2011--Introduced.
Hyde Amendment Codification Act - Prohibits the expenditure of funds authorized or appropriated by federal law or funds in any trust fund to which funds are authorized or appropriated by federal law (federal funds) for any abortion.Prohibits federal funds from being used for any health benefits coverage that includes coverage of abortion. (Currently, federal funds cannot be used for abortion services and plans receiving federal funds must keep federal funds segregated from any funds for abortion services.) Excludes from such prohibitions an abortion if: (1) the pregnancy is the result of rape or incest; or (2) the woman suffers from a physical disorder, injury, or illness, including a life-endangering physical condition caused by or arising from the pregnancy itself, that would place her in danger of death unless an abortion is performed, as certified by a physician.</summary>
</bill>
