<bill session="111" type="s" number="3566" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Maritime Administration Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Maritime Administration Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize certain maritime programs of the Department of Transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2010-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2010-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-17">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-12-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="712">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 712.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>By Senator Rockefeller from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 111-382.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/17/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Maritime Administration Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011 - (Sec. 2) Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) for FY2011 for the Maritime Administration for: (1) operations and training activities, including earmarks for U.S. Merchant Marine Academy capital improvements and maintenance and repair for State Maritime Schools training ships; (2) administrative expenses related to maritime guaranteed loan commitments; (3) the disposal of non-retention vessels in the National Defense Reserve Fleet; and (4) maintenance of a U.S.-flag merchant fleet. (Sec. 3) Revises the purposes of the United States Merchant Marine Academy to emphasize: (1) its status as an institution of higher education; and (2) maritime-related research and provision of other appropriate academic support, assistance, training, and activities to prepare individuals for service in the U.S. merchant marine. (Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary, not later than July 31, 2012, to report to Congress on the status of the nation's coastal and inland waterways infrastructure. Authorizes the Secretary to investigate, make determinations concerning, and develop a repository of statistical information on intercoastal water transportation. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Maritime Administration to assess, and report to Congress on, the potential for using container-on-barge transportation on the inland waterways system. (Sec. 5) Eliminates separate landside congestion mitigation projects from the short sea transportation program. Authorizes the Secretary to designate a project as a short sea transportation project if it will provide transportation services for passengers or freight (or both) that may reduce congestion on landside infrastructure or lead to other public benefits. (Sec. 6) Declares that certain maritime law limitations shall not affect the Maritime Administration's authority to dispose of National Defense Reserve Fleet vessels or shipyards for recycling. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the Secretary to establish a green ships program to: (1) identify, evaluate, demonstrate, or improve emerging marine technologies likely to achieve environmental improvements through reduction of air or water emissions, increased fuel economy, or control of aquatic invasive species; and (2) develop and approve a validation and testing regime to certify or validate emerging technologies that demonstrate significant environmental benefits. (Sec. 8) Authorizes the donation, instead of sale, of non-retention (obsolete) vessels in the National Defense Reserve Fleet.</summary>
</bill>
