<bill session="111" type="h" number="5048" updated="2013-07-19T23:57:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Heroes Credit Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to enhance the protection of credit ratings of servicemembers serving on active duty, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="2010-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2010--Introduced.
National Heroes Credit Protection Act - Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to authorize a servicemember, after having served on active duty for more than 180 days, to request that a consumer reporting agency (CRA) include in that servicemember's file a military service deployment alert. Requires the CRA to: (1) provide the alert to each person who requests the credit score or consumer report of such servicemember; and (2) develop and maintain procedures for referral of such alert to other CRAs. Requires: (1) a reseller of credit reporting information to include in any report on a servicemember any alert placed in such servicemember's file by another CRA; and (2) any user of a consumer credit report containing such alert to acknowledge to the servicemember the receipt of the alert.</summary>
</bill>
