<bill session="110" type="s" number="1931" updated="2013-07-19T22:37:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Surface Owner Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Mineral Leasing Act to ensure that development of certain Federal oil and gas resources will occur in a manner that protects water resources and respects the rights of surface owners, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10623"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2007--Introduced.
Surface Owner Protection Act - Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to require an operator producing oil or gas (including coalbed methane) under a federal lease to: (1) replace the water supply of a water user who obtains all or part of it from an underground or surface source affected by contamination, diminution, or interruption proximately resulting from such drilling operations; and (2) comply with federal and state law governing discharge of water produced under the lease. Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior from authorizing exploration and drilling operations on land with respect to which title to oil and gas resources is held by the United States but not the title to the surface estate, unless the operator has filed a document with the Secretary, signed by the operator and surface owners, that a written surface use agreement has been consummated meeting certain criteria. Cites conditions under which the Secretary may authorize an operator to conduct exploration and drilling operations in the absence of such an agreement. Requires the Secretary to comply with specified surface owner notification requirements.Sets forth reclamation and bond requirements.</summary>
</bill>
