<bill session="112" type="s" number="1994" updated="2013-07-20T02:33:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Deceptive Practices and Voter Intimidation Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit deceptive practices in Federal elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2011-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-26">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/14/2011--Introduced.
Deceptive Practices and Voter Intimidation Prevention Act of 2011 - Amends the Revised Statutes and federal criminal law to prohibit any person, whether acting under color of law or otherwise, from knowingly misleading voters regarding: (1) the time or place of holding any federal election, (2) the qualifications for or restrictions on voter eligibility for any such election, or (3) an endorsement. Prohibits hindering, interfering with, or preventing another person from voting, registering to vote, or aiding another person to vote or register to vote in a federal election. Creates a private right of action for any person aggrieved by a violation of such prohibition. Amends the federal criminal code to prescribe criminal penalties for such deceptive acts. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and, if appropriate, amend the federal sentencing guidelines and policy statements applicable to persons convicted of any offense under this Act. Authorizes any person to report to the Attorney General false election information. Requires the Attorney General, if receiving a credible report that materially false information has been or is being communicated, to communicate to the public accurate information designed to correct the materially false information if the Attorney General determines that state and local election officials have not taken adequate steps to promptly communicate accurate information to correct the materially false information.</summary>
</bill>
