<bill session="109" type="h" number="4999" updated="2013-07-19T19:48:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance security and protect against terrorist attacks at chemical facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2006-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman .</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5695"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="2145"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Ammonia"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Industrial buildings"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Nitrates"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2006--Introduced.
Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Act of 2006 - Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) establish criteria for designating chemical sources, using specified risk factors, and evaluating the types of facilities (other than Department of Defense or Department of Energy facilities) in consideration; and (2) designate chemical sources already in existence. Directs the Secretary to promulgate rules establishing a risk-based tier system of chemical sources, based on such criteria, which enables a chemical source to develop appropriate site-specific measures to meet the security performance standards established for the applicable tier. Requires such rules to provide guidance to the chemical source owner or operator on steps that would enable the source to move to a lower risk tier. Directs the Secretary to promulgate regulations that require chemical source owners or operators to make vulnerability assessments, site security plans, and emergency response plans. Requires chemical sources regulated under the Maritime Transportation Security Act (MTSA-regulated facilities) to comply with this Act. Requires the Secretary to establish an office under the Assistant Secretary for Infrastructure Protection that shall be responsible for implementing and enforcing this Act. Directs the Secretary to establish in each Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) Region an Infrastructure Protection Regional Security Office. Establishes Area Security Committees for geographic areas designated by the Secretary, which shall prepare Area Security Plans for the Secretary's approval. Directs the Secretary to conduct drills and exercises periodically in each area for which an Area Security Plan is required and under the site security plan and emergency response plans of relevant chemical sources. Authorizes the Secretary to order mandatory security measures for a chemical source if the Secretary determines that additional measures are necessary to respond to a threat assessment or to a specific threat against the chemical sector. Prescribes administrative, civil, and criminal penalties for failure to comply with an order or directive issued by the Secretary under this Act or with a site security plan.</summary>
</bill>
