<bill session="111" type="h" number="2068" updated="2013-07-19T23:30:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Telehealth Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the provision of telehealth services under the Medicare Program, to provide grants for the development of telehealth networks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400403"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2009-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2009-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2009-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400254" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2009-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2009-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2009-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2009-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/2009--Introduced.
Medicare Telehealth Enhancement Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act regarding telehealth services (furnished via a telecommunication system by a physician to an enrolled individual). Removes current geographic restrictions on the provision of such services. Extends the meaning of store-and-forward technology, for any federal telemedicine demonstration program in Alaska or Hawaii, to include any telehealth program that has received any federal support from the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMMS), the Indian Health Service, or the Health Services and Resources Administration (HSRA). Authorizes a renal dialysis facility to participate in the telehealth program. Authorizes payment of eligible telehealth providers or suppliers other than a physician or telemedicine practitioner. Declares that any telemedicine practitioner credentialed by a hospital in compliance with the Joint Commission Standards for Telemedicine shall be considered in compliance with Medicare condition of participation and reimbursement credentialing requirements for telemedicine services. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to treat telehealth services furnished by a home health agency as a home health visit for Medicare purposes. Authorizes coverage of remote patient management services, including home health remote patient management services, for certain chronic health conditions. Directs the Secretary to establish a fee schedule for home health remote patient management services. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the CMMS Administrator should be encouraged to: (1) expand the types of medical conditions for which remote patient management services are reimbursed under Medicare; (2) provide for separate, non-bundled Medicare payment for such services; and (3) create, revise, and adjust codes for the accurate reporting and billing for such payment. Establishes the Telehealth Advisory Committee. Requires the Secretary to take its recommendations into account when adding or deleting telehealth services and in establishing related CMMS policies. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the HSRA Office for the Advancement of Telehealth, to make grants to expand access via telehealth to health care services for individuals in medically underserved rural, frontier, and urban areas. Amends the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize telehealth network and telehealth resource centers grant programs.</summary>
</bill>
