<bill session="110" type="h" number="5773" updated="2013-07-19T21:54:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a long-term ground lease for the operation and maintenance of Rock Creek, Langston, and East Potomac as golf courses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2008-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="4033"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Blacks"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in public facilities"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Golf"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Segregation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports facilities"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2008--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, to: (1) solicit proposals to procure the lease for the continued operation and maintenance of the Rock Creek, Langston, and East Potomac golf courses in the District of Columbia; and (2) ensure that month-to-month concessions contracts are continued for the operation and maintenance of Rock Creek and Langston golf courses until the lease in force on the date of this Act's enactment for East Potomac expires. Requires the lease to include the three golf courses in one lease agreement and mandate that the courses be operated and maintained in a manner that: (1) retains the historic nature of the courses, including an appropriate commemoration of the Langston Golf Course's historic place in African American golf history; (2) ensures that at least two of the courses maintain fees related to use that are affordable; (3) may allow fees collected at one course to subsidize the maintenance and operation of one or more of the others; and (4) allows for a long-term ground lease on the three courses. Directs the Secretary to solicit the request for proposals in a manner that: (1) provides that the lease shall be entered into within a specified time frame; and (2) ensures the participation of disadvantaged business enterprises among the equity partners of the sponsors of the proposals.Makes the National Park Service Concessions Management Improvement Act of 1998 inapplicable to requests for proposals submitted and leases and agreements entered into under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
