<bill session="113" type="h" number="2345" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Internal Resource Slush Fund Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to prohibit the transfer or reprogramming of discretionary appropriations made available to the Internal Revenue Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400411"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2013--Introduced.
Stop Internal Resource Slush Fund Act - Prohibits the transfer or reprogramming of funds made available to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) if such funds are derived from: (1) fees for services provided by the IRS, (2) discretionary appropriations for salaries and expenses or other personnel and hiring programs, or (3) reimbursable programs. Rescinds any unobligated funds resulting from this Act and directs their return to the general fund of the Treasury for the sole purpose of deficit reduction.</summary>
</bill>
