<bill session="109" type="s" number="1410" updated="2013-07-19T20:25:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300020"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2005-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-07-20">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-09-06">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe without amendment. With written report No. 109-132.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-09-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="201">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 201.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="518"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="518"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="518"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/6/2005--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Improvement Act of 2005 - Amends the Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Act to apply to migratory bird species from Canada. Increases (from 25 to 50 percent) the federal share of costs for funded projects. Prescribes forms of payment for projects undertaken in the United States and Canada and for projects undertaken in Latin America and the Caribbean. Revises the reporting requirements under this Act to require the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) report to Congress not later than two years after the enactment of this Act; and (2) include a description of the activities of the advisory group convened by the Secretary. Replaces provisions establishing the Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Account within the Multinational Species Conservation Fund with provisions establishing the Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Fund and directs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer Account amounts to such Fund. Authorizes appropriations to the Fund through FY2010. Requires not less than 75 percent of such appropriations to be used for projects outside the United States. Increases the amount of funds that the Secretary may expend to administer the Act.</summary>
</bill>
