<bill session="111" type="s" number="582" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Interest Rate Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Truth in Lending Act to protect consumers from usury, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3076-3077"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1640"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2009--Introduced.
Interest Rate Reduction Act - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to prohibit the annual percentage rate of interest (APR) applicable to any extension of credit to a consumer from exceeding 15% on unpaid balances, inclusive of all finance charges. Authorizes the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to establish an APR ceiling exceeding the 15% annual rate for periods not to exceed 18 months, upon a determination that: (1) money market interest rates have risen over the preceding six-month period; and (2) prevailing interest rate levels threaten the safety and soundness of individual lenders, as evidenced by adverse trends in liquidity, capital, earnings, and growth. Declares the interest rate limitation inapplicable to an extension of credit by an insured credit union.Subjects a creditor who violates this Act to a civil penalty.</summary>
</bill>
