<bill session="110" type="s" number="3318" updated="2013-07-19T22:50:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Physician Payment Equity Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for recognition of equality of physician work in all geographic areas and revisions to the practice expense geographic adjustment under the Medicare physician fee schedule.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7156-7157"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7157-7158" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2008--Introduced.
Medicare Physician Payment Equity Act of 2008 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to recognize equality of physician work in all geographic areas under the Medicare physician fee schedule. Makes the geographic index 1.0 in all fee schedule areas for physician services furnished on or after January 2010. Requires the Secretary, after calculating the practice expense geographic index, for purposes of payment for services furnished in 2009, to increase the practice expense geographic index to 1.0 for any locality for which such practice expense geographic index is less than 1.0. Requires the practice expense geographic index, for services furnished on or after January 1, 2010, to reflect half the difference between the relative costs of employee wages and office rents in each of the different fee schedule areas and the national average of such wages and rents.</summary>
</bill>
