<bill session="111" type="h" number="1287" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-08T14:30:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-09-08T14:30:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center Partnership Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center Partnership Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center Partnership Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a partnership with the Porter County Convention, Recreation and Visitor Commission regarding the use of the Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center as a visitor center for the Indiana Dunes National Lakeshore, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400417"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2009-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-08T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-08T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9289" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-08T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1287.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-09-08T14:30:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9289" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-09-08T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 111-148.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="298">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 298.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Seashores and lakeshores"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2010--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center Partnership Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a memorandum of understanding to establish a joint partnership with the Porter County Convention, Recreation and Visitor Commission with regard to the use of the Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center as a visitor center for the Indiana Dunes National Lakeshore. Allows the Secretary to: (1) plan, design, construct, and install exhibits in the Center related to the use and management of the resources at the Lakeshore, at a cost under $1.5 million; and (2) use park staff from the Lakeshore in the Center to provide visitor information and education. States that, for the purposes of the acquisition of lands or interests in lands outside the present boundaries of the Lakeshore, lands may be considered contiguous to other lands if the lands touch them, or are separated from them by only a public or private right-of-way, such as a road, railroad, or utility corridor.</summary>
</bill>
