<bill session="111" type="s" number="3766" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stem Cell Research Advancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for human stem cell research, including human embryonic stem cell research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2010-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2010-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2010-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7036-7038"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4808"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cell biology and embryology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2010--Introduced.
Stem Cell Research Advancement Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to conduct and support research that utilizes human stem cells, including human embryonic stem cells. Limits such research to stem cells that meet the following requirements: (1) the stem cells were derived from human embryos donated from in vitro fertilization clinics, were created for the purposes of reproductive treatment, and were in excess of the needs of the individuals seeking such treatment; (2) it was determined through consultation with the individuals seeking reproductive treatment that the embryos would never be implanted in a woman and would otherwise be discarded; and (3) the individuals seeking reproductive treatment donated the embryos with written informed consent and received no financial or other inducements. Requires the Secretary to maintain, review every three years, and update as scientifically warranted, guidelines applicable to the conduct or support of human stem cell research by HHS. Prohibits the Secretary from using any funds for the conduct or support of human cloning. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to include in its biennial report to Congress a summary of research activities on human stem cells.</summary>
</bill>
