<bill session="109" type="s" number="937" updated="2013-07-19T20:21:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">End Demand for Sex Trafficking Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to combat commercial sexual activities by targeting demand, to protect children from being exploited by such activities, to prohibit the operation of sex tours, to assist State and local governments to enforce laws dealing with commercial sexual activities, to reduce trafficking in persons, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2005-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4553-4558"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2012"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's shelters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2005--Introduced.
End Demand for Sex Trafficking Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to states and political subdivisions to: (1) establish model law enforcement programs that promote the effective prosecution of persons who solicit an unlawful commercial sex act, persons who purvey others to engage in such an act, and sex traffickers; and (2) assist victims of such an act. Amends the federal criminal code to modify prohibitions against transportation for illegal sexual activity and related crimes (generally) and for coercion and enticement to engage in prostitution or criminal sexual activity to explicitly cover purchasers of commercial sexual activities and acts. Directs federal agencies involved in combating sex trafficking and providing services to victims of commercial sex acts inside the United States to coordinate their activities with the Senior Policy Operating Group established by the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) report annually to the Senate and House Judiciary Committees regarding grants and evaluating success in enhancing the prosecution and conviction of purchasers, sex traffickers, and exploiters and in reducing demand for commercial sexual activity; (2) disseminate best methods and practices for training state and local law enforcement personnel involved in enforcing laws prohibiting commercial sexual acts at each annual conference conducted by the Department of Justice; and (3) carry out a biennial comprehensive statistical review and analysis of commercial sexual acts in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
