<bill session="111" type="h" number="6256" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening FHA Through Shared Equity Homeownership Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a shared equity homeownership pilot program for FHA mortgage insurance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Strengthening FHA Through Shared Equity Homeownership Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to carry out a shared equity homeownership pilot program to analyze the effectiveness of providing mortgage insurance under the Federal Housing Administration (FHA) mortgage insurance program for mortgages for the acquisition or refinancing of 1- to 4-primary family residences that are financed in part through a shared equity arrangement under which independent, private sector investors invest, together with the mortgagors, equity funds for such residences and thereby share in their ownership. Requires the Secretary to select up to 8 financial institutions, nonprofit organizations, housing associations, investment pools, and other appropriate individuals and entities to participate in the pilot. Requires a mortgagor to: (1) make a downpayment of at least 3.5% of the appraised value of the residence involved; and (2) retain a minimum equity in the residence under the shared equity arrangement of at least 60%.</summary>
</bill>
