<bill session="110" type="h" number="6578" updated="2013-07-19T22:01:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-24T14:44:00-04:00">PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-24T14:44:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Energy Supply Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the sale of light grade petroleum from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve and its replacement with heavy grade petroleum.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400229"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2008-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Barrow moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7079-7093" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7079-7080" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6578.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24T13:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Mr. Barton (TX) asked unanimous consent that debate on the motion to suspend the rules and pass H.R. 6578 be extended by 15 minutes, equally divided and controlled. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="2008-07-24T14:44:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="527" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 268 - 157 (Roll no. 527).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7092-7093" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2008--Introduced.
Consumer Energy Supply Act of 2008 - Instructs the Secretary of Energy to publish a plan to: (1) sell prescribed amounts of light grade petroleum from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) and acquire an equivalent volume of heavy grade petroleum; (2) deposit cash proceeds from those sales into the SPR Petroleum Account; and (3) withdraw from such proceeds the administrative and operational costs of the sale and acquisition. Requires an offer for sale of 70 million barrels of light grade petroleum from the SPR. Requires the sale to: (1) commence within 30 days after enactment of this Act, regardless of whether the Secretary's plan has been published; and (2) be completed within six months after enactment, with at least 20 million barrels offered for sale within the first 60 days after enactment. Sets forth an acquisitions schedule for heavy grade petroleum to replace the light grade petroleum sold under this Act. Encourages the Secretary to grant requests to defer scheduled deliveries of petroleum to the SPR if deferral will result in a premium paid in additional barrels of oil which will reduce the cost of oil acquisition and increase the volume of oil delivered to the SPR or yield additional cash bonuses.</summary>
</bill>
