<bill session="111" type="hr" number="404" updated="2013-07-19T22:59:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Directing the Secretary of Homeland Security to transmit to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, copies of documents relating to the Department of Homeland Security Intelligence Assessment titled, "Rightwing Extremism: Current Economic and Political Climate Fueling Resurgence in Radicalization and Recruitment".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412265" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400060" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2009-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04T10:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 111-134.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-06-04T10:52:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="63">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 63.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/2009--Reported to House amended.
Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to transmit to the House of Representatives copies of all documents relating to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) Office of Intelligence and Analysis (OIA) Intelligence Assessment entitled "Rightwing Extremism: Current Economic and Political Climate Fueling Resurgence in Radicalization and Recruitment," including: (1) all source materials used in drafting that Assessment; (2) written material reflecting when the research and writing of that Assessment began; (3) a written description of the clearance process for that Assessment and all other OIA-generated products disseminated to law enforcement agencies both prior to and since April 20, 2009; (4) a written description of the role the Chief Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties, the Chief Privacy Officer, and the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis played in that process; (5) any written opinions or guidance produced by DHS's Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties or by the Chief Privacy Officer for OIA on production and dissemination of assessments to law enforcement prior to that date; and (6) the schedule of privacy and civil liberties training for OIA employees.</summary>
</bill>
