<bill session="109" type="h" number="4630" updated="2013-07-19T19:45:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the David L. Boren National Security Education Act of 1991 to allow scholarship and fellowship recipients to work in a field of education if no position in the Federal Government relating to national security is available.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2005-12-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-17">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-17">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-17">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="21st Century Competitiveness" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Area studies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intelligence community staff"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/17/2005--Introduced.
Amends the David L. Boren National Security Education Act of 1991 to revise the service requirements for certain National Security Scholarship and Fellowship recipients. Repeals the conditions that a recipient work: (1) one year of service for each year for which the scholarship or fellowship assistance was provided; and (2) in order to utilize the unique language and region expertise acquired by the recipient pursuant to such study. Requires the recipient to work at least one year in a position contributing to national security in the Department of Defense (as under current law), any element of the intelligence community (as under current law), the Department of Homeland Security, or the Department of State. Allows the recipient to work at least one year in such a position in any other federal agency if none is available in any of the primary departments specified, or if none is available in another federal agency, at least one academic year in a position in a field of education in a discipline related to the studies supported by the scholarship or fellowship.</summary>
</bill>
