<bill session="109" type="s" number="2264" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Phone Record Security Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide enhanced consumer protection from unauthorized sales and use of confidential telephone information by amending the Communications Act of 1934, prohibiting certain practices, and providing for enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission and States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2006-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2389"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2006--Introduced.
Consumer Phone Record Security Act of 2006 - Makes it unlawful for a person to: (1) obtain, or attempt to obtain, through fraud an individual's customer proprietary network information (CPNI), or cause, or attempt to cause, such individual's CPNI to be disclosed to another person without that person's authorization; (2) sell, or offer for sale, a person's CPNI without their authorization; or (3) request another person to obtain a person's CPNI from a telecommunications carrier without proper authorization (with an exception authorizing a law enforcement official to obtain a person's CPNI provided certain conditions are met). Requires enforcement of the requirements of this Act by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), and the states. Authorizes a person whose CPNI has been obtained, used, or sold in violation of the requirements of this Act to file an action for civil relief against the violator in the appropriate court. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require telecommunications carriers to implement certain measures to protect a person's CPNI.</summary>
</bill>
