<bill session="111" type="h" number="4933" updated="2013-07-19T23:56:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global HEALTH Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Health Expansion, Access to Labor, Transparency, and Harmonization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a strategy to coordinate all health-related United States foreign assistance, to assist developing countries in improving delivery of health services, and to establish an initiative to assist developing countries in strengthening their indigenous health workforces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400237"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2010-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2010-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/2010--Introduced.
Global Health Expansion, Access to Labor, Transparency, and Harmonization Act of 2010 or the Global HEALTH Act of 2010 - Directs the President to: (1) transmit to Congress and make publicly available a comprehensive five-year United States Global Health Strategy to coordinate all health-related U.S. foreign assistance and to harmonize such assistance with the work of relevant U.S. executive branch agencies, governments of other countries, and international organizations; and (2) designate a Strategy Coordinator. Provides for an evaluation of the Global Health Strategy by the Institute of Medicine of the National Academics or another appropriate entity. Authorizes the President to provide assistance to developing countries to improve health services delivery. Authorizes the President to establish a Global Health Workforce Initiative to provide technical and direct financial assistance to support the recruitment, training, and equitable distribution of skilled health workers in at least 12 developing countries. Directs the President to transmit to Congress and make publicly available a five-year strategy for implementing the Initiative. Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should: (1) address the urgent shortage of U.S. health professionals without exacerbating the health professional shortage in developing countries; and (2) pursue trade and investment policies that support United States Global Health Strategy goals. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct: (1) the U.S. Executive Director at each international financial institution to oppose any loan, grant, or policy that would result in the imposition of user fees or service charges on poor individuals in connection with such institution's financing programs for primary education or primary health care; and (2) the U.S. Executive Director at the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to oppose any loan or program that would not exempt government spending on health care, health infrastructure, and education from national budget caps and restraints, hiring and wage ceilings, and other IMF-imposed limits.</summary>
</bill>
