<bill session="109" type="s" number="2989" updated="2013-07-19T20:39:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Franchise Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reform the franchise procedure relating to cable service and video service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300054"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2006--Introduced.
Franchise Reform Act of 2006 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to designate the State Commission of each state as the franchising authority for any state-issued franchise for the provision of cable or video service in that state. Outlines application requirements for any entity or person seeking to obtain a state-issued certificate of franchise authority. Exempts existing franchises from such application requirements. Requires the holder of a state-issued certificate to pay each municipality in which the holder provides cable or video service a franchise fee of five percent of the gross revenues of such holder. Requires certificate holders to: (1) comply with applicable customer service standards until there are two or more providers offering service in a municipality; (2) provide municipalities, upon request, with capacity to allow public, educational, and governmental (PEG) access channels for noncommercial programming (with a required minimum number of such channels); and (3) provide for the interconnection of cable and video systems within a municipality for the purpose of providing PEG programming. Requires local municipalities to allow certificate holders to install, construct, and maintain necessary communications networks within public rights-of-way. Prohibits certificate holders from denying access to cable or video service to any group of residential subscribers because of the income of the residents in the local area.</summary>
</bill>
