<bill session="110" type="s" number="2526" updated="2013-07-19T22:43:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Worker Infection Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect health care workers and first responders, including police, fire-fighters, emergency medical personnel, and other workers at risk of workplace exposure to infectious agents and drug resistant infections, such as MRSA and pandemic influenza.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Antibiotics"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Drug resistance in microorganisms"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Influenza"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2007--Introduced.
Worker Infection Protection Act - Directs the Secretaries of Labor and of Health and Human Services (HHS) to jointly develop and issue workplace standards, recommendations, and plans to protect health care workers and first responders and other workers at risk of workplace exposure to infectious agents and drug resistant infections, such as Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) and pandemic influenza.Directs the Secretary of Labor to develop and issue an emergency temporary standard and, not later than six months after such issuance, a permanent standard for the protection of workers at risk of exposure, to prevent occupational exposure to infectious agents and toxins, such as MRSA and pandemic influenza. Sets forth minimum requirements for such standards concerning: (1) influenza exposure; (2) personal protective equipment; (3) training and information; (4) medical surveillance for exposed workers; and (5) immunization against the pandemic influenza virus, if such a vaccine has been approved and is available.Requires the HHS Secretary to revise the provisions of the HHS pandemic influenza plan to conform with the minimum worker protection requirements described in this Act and with the permanent occupational safety and health exposure standard issued by the Secretary of Labor under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
