<bill session="112" type="s" number="1626" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Aggregate Risk and Revenue Management Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ARRM Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to reform agricultural programs by establishing the aggregate risk and revenue management program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3111"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1658"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2011--Introduced.
Aggregate Risk and Revenue Management Act of 2011 or the ARRM Act of 2011 - Amends the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), regarding all covered commodities and peanuts during each of the 2013-2017 crop years, to give the operator, tenant, or sharecropper on a farm an opportunity to make an annual election for all producers on the farm to receive aggregate risk and revenue management payments for the crop year for which the election is made. (Replaces the average crop revenue election program with the ARRM program.) Repeals the direct and counter-cyclical payment programs for covered commodities and peanuts beginning with the 2013 crop year. Suspends permanent price support authority through December 31, 2017.</summary>
</bill>
