<bill session="109" type="s" number="3731" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Presidential Signing Statements Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to regulate the judicial use of presidential signing statements in the interpretation of Acts of Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8271-8272"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional legal counsel"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2006--Introduced.
Presidential Signing Statements Act of 2006 - Prohibits any state or federal court from relying on or deferring to a presidential signing statement as a source of authority when determining the meaning of any Act of Congress. Provides that: (1) any U.S. court, upon the filing of an appropriate pleading by the Senate, through its Office of Senate Legal Counsel, and/or the House of Representatives, through its Office of General Counsel, may declare the legality of any presidential signing statement, whether or not further relief is or could be sought; and (2) any such declaration shall have the force and effect of a final judgment or decree and shall be reviewable as such. Amends federal law to provide for congressional intervention in any action, suit, or proceeding in the Supreme Court involving the construction or constitutionality of any Act of Congress for which a presidential signing statement was issued, including passage of a concurrent resolution declaring the view of Congress on the proper interpretation of the Act at issue.</summary>
</bill>
