<bill session="111" type="h" number="5431" updated="2013-07-20T00:01:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Start Healthy Habits Early Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 17 of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to promote health and wellness in child care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2010-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/2010--Introduced.
Start Healthy Habits Early Act - Amends the child and adult care food program (CACFP) under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture, at least once every ten years, to review and, as appropriate, update nutritional requirements for meals and snacks served under the CACFP to ensure that they meet the most recent Dietary Guidelines for Americans and promote the health of those served. Prohibits CACFP providers from using reimbursable meal service as a punishment or reward. Requires fluid milk served as part of a reimbursable meal or snack to meet the most recent Dietary Guidelines and appropriate authoritative scientific recommendations for young children. Allows nondairy substitutes to be served to children who cannot consume fluid milk, provided the substitutes are nutritionally equivalent to fluid milk and meet certain nutritional standards. Requires CACFP providers to make potable water available to children throughout the day, including at meal times. Directs the Secretary to provide technical assistance and guidance to CACFP providers and states regarding: (1) nutritional requirements; (2) age-appropriate physical activity and electronic media use by children; (3) parental involvement in nutrition and wellness initiatives; and (4) food choking hazards. Requires the Secretary to: (1) award competitive grants to states and, through them, subgrants to institutions participating in the CACFP to promote health and nutrition in child care settings; and (2) provide states and such institutions with best practices for implementing effective nutrition and wellness initiatives.</summary>
</bill>
