<bill session="111" type="h" number="652" updated="2013-07-19T23:17:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Skilled Trades Second Responders Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a comprehensive national system for skilled construction workers to assist first responders in disasters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400219"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-22">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-22">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/2009--Introduced.
Skilled Trades Second Responders Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences to establish a national program for the training, certification, registration, tracking, and integration of skilled construction workers to assist first responders in responding to disasters, including natural and manmade disasters and terrorist attacks. Requires the Director to coordinate and consult with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), including the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), other relevant agencies, and private organizations, including construction industry contractors, joint labor-management training funds, and building trade unions, that are experienced in providing rescue and recovery assistance to first responders and in the cleanup, demolition, rehabilitation, and reconstruction of disaster sites after recovery operations.</summary>
</bill>
