<bill session="111" type="s" number="914" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cures Acceleration Network and National Institutes of Health Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish an independent Cures Acceleration Network agency, to sponsor promising translational research to bridge the gap between laboratory discoveries and life-saving therapies, to reauthorize the National Institutes of Health, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4813-4814"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4815-4817" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2009--Introduced.
Cures Acceleration Network and National Institutes of Health Reauthorization Act of 2009 - Establishes the Cures Acceleration Network, an independent agency, to awards grants and contracts to eligible entities to accelerate the development of cures and treatments of diseases, including through the development of medical products and behavioral therapies. Defines "medical product" as a drug, device, biological product, or product that is a combination of drugs, devices, and biological products. Sets forth the functions of the Network. Establishes the Cures Acceleration Network Review Board. Directs the Chairperson of the Board to award matching grants and contracts to eligible entities to: (1) accelerate the development of cures and treatments, including through the development of medical products, behavioral therapies, and biomarkers that demonstrate the safety or effectiveness of medical products; or (2) establish protocols that comply with the standards of the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) and otherwise meet regulatory requirements at all stages of development, manufacturing, review, approval, and safety surveillance of a medical product. Sets forth provisions governing conflict of interest policies for the Network. Amends the Public Health Service Act to rename the National Center on Minority Health and Health Disparities as the National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to develop and enforce NIH's conflict of interest policies and respond in a timely manner when such policies have been violated by a recipient of funds provided under a grant or contract. Reauthorizes appropriations for NIH for FY2010-FY2012.</summary>
</bill>
