<bill session="110" type="s" number="2999" updated="2013-07-19T22:47:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Access to Cancer Clinical Trials Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require group and individual health insurance coverage and group health plans to provide coverage for individuals participating in approved cancer clinical trials.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2676"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor contracts"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2008--Introduced.
Access to Cancer Clinical Trials Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and the Internal Revenue Code to prohibit a group health plan from: (1) denying an eligible participant or beneficiary participation in clinical trials related to the treatment of cancer that are federally funded or conducted under an investigational new drug application reviewed by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA); (2) denying (or limiting or imposing additional conditions on) the coverage of routine patient costs for items and services furnished in connection with such participation; or (3) discriminating against an individual on the basis of such participation. Includes as routine patient costs all items and services provided in the clinical trial that are otherwise generally available to a qualified individual, with certain exceptions. Applies such prohibitions to coverage offered in the individual market.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to study the impact on group health plans and health insurance issuers of requiring them to cover routine patient care costs for individuals with serious and life threatening diseases other than cancer.</summary>
</bill>
