<bill session="109" type="h" number="3124" updated="2013-07-19T19:31:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area Natural Gas Pipeline Enlargement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area Natural Gas Pipeline Enlargement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to allow the Columbia Gas Transmission Corporation to increase the diameter of a natural gas pipeline located in the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400372"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-07">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-12T13:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-334.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-12-12T13:13:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="184">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 184.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1310"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1310"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2005--Reported to House amended.
Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area Natural Gas Pipeline Enlargement Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to grant an easement to the Columbia Gas Transmission Corporation to enlarge the diameter of a specified natural gas pipeline from 14 inches to not more than 20 inches, consistent with the recreational values and protection of the resources of the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area in Pennsylvania. Authorizes the Superintendent of the Recreation Area to issue a permit to the Corporation for the use of the Recreation Area in accordance with specified procedural requirements for the temporary construction and staging areas required for the construction of the enlarged pipeline. Requires the Corporation to comply with Federal Energy Regulatory Commission certification requirements for the increase in pipeline size. Prohibits the Secretary from granting additional increases in the diameter of, or easements for, the pipeline within the boundary of the Recreation Area after the date of enactment of this Act. Authorizes the Attorney General, at the Secretary's request, to bring against the Corporation a civil action for damages and response costs if the Corporation violates easement or permit provisions, fails to submit or timely implement an approved restoration and mitigation plan, or the violation or failure destroys, results in the loss of, or injures park system resources.</summary>
</bill>
