<bill session="113" type="s" number="503" updated="2013-11-02T06:56:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sangre de Cristo National Historical Park Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Sangre de Cristo National Historical Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1271"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/2013--Introduced.
Sangre de Cristo National Historical Park Establishment Act - Establishes the Sangre de Cristo National Historical Park in Colorado as a unit of the National Park System. Requires the Park to be composed of cultural and historical sites and byways within the Sangre de Cristo Mountain Range-San Luis Valley region of southern Colorado. Directs the Secretary of the Interior, through the National Park Service (NPS), to study the feasibility of including additional cultural and historical sites in Huerfano and Las Animas Counties in the Park. Allows the Secretary to acquire water rights by donation or purchase from willing sellers. Requires the completion of a general management plan for the Park. Requires the head of the federal agency having jurisdiction over a part of the Old Spanish Trail that is included within the Park to continue to manage that part of the Trail.</summary>
</bill>
