<bill session="111" type="h" number="3171" updated="2013-07-19T23:40:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bridging Bank to Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To help stabilize and restore the economy by providing for greater access to credit for the underbanked, the unbanked, and consumers with low credit scores through the establishment of bridging bank depository institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2009-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2009--Introduced.
Bridging Bank to Recovery Act of 2009 - Authorizes an appropriate federal or state banking agency to charter and license a de novo bridging bank depository institution to enable underbanked and unbanked consumers, and consumers with credit scores at or below 680, to transition or return to the financial mainstream more easily through comprehensive banking services, including access to credit products, financial and credit training, loan restructurings and other tailored financial products and services to meet the needs of such consumers. Defines underbanked consumers as individuals or families who have a deposit account with an insured depository institution or credit union, but who have limited or no ability to access nondepository services from such institutions. Defines unbanked consumers as individuals or families who have neither an account with an insured depository institution or insured credit union, nor a transaction account with a money market mutual fund or brokerage firm. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) exempt from federal income taxation the interest on deposits paid by bridging bank depository institutions; and (2) exclude from gross income the income from the discharge of indebtedness in connection with modification or repurchase of a subprime debt instrument if the beneficial owner of such instrument is a bridging bank depository institution. States that modification of a subprime debt instrument shall not result, for purposes of nonrecognition of gain or loss, in a sale or other disposition of property if a bridging bank depository institution is the beneficial owner of such instrument at the time of modification.</summary>
</bill>
