<bill session="109" type="s" number="2280" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STOP FRAUD Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stopping Transactions which Operate to Promote Fraud, Risk, and Underdevelopment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to stop transactions which operate to promote fraud, risk, and under-development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1177-1178"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mortgage banks"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2006--Introduced.
Stopping Transactions which Operate to Promote Fraud, Risk, and Underdevelopment Act or the STOP FRAUD Act - Amends federal criminal law to make it unlawful for any mortgage professional (as defined by this Act) to execute, or attempt to execute, a scheme or artifice to: (1) defraud any natural person or financial institution in connection with the offer of consumer credit secured by an interest in real property, or in personal property used or expected to be used as a principal dwelling; or (2) falsely obtain any money or property from a natural person in connection with an extension of consumer credit secured by an interest in real property, or in personal property used or expected to be used as the principal dwelling of such natural person. Provides for: (1) fines and/or imprisonment for violations of such provisions; and (2) a private right of action. Includes within the definition of "financial institution" for specified federal monetary transaction provisions the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), the Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae), the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), mortgage appraisers, real estate accountants, real estate attorneys, real estate brokers, mortgage underwriters, mortgage processors, mortgage settlement and title companies, mortgage brokers, mortgage loan originators, and any other mortgage professional engaged in the mortgage industry. Amends the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968 to authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to provide tenants, homeowners, and other consumers with mortgage fraud counseling.</summary>
</bill>
