<bill session="112" type="s" number="1865" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patient Access to Medical Innovation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve patient access to medical innovation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2011--Introduced.
Patient Access to Medical Innovation Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to extend for five years and revise the program for humanitarian exemptions for pediatric medical devices. Removes provisions requiring the device to have been approved on or after September 27, 2007. Eliminates the authority of the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish an annual distribution number setting the maximum number of devices that could be distributed under the exemption. Sets such number as the number of devices needed to treat, diagnose, or cure a population of 4,000 individuals in the United States. (Currently, this is the maximum number the Secretary may set.) Eliminates the limitation on the number of waivers the Secretary may grant from conflict of interest provisions pertaining to service on an advisory committee. Requires the Secretary to ensure that each determination to waive such provisions considers the scope and magnitude of the financial interest at issue with the public health need for the expertise of the member on the committee.</summary>
</bill>
