<bill session="111" type="h" number="6236" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Data Breach Notification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require Federal agencies, and persons engaged in interstate commerce, in possession of data containing sensitive personally identifiable information, to disclose any breach of such information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400361"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Financial Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="139"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2010--Introduced.
Data Breach Notification Act - Requires any federal agency or business entity engaged in interstate commerce that uses, accesses, or collects sensitive personally identifiable information, following the discovery of a security breach, to notify: (1) any U.S. resident whose information may have been accessed or acquired; and (2) the owner or licensee of any such information that the agency or business does not own or license. Exempts: (1) agencies and business entities from notification requirements for national security and law enforcement purposes and for security breaches that a risk assessment concludes do not have a significant risk of resulting in harm if specified certification or notice is provided, subject to review by the Secret Service; and (2) business entities which utilize a security program that blocks the use of sensitive personally identifiable information and provide notice of a breach to affected individuals. Requires notifications regarding security breaches under specified circumstances to the Secret Service, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), the Postal Inspection Service, and state attorneys general.Authorizes the Attorney General to bring a civil action in U.S. district court against any business entity that violates this Act. Sets civil penalties for violations.Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require agencies to include a fraud alert in the file of a consumer that submits evidence of compromised financial information to a consumer reporting agency.Authorizes: (1) civil actions by state attorneys general to enforce this Act; and (2) appropriations for costs incurred by the Secret Service to investigate and conduct risk assessments of security breaches.</summary>
</bill>
