<bill session="110" type="h" number="3774" updated="2013-07-19T21:36:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-03T15:36:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-06-03T15:36:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Senior Executive Service Diversity Assurance Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Senior Executive Service Diversity Assurance Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Senior Executive Service Diversity Assurance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for greater diversity within, and to improve policy direction and oversight of, the Senior Executive Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2008-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2008-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2007-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2089-2090"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-05-01">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T21:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government. H. Rept. 110-672.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-05-22T21:08:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="423">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 423.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-03T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis (IL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-03T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4846-4848" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-03T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3774.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-06-03T15:36:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4846-4847" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-06-03T15:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Reporting" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="2148"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2148"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Affirmative action programs"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in government"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in government"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2008--Passed House amended.
Senior Executive Service Diversity Assurance Act - Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to establish within OPM the Senior Executive Service Resource Office to make recommendations to the Director with respect to regulations, and to provide guidance to agencies, concerning the structure, management, and diverse composition of the Senior Executive Service (SES).Makes it the Office's mission to: (1) improve the efficiency, effectiveness, and productivity of the SES through policy formulation and oversight; (2) advance the professionalism of the SES; and (3) ensure that, in seeking to achieve an SES reflective of the nation's diversity, recruitment is from qualified individuals from appropriate sources.Requires the Office to make statistics concerning career reserved positions accessible to the public through the official public website of OPM.Revises the career appointments recruiting process to require agency heads to ensure diversity of executive resources boards, and any subgroup or other evaluation panel related to the merit staffing process for career appointees, by including members of racial and ethnic minority groups, women, and individuals with disabilities. Requires the Director to promulgate necessary regulations and report to Congress on agency efforts to improve diversity in executive resources boards and of qualifications review boards, based on the collection of statistics concerning race, ethnicity, sex, and disability required by this Act.Requires each agency, within one year after enactment of this Act, to submit to OPM a plan to enhance and maximize opportunities for the advancement and appointment of minorities, women, and individuals with disabilities in the agency to the SES. Requires the plans to: (1) address how the agency is identifying and eliminating barriers that impair the ability of such employees to obtain appointments and any actions the agency is taking to provide advancement opportunities; and (2) be updated at least biennially. Requires the Director to report to Congress on plans and updates.</summary>
</bill>
