<bill session="111" type="h" number="4198" updated="2013-07-19T23:50:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Unclaimed Savings Bond Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a program to reunite bondholders with matured unredeemed United States savings bonds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2010-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412217" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2009-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="827"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2009--Introduced.
Unclaimed Savings Bond Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to conduct a demonstration program to: (1) identify and locate the owners of specified unredeemed U.S. savings bonds; and (2) provide bondholder location and assistance grants to states for the purpose of bond owner location and notification activities. Requires the Secretary to attempt to locate owners of specified unredeemed savings bonds for which the registered address: (1) is located in a state not participating in the demonstration program in the fiscal year in which such bond would otherwise have been referred to such state; or (2) is not located in any state. Requires the Secretary to deduct and withhold from the proceeds of any matured outstanding U.S. savings bond, on the later of the date of maturity of such bond or the date of the enactment of this Act, a tax in an amount equal to the applicable percentage of the amount which, if such bond were redeemed, would constitute interest. Includes the deemed interest amount in the bondholder's gross income.</summary>
</bill>
