<bill session="110" type="s" number="1395" updated="2013-07-19T22:32:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Unfair Practices in Credit Cards Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prevent unfair practices in credit card accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2007-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6131-6135"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6135-6137" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="5280"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2007--Introduced.
Stop Unfair Practices in Credit Cards Act of 2007 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act regarding open-end consumer credit plans. Prohibits imposition of an interest charge upon debt paid on time and in full. Sets restrictions upon interest rate increases. Limits penalty rate increases to: (1) seven percentage points above the current interest rate; and (2) future credit extensions only. Prohibits interest charges on fees. Specifies restrictions upon over-the-limit fees. Requires the primary federal regulator of a card issuer to conduct annual audits of the credit card operations and procedures used by the issuer. Requires the card issuer to: (1) apply payment first to the card balance bearing the highest rate of interest, and then to each successive balance bearing the next highest rate of interest, until the payment is exhausted; and (2) apply the payment in the most effective way to minimize the imposition of any finance charge. Requires a card issuer to define and display the term "prime rate" or similar rate or index as the bank prime loan rate posted by a majority of the top 25 U.S. chartered commercial banks, as published by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Board). Revises requirements governing credit card information collected by the Board. Directs the Board to report annually to Congress its assessment of the profitability of credit card operations of depository institutions.</summary>
</bill>
