<bill session="109" type="h" number="6228" updated="2013-07-19T19:59:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wright Amendment Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 29 of the International Air Transportation Competition Act of 1979 relating to air transportation to and from Love Field, Texas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400302" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2006-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5830"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3661"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Charter airlines"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2006--Introduced.
Wright Amendment Reform Act of 2006 - Amends the International Air Transportation Competition Act of 1979, regarding air transportation to or from Love Field, Texas, (the Wright Amendment), to authorize domestic and foreign air carriers to offer for sale and to provide air transportation to or from Love Field, Texas, and any U.S. or foreign destination through any point within specified states (effectively expanding domestic and foreign air service at Love Field, Texas). Repeals the Wright Amendment eight years after enactment of this Act. Prohibits: (1) a person from providing nonstop air passenger service between Love Field, Texas, and any point or points outside the 50 states or the District of Columbia; and (2) a federal official or employee from designating Love Field, Texas, as an initial point of entry into the United States or a last point of departure from the United States. Limits charter flights at Love Field, Texas. Requires the city of Dallas, Texas, to reduce the number of gates available for air service at Love Field. Prohibits federal funds or passenger facility charges from being used to remove gates at the Lemmon Avenue facility, Love Field, to reduce the number of gates, but permits the use of such funds for other airport facilities. Prohibits anything in this Act from affecting general aviation service at Love Field, Texas.</summary>
</bill>
