<bill session="109" type="s" number="3914" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">GEDI Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gestational Diabetes Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish an Advisory Committee on Gestational Diabetes, to provide grants to better understand and reduce gestational diabetes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2006-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2006-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9788-9791"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="6147"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Obesity"/>
    <term name="Pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Vital statistics"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2006--Introduced.
Gestational Diabetes Act of 2006 or the GEDI Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to convene a Research Advisory Committee. Requires the Director of CDC, in consultation with such Committee, to develop a multisite research project to expand and enhance surveillance data and public health research on gestational diabetes. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of CDC, to award competitive grants to nonprofit organizations or state health agencies for demonstration projects that test specified hypotheses about interventions designed to reduce the incidence of gestational diabetes and obesity among young women and implement relevant activities. Requires the Director of CDC and the Director of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, in collaboration with the National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases, to conduct and support basic, clinical, and public health research regarding gestational diabetes and obesity during pregnancy. Requires the Director of CDC to encourage screening for gestational diabetes within state-based diabetes prevention and control programs to reduce the incidence of gestational diabetes and its related complications.</summary>
</bill>
