<bill session="111" type="s" number="1416" updated="2013-07-20T00:36:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">North Korea Accountability Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill require the redesignation of North Korea as a state sponsor of terrorism, to impose sanctions with respect to North Korea, to require reports on the status of North Korea's nuclear weapons program and counterproliferation efforts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2009-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2009-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2009-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2009--Introduced.
North Korea Accountability Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of State to designate North Korea, for specified purposes of the Export Administration Act of 1979, the Arms Export Control Act, and the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as a country that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism. Authorizes the President to waive such requirement upon a certification to Congress that North Korea has taken certain actions regarding: (1) nuclear program and proliferation disclosures; (2) the illegal transfer of missile or nuclear technology; (3) support of international terrorist groups; and (4) prisoner release. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to prohibit, with waiver authority, a financial institution from engaging in financial transactions with a foreign bank that is engaged in a financial transaction with the government or a governmental agent of North Korea or a senior government or military official of North Korea. Directs the President to strengthen military cooperation with Japan and South Korea. Sets forth reporting requirements regarding: (1) implementation of the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004; (2) financial transaction with North Korea or trade in precious metals produced in North Korea; (3) the North Korean nuclear weapons program; (4) counterproliferation efforts; (5) implementation of specified U.N. Security Council Resolutions; and (6) North Korean refugees admitted into the United States. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) completion of ground-based missile interceptor deployment at Fort Greely, Alaska; (2) development of a variant of the F-22 fighter aircraft for sale to Japan; and (3) expansion of radio broadcasting to North Korea. Directs the Secretary of State to reallocate specified funds for programs to advance human rights for the people of North Korea.</summary>
</bill>
