<bill session="109" type="s" number="749" updated="2013-07-19T20:19:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to establish a governmentwide policy requiring competition in certain executive agency procurements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300015" joined="2005-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2005-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2005-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300097" joined="2005-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3421"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3421-3423" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2965"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal Prison Industries, Inc."/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="New products"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to require an executive agency, when procuring Federal Prison Industries (FPI) products or services, to: (1) use competitive procedures; or (2) make an individual purchase under a multiple award contract in accordance with applicable competition requirements. Requires an agency to: (1) timely notify FPI of procurements; (2) consider a timely offer from FPI in the same manner as other offers; and (3) consider a timely offer from FPI without limitation as to the dollar value, unless competition is limited to small business concerns. Outlines exceptions to the competitive procedures requirement. Prohibits requiring a contractor to use FPI as a subcontractor or supplier. Prohibits access to classified and sensitive information by an inmate worker. Restricts the interstate and foreign commerce of services resulting from convict labor. Subjects knowing violators of such restrictions to fine or imprisonment, or both. Requires Federal, State, and local prison work programs to meet specified requirements. Allows FPI to sell or donate a product or service to tax-exempt charitable organizations which may then donate or sell any such product or service to low-income individuals. Establishes the Enhanced In-Prison Educational and Vocational Assessment and Training Program within the FPI. Directs FPI to increase inmate employment by producing products for the public sector that would otherwise be produced outside the United States. Authorizes priority placement in the Bureau of Prisons for FPI employees displaced because FPI loses business following enactment.</summary>
</bill>
