<bill session="112" type="sr" number="26" updated="2013-07-20T02:10:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-26">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution recognizing the anniversary of the tragic earthquake in Haiti on January 12, 2010, honoring those who lost their lives in that earthquake, and expressing continued solidarity with the Haitian people.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-01-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S261-263" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S261-263" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S290-291" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="35"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2011--Passed Senate without amendment.
Honors: (1) those who lost their lives due to the tragic earthquake of January 12, 2010; and (2) the sacrifice of the men and women of the Haitian government, the U.S. government, the United Nations (U.N.), and the international community for their response to those affected by the earthquake. Expresses solidarity with the people of Haiti as they work to rebuild. Reaffirms the Senate's commitment to support long-term Haitian reconstruction. Supports the Executive Branch's efforts to improve Haitian water, sanitation, and health systems. Supports: (1) all U.S. personnel and members of international organizations who have persevered through adverse conditions to serve Haiti, and (2) the continued efforts of the Interim Haiti Recovery Commission to bring donors and the Haitian government together to effectively lead the reconstruction process. Urges the international community to: (1) call on Haitian leaders to reach a democratic resolution to the current electoral crisis, (2) focus assistance on the priorities of the Haitian government, (3) involve Haitian civil society in all disaster responses, and (4) give priority to programs that protect and involve vulnerable populations. Urges aid agencies to: (1) train and use Haitian local and national authorities to deliver assistance, and (2) enhance coordination with the Haitian people and key Haitian government ministries. Supports: (1) continuing the work of U.S. agencies, nongovernmental organizations, regional institutions, and U.N. agencies to confront the consequences of the Haitian crises; (2) assessments of the long-term needs for confronting the Haiti's cholera epidemic; and (3) continuing humanitarian and development efforts between all actors supporting a better future for Haiti.</summary>
</bill>
