<bill session="113" type="h" number="2719" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation Security Acquisition Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Transportation Security Administration to implement best practices and improve transparency with regard to technology acquisition programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412432" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2013-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Transportation Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2013--Introduced.
Transportation Security Acquisition Reform Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to develop, and update biennially, a strategic multiyear technology acquisition plan, which may include a classified addendum to report sensitive transportation security risks, technology vulnerabilities, or other sensitive security information. Directs the Administrator to analyze the TSA's acquisition of any security-related technology to determine if it is justified. Requires the Administrator, 30 days before any TSA award of a contract for acquisitions exceeding $30 million, to report to Congress the results of the analysis and certify that the security benefits justify the contract cost. Directs the Administrator to establish certain performance baseline requirements before any TSA security-related technology acquisition. Requires the Administrator to review and assess each acquisition for meeting the baseline requirements and to report those results to Congress. Requires the Administrator, before the procurement of additional quantities of equipment to fulfill a TSA mission need, to utilize, to the extent practicable, any existing units in the TSA's inventory to meet that need. Directs the Administrator to report annually to Congress on TSA's goals for contracting with small and disadvantaged businesses. Directs the Comptroller General to evaluate, and report to Congress on, TSA's progress in implementing the plan.</summary>
</bill>
