<bill session="111" type="h" number="5968" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Full Self-Government Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the charter for the government of the District of Columbia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1477"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2010--Introduced.
District of Columbia Full Self-Government Act - Declares that: (1) this Act shall have no effect on existing law or regulation unless otherwise repealed or amended by this Act or an Act of Congress; and (2) the legislative power of the District shall extend to all rightful subjects of legislation within the District consistent with the U.S. Constitution and the provisions of this Act, subject to all the restrictions and limitations imposed upon the states by the Constitution. Establishes a Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of the Mayor. Prescribes requirements for treatment of District employees formerly covered by the Federal Civil Service System. Prohibits the Mayor's planning responsibility from extending to federal and District international projects and developments. Prescribes requirements granting the President emergency control of the Metropolitan Police Department. Declares that the District's judicial powers and the provisions of the District charter applicable to District judges and courts shall be those set forth in the District of Columbia Home Rule Act as in effect on the enactment of this Act. Subjects the process by which the District develops and enacts its fiscal year budget and related financial management activities to such laws as the District may enact. Declares that the full faith and credit of the United States is not pledged for any District obligations, nor is the United States responsible or liable for them. Exempts all District bonds and notes (and interest) from federal taxation, except estate, inheritance, and gift taxes. Authorizes certain entities to invest in District bonds and notes. Reserves Congress the right to exercise constitutional authority as legislature for the District. Repeals the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (establishing the existing District charter), but not any provision of law amended or repealed by such Act.</summary>
</bill>
