<bill session="111" type="h" number="4135" updated="2013-07-19T23:49:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Keep Americans Working Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To keep Americans working by strengthening and expanding short-time compensation programs that provide employers with an alternative to layoffs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1646"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2831"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2009--Introduced.
Keep Americans Working Act - Declares that the purpose of this Act is to keep Americans working by strengthening and expanding short-time compensation programs that provide employers with an alternative to layoffs. Requires the Secretary of Labor to: (1) provide guidance to states in enacting short-term compensation programs; and (2) award start-up grants to state agencies in states that have enacted programs and meet certain requirements. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to define "short-time compensation program" as one in which: (1) participation of an employer is voluntary; (2) an employer reduces the number of hours worked by employees through certifying that such reductions are in lieu of temporary layoffs; (3) an employee whose workweek that has been reduced by at least 10% is eligible for unemployment compensation; (4) an eligible employee may participate in an employer-sponsored job skills training program; and (5) an employer is required to certify that continuation of employee health and retirement benefits will not be affected by participation in the program. Directs the Secretary to make payments to a state's unemployment compensation trust fund for the payment of unemployment compensation if the Secretary approves a state's application for certification to operate a short-time compensation program that requires the maintenance of health and retirement employee benefits.</summary>
</bill>
