<bill session="109" type="s" number="2676" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Forest Service Partnership Enhancement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into partnership agreements with entities and local communities to encourage greater cooperation in the administration of Forest Service activities on the near National Forest System land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300030"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2006-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3716"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3818"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2006--Introduced.
Forest Service Partnership Enhancement Act of 2006 - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture, in connection with the administration of Forest Service activities on and near National Forest System (NFS) lands, to enter into agreements with cooperators for the mutual benefit of parties to the agreement for specified activities, including for: (1) developing, conducting, producing, or selling education and interpretive materials, products, programs, and services; (2) constructing, maintaining, and operating facilities; (3) selling health and safety convenience products and photography supplies; (4) collecting funds from the sale of materials, products, programs, and services; (5) activities to restore and maintain ecological integrity and biodiversity of NFS lands; (6) watershed restoration and enhancement activities on NFS lands, or on other lands that benefit resources on NFS land within the same watershed for protecting, restoring, and enhancing resources or reducing risk from natural disaster where public safety is threatened; and (7) such other cooperative activities as the Secretary considers to be appropriate. Amends the National Forest Foundation Act to: (1) double the number of members who shall serve on the Board of Directors of the National Forest Foundation; (2) extend to October 1, 2006, the provision of matching funds for administrative and project expenses incurred by the Foundation; and (3) extend for the five-year period beginning on October 1, 2006, the authorization of appropriations for the Foundation to match private contributions made to it.</summary>
</bill>
