<bill session="111" type="s" number="3340" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">NIST Grants for Energy Efficiency, New Job Opportunities, and Business Solutions Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">NIST GREEN JOBS Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to create jobs, increase energy efficiency, and promote technology transfer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3541"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2010--Introduced.
NIST Grants for Energy Efficiency, New Job Opportunities, and Business Solutions Act of 2010 or the NIST GREEN JOBS Act of 2010 - Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to require the themes under the competitive grant program within the Regional Centers for the Transfer of Manufacturing Technology program to be related to projects: (1) designed to increase the viability both of traditional manufacturing sectors and other sectors, such as construction, that increasingly rely on manufacturing through the use of manufactured components and manufacturing techniques, including supply chain integration and quality management; and (2) related to the transfer of technology based on the technological needs of manufacturers and available technologies from institutions of higher education, laboratories, and other technology producing entities. Authorizes such themes to extend beyond such areas to include projects related to construction industry modernization. Revises the selection criteria for such grants. Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to: (1) endeavor to select at least one proposal in each of the nine statistical divisions of the United States (as designated by the Bureau of the Census) for a grant; and (2) award grants to proposals that will create jobs or train newly hired employees, promote technology transfer and commercialization of environmentally focused materials, products, and processes, increase energy efficiency, and improve the competitiveness of industries in regions in which the Centers are located. Limits award duration to three years. Authorizes awards to be used by Centers to assist small or medium-sized construction firms. Authorizes appropriations for FY2011-FY2014.</summary>
</bill>
