<bill session="111" type="h" number="2843" updated="2013-07-19T23:37:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-03T10:57:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-02-03T10:57:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Architect of the Capitol Appointment Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Architect of the Capitol Appointment Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Architect of the Capitol Appointment Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the joint appointment of the Architect of the Capitol by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President pro tempore of the Senate, the Majority and Minority Leaders of the House of Representatives and Senate, and the chairs and ranking minority members of the committees of Congress with jurisdiction over the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To provide for the joint appointment of the Architect of the Capitol by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President pro tempore of the Senate, the majority and minority leaders of the House of Representatives and Senate, the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the chairs and ranking minority members of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate, and two other designated members of the Senate, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400623"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400004" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2009-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House House Administration"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House House Administration"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10T17:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 111-372, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10T17:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-12-10T17:41:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="216">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 216.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-02-03T10:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Wasserman Schultz moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-03T10:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H480-482" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-03T10:45:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2843.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-02-03T10:57:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H480" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-02-03T10:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-03T10:57:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2185"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2185"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Architect of the Capitol"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="U.S. Capitol"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/2010--Passed House amended.
Architect of the Capitol Appointment Act of 2010 - Requires the Architect of the Capitol (AOC) to be appointed jointly by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President pro tempore of the Senate, the Majority and Minority Leaders of the House of Representatives and Senate, the chair and ranking Minority Member of the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, the chair and ranking Minority Member of the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration, the chair and ranking Minority Members of the congressional appropriations committees, a Member of the Senate designated by the Senate Majority Leader, and a Member of the Senate designated by the Senate Minority Leader. Establishes a 10-year term for the AOC, as under current law, but permits additional reappointments. Repeals the requirement of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1990 that the AOC be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</summary>
</bill>
