<bill session="112" type="s" number="851" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Time for Innovation Matters in Education Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish expanded learning time initiatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2011-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2529-2530"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1636"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2011--Introduced.
Time for Innovation Matters in Education Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive matching grants to states to enable them to award competitive subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) or partnerships between LEAs and other public or nonprofit entities to plan and implement expanded learning time initiatives at high-need schools that they serve. Requires such initiatives to: (1) increase the total number of school hours each year at participant schools by at least 300 hours, compared to the school hours per year that are standard for comparable schools served by their LEAs; and (2) expand learning time for all students in all grade levels in such schools, though on-site prekindergarten programs may be excepted. Directs states to give subgrant priority to entities that: (1) serve a high percentage of students from low-income families; (2) include a nonprofit community-based organization experienced in expanding learning opportunities or helping schools redesign their educational programs; (3) take certain steps to facilitate collaboration between high-need schools and community partners; and (4) will coordinate this Act's funding with other federal, state, local, and private funding to implement high-quality expanded learning time initiatives in high-need schools. Permits the Secretary to: (1) award planning and implementation grants directly to a partnership that serves more that one area in more than one state, and (2) provide technical assistance to grantees and subgrantees in developing and implementing expanded learning time initiatives. Requires the Secretary to contract with an independent organization with expertise in school improvement, program evaluation, and measurement to evaluate this Act's program and provide technical assistance to grantees and subgrantees in collecting data and evaluating their programs pursuant to specified performance measures.</summary>
</bill>
