<bill session="111" type="h" number="3047" updated="2013-07-19T23:39:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Balancing Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Afterschool Education Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Child Care Facilities Financing Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Domestic Violence Leave Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Education Begins at Home Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Family and Medical Leave Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Family Leave Insurance Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Healthy Early Education Workforce Grant Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Healthy Families Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">United States Business Telework Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Universal Prekindergarten Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the lives of working families by providing family and medical need assistance, child care assistance, in-school and afterschool assistance, family care assistance, and encouraging the establishment of family-friendly workplaces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400436"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2009-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2009-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2010-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2009-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2009-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2009-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2009-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Armed Services, Ways and Means, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2009--Introduced.
Balancing Act of 2009 - Family Leave Insurance Act of 2009 - Amends the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to direct the Secretary of Labor to establish a Family and Medical Insurance Program, which may involve contracts with state programs, under which, for specified reasons, an eligible employee of a covered employer shall be entitled to family and medical leave insurance benefits for a total of 12 workweeks of leave during any 12-month program. Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to establish a similar Civil Service Family and Medical Leave Insurance Program for federal employees. Creates in the Treasury the Family and Medical Leave Insurance Fund. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a family and medical leave premium on employees and employers. Family and Medical Leave Enhancement Act of 2009 - Amends the FMLA to increase the number of employers to which it applies by reducing from 50 to 25 employees the threshold number triggering application of the Act. Entitles eligible employees and federal employees to take specified additional leave for parental involvement and family wellness. Domestic Violence Leave Act - Entitles eligible employees, including federal employees, to leave to address domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking. Includes within the purview of FMLA same-sex spouses and domestic partners and their children. Healthy Families Act - Requires certain employers to provide paid sick time to their employees, including time to address domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking. Prohibits such employers from discriminating against employees for their legitimate use of paid sick time. Directs the Commissioner of Labor Statistics to compile specified information relating to use of paid sick time Family and Medical Leave Enhancement Act of 2009 [sic] - Amends the FMLA to increase the number of employers to which it applies by reducing from 50 to 25 employees the threshold number triggering application of the Act. Entitles eligible employees and federal employees to take specified additional leave for parental involvement and family wellness. Education Begins at Home Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to enable states, Indian tribes, tribal organizations, territories and possessions to establish or expand quality programs of early childhood home visitation, including to families with English language learners. Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to make competitive grants to support and expand efforts to deliver services through high quality programs of early childhood home visitation to eligible families with a member in the military. Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to authorize additional funds for expanding child care activities for young children under age three. Authorizes the Secretary to allot funds to eligible states, Indian tribes, and tribal organizations for the federal share of access to affordable health benefits coverage for eligible child care providers. Establishes: (1) the Child Care Provider Development and Retention Grant Program; and (2) the Child Care Provider Scholarship Program. Healthy Early Education Workforce Grant Program Act - Requires a state receiving certain funds to expend them for the federal share of the cost of providing access to affordable health benefits coverage for eligible child care providers and, at state discretion, their spouses, domestic partners, and dependents. Child Care Facilities Financing Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Secretary to make competitive technical and financial assistance grants to Department of the Treasury-certified community development financial institutions and other specified organizations for the acquisition, construction, or renovation of child care facilities. Directs the Secretary to establish a program to award competitive grants to assist states in providing incentive funds to encourage the establishment and operation of employer-operated child care programs. Universal Prekindergarten Act - Directs the Secretary to make grants to state agencies to develop high-quality full-day, full-year universal prekindergarten programs for all children three, four, and five years old. Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to require the school breakfast program to provide free breakfasts to school children without regard to family income. Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to deem a child who is eligible for reduced price lunches for any school year also eligible for free lunches for that school year. Repeals the limitation on reimbursement in ten states (thus allowing them full reimbursement) for afterschool meals served to at-risk school children. Afterschool Education Enhancement Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 with respect to requirements for state applications for 21st century community learning center grants. Repeals the restriction in such applications to students attending schools: (1) eligible for certain schoolwide programs; (2) serving a high percentage of students from low-income families; or (3) in need of academic improvement. Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to require that certain employees working at less than full-time under participation, vesting, and accrual rules governing pension plans be treated as meeting full-time year-of-service criteria. Qualifies such workers for group health plans. Extends ERISA coverage to certain individuals whose services are leased or contracted for. United States Business Telework Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor to conduct a pilot program in up to five states to raise awareness about telework among employers and to encourage them to offer telework options to employees.</summary>
</bill>
