<bill session="109" type="s" number="321" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Support Distribution Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide more child support money to families leaving welfare, to simplify the rules governing the assignment and distribution of child support collected by States on behalf of children, to improve the collection of child support, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2005-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Garnishment"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2005--Introduced.
Child Support Distribution Act of 2005 - Amends title IV part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to revise requirements for: (1) denial of assistance to families that do not assign certain support rights to the State; and (2) the distribution of child support collected by States on behalf of children receiving certain welfare benefits. Reduces from $5,000 to $2,500 the amount of child support arrearage which shall trigger denial of a passport.Revises requirements for the use of the tax refund intercept program to collect past-due child support on behalf of non-minor children.Prohibits garnishment of certain compensation for a service-connected disability paid to a former member of the Armed Forces for: (1) alimony; or (2) child support less than 60 days in arrears. Permits no more than 50 percent of such compensation to be garnished to pay for such child support.Provides for mandatory review and adjustment of child support orders for families receiving TANF.Requires the Secretary to disclose new hire information to a State to assist in the administration of unemployment compensation programs.Provides for a payment rate increase to States for short term training of staff of State-licensed or State-approved child welfare agencies providing services.</summary>
</bill>
