<bill session="111" type="h" number="6211" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Back and Spinal Therapy Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot program to evaluate the effectiveness of treating veterans with spinal, back, and musculoskeletal injuries and pain using non-invasive techniques.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412301" joined="2010-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2010--Introduced.
Veterans Back and Spinal Therapy Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a two-year pilot program to: (1) provide covered veterans with non-invasive techniques to treat spinal, back, and musculoskeletal injuries and pain; and (2) use an evidence-based medicine framework to assess the effectiveness of such techniques. Includes as a covered veteran one who: (1) has a service-connected spinal, back, or musculoskeletal injury; or (2) is eligible for VA hospital or nursing home care or medical services by reason of active duty in a theater of combat operations during a period of war after the Persian Gulf War. Requires the Secretary, in selecting program participants, to give a preference to veterans who served in Operations Enduring Freedom, Iraqi Freedom, or New Dawn.</summary>
</bill>
