<bill session="111" type="h" number="2402" updated="2013-07-19T23:33:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Woman's Health Insurance Fairness Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to ensure fairness in the coverage of women in the individual health insurance market.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400291"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2009-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1139-1140"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="969"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2009--Introduced.
Woman's Health Insurance Fairness Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to prohibit health insurance issuers offering individual health insurance coverage from: (1) considering the gender of an enrollee when determining premium; (2) imposing any preexisting condition exclusion relating to pregnancy; or (3) otherwise discriminating against women on the basis of a current or past pregnancy, past or future method of delivery, and past pregnancy outcome. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) develop a minimum benefit standard for the provision of comprehensive maternity coverage under an individual health plan, which shall require coverage for the full scope of maternity services from preconception through postpartum; and (2) require health insurance issuers to provide data to the Secretary to monitor compliance. Directs the Comptroller General to report to the appropriate congressional committees on health insurance coverage offered on the individual insurance market and on problems remaining for women after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
