<bill session="111" type="s" number="605" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Securities and Exchange Commission to reinstate the uptick rule and effectively regulate abusive short selling activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412329"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2009-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2009-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3120-3121, S3121"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3121" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3636-3539"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="302"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1406"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2009--Introduced.
Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to take specified actions to regulate short sales of securities, including: (1) reinstating regulations in effect on July 5, 2007, prohibiting short sales of securities unless the previous price movement on such securities had been upward (the uptick rule); (2) rescinding the prohibition against applying certain price tests to short sales; (3) requiring trades by short sellers to yield priority and preference to transactions effected by long sellers of securities; (4) prohibiting short sales of securities of financial institutions unless such trades are effected at a price (in minimum lots, as specified by the SEC) that is at least 5 cents higher than the immediately preceding transaction in such securities; and (5) issuing regulations that prohibit short sales unless the seller can demonstrate a legally enforceable right to deliver the securities at the required delivery date and that require all short sales to settle on the same time frame employed for long sales of the same securities.</summary>
</bill>
