<bill session="112" type="h" number="2778" updated="2013-07-20T01:34:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dollars and Sense Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent the overproduction of $1 presidential coins by the United States Mint in order to efficiently meet collector demand while reducing the surplus of already produced $1 coins in Federal Reserve System vaults, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2011-10-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic Monetary Policy and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Presidential administrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2011--Introduced.
Dollars and Sense Act of 2011 - Repeals the requirement that the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Federal Reserve Board) and the Secretary of the Treasury ensure that, during an introductory period, all institutions that want unmixed supplies of each newly-issued coin design minted under the Presidential $1 Coin and First Spouse Bullion Coin Programs are able to obtain such unmixed supplies. Reduces, from four to two, the number of presidents honored each year. Postpones the Native American $1 coin series until the termination of the Presidential $1 Coin Program. Limits the aggregate number of presidential coins issued for circulation for any year to the number of $1 coins sold only as numismatic items during the previous calendar year. Limits the availability of the Circulating $1 Coin Direct Ship Program to persons purchasing coins for collection purposes. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Federal Reserve Board should address the backlog of $1 coins in its vaults by making them as publicly accessible as possible for circulation purposes, and (2) the U.S. Mint should continue producing Sacagawea coins for circulation purposes upon completion of the Presidential $1 Coin Program.</summary>
</bill>
