<bill session="112" type="h" number="1741" updated="2013-07-20T01:25:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Secure Visas Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Secure Visas Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State to refuse or revoke visas to aliens if in the security or foreign policy interests of the United States, to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to review visa applications before adjudication, to provide for the immediate dissemination of visa revocation information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412395" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2011-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 17 - 11.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08T15:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 112-411, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08T15:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-03-08T15:47:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="283">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 283.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration Policy and Enforcement" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Algeria"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Jordan"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Kuwait"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Malaysia"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Morocco"/>
    <term name="Nigeria"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="South Africa"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="United Arab Emirates"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2012--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Secure Visas Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to grant the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) (Secretary), except for the Secretary of State's authority with respect to diplomatic- and international organization-related visas, exclusive authority to issue regulations, establish policy, and administer the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) and all other immigration or nationality laws relating to U.S. consular officer visa functions. Authorizes the Secretary to refuse or revoke any visa to an alien or class of aliens if necessary or advisable for U.S. security interests. Provides that such visa revocation shall become effective immediately and cancel any other visa in an alien's possession. Prohibits judicial review of the Secretary's refusal or revocation of visa, or of any claim arising from such revocation. Authorizes the Secretary of State to direct a consular officer to refuse or revoke a visa if necessary or advisable for U.S. interests. Prohibits a visa approval decision by the Secretary of State from overriding a revocation or refusal determination by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to review on-site all visa applications and supporting documentation before adjudication at visa-issuing posts in Algeria, Canada, Colombia, Egypt, Germany, Hong Kong, India, Indonesia, Iraq, Jerusalem and Tel Aviv in Israel, Jordan, Kuala Lumpur in Malaysia, Kuwait, Lebanon, Mexico, Morocco, Nigeria, Pakistan, the Philippines, Saudi Arabia, South Africa, Syria, Turkey, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, Venezuela, and Yemen and authorizes the Secretary to asign DHS personnel to each diplomatic and consular post at which visas are issued unless, in the Secretary's sole and unreviewable discretion, the Secretary determines that such an assignment at a particular post would not promote national or homeland security. Directs the Secretary of State to ensure that any such DHS personnel have been stationed and are operational within one year of enactment of this Act. States that if the Secretary or the Secretary of State revokes a visa: (1) the relevant consular, law enforcement, and terrorist screening databases shall be immediately updated; and (2) look-out notices shall be posted to all DHS port inspectors and Department of State consular officers. Amends INA to: (1) eliminate the exception permitting judicial review of a visa revocation where such revocation is the sole ground for a deportation process based upon an alien's unlawful U.S. presence, and (2) prohibit any court from hearing a claim arising from a visa revocation.</summary>
</bill>
