<bill session="110" type="h" number="276" updated="2013-07-19T21:06:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-05T14:25:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-03-05T14:25:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate the Piedras Blancas Light Station and the surrounding public land as an Outstanding Natural Area to be administered as a part of the National Landscape Conservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-05T14:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-05T14:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2126-2128" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-05T14:22:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 276.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-03-05T14:25:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2126-2127" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-03-05T14:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-03">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-91.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-118.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-06-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="251">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 251.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Lighthouses and lightships"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2007 - Establishes the Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area (Outstanding Natural Area) in San Luis Obispo County, California. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to manage the Outstanding Natural Area as part of the National Landscape Conservation System.Directs the Secretary of the Interior to manage the Outstanding Natural Area as part of the National Landscape Conservation System and to allow only those uses that further the purposes for the establishment of the Area, the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, and other applicable laws. Withdraws the federal lands and interests in lands included within the Outstanding Natural Area from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the public land mining laws, and (3) operation of the mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws and the mineral material laws. Requires the Secretary to: (1) manage the Outstanding Natural Area in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the unique and nationally important historical, natural, cultural, scientific, educational, scenic, and recreational values of that area, including an emphasis on preserving and restoring the Light Station facilities; and (2) complete a comprehensive management plan to provide long-term management guidance for the public lands within the Outstanding Natural Area and fulfill the purposes for which it is established. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with Federal, State, and local agencies to implement the management plan in the Outstanding Natural Area and to continue partnerships with local communities and the Hearst San Simeon State Historical Monument. Provides for the acquisition of State and privately held lands adjacent to the Outstanding Natural Area as additions to the Outstanding Natural Area.Prohibits restrictions on overflights and law enforcement activities in the Outstanding Natural Area. Directs the Secretary to ensure access to the Outstanding Natural Area by Indians and Indian tribes for cultural and religious purposes. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
