<bill session="111" type="hr" number="379" updated="2013-07-19T22:59:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-30T11:39:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-04-30T11:39:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for further consideration of the bill (H.R. 627) to amend the Truth in Lending Act to establish fair and transparent practices relating to the extension of credit under an open end consumer credit plan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29T18:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-92, by Mr. Perlmutter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29T18:51:00-04:00">
      <text>It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill. All points of order against the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute are waived except those arising under clause 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-04-29T18:52:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="49">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 49.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30T10:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5003-5012" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30T10:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 379.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30T11:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5012" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30T11:11:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 379, the Chair put the question on adoption of H.Res. 379, and by voice vote announced that the yeas had prevailed. Mr Sessions demanded the yeas and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30T11:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5012-5013" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-04-30T11:39:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="224" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 249 - 175 (Roll no. 224).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5003" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30T11:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="627"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 627 (Credit Cardholders' Bill of Rights Act of 2009).</summary>
</bill>
