<bill session="109" type="h" number="5279" updated="2013-07-19T19:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oil and Gas Industry Antitrust Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">No Oil Producing and Exporting Cartels Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">NOPEC</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve competition in the oil and gas industry, to strengthen antitrust enforcement with regard to industry mergers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2006-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2006-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2006-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2006-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2006-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2006-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2006-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2006-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2006-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2006-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E710"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="2557"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Cartels"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consent decrees"/>
    <term name="Corporate divestiture"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/3/2006--Introduced.
Oil and Gas Industry Antitrust Act of 2006 - Amends the Clayton Act to make it unlawful for any person to refuse to sell, or to export or divert, existing supplies of petroleum, gasoline, or other fuel derived from petroleum, or natural gas, with the primary intention of increasing prices or creating a shortage in a geographic market. Directs the Attorney General (AG) and the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to study whether section 7 of the Clayton Act (prohibiting certain mergers or acquisitions) should be amended to modify how that section applies to persons engaged in the business of exploring for, producing, refining, or otherwise processing, storing, marketing, selling, or otherwise making available petroleum, gasoline or other fuel derived from petroleum, or natural gas. Requires the Comptroller General to study the effectiveness of divestitures required under certain prior oil and gas industry consent decrees. Directs the AG and FTC Chairman to establish a joint federal-state task force to investigate information sharing among persons in the oil and gas industry. No Oil Producing and Exporting Cartels Act of 2006 or NOPEC - Amends the Sherman Act to make it illegal for any foreign state or instrumentality thereof to act collectively with any other foreign state or instrumentality to: (1) limit oil production or distribution; (2) set or maintain the price of oil; or (3) take any other action in restraint of trade for oil, natural gas, or any petroleum product.</summary>
</bill>
