<bill session="111" type="h" number="1739" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Overseas Voting Practical Amendments Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to prohibit States from refusing to accept balloting materials solely because the materials are generated through the use of a computer program, are not printed on a specific type of paper, or do not otherwise meet similar extraneous requirements which are not clearly necessary to prevent fraud in the conduct of elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412299" joined="2009-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2009-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E793"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2009--Introduced.
Overseas Voting Practical Amendments Act of 2009 - Amends the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (UOCAVA) to rename the official post card form containing both an absentee voter registration application and an absentee ballot application the Federal Voter Registration and Absentee Ballot Application. Prohibits states from refusing to accept balloting materials on any of specified grounds, including that the materials are not printed on a post card, do not include certain information, are not notarized or witnessed by an authorized official, are not delivered by the U.S. Postal Service, or do not meet certain other nonessential requirements. Prohibits a state from requiring an absent uniformed services voter or overseas voter who submits a voter registration application or absentee ballot application to include any form of documentation which may be issued only to an individual who physically resides in the state (such as a current state motor vehicle operator's license or a current utility bill). Prescribes requirements for postage markings on pre-printed return envelopes prepared by a state for the submission of materials by an absent uniformed services voter or overseas voter. Amends UOCAVA to: (1) permit voters to request absentee ballots in all subsequent elections; (2) repeal the requirement to provide absentee ballots in subsequent elections to individuals with unknown addresses; (3) sets forth special rules for use of federal absentee ballots in certain states; (4) apply it to individuals who have never resided in the United States (whose parents are overseas voters); (5) require prompt notification of rejection of a voter registration or absentee ballot request; and (6) provide for use of a U.S. state Department diplomatic pouch for returning completed absentee ballots. Directs the Election Assistance Commission (EAC) to establish a grant program for outreach to absentee uniformed services voters and overseas voters. Requires the head of each office of the federal government that has employees whose designated post of duty is outside the United states to notify such employees of their UOCAVA rights to submit voter registration and absentee ballot requests as well as absentee ballots (including the federal write-in absentee ballot). Requires the Secretary of State to ensure that each passport issued on or after the enactment of this Act includes a page: (1) describing such rights; and (2) listing resources through which individuals may obtain additional information regarding them.</summary>
</bill>
