<bill session="112" type="h" number="435" updated="2013-07-20T01:14:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Flood Insurance Program Termination Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To terminate the National Flood Insurance Program and related mandatory purchase and compliance requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400276"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2011-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412483" joined="2011-05-02" withdrawn="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412414" joined="2011-05-02" withdrawn="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2011-05-02" withdrawn="2011-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2011--Introduced.
National Flood Insurance Program Termination Act of 2010 [sic] - Prohibits the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) from providing any new flood insurance coverage after December 31, 2013, or renewing any coverage provided before such date, under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968. Terminates the National Flood Insurance Program on such date. Makes conforming repeal amendments to the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, the Bunning-Bereuter-Blumenauer Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2004, the National Flood Insurance Reform Act of 1994, and the Federal Flood Insurance Act of 1956. Grants the consent of Congress to any two or more states to enter into agreements or compacts for making flood insurance available to interested persons for loss and damage arising from any flood occurring in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
