<bill session="112" type="s" number="617" updated="2013-07-20T02:21:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Elko Motocross and Tribal Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal land to Elko County, Nevada, and to take land into trust for the Te-moak Tribe of Western Shoshone Indians of Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2011-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1834-1835"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1835-1836" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-18">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-39.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3815"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2011--Introduced.
Elko Motocross and Tribal Conveyance Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to Elko County, Nevada, without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to approximately 275 acres of land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), Elko District, Nevada, as depicted on the map as "Elko Motocross Park." Requires the land conveyed to be used only: (1) as a motocross, bicycle, off-highway vehicle, or stock car racing area; or (2) for any other public purpose consistent with the Recreation and Public Purposes Act. Holds approximately 373 acres of BLM administered land in trust for the Te-moak Tribe of Western Shoshone Indians of Nevada. Makes such land part of the Tribe's reservation. Prohibits class II or III gaming on such land. Limits the use of such land to: (1) traditional and customary uses, (2) stewardship conservation for the benefit of the Tribe, and (3) residential or recreational development. Requires the Tribe to pay the Secretary of the Interior the fair market value of any portion of such land used for another purpose.</summary>
</bill>
