<bill session="112" type="h" number="6677" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common Sense Housing Investment Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to replace the mortgage interest deduction with a nonrefundable credit for indebtedness secured by a residence, to provide affordable housing to extremely low-income families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2012-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-18">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Cooperative and condominium housing"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/18/2012--Introduced.
Common Sense Housing Investment Act of 2012 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the tax deduction for mortgage interest, to: (1) allow, in lieu of such deduction, a tax credit for 20% of mortgage interest paid in a taxable year for the taxpayer's principal residence and one other residence; (2) provide for a phaseout of the tax deduction for mortgage interest between 2013 and 2017; (3) allow a deduction for interest and taxes relating to land for dwelling purposes owned or leased by cooperative housing corporations; and (4) increase the state housing credit ceiling for the low-income housing tax credit. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to apply the savings from the enactment of this Act to the Housing Trust Fund, for assistance under the Section 8 low-income housing program, and for the Public Housing Capital Fund.</summary>
</bill>
