<bill session="110" type="h" number="1100" updated="2013-07-19T21:13:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-23T16:46:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-05-23T16:46:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site Boundary Revision Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site Boundary Revision Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site Boundary Revision Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site Boundary Revision Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To revise the boundary of the Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site in the State of North Carolina, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412225"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400631" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412206" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400280" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-19">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-05-17T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-157.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-05-17T15:10:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="93">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 93.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-05-22T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 429 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1100 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T13:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 429 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T13:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 429.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5648-5654" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T13:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1100 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T13:44:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 429 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T13:44:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ed Pastor to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T13:44:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1100.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T14:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 429, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment numbered 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T14:14:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment numbered 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Bishop (UT) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 429, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment numbered 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T14:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 429, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Heller amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T14:33:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Heller amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Heller demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Grijalva moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1100 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5664-5668" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1100.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5666" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5651" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pearce moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5666-5667" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5666-5667" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pearce motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to prohibit the Secretary of the Interior from using eminent domain to acquire land, water, or interests in land or water under section 3 of the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T16:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 192 - 228 (Roll no. 408).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-05-23T16:46:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="409" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 268 - 150 (Roll no. 409).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-158.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-07-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-09-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-180.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-09-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="378">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 378.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="429"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="488"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="488"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Poetry"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h227"/>
    <amendment number="h228"/>
    <amendment number="h229"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/17/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site Boundary Revision Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire from willing sellers by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange not more than 110 acres of certain land, water, or interests in land and water to be added to the Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site. Permits the Secretary, in order to preserve the historic character and landscape of the Site, to also acquire up to five acres of land for the development of a visitor center and visitor parking area adjacent to or in the vicinity of the Site. Instructs the Secretary, upon the acquisition of any land or interest in land under this Act, to revise the boundary of the Site to reflect the acquisition. Requires any land added to the Site by this Act to be administered as part of the Site in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.</summary>
</bill>
