<bill session="112" type="s" number="392" updated="2013-07-20T02:19:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Promoting Health as Youth Skills In Classrooms And Life Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to support and encourage the health and well-being of elementary school and secondary school students by enhancing school physical education and health education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2011-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2012-11-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2011-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2816"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2011--Introduced.
Promoting Health as Youth Skills In Classrooms And Life Act - Amends the Department of Education Organization Act to establish an Office of Safe and Healthy Students in the Department of Education to assume the responsibilities of the Office of Safe and Drug-Free Schools and expand such responsibilities to broader health and physical education issues. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to include health education and physical education in the definition of "core academic subjects." Requires each state to determine the most feasible measure for assessing students in health education and physical education, including through adaptive assessments, to measure student knowledge and performance against state standards. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to, and enter into contracts with, local educational agencies (LEAs), community-based organizations, and nonprofit organizations to initiate, expand, and improve health education programs for students in kindergarten through grade 12, especially in rural areas. Authorizes appropriations for FY2012-FY2016 for the Carol M. White Physical Education Program, which provides matching grants to LEAs and community-based organizations to initiate, expand, and improve physical education programs (including after-school programs) for students in kindergarten through grade 12.</summary>
</bill>
