<bill session="111" type="h" number="2148" updated="2013-07-19T23:31:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Marine Renewable Energy Promotion Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote the development and use of marine renewable energy technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2009-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1003"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2009--Introduced.
Marine Renewable Energy Promotion Act of 2009 - Requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a program of marine renewable energy research, separated from the Wind and Hydropower program, focused on: (1) developing new marine renewable energy technologies; (2) reducing the manufacturing and operation costs of such technologies; (3) increasing the reliability and survivability of marine renewable energy facilities; (4) integrating marine renewable energy into the national electric grid; (5) identifying opportunities for cross pollination and development of economies of scale between offshore wind and marine renewable energy sources; (6) identifying the environmental impacts of marine renewable energy and ways to address negative impacts; (7) applying advanced systems engineering and system integration methods to identify critical interfaces and develop open standards for marine renewable energy; (8) transferring the resulting intellectual property to industry stakeholders as public information through published interface definitions, standards, and demonstration projects; and (9) developing incentives for industry to comply with such standards. Requires DOE to establish a Marine-based Energy Device Verification Program to provide a bridge from the wave, tidal, or current energy capture device design and development efforts underway across the industry to commercial deployment of marine renewable energy devices. Requires the Program to fund, facilitate the development and installation of, and evaluate marine renewable energy projects, in partnership with the Electric Power Research Institute, the National Renewable Energy Laboratory, the Pacific Northwest National Laboratory Marine Sciences Laboratory, and the Sandia National Laboratories in order to: (1) increase marine renewable energy experience; and (2) build and operate enough candidate devices to obtain statistically significant operating and maintenance data. Requires DOE to establish an Adaptive Management and Environmental Fund to provide grants for complying with requirements to assess and demonstrate the environmental effects of marine renewable energy projects. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to include as "five-year property" for purposes of accelerated depreciation provisions equipment that converts marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy into useable electricity.</summary>
</bill>
