<bill session="111" type="h" number="2690" updated="2013-07-19T23:36:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">School Meal Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create a universal, paperless school meal program that is nationally available.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412232"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2009-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2009-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2009-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2803"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2009--Introduced.
School Meal Enhancement Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to implement a school-wide paperless free school meal program which allows local educational agencies (LEAs) to select certain schools to provide free meals to all their students without the use of paper applications to determine their eligibility for free or reduced price breakfasts or lunches under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 or the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act. Prohibits the participation of schools that do not have a student enrollment of which at least: (1) 65% are estimated to be eligible for free meals under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966; or (2) 75% are estimated to be eligible for free or reduced price meals under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act. Requires the Secretary to issue guidance that establishes an alternate, paperless method of determining such estimated eligibility rates. Reimburses the school food service authority of each participating LEA pursuant to a formula that factors in such estimated eligibility rates.</summary>
</bill>
