<bill session="112" type="s" number="3236" updated="2013-07-20T02:44:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Servicemember Employment Protection Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the protection and enforcement of employment and reemployment rights of members of the uniformed services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2012-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2012-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-567.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2012--Introduced.
Servicemember Employment Protection Act of 2012 - Makes unenforceable any clause of an agreement between and employer and employee requiring arbitration of a dispute arising under the Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act (USERRA). Provides an exception when both parties voluntarily agree to arbitration. Requires any issue as to whether such requirement applies to an arbitration clause to be determined by federal law and the validity or enforceability of an agreement to arbitrate to be determined by a court rather than an arbitrator. Protects under USERRA an individual who is absent from employment in order to receive medical or dental treatment for an injury or illness incurred or aggravated in the line of duty. Authorizes the suspension, termination, or debarment of federal contractors for repeated failures or refusals to comply with USERRA protections.</summary>
</bill>
