<bill session="112" type="h" number="1646" updated="2013-07-20T01:24:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Angler Preservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to preserve jobs and coastal communities through transparency and accountability in fishery management, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2011-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412408" joined="2011-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-01">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2772"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="632"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2011--Introduced.
American Angler Preservation Act - Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to require each scientific and statistical committee of the eight Regional Fishery Management Councils to provide its respective Council with ongoing risk neutral scientific advice (current law does not specify that such advice be risk neutral) for fishery management decisions. Prohibits such a committee from recommending to increase or decrease an annual catch limit by 20% or greater unless the recommendation has been approved in a peer review process conducted exclusively by nongovernmental entities. Requires fishery management plans, amendments, or regulations for overfished fisheries to specify a time period for ending overfishing and rebuilding the fishery that is as short as practicable (under current law, as short as possible). Modifies the exceptions to the requirement that such period not exceed ten years. Requires consideration, in evaluating progress to end overfishing and rebuild overfished stocks, of factors other than commercial and recreational fishing. Requires, when the Secretary of Commerce extends the rebuilding period under specified provisions, that the maximum rebuilding time not exceed the sum of the initial ten-year period, the expected time to rebuild the stock absent any fishing mortality and under prevailing environmental conditions, and the mean generation time of the stock. Directs the Secretary, within 60 days after receiving a request from the governor of an affected state or a fishing community, to determine whether there is a commercial fishery failure due to a fishery resource disaster resulting from certain causes. Sets forth procedures for certification of a fishery management plan (or amendment) requested by a percentage of eligible fisherman to establish a limited access privilege program to harvest in fisheries under the authority of the New England, Mid-Atlantic, South Atlantic, or Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council. Prohibits the Secretary, acting through the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), from closing a fishery that would have an affect of at least $50,000 on each of more than 25 small businesses related to the recreational, charter, or commercial fishing industries involved in the fishery being closed, unless the Secretary certifies that specified conditions have been met.</summary>
</bill>
