<bill session="109" type="s" number="376" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Port Security bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Intermodal Shipping Container Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve intermodal shipping container transportation security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300054"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1415"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1415-1417" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Containerization"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Freight forwarders"/>
    <term name="Geographic information systems"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2005--Introduced.
Intermodal Shipping Container Security Act - Directs the Under Secretary of Homeland Security for Border and Transportation Security to take into account a certain National Maritime Transportation Security Plan to ensure that the strategy for dealing with threats to transportation security incorporates relevant aspects of the Plan and addresses all modes of commercial transportation to, from, and within the United States. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to submit to Congress a strategic plan for integrating security for all modes of transportation by which intermodal shipping containers arrive, depart, or move in interstate commerce. Establishes the Senior Steering Group to develop solutions to conflicts among constituent agencies regarding intermodal shipping container security. Amends Federal shipping law to direct the Secretary of Transportation to develop a system to increase the number of intermodal shipping containers physically inspected (including nonintrusive inspection by scanning technology), monitored, and tracked within the United States. Requires, beginning in 2007, no less than 50 percent of all ocean-borne shipping containers entering the United States to incorporate "Smart Box" or equivalent technology. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) report to Congress a preliminary plan for strengthening the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection's container targeting system; (2) issue regulations reducing from 60 days to 45 days after arrival at a U.S. port the time period for revisions to a container manifest that is submitted to the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection; (3) develop a system to share threat and vulnerability information with all of the industries in the supply chain; and (4) substantially increase under the Container Security Initiative the number of U.S. Customs Service inspectors assigned to duty outside of the United States with responsibility for inspecting intermodal shipping containers being shipped to the United States. Directs the Under Secretary to implement a plan for random inspection of shipping containers in addition to any targeted or preshipment inspection of such containers required by law. Sets forth civil penalties for discrepancies found in container manifests.</summary>
</bill>
