<bill session="111" type="h" number="5354" updated="2013-07-20T00:00:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-30T00:40:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-09-30T00:40:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">GEDI Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gestational Diabetes Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">GEDI Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Gestational Diabetes Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">GEDI Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Gestational Diabetes Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish an Advisory Committee on Gestational Diabetes, to provide grants to better understand and reduce gestational diabetes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To provide grants to better understand and reduce gestational diabetes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412229" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="2010-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-09-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T15:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 111-633.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-28T15:13:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="373">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 373.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T21:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pallone moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T21:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7178-7180" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T21:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5354.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T21:36:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Burgess objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-30T00:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7379" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-09-30T00:40:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/28/2010 H7178-7179" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-30T00:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-30T00:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3966"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/2010--Passed House amended.
Gestational Diabetes Act of 2010 or the GEDI Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to develop a multisite gestational diabetes research project within the diabetes program of the CDC to expand and enhance surveillance data and public health research on gestational diabetes.&#160; Requires such research project to address: (1) procedures to establish accurate and efficient systems for the collection of gestational diabetes data; (2) the progress of collaborative activities with the National Vital Statistics System, the National Center for Health Statistics, and state health departments to improve surveillance of gestational diabetes; (3) postpartum methods of tracking women with gestational diabetes after delivery and targeted interventions to&#160;lower the incidence of type 2 diabetes in such women; (4) variations in the distribution of diagnosed and undiagnosed gestational diabetes; and (5) factors and culturally sensitive interventions that influence risks and reduce the incidence of gestational diabetes and related complications during childbirth. Requires the Secretary, not later than two years after the enactment of this Act, to report on the findings and recommendations of the research project. Requires the Secretary to expand and intensify public health research on gestational diabetes, including; (1) developing and testing novel approaches for improving postpartum testing or screening and for preventing type 2 diabetes in women with a history of gestational diabetes; and (2) conducting research to&#160;further understanding of the&#160;factors and health systems that influence the risk&#160;of gestational diabetes and the development of type 2 diabetes in women with a history of gestational diabetes. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the CDC, to: (1) award grants on a competitive basis for demonstration projects that implement evidence-based interventions to reduce the incidence of gestational diabetes, the recurrence of such disease in subsequent pregnancies, and the development of type 2 diabetes in women with a history of gestational diabetes; and (2) report to Congress, not later than four years after the enactment of this Act, on the results of the demonstration projects. Sets forth priorities for awarding grants and requirements for the use of grant funds for carrying out demonstration projects. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the CDC, to work with state and Indian tribal-based diabetes prevention and control programs assisted by the CDC to encourage postpartum follow-up after gestational diabetes to reduce the incidence of gestational diabetes and its recurrence, the development of type 2 diabetes in at-risk women, and&#160;related complications. Authorizes appropriations for FY2012-FY2016.</summary>
</bill>
