<bill session="112" type="h" number="6396" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">End Radon in Schools Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a grant program to test and mitigate radon levels in public schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412208"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2012--Introduced.
End Radon in Schools Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to review, update, revise, and publish the Radon Measurements In Schools Guidelines with current information and guidance on radon testing in public elementary and secondary schools. Directs the Administrator, subject to the availability of appropriations, to award grants to states to: (1) follow the updated Guidelines, (2) conduct short-term tests of radon levels in their public elementary and secondary schools, and (3) provide funds to their local educational agencies (LEAs) to mitigate and reevaluate radon levels in schools found to have unsafe quantities of radon. Requires the Administrator to conduct such mitigation directly or by contract if an LEA does not certify to its state that it will use grant funds to mitigate unsafe radon levels at its schools. Considers radon levels of at least four picocuries per liter to be unsafe. Gives grant priority to states whose total landmass lies in Radon Zone 1.</summary>
</bill>
