<bill session="109" type="s" number="4077" updated="2013-07-19T20:48:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Australian Wheat Board Accountability Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the United States Trade Representative to initiate a section 301 investigation into abuses by the Australian Wheat Board with respect to the United Nations Oil-for-Food Programme, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-12-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11316-11317"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Wheat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2006--Introduced.
Australian Wheat Board Accountability Act of 2006 - Directs the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR) to initiate an investigation in accordance with title III of the Trade Act of 1974 to determine if actions by the Australian Wheat Board with respect to the Board's abuse of the United Nations Oil-for-Food Programme constitutes an act, policy, or practice and justifies taking action against unfair trade practices and to enforce U.S. rights under trade agreements. Deems economic damage suffered by U.S. wheat farmers as a result of the practices of the Australian Wheat Board related to the United Nations Oil-for-Food Programme during the period 1999 to 2003 to be such an act, policy, or practice. Requires the USTR to seek a negotiated settlement with the Australian government upon an affirmative determination that the actions of the Australian Wheat Board have resulted in barriers to U.S. wheat exports or meet the requirements for mandatory action. Imposes additional duties upon Australian imports in the event of failure to reach a negotiated settlement.</summary>
</bill>
