<bill session="113" type="h" number="304" updated="2013-11-02T06:21:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to change the membership of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority board of directors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400435"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E34"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/15/2013--Introduced.
Revises membership requirements for and reduces to nine the number of members on the board of directors of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority. Makes corresponding reductions in the number of members appointed by the governors of Virginia and Maryland, the mayor of the District of Columbia, and the President. Reduces from 10 to 5 the number of votes required to approve bond issues and the annual budget. Makes conforming amendments to the District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985. Limits members to one term. Prescribes certain term limits for the first six members appointed by the governor of Virginia.</summary>
</bill>
