<bill session="113" type="s" number="1383" updated="2013-11-02T07:03:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pathways Back to Work Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide subsidized employment for unemployed, low-income adults, provide summer employment and year-round employment opportunities for low-income youth, and carry out work-related and educational strategies and activities of demonstrated effectiveness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2013-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2381"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2721"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2770"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2821"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2821"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1170"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2013--Introduced.
Pathways Back to Work Act of 2013 - Establishes in the Treasury the Pathways Back to Work Fund, with an initial appropriation of $12.5 billion. Requires the Secretary of Labor to make certain Fund allocations to states with approved plans, qualifying outlying areas (U.S. Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Republic of Palau), and Native American program grantees to provide: (1) subsidized employment to unemployed, low-income adults; and (2) summer and year-round employment opportunities to low-income youth. Requires the Secretary to award competitive grants to local entities for work-based training and other work-related and educational strategies and activities of demonstrated effectiveness to provide unemployed, low-income adults and low-income youths with skills that will lead to employment. Subjects activities funded under this Act to federal labor standards and nondiscrimination protections.</summary>
</bill>
