<bill session="109" type="s" number="488" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commercial Truck Highway Safety Demonstration Program Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a commercial truck highway safety demonstration program in the State of Maine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2005-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1876"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="1012"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2005--Introduced.
Commercial Truck Highway Safety Demonstration Program Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to carry out a program to demonstrate the effects on the safety of the highway network in Maine of permitting operation on the Interstate System highways within the State of a vehicle that weighs over 80,000 pounds, that consists of a three-axle tractor unit hauling a single trailer or semitrailer, and that does not exceed any vehicle weight limitation applicable under Maine law. Waives highway funding reduction relating to weight of vehicles using Interstate System highways with respect to vehicles allowed pursuant to this program. Provides for program termination and for the responsibilities of the State of Maine, including: (1) submitting a plan to the Secretary of Transportation; (2) establishing a highway safety committee; and (3) collecting data on the net effects of the operation of such vehicles on safety.</summary>
</bill>
