<bill session="109" type="h" number="4633" updated="2013-07-19T19:45:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HIV/AIDS Emergency Hurricane Relief Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish within the Department of Health and Human Services the position of HIV/AIDS Emergency Response Coordinator in order to coordinate the provision of certain services to individuals with HIV disease who have been displaced as a result of Hurricane Katrina or Rita, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400237"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2006-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2006-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Psychotherapy"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/17/2005--Introduced.
HIV/AIDS Emergency Hurricane Relief Act - Requires the President to appoint an HIV/AIDS Emergency Response Coordinator to coordinate the provision of services under federal programs to individuals who: (1) are living with HIV; (2) are residents or were residents of a declared major disaster area at the time of Hurricane Katrina, Rita, or Wilma; and (3) have been displaced by such hurricane or have been unable to access comprehensive medical care and treatment, including housing, case management, drug and alcohol treatment, and other supportive services. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Coordinator, to award grants or cooperative agreements to public and nonprofit private entities that: (1) have experience in providing services to eligible individuals; and (2) have received or are eligible to receive funding from the federal government through the HIV health care services program or the Housing Opportunities for Persons With AIDS program. Allows the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to waive matching requirements and any other appropriate conditions for grants under the HIV health care services program. Allows the Coordinator to award grants or cooperative agreements to public and nonprofit private entities that provide covered services to eligible individuals in order to provide such entities with emergency infrastructure support. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, to conduct a public awareness campaign directed toward eligible individuals who were receiving services through the federal HIV health care services program and for whom the hurricanes caused the disruption or termination of such services.</summary>
</bill>
