<bill session="110" type="h" number="709" updated="2013-07-19T21:09:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Total Overhaul of Totalization Agreements Law of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to restrict totalization agreements between the United States and other countries to providing for appropriate exchange of Social Security taxes or contributions between the parties to such agreements, and to prohibit crediting of individuals under such title with earnings from employment or self-employment in the United States performed while such individuals are not citizens, nationals, or lawful permanent residents of the United States and are not authorized by law to be employed in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax treaties"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/29/2007--Introduced.
Total Overhaul of Totalization Agreements Law of 2007 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to revise requirements for agreements establishing a totalization arrangement between the United States and another country with respect to the exchange of funds and information between the countries on behalf citizens, nationals, or permanent residents of one country who become entitled to cash benefits under the other country's social security system. Prohibits, in computing an individual's average indexed monthly earnings, the crediting of individuals under OASDI with wages from employment or self-employment in the United States performed while such individuals: (1) are not citizens, nationals, or lawful permanent residents of the United States; and (2) are not authorized by law to be employed in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
