<bill session="112" type="sr" number="85" updated="2013-07-20T02:11:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-01">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution strongly condemning the gross and systematic violations of human rights in Libya, including violent attacks on protesters demanding democratic reforms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2011-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-03-01" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1075-1076" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1076" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1068-1069" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2011--Passed Senate without amendment.
Applauds the courage of the Libyan people in standing up against the dictatorship of Muammar Gadhafi and for demanding democratic reforms and respect for human and civil rights. Condemns systematic violations of human rights in Libya, including attacks on protesters demanding democratic reforms. Calls on Muammar Gadhafi to desist from further violence, recognize the Libyan people's demand for democratic change, resign his position, and permit a peaceful transition to democracy. Welcomes the vote of the U.N. Security Council on resolution 1970 referring the situation in Libya to the International Criminal Court (ICC), imposing an arms embargo on the Libyan Arab Jamahiriya, freezing Gadhafi family assets, and banning international travel by Gadhafi, members of his family, and senior advisors. Urges: (1) the Gadhafi regime to abide by Security Council Resolution 1970, and (2) the Security Council to take such further action to protect civilians in Libya from attack, including the possible imposition of a no-fly zone over Libyan territory. Welcomes: (1) the African Union's (AU) condemnation of the disproportionate use of force in Libya and urges the AU to take action to address the human rights crisis in Libya, (2) the United Nations Human Rights Council's (UNHRC) decision to recommend Libya's suspension from the Council and urges the U.N. General Assembly to vote to suspend Libya's rights of Council, (3) Secretary of State Clinton's attendance at the UNHRC meeting in Geneva and urges the Council's assumption of a country mandate for Libya that employs a Special Rapporteur on the human rights situation in Libya, and (4) U.S. outreach to Libyan opposition figures in support of an orderly transition to a democratic government in Libya.</summary>
</bill>
