<bill session="110" type="s" number="2155" updated="2013-07-19T22:39:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Clean Energy Technologies Deployment and Global Energy Markets Investment Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to encourage the development of clean energy technologies for deployment in markets abroad, to assist the Department of Energy's promotion of research and development of clean and efficient energy systems, to encourage the Department of Energy and other Federal agencies to work together to improve the advancement of sustainable energy use and reduce greenhouse gas emissions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy consumption"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fluorocarbons"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sulphur"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Waste reduction"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/2007--Introduced.
International Clean Energy Technologies Deployment and Global Energy Markets Investment Act of 2007 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to set forth a program for clean energy assistance to developing countries. Instructs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) establish a pilot program of financial assistance for clean energy projects in developing countries that will result in reduced greenhouse gas emissions; and (2) make a loan or loan guarantee for not more than 50% of project costs for each pilot program participant. Includes in such pilot program projects for clean energy technologies, including clean coal, small or advanced nuclear, small or advanced hydropower, biofuels, renewable, and energy efficiency technologies. Directs the President to establish a Task Force on International Clean Energy Technologies Cooperation. Requires the Task Force to establish an Interagency Working Group on Clean Energy Technology Exports. Requires such Task Force to identify developing countries that represent the predominant share of energy use, and to submit to the President a strategy that includes: (1) adoption and deployment of clean energy technologies and strategies in developing countries; (2) expansion of clean energy technology markets and facilitation of clean energy technology exports to developing countries; (3) integration into U.S. foreign policy objectives of the promotion of clean energy technology deployment and reduced greenhouse gas emissions in developing countries, and clean energy technology exports; (4) a pilot program of financial assistance for qualifying projects; and (5) development of financial mechanisms and instruments that are cost-effective and facilitate private capital investment in such technologies.</summary>
</bill>
