<bill session="109" type="s" number="690" updated="2013-07-19T20:19:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Indian Reservation Transportation Improvement Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century to provide from the Highway Trust Fund additional funding for Indian reservation roads, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300036"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3151"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3151-3152" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/2005--Introduced.
American Indian Reservation Transportation Improvement Program Act - Amends the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century to authorize appropriations for Indian reservation roads under the Federal Lands Highways Program through FY 2009. Authorizes appropriations to carry out the planning, design, engineering, preconstruction, construction, and inspection of certain projects concerning deficient Indian reservation road bridges through FY 2009. Directs the Secretary to issue grants to Indian tribes to establish rural transit programs on reservations or other land under the jurisdiction of the tribes. Directs the Secretary to establish and maintain: (1) intra-agency cooperation between the Federal Highway Administration (FHA) and the Federal Transit Administration (FTA) in administering tribal transit programs funded by the FHA, and exploring options for the transfer of funds from the FHA to the FTA for the direct funding of tribal transit programs; and (2) working relationships with representatives of regional tribal technical assistance programs to ensure proper administration of ongoing and future tribal transit programs carried out using Federal funds.</summary>
</bill>
