<bill session="110" type="sr" number="31" updated="2013-07-19T22:13:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-17">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-01-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing support for democratic forces in Serbia and encouraging the people of Serbia to remain committed to a democratic path.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-01-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2007-01-17" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S707-708" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S707-708" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S703" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="Serbia"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="Yugoslavia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/17/2007--Passed Senate without amendment.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States should be committed to a strong relationship with a democratic Serbia as Serbia moves toward its goals of membership in the European Union (EU) and cooperation with the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation (NATO); (2) the inclusion of Serbia in the NATO Partnership for Peace Program was a critical step in bringing Serbia closer to the Euro-Atlantic Alliance; (3) Serbia will now have the opportunity to enact defense reforms and apply for a Membership Action Plan for NATO; (4) Serbia should continue its reform progress; (5) Serbia should move quickly to fulfill its obligations to the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia, including by immediately arresting Ratko Mladic and transferring him to the Hague; and (6) the United States should continue its defense and security cooperation with Serbia, and should remain a friend to the people of Serbia as they continue on the path of democracy.</summary>
</bill>
