<bill session="111" type="h" number="3961" updated="2013-07-19T23:25:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-27">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Physician Payment Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Medicare Physician Payment Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to reform the Medicare SGR payment system for physicians.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to reform the Medicare SGR payment system for physicians and to reinstitute and update the Pay-As-You-Go requirement of budget neutrality on new tax and mandatory spending legislation, enforced by the threat of annual, automatic sequestration.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An Act to extend expiring provisions of the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 and Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 until February 28, 2011.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2009-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-07T02:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 903 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3962 and H.R. 3961 with 4 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-07T13:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 903 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T13:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 903.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13289-13319" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T13:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3962 and H.R. 3961 with 4 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T13:46:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3961.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T15:19:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13308" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T15:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gingrey (GA) moved to recommit with instructions to Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13308-13315" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H13308-13315" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T15:19:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gingrey motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House forthwith with an amendment in the nature of a substitute relating to Medicare SGR improvement and reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T15:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Waxman raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Waxman stated that the motion to recommit seeks to exceed the scope of the bill and the amendment is therefore, not germane. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T15:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T15:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gingrey (GA) appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T15:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Waxman moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T15:54:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 251 - 177 (Roll no. 907).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13316-13317" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T15:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Cantor moved to recommit with instructions to Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13317" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H13317" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T15:55:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cantor motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House with an amendment to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to implement an adjustment in payments for physician services under section 1848 of the Social Security Act.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T16:05:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13318" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T16:22:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 177 - 252 (Roll no. 908).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-11-19T16:29:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="909" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 243 - 183 (Roll no. 909).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13289-013291" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T16:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-24">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-01-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="252">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 252.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-02-24">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S736-737" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2010-02-24" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-02-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T16:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1109, Mr. Conyers took from the Speaker's table H.R. 3961 with the Senate amendments thereto, and was recognized for a motion.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H895-901, H906-907" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T16:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Conyers moved that the House agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H895" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T16:28:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Conyers motion to agree to the Senate amendments to H.R. 3961.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T17:23:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H901" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T17:23:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule 19, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the Conyers motion to concur in the Senate amendments to H.R. 3961 until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T18:37:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on concurring in the Senate amendments and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Posey objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Pursuant to clause 6 of rule XX, the yeas and nays were ordered.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-02-25T19:26:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="67" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 315 - 97 (Roll no. 67).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H895" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T19:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-02-25">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-02-26">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-02-27">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-02-27" type="public" number="111-141">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-141.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="111" type="hr" number="903"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="1109"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2920"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="House Committee on the Budget"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Senate Committee on the Budget"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3331"/>
    <amendment number="s3332"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>2/25/2010--Public Law.
(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on February 24, 2010. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Amends the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 to extend through February 28, 2011, provisions: (1) granting roving surveillance authority under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) where the court finds that the actions of the target may thwart the identification of a specified person or other persons (by using multiple devices or modes of communication, among other means); and (2) authorizing the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to apply for a court order requiring production of tangible things (including books, records, papers, and documents), not merely business records, for foreign intelligence and international terrorism investigations. Amends the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to extend through February 28, 2011, an amendment to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) that redefines "agent of a foreign power" to include any non-U.S. person who engages in international terrorism or activities in preparation for such terrorism ("lone wolf" provision).</summary>
</bill>
