<bill session="109" type="s" number="2441" updated="2013-07-19T20:34:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Innovation Districts for School Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize resources for a grant program for local educational agencies to create innovation districts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2334-2335"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Charter schools"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Rating of teachers"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2006--Introduced.
Innovation Districts for School Improvement Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to 10 urban and 10 non-urban local educational agencies (LEAs) for the creation of innovation districts. Requires the LEAs to: (1) establish tests and longitudinal data systems to track the academic progress of each elementary and secondary school student and use such performance measures in evaluating and awarding school personnel and programs; (2) work with teacher representatives and other community partners to attain the administrative flexibility to staff more equitably all agency schools with effective personnel; (3) evaluate and award effective teachers on the basis of student progress and observations of teacher performance; (4) provide grants to recent college graduates and mid-career professionals to attend LEA-established Teacher Academies which provide classroom mentoring and concurrent teacher education from partner institutions in exchange for three years of service in hard-to-staff schools; (5) establish career ladders allowing teachers to progress from novice to master with a concomitant increase in compensation and responsibility for the development of fellow teachers; and (6) plan for the recruitment, training, and evaluation of school principals who are to serve as instructional leaders in the schools and hold significant responsiblity for teacher hiring and placement. Allows the LEAs to support new schools or networks of public schools, serving predominantly disadvantaged students, which are sponsored by universities, education management organizations, or nonprofit organizations.</summary>
</bill>
