<bill session="110" type="sj" number="46" updated="2013-07-19T22:13:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-12-19">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A joint resolution ensuring that the compensation and other emoluments attached to the office of Secretary of State are those which were in effect on January 1, 2007.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2008-12-10" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10885-10886" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10885-10886" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10883" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T20:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T20:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis (IL) asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T20:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10944-10945" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2008-12-10T20:58:00-05:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10945" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T20:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2008-12-12">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2008-12-19">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2008-12-19" type="public" number="110-455">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 110-455.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Cabinet officers"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2008--Public Law.
States that the compensation and other emoluments attached to the office of Secretary of State shall be those in effect January 1, 2007, notwithstanding any increase in such compensation or emoluments after that date under any provision of law or provision which has the force and effect of law, that is enacted or becomes effective during the period beginning at noon of January 3, 2007, and ending at noon of January 3, 2013. States that: (1) any person aggrieved by an action of the Secretary may bring a civil action in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia (under a three-judge panel) to contest the constitutionality of the appointment and continuance in office of the Secretary on the ground that such appointment and continuance in office is in violation of article I, section 6, clause 2, of the Constitution; (2) the Court shall have exclusive jurisdiction over such action; and (3) an appeal may be taken directly to the U.S. Supreme Court from any interlocutory or final judgment, decree, or order upon the validity of the appointment and continuance in office of the Secretary under article I, section 6, clause 2, of the Constitution, entered in any action brought under this resolution. Makes this resolution effective at noon of January 20, 2009.</summary>
</bill>
