<bill session="109" type="s" number="718" updated="2013-07-19T20:19:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State and Local Law Enforcement Discipline, Accountability, and Due Process Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide standards and procedures to guide both State and local law enforcement agencies and law enforcement officers during internal investigations, interrogation of law enforcement officers, and administrative disciplinary hearings, and to ensure accountability of law enforcement officers, to guarantee the due process rights of law enforcement officers, and to require States to enact law enforcement discipline, accountability, and due process laws.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2005-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2006-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2006-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3283-3284"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3284-3288" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="354"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government employee unions"/>
    <term name="Government employees' political activities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police brutality"/>
    <term name="Police corruption"/>
    <term name="Police questioning"/>
    <term name="Police-community relations"/>
    <term name="Polygraphs"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Self-incrimination"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2005--Introduced.
State and Local Law Enforcement Discipline, Accountability, and Due Process Act of 2005 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to set forth the due process rights, including procedures, that shall be afforded a law enforcement officer (officer) who is the subject of an investigation or disciplinary hearing. Declares that an officer shall not be: (1) prohibited from engaging in political activity or be denied the right to refrain from engaging in such activity, except when on duty or acting in an official capacity; and (2) prohibited from being a candidate for an elective office or from serving in such elective office solely because of the officer's status as an officer, with exceptions.Requires that: (1) each agency adopt and thereafter comply with a written complaint procedure that meets specified requirements; and (2) an investigation based on a complaint from outside the agency commence not later than 15 days after receipt of the complaint by the agency employing the officer against whom the complaint has been made, or any other agency charged with investigating such complaint.Directs that any officer who is the subject of an investigation be notified of the investigation 24 hours before the commencement of questioning. Establishes rights of officers before and during questioning, including the right to counsel. Requires questioning to be conducted at reasonable hours. Prohibits an officer from being compelled to submit to the use of a lie detector.</summary>
</bill>
