<bill session="112" type="s" number="3565" updated="2013-07-20T02:47:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pregnant Workers Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to eliminate discrimination and promote women's health and economic security by ensuring reasonable workplace accommodations for workers whose ability to perform the functions of a job are limited by pregnancy, childbirth, or a related medical condition.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-11-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2012-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2012-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2012-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="5647"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2012--Introduced.
Pregnant Workers Fairness Act - Declares it an unlawful employment practice for employers, employment agencies, labor organizations, and other specified entities to: (1) not make reasonable accommodations to known limitations related to the pregnancy, childbirth, or related medical conditions of job applicants or employees, unless the accommodation would impose an undue hardship on such an entity's business operation; (2) deny employment opportunities based on the need of the entity to make such reasonable accommodations; (3) require such job applicants or employees to accept an accommodation that they choose not to accept; or (4) require such employees to take leave if another reasonable accommodation can be provided to their known limitations. Sets forth enforcement procedures and remedies under the Civil Rights Act of 1964, Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, Government Employee Rights Act of 1991, and the rights and protections extended to presidential offices. Directs the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) to issue regulations to carry out this Act, including the identification of reasonable accommodations addressing known limitations related to pregnancy, childbirth, or related medical conditions.</summary>
</bill>
