<bill session="112" type="s" number="3229" updated="2013-07-20T02:44:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Long-Term Care Insurance Consumer Right-to-Know Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to develop a model disclosure form to assist consumers in purchasing long-term care insurance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2012-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2012--Introduced.
Long-Term Care Insurance Consumer Right-to-Know Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to request the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC) to review and describe, and report to Congress on: (1) disclosure requirements for long-term care insurance policies under the long-term care insurance model regulation and Act promulgated by NAIC (as adopted as of October 2000 and December 2006); (2) disclosure requirements for long-term care insurance policies under state laws; (3) differences in long-term care services, providers, and settings among states; and (4) key issues to consider in the development of a proposed model form for marketing long-term care insurance policies. Directs the Secretary to request NAIC to: (1) establish a Working Group to develop and issue a model disclosure form for marketing long-term care insurance policies, and (2) amend the model regulation and Act to require the use of such form. Requires: (1) the Secretaries of the Treasury and HHS to promulgate regulations requiring issuers of a qualified long-term care insurance contract under certain tax-qualified or Medicaid Partnership policies to use such form for marketing such contracts, and (2) each state to require any issuer of a long-term care insurance policy to use such form when marketing such a policy in the state.</summary>
</bill>
