<bill session="113" type="s" number="32" updated="2013-11-02T06:52:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Custody Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit taking minors across State lines in circumvention of laws requiring the involvement of parents in abortion decisions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2013-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S716-717" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S716-717" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="732"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="369"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/2013--Introduced.
Child Custody Protection Act of 2013 - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit knowingly transporting a minor child across a state line to obtain an abortion (deems such transporting to be a de facto abridgment of the right of a parent under any law in the minor's state of residence that requires parental involvement in the minor's abortion decision). Makes an exception for an abortion necessary to save the life of the minor. Makes it an affirmative defense to a prosecution or civil action under this Act that a defendant reasonably believed that before the minor obtained the abortion, the required parental consent or notification or judicial authorization took place. Imposes a fine and/or prison term of up to one year on anyone who has committed an act of incest with a minor and knowingly transports such minor across a state line to obtain an abortion.</summary>
</bill>
