<bill session="111" type="h" number="5587" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a United States Commission on Planetary Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2010-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Astronomy"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2010--Introduced.
Establishes in the legislative branch the United States Commission on Planetary Defense to: (1) review the structure, coordination, management policies, and procedures of the federal government, and as appropriate, international bodies, and nongovernmental entities, relative to the detection, characterization, mitigation, and over all response efforts to dangerous Near-Earth Objects (NEOs); (2) assess U.S. and foreign technology readiness levels required to provide effective planetary defense and make recommendations to develop required technologies, including NEO detection and characterization systems, spacecraft, nuclear devices, and laser systems; and (3) submit interim reports and a final report to the President and Congress containing such findings, conclusions, and recommendations as the Commission shall determine for corrective measures. Sets forth provisions regarding the membership, powers, and staff of the Commission.</summary>
</bill>
