<bill session="110" type="s" number="3013" updated="2013-07-19T22:47:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-10-01">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Non-Foreign AREA Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Non-Foreign Area Retirement Equity Assurance Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Non-Foreign AREA Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Non-Foreign Area Retirement Equity Assurance Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for retirement equity for Federal employees in nonforeign areas outside the 48 contiguous States and the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-05-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4109"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4109-4111" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-06-25">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with amendments. With written report No. 110-456.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="954">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 954.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-10-01">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10390-10394" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10390-10392" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-01">
      <text>The committee amendments were agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2008-10-01" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10392-10394" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-10-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-02T12:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-02">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-02">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="6516"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5689"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/1/2008--Passed Senate amended.
Non-Foreign Area Retirement Equity Assurance Act of 2008 or the Non-Foreign AREA Act of 2008 - Revises federal employee locality-based comparability payments provisions to include U.S. territories and possessions, including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, within a pay locality. Sets forth maximum rates of pay for Senior Executive Service (SES) personnel in such areas.Revises the calculation of allowances based on living costs and conditions of environment for pay of employees stationed outside the continental United States or in Alaska to apply it only to areas designated as of December 31, 2008. Provides a formula for adjustment of such rate using a transition schedule for calendar years 2009-2011.Requires adjustment of special rates of pay in such areas in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) or by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for VA personnel. Allows a temporarily raised limitation on the amount of special rates during the transition period.Expresses the sense of Congress that application of this Act to an employee should not result in a decrease in take home pay.Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Bureau of Labor Statistics will conduct separate surveys pursuant to the establishment by the President's Pay Agent of one new locality area for each of the entire state of Hawaii and the entire state of Alaska; and (2) upon the completion of the phase-in period no employee shall receive less than the rest of the U.S. locality pay rate.Describes application of this Act to postal employees.Defines as covered employees for purposes of this Act those who are or will be eligible for a cost-of-living allowance (COLA).Allows an employee subject to this Act's transition schedule and who retires from service during the period from January 1, 2009, through December 31, 2011, to elect to have the COLA paid during that period considered as basic pay for purposes of annuity computation.</summary>
</bill>
