<bill session="112" type="s" number="860" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that methodologies and technologies used by the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection to screen for and detect the presence of chemical, nuclear, biological, and radiological weapons in municipal solid waste are as effective as the methodologies and technologies used by the Bureau to screen for those materials in other items of commerce entering the United States through commercial motor vehicle transport.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2011-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2533"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2533-2534" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2011--Introduced.
Requires the Commissioner of the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection (CBP): (1) to report on whether the methodologies and technologies used by&#160; CBP to screen for and detect the presence of chemical, nuclear, biological, and radiological weapons in municipal solid waste are as effective as those used to screen for&#160;such materials in other items of commerce entering the United States through commercial motor vehicle transport; and (2) if such waste screening measures are less effective, to report on the actions CBP will take to achieve the same level of effectiveness. Bars entry of such waste into the United States if such actions are not fully implemented within a specified period following such report until such screening measures are certified to be as effective for such waste as for other items entering U.S. commerce.</summary>
</bill>
