<bill session="112" type="h" number="2425" updated="2013-07-20T01:31:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transparency and Security in Mortgage Registration Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, and Ginnie Mae from owning or guaranteeing any mortgage that is assigned to the Mortgage Electronic Registration Systems or for which MERS is the mortgagee of record.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2011-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae)"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/6/2011--Introduced.
Transparency and Security in Mortgage Registration Act of 2011 - Amends the National Housing Act to prohibit the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) from purchasing, acquiring, newly lending on the security of, newly investing in securities consisting of, or otherwise newly dealing in any Mortgage Electronic Registration System, Inc. (MERS) mortgage or mortgages. Prohibits the Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae) from newly guaranteeing the payment of principal of or interest on any trust certificate or other security based or backed by a trust or pool that contains, or purchase or acquire, any MERS mortgage. Directs Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, and Ginnie Mae to require all their current MERS mortgages to be assigned to the proper servicer, holder, or creditor. Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to study: (1) the impacts of the lack of electronic records and uniform standards found in local land title recordation systems currently used in the various states; (2) any progress states have made in developing electronic land title recordation systems containing uniform standards; (3) the current oversight role of the federal government in the transfer and recordation of land titles; and (4) the feasibility of creating a federal land title recordation system for property transfers that would maintain all previous records of the land-property without invalidating, interfering with, or preempting state real property law governing the transfer and perfection of land title.</summary>
</bill>
