<bill session="112" type="sr" number="251" updated="2013-07-20T02:12:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-16">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing support for improvement in the collection, processing, and consumption of recyclable materials throughout the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2011-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2011-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2011-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5267-5268" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-16">
      <text>Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7627-7628" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-11-16" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7627-7628" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/2011--Passed Senate without amendment.
Expresses support for: (1) improvement in the collection, processing, and consumption of recyclable material throughout the United States in order to create well-paying jobs, foster innovation and investment in recycling infrastructure, and stimulate the economy; (2) strengthening the U.S. manufacturing base in order to rebuild the domestic economy; (3) a competitive marketplace for recyclable materials; (4) the trade of recyclable commodities; (5) U.S. policies that promote recycling, that promote recyclable materials as essential economic commodities rather than wastes, that promote using recyclable materials as feedstock to produce new basic materials and finished products, and that establish the equitable treatment of recycled materials; (6) research and development of new technologies to more efficiently and effectively recycle materials, such as automobile shredder residue and cathode ray tubes, and of new technologies to remove materials that are impediments to recycling, such as radioactive material, polychlorinated biphenyls, mercury-containing devices, and chlorofluorocarbons; (7) Design for Recycling to ensure that a good can be recycled safely and economically at the end of its useful life; and (8) the participation of U.S. households, businesses, and governmental entities in recycling programs. Recognizes that the U.S. scrap recycling industry is critical to the future of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
