<bill session="110" type="h" number="1639" updated="2013-07-19T21:18:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that no entity performing lead system integrator functions in the acquisition of a major system by the Department of Homeland Security may have any direct financial interest in the development or construction of any individual system or element of any system of systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412234"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Management, Investigations, and Oversight.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-25">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.2206.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM09" subcommittee="Management, Investigations, and Oversight" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2206"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2007--Introduced.
Prohibits any entity performing lead system integrator functions in the acquisition of a major system by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) from having any direct financial interest in the development or construction of any individual system or element of any system of systems with respect to contracts entered into after May 1, 2007. Makes exceptions if: (1) the Secretary of Homeland Security certifies that an entity was selected by DHS as a contractor through competitive procedures and DHS took appropriate steps to prevent any organizational conflict of interest in the selection process; (2) an entity was selected by a subcontractor to serve as a lower-tier subcontractor through a process over which the entity exercised no control; or (3) the work to be performed is work necessary to integrate two or more individual systems or elements.Directs the Secretary, by May 1, 2007, to update DHS's acquisition regulations to: (1) specify the matters regarding lead system integrators set forth in this Act; and (2) include a definition of "lead system integrator" modeled after that used by the Department of Defense (DOD) and a specification of appropriate types of contracts and fee structures for use by integrators in the production, fielding, and sustainment of complex systems.</summary>
</bill>
