<bill session="111" type="s" number="3742" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Data Security and Breach Notification Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect consumers by requiring reasonable security policies and procedures to protect data containing personal information, and to provide for nationwide notice in the event of a security breach.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2010-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation Subcommittee on Consumer Protection, Product Safety, and Insurance . Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-1040.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSCM20" subcommittee="Consumer Protection, Product Safety, and Insurance" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2221"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Data Security and Breach Notification Act of 2010 - Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate regulations requiring each covered entity (proprietorships, partnerships, estates, trusts, cooperatives, and nonprofit and for-profit corporations) engaged in interstate commerce owning or possessing data containing personal information to establish specified security policies and procedures to treat and protect such information. Requires the regulations to include methods for disposing of both electronic and nonelectronic data. Requires information brokers to submit their security policies to the FTC in conjunction with a notification of a security breach notification or on FTC request. Authorizes the FTC to conduct information security practices audits of brokers or require brokers to conduct independent audits. Requires information brokers to: (1) establish procedures to verify the accuracy of information that identifies individuals; (2) provide to individuals whose personal information it maintains a means to review it; (3) place a conspicuous notice on the Internet instructing individuals how to request access to such information; and (4) correct inaccurate information. Directs the FTC to require information brokers to establish measures which facilitate the auditing or retracing of access to, or transmissions of, any data containing personal information. Makes it unlawful for information brokers to obtain or disclose personal information by false pretenses (pretexting). Requires a covered entity to notify the FTC and affected individuals of information security breaches. Sets forth requirements concerning such notification, including method of notification requirements and timeliness requirements. Allows an exemption from notification requirements if the covered entity determines that there is no reasonable risk of identity theft, fraud, or other unlawful conduct. Preempts state information security laws.</summary>
</bill>
