<bill session="113" type="s" number="147" updated="2013-11-02T06:53:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Common Sense Concealed Firearms Permit Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish minimum standards for States that allow the carrying of concealed firearms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="21"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2013--Introduced.
Common Sense Concealed Firearms Permit Act of 2013 - Amends the federal criminal code to direct each state that allows its residents to carry concealed firearms to establish a process through which a resident must obtain a permit to carry a concealed firearm. Requires a state to: (1) ensure that a local law enforcement agency participates in the process; and (2) require that an applicant be a legal resident of the United States, be not less than 21 years of age, demonstrate good cause for requesting the permit, and demonstrate that he or she is worthy of the public trust to carry a concealed firearm in public. Requires any such process that allows an agency other than a law enforcement agency to issue such permits to require: (1) a local law enforcement agency to submit to the agency responsible a written report that describes whether the applicant meets the state's standards to carry a concealed firearm, and (2) the agency responsible to maintain such report in the applicant's file.</summary>
</bill>
