<bill session="109" type="h" number="1223" updated="2013-07-19T19:15:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Our Children from Violence Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that appropriate State social services officers have the authority to access certain Federal databases for the purpose of carrying out checks in cases of child abuse and neglect and cases of missing children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400136"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2005-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2005-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Missing children"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2005--Introduced.
Protecting Our Children from Violence Act of 2005 - Directs the Attorney General, upon request of the chief executive of a State, to ensure that a covered State social services officer has the authority for online access to the Federal Bureau of Investigation's National Crime Information Center (NCIC) databases and the Interstate Identification Index to carry out criminal history records checks. Limits such authority to a check of an individual who: (1) resided with a minor at the time of an actual or alleged incident of abuse or neglect of that minor, or at the time during which such an incident may have occurred; or (2) is the subject of an investigation relating to an incident of abuse or neglect of a minor. Requires the Attorney General to ensure that such an officer has the authority for "read only" electronic access to the NCIC databases for the purpose of carrying out checks of records relating to missing persons or warrants. Directs such officer to use access only for an investigation relating to a missing child and to share any information obtained with appropriate Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies. Directs the Attorney General to ensure that the Case Analysis Division, the Missing Children's Division, and the Exploited Child Unit of the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children each have access to the Index, subject to specified limitations. Limits the release of information. Sets criminal penalties for knowingly releasing information in violation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
