<bill session="110" type="s" number="3739" updated="2013-07-19T22:54:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Derivatives and Hedge Fund Regulatory Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to address the regulation of derivatives and unregistered hedge funds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300037"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2008-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-12-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Bank fraud"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Commodity exchanges"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Derivative securities"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2008--Introduced.
Derivatives and Hedge Fund Regulatory Improvement Act of 2008 - Directs the appropriate federal banking agencies, with respect to the entities under their respective jurisdictions that engage in transactions involving unregistered hedge funds or over-the-counter derivatives, to initiate a coordinated rulemaking to: (1) extend to unregistered hedge funds the requirements governing the safety and soundness of the financial system applicable to mutual funds; (2) provide for the regulation of over-the-counter derivatives that are not traded on a national securities exchange or by a registered securities association (including credit default swaps, interest rate swaps, currency swaps, mortgage-backed securities, asset-backed securities, and collateralized debt obligations); and (3) prohibit insured depository institutions from trading derivatives for their own accounts. Requires the appropriate federal banking agencies and the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to promulgate rules designed to: (1) avoid systemic risks to the financial markets; (2) ensure safe and sound operation of banks, including mandatory maintenance of sufficient capital levels and limits on aggregate leverage, and restrictions on buying, selling, or entering into derivatives by an insured depository institution for its own account; and (3) provide means to prevent fraudulent, deceptive, or manipulative practices.</summary>
</bill>
