<bill session="110" type="s" number="111" updated="2013-07-19T22:21:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to recognize the United States Military Cancer Institute as an establishment within the Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences, to require the Institute to promote the health of members of the Armed Forces and their dependents by enhancing cancer research and treatment, to provide for a study of the epidemiological causes of cancer among various ethnic groups for cancer prevention and early detection efforts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S115"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S115" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Carcinogens"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Establishes in the Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences the United States Military Cancer Institute, headed by a Director, to carry out research studies on: (1) the epidemiological features of cancer among populations of various ethnic origins, as well as complementary research on oncologic nursing; (2) the prevention and early detection of cancer; and (3) basic, translational, and clinical investigation matters relating to such studies. Directs the Institute to conduct the study in collaboration with other cancer research organizations and entities selected by the Institute.</summary>
</bill>
