<bill session="112" type="s" number="2064" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Freedom and Economic Prosperity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to terminate certain energy tax subsidies and lower the corporate income tax rate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2012-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2012-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-02-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="309">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 309.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3308"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2012--Introduced.
Energy Freedom and Economic Prosperity Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal: (1) the excise tax credits for alcohol fuel, biodiesel, and alternative fuel mixtures; (2) the tax credits for the purchase of certain plug-in electric vehicles and alternative motor vehicles; (3) the alternative fuel vehicle refueling property tax credit; (4) the tax credits for alcohol used as fuel and for biodiesel and renewable diesel used as fuel; (5) the enhanced oil recovery tax credit and the tax credit for producing oil and gas from marginal wells; (6) the tax credit for carbon dioxide sequestration; (7) the energy tax credit; and (8) the tax credits for investment in qualifying advanced coal projects and qualifying gasification projects. Terminates after 2012 the tax credits for the production of electricity from certain renewable resources and from advanced nuclear power facilities. Repeals the grant program under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 for payments to invest in alternative and renewable energy property in lieu of tax credits. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to reduce the corporate income tax rates by prescribing proportionate modifications to such rates based upon revenue savings resulting from the repeal of energy tax expenditures by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
