<bill session="111" type="s" number="3672" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coordination of Wind and Flood Perils Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to clarify and improve the payment of multiperil insurance claims, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400432"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2010--Introduced.
Coordination of Wind and Flood Perils Act of 2010 - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to direct the Administrator of Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and any insurer (including a state-run windpool), in the event of loss resulting from physical damage to real property or personal property arising from the combined perils of flood and wind, to enter into good faith negotiations regarding: (1) payment and adjustment of proven claims for multiperil losses; and (2) the allocation of such payments among the insurer, the Administrator, and the insured. Directs the Administrator to pay 50% percent of the disputed claim until it can be settled, if the Administrator and the insurer cannot agree as to the specific distribution of perils that resulted in a loss. Requires such good faith negotiations to require that: (1) in order to fully compensate the insured for losses as soon as practicable, the insurer against wind peril shall pay 50% of any disputed claim until the claim can be settled; and (2) if an insurer against wind peril and the Administrator fail to agree regarding multiperil losses, then each shall agree to have any dispute resolved by the arbitration panel established under this Act. Directs the Administrator to establish an arbitration panel to resolve disputes relating to multiperil losses between the Administrator and an insurer against wind peril.</summary>
</bill>
