<bill session="111" type="h" number="466" updated="2013-07-19T23:16:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-08T15:43:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-06-08T15:43:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wounded Veteran Job Security Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Wounded Veteran Job Security Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Wounded Veteran Job Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to prohibit discrimination and acts of reprisal against persons who receive treatment for illnesses, injuries, and disabilities incurred in or aggravated by service in the uniformed services.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for certain rights and benefits for persons who are absent from positions of employment to receive medical treatment for service-connected disabilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2009-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="2009-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2009-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400302" joined="2009-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19T15:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 111-118.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-05-19T15:02:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="61">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 61.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Filner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6287-6289" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 466.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-06-08T15:43:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6287" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1607"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2009--Passed House amended.
Wounded Veteran Job Security Act - Entitles a person who is absent from employment by reason of the receipt of medical treatment for a service-connected disability (absent employee) to: (1) be retained by the person's employer; (2) the seniority and other rights and benefits determined by seniority that the person had on the commencement of such treatment plus the additional seniority and rights and benefits that the person would have attained if the person had remained continuously employed; and (3) be considered on furlough or leave of absence during such treatment and therefore entitled to other rights and benefits not determined by seniority as are other persons of similar seniority, status, and pay who are on furlough or leave of absence. Terminates such entitlement when a person knowingly provides written notice of the intent not to return to such position following treatment. Allows the absent employee to use any vacation, annual, medical, or similar leave with pay accrued before the commencement of the treatment. Provides that an employer shall not be required to comply with the requirements of this Act if: (1) the employer's circumstances have so changed as to make such compliance impossible or unreasonable; (2) such compliance would pose an undue hardship on the employer; or (3) the employment in question is for a brief, nonrecurring period without a reasonable expectation of continuing indefinitely or for a significant period. Applies health insurance continuation requirements to absences from employment described in this Act. Prohibits any employer discrimination or acts of reprisal against an absent employee.</summary>
</bill>
