<bill session="109" type="s" number="2616" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act Amendments of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 and the Mineral Leasing Act to improve surface mining control and reclamation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300085"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2006-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300004" joined="2006-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2006-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="2006-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2006-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2006-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2006-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2006-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="2006-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="2006-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2006-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2006-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="2006-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/2006--Introduced.
Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act Amendments of 2006 - Amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to set forth a general limitation upon the obligation authority of the Secretary of the Interior with respect to the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund (Fund). Reduces the reclamation fee for coal mining operations. Revises guidelines governing transfers of interests to: (1) the United Mine Workers of America Combined Benefit Fund; (2) the United Mine Workers of America 1992 Benefit Plan; and (3) the Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan established after July 20, 1992. Revises statutory objectives of the Fund, including the development of publicly owned land adversely affected by coal mining practices. Removes the date qualification restricting liens for reclamation expenses against property owners not involved in mining operations necessitating reclamation. Revises certification procedures made by the Secretary on behalf of certain states or Indian tribes. Sets forth remining incentives. Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to modify requirements for disposition of moneys received from sales, bonuses, and royalties collected under the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982. Amends the Internal Revenue Code (with respect to liability of assigned signatories to coal wage agreements) to: (1) prescribe guidelines under which certain related persons and successors in interest are relieved of liability if health or death benefits or unassigned beneficiaries premiums are prepaid; and (2) modify guidelines governing federal transfers under mining laws and the board of trustees of the Combined Fund.</summary>
</bill>
