<bill session="109" type="h" number="5439" updated="2013-07-19T19:52:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Orphan Works Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 17, United States Code, to provide for limitation of remedies in cases in which the copyright owner cannot be located, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2006--Introduced.
Orphan Works Act of 2006 - Limits the remedies available in a copyright infringement action if the infringer proves that: (1) the infringer performed and documented a reasonably diligent search in good faith to locate the copyright owner before using the work, but was unable to locate the owner; and (2) the infringing use of the work provided attribution to the author and owner of the copyright, if known. Requires the Register of Copyrights to make information available from authoritative sources to assist users in conducting and documenting a reasonably diligent search. Permits an award of reasonable compensation for the use of the infringed work, except if: (1) the infringement is performed without any commercial advantage and for primarily a charitable, religious, scholarly, or educational purpose; and (2) the infringer ceases the infringement expeditiously after receiving notice of the claim for infringement. Allows the court to impose injunctive relief to prevent or restrain the infringing use, but such relief shall account for harm caused to the infringer due to reliance on having performed a reasonably diligent search. Prohibits the court from imposing injunctive relief that restrains the continued preparation or use of a new work that recasts, transforms, adapts, or integrates the infringed work with the infringer's original expression in a new work of authorship if the infringer pays reasonable compensation and provides attribution to the copyright owner. Requires the Register of Copyrights to conduct an inquiry with respect to remedies for copyright infringement claims seeking limited amounts of monetary relief, including consideration of alternatives to disputes currently heard in the U.S. district courts.</summary>
</bill>
