<bill session="110" type="h" number="2568" updated="2013-07-19T21:26:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Credit Agencies Identity Theft Responsibilities Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to establish additional reporting requirements to enhance the detection of identity theft, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2007-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2007-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2007--Introduced.
Credit Agencies Identity Theft Responsibilities Act of 2007 - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require a consumer reporting agency which has reason to suspect identity theft to: (1) report such suspicion to the U.S. Secret Service; and (2) inform the Attorney General for criminal prosecution. Requires the Secret Service to forward such information to either the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) or the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), respectively, if it has reason to believe that a suspected case of identity theft involves any suspicion of terrorism or immigration violations. Cites factors for suspicion of identity theft. Requires a consumer reporting agency to review, at regular intervals, all information on consumers it maintains or controls in order to determine whether there is any basis for suspicion of identity theft. Sets forth criminal penalties for agency failure to comply with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
