<bill session="109" type="h" number="711" updated="2013-07-19T19:10:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand the powers of the Attorney General to regulate the manufacture, distribution, and sale of firearms and ammunition, and to expand the jurisdiction of the Attorney General to include firearm products and nonpowder firearms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400384" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2005-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Firearms injuries"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2005--Introduced.
Firearms Safety and Consumer Protection Act of 2005 - Directs the Attorney General to prescribe regulations governing the design, manufacture, and performance of, and commerce in, firearm products in order to reduce or prevent unreasonable risk of injury. Authorizes individuals to petition the Attorney General to issue or revise product regulations or to require the recall, repair, or replacement of, or the provision of refunds regarding, a firearm product. Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) take such action; (2) prohibit the manufacture, sale, or transfer of firearm products made, imported, transferred, or distributed in violation of regulations; (3) prohibit the manufacture, importation, transfer, distribution, or export of unreasonably risky firearm products; and (4) conduct inspections. Sets forth prohibitions against a manufacturer: (1) transferring, distributing, or exporting a firearm product that the manufacturer has not tested and certified as conforming to such regulations or that is not appropriately labeled; (2) producing a new type of firearm product without providing notice to the Attorney General; or (3) failing to maintain records and supply information to the Attorney General. Prohibits any person from: (1) importing or exporting a firearm product that has not been so certified; or (2) manufacturing, purchasing, or importing products before regulations take effect at a greater rate than before enactment of this Act. Sets forth provisions regarding civil and criminal penalties for violations of this Act. Authorizes: (1) injunctive enforcement and condemnation and seizure of qualified firearm products; (2) actions to restrain the manufacture or distribution of imminently hazardous products; and (3) private actions by persons aggrieved by violations of this Act or to enforce this Act. Directs the Attorney General : (1) in cooperation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, to collect and share with other appropriate agencies circumstances of death and injury associated with firearms and to conduct continuing studies and investigations of economic costs and losses resulting from firearm-related deaths and injuries; (2) maintain firearms production and sales figures for licensed manufacturers; and (3) conduct research on firearm product safety and develop safety testing methods and devices.</summary>
</bill>
