<bill session="112" type="h" number="1932" updated="2013-07-20T01:26:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Keep Our Communities Safe Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Keep Our Communities Safe Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for extensions of detention of certain aliens ordered removed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2011-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2011-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412395" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412464" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2011-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2011-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2011-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2011-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2011-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412416" joined="2011-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-07-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 17 - 14.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-18T11:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 112-255.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-10-18T11:33:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="171">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 171.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration Policy and Enforcement" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/18/2011--Reported to House amended.
Keep Our Communities Safe Act of 2011 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) to revise provisions regarding the detention and removal of aliens ordered removed. Begins the removal period on the latest of: (1) the date the removal order becomes administratively final; (2) the date the alien is taken into Department of Homeland Security (DHS) custody if the alien is not in DHS custody on the date the removal order becomes administratively final; or (3) if the alien is detained or confined (except under an immigration process) on the date the removal order becomes administratively final, the date the alien is taken into DHS custody after the alien is released from detention or confinement. Extends the removal (and detention) period beyond 90 days if: (1) the alien fails or refuses to comply with the removal order or to fully cooperate with DHS efforts to establish the alien's identity and carry out the removal order; (2) a court, the Board of Immigration Appeals, or an immigration judge orders a stay of removal of an alien who is subject to a final removal order; or (3) DHS transfers custody of the alien to another federal agency or to a state or local agency. Begins a new removal period in the case of such an extended removal on the date: (1) the alien makes all reasonable efforts to comply with the removal order or to fully cooperate with DHS efforts to establish the alien's identity and carry out the removal order, (2) the stay of removal is no longer in effect, or (3) the alien is returned to DHS custody. Authorizes DHS to detain indefinitely, subject to six-month review, an alien under removal order who cannot be removed if: (1) the alien will be removed in the reasonably foreseeable future; (2) the alien would have been removed but for the alien's refusal to cooperate with DHS identification and removal efforts; (3) the alien has a highly contagious disease that poses a public safety threat; (4) release would have serious adverse foreign policy consequences or would threaten national security; (5) release would threaten the safety of the community or any person and the alien has been convicted of either one or more aggravated felonies or crimes of violence and, because of a mental or personality condition, is likely to engage in future acts of violence; or (6) release would threaten the safety of the community or any person and the alien has been convicted of one or more aggravated felonies. Authorizes unlimited detention of certain aliens during removal proceedings. States that habeas corpus review of such detention and related actions or decisions shall be available only in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia after exhaustion of administrative remedies. Subjects a criminal alien to mandatory DHS detention upon release without regard to whether the alien's release is related to: (1) certain activities, offenses, or convictions under INA; (2) whether the alien is released on parole, supervised release, or probation; or (3) whether the alien may be arrested or imprisoned again for the same offense. Limits the Attorney General's (DOJ) review of DHS custody determinations to whether the alien may be detained, released with no bond, or released on bond of at least $1,500. Limits the Attorney General's review of DHS custody determinations for an alien in certain categories to whether the alien was properly included in such category. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) this Act should ensure that constitutional rights are protected, and (2) it is the intention of Congress to uphold the constitutional principles of due process and that due process is a right of everyone in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
