<bill session="109" type="s" number="314" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fairness in Bankruptcy Litigation Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect consumers, creditors, workers, pensioners, shareholders, and small businesses, by reforming the rules governing venue in bankruptcy cases to combat forum shopping by corporate debtors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2005-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2005-02-14" withdrawn="2005-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1125-1129"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy courts"/>
    <term name="Change of venue"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate management"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2005--Introduced.
Fairness in Bankruptcy Litigation Act of 2005 - Amends the Federal judicial code to establish that domicile and residence of a debtor, for purposes of establishing venue in bankruptcy cases on the basis of domicile and residence, is located where the debtor's principal place of business is located. Provides that venue also lies in the district in which such a case concerning the controlling corporation is pending: (1) if the debtor is controlled by another corporation, the financial statements of the debtor have been consolidated with those of the controlling corporation within a specified period of time before filing for bankruptcy, and the controlling corporation is a debtor in bankruptcy proceedings; or (2) if the debtor is not such a corporation, the debtor has been controlled by another corporation for a specified time period before filing, and the controlling corporation is a debtor in bankruptcy proceedings. Adds bankruptcy courts to the list of district courts required to dismiss or transfer cases laying venue in the wrong division or district.</summary>
</bill>
