<bill session="111" type="h" number="4643" updated="2013-07-19T23:54:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Transportation Safety Program Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 53 of title 49, United States Code, to establish a public transportation safety program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2010-02-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-02-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E193-194"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3015"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3015"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/22/2010--Introduced.
Public Transportation Safety Program Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish a federal public transportation safety program to improve the safety of, and reduce the number of accidents involving, rail fixed guideway public transportation systems and public transportation bus systems that receive federal assistance. Requires the Secretary to promulgate regulations to establish a federal certification program for employees and contractors who carry out state public transportation safety program activities in compliance with this Act. Delineates requirements for state preemption of federal law with respect to public transportation safety. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out certain public transportation safety program activities, including inspection and testing of public transportation systems and accident prevention and investigation. Allows a state to establish a state public transportation safety program that complies with federal regulations and policies issued by the Secretary. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants or enter into agreements to carry out such state programs, including to: (1) train employees to administer the program; and (2) enforce federal and state public transportation safety laws and regulations. Grants the Secretary enforcement authority for violations of public transportation safety, including alcohol and controlled substances testing. Authorizes the Secretary immediately, without regard to ordinary administrative procedure, to order restrictions and prohibitions to abate an emergency situation.</summary>
</bill>
