<bill session="111" type="h" number="4476" updated="2013-07-19T23:52:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Equity in Government Compensation Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To suspend the current compensation packages for the senior executives of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac and establish compensation for such positions in accordance with rates of pay for senior employees in the Executive Branch of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2010-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2010-01-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/20/2010--Introduced.
Equity in Government Compensation Act of 2010 - Requires the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency to: (1) suspend immediately the compensation packages approved for 2010 for the executive officers of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac); and (2) establish, in lieu of such packages, a compensation system for such officers in accordance with the rates of pay for positions in the Executive Schedule and the Senior Executive Service of the federal government. Expresses the sense of Congress that each executive officer of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac should return to the Secretary of the Treasury (clawback) any compensation earned in 2009 that was in excess of the maximum annual rate of basic pay authorized for a position in level I of the Executive Schedule. Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer any such amounts returned to the Secretary to a specified account in the Treasury for receiving gifts and proceeds from their sale or redemption, and dedicated to reducing the public debt.</summary>
</bill>
