<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1001" updated="2013-07-19T20:59:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-27T12:51:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-02-27T12:51:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5351) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax incentives for the production of renewable energy and energy conservation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400663"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-26T17:58:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-530, by Ms. Matsui.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-26T17:58:00-05:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. An amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the Congressional Record pursuant to clause 8 of rule XVIII, if offered by Representative McCrery of Louisiana or his designee, which shall be in order without intervention of any point of order</text>
      <reference ref="except those arising under clause 7"/>
      <reference ref="of rule XVI"/>
      <reference ref="clause 9"/>
      <reference ref="of rule XXI"/>
      <reference ref="or clause 10"/>
      <reference ref="of rule XXI"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-02-26T17:58:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="191">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 191.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27T10:11:00-05:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Ms. Matsui called up H. Res. 1001, and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27T10:28:00-05:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Conaway raised a point of order against the provisions of H. Res. 1001 because it violates the Congressional Budget Act. The Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H. Res. 1001. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27T11:07:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to consider the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 186 (Roll no. 78).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1079-1082" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27T11:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1082" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27T11:08:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1001.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27T12:14:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1001, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lincoln Diaz-Balart demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27T12:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1090-1091" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27T12:45:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 214 - 189 (Roll no. 80).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1090" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-02-27T12:51:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="81" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 188 (Roll no. 81).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1079" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27T12:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hr" number="983"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hr" number="983"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="110" type="h" number="5351"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2008--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 5351 (Renewable Energy and Energy Conservation Tax Act of 2008).</summary>
</bill>
