<bill session="110" type="h" number="2913" updated="2013-07-19T21:29:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pollinator Habitat Protection Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the administrative requirements for conservation programs administered by the Department of Agriculture to ensure a greater emphasis on increasing habitat for native and managed pollinators and establishing cropping systems, integrated pest management regimes, and other practices to protect native and managed pollinators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400642" joined="2007-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1459"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Horticulture and Organic Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Horticulture and Organic Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Bees"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Integrated pest management"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2007--Introduced.
Pollinator Habitat Protection Act of 2007 - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to require that conservation programs, except the farmland protection program, establish a priority and provide incentives for: (1) increasing habitat for native and managed pollinators; and (2) establishing cropping systems, integrated pest management regimes, and other practices to protect native and managed pollinators. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Agriculture should: (1) designate pollinator protection as a national priority resource concern for conservation programs administered by the Department of Agriculture; and (2) continue efforts to make nurseries and land managers aware of pollinator-friendly plants.</summary>
</bill>
