<bill session="109" type="hr" number="1026" updated="2013-07-19T19:03:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">For the re-opening of investigative hearings into the Counter-Intelligence Program (COINTELPRO) and other intelligence and law enforcement programs and agencies, and an expansion of those hearings to include reneweal of previously curtailed abuses, and other activities sanctioned by the USA PATRIOT ACT.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400513"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Official secrets"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2006--Introduced.
Declares that Congress will release classified documents that do not involve compromise of an existing source, agent, or method and will renew and administer hearings or form a select oversight committee to: (1) investigate past abuses and legal relief due to the victims of abuses carried out under COINTELPRO (the Counter Intelligence Program carried out by the Federal Bureau of Investigation [FBI]) and related programs; and (2) identify any renewal of similar abuses following the 9/11 attacks by federal or local agencies or executive branch orders or under the USA PATRIOT Act. Expresses the intent to renew legislation that will end such abuses and fully protect the rights of all U.S. citizens and others who fall under the protection of U.S. laws and international laws and treaties to which the United States is a signatory.</summary>
</bill>
