<bill session="112" type="h" number="4118" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Procurement Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to provide for increased small business participation in multiple award contracts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412498" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412432" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="2012-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21T16:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 112-726, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21T16:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Oversight and Government discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-12-21T16:25:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="529">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 529.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2012--Introduced.
Small Business Procurement Improvement Act of 2012 - Amends the Small Business Act to require (under current law, permit) federal agencies involved in procurement, to the maximum extent practicable, to include small businesses in multiple award contracts. Requires such agencies to make full use of the contract set-aside programs of the Small Business Administration (SBA). Directs the SBA Administrator, in consultation with the Administrator of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy (OFPP) and any agency that obtains 5% of its procurement requirements through a multiple award contract, to carry out a program to increase small business participation in such contracts. Requires the President to annually establish government-wide goals for the total value of all task and delivery orders placed against multiple award contracts, blanket purchase agreements, and basic ordering agreements awarded to small businesses, small businesses owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, qualified HUBZone small businesses, small businesses owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, and small businesses owned and controlled by women. Requires each federal contract for the purchase of goods and services with an anticipated value greater than $2,500 but not greater than $200,000 (under current law, $100,000) to be reserved exclusively for small businesses (with an exception). Directs the Administrator to issue regulations concerning General Services Administration (GSA) oversight of task or delivery orders placed against multiple award contracts. Requires: (1) inclusion of the Administrator on the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council, and (2) the OFPP Administrator to have the deciding vote in case of a tie vote among Council membership.</summary>
</bill>
