<bill session="109" type="h" number="4876" updated="2013-07-19T19:47:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-27T23:38:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-27T23:38:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ratify a conveyance of a portion of the Jicarilla Apache Reservation to Rio Arriba County, State of New Mexico, pursuant to the settlement of litigation between the Jicarilla Apache Nation and Rio Arriba County, State of New Mexico, to authorize issuance of a patent for said lands, and to change the exterior boundary of the Jicarilla Apache Reservation accordingly, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400434" joined="2006-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E269"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-07">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gohmert moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7662-7663" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4876.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-09-27T23:38:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7662" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2006--Passed House without amendment.
States that the ratification and approval of the Jicarilla Apache Nation's deed for specified settlement lands and the issuance of a patent pursuant to this Act shall not take effect until the Secretary of the Interior finds the following events have occurred: (1) the Board of Commissioners of the Rio Arriba County, New Mexico, has enacted a resolution permanently abandoning a specified disputed county road and has submitted a copy of that resolution to the Secretary; and (2) the Jicarilla Apache Nation has executed a quitclaim deed to Rio Arriba County for specified settlement lands subject to the exceptions identified in the Settlement Agreement and has submitted a copy of such deed to the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to publish such findings in the Federal Register. Ratifies and approves the Jicarilla Apache Nation's quitclaim deed for the settlement lands to the County, but such ratification and approval shall be effective only upon satisfaction of all conditions specified above and only as of the date that the Secretary's findings are published in the Federal Register. Requires the Secretary to issue to the County a patent for the settlement lands. Subjects the patent to all valid existing rights of third parties, including but not limited to easements of record. Requires that the patent include a specified perpetual restrictive covenant running with the Settlement Lands for the benefit of the lands comprising the Jicarilla Apache Reservation adjacent to the Settlement Lands. Provides that the lands conveyed to the County in such patent shall cease to be a part of the Jicarilla Apache Reservation and the exterior boundary of the Reservation shall be deemed relocated accordingly.</summary>
</bill>
