<bill session="110" type="h" number="7234" updated="2013-07-19T22:06:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Integrated Risk Information System Authorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase research, the synthesis of research findings, and the production of scientific information on chemicals, and to expedite the listing of information in the Integrated Risk Information System maintained by the Office of Research and Development of the Environmental Protection Agency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400280"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2008--Introduced.
Integrated Risk Information System Authorization Act - Requires the Assistant Administrator for the Office of Research and Development of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to maintain a publicly accessible database of scientific information on the toxicity of chemicals, including hazard identification, dose response assessments, reference doses, and other information that would facilitate the development of risk assessments.Requires the Assistant Administrator to: (1) publish final assessments for at least 15 new chemicals per year and at least five updates to existing assessments per year; (2) solicit nominations for chemical assessments; (3) issue a list of chemicals proposed for assessment two years prior to initiation of the assessment, which shall be made available on the database within four years of its appearance on such list; (4) determine the information to be used to assess chemicals and establish a process for reviewing chemical assessments prior to their inclusion on the database; (5) ensure that federal agencies with real or perceived conflicts of interests do not participate in the development or internal review of chemical assessments; and (6) finalize and publish within six months chemical assessments that have been in development for Integrated Risk Information System entries prior to this Act's enactment. Declares that such list is not subject to review or approval by other federal agencies or officials. Requires the Assistant Administrator to develop and review chemical assessments without review by the President and to publish final assessments without prior review by the President or other federal agencies or officials. Prohibits the preparation and review of chemical assessments from being subject to the provisions of Bulletin No. 07-02, Final Bulletin for Agency Good Guidance Practices, and the Final Information Quality Bulletin for Peer Review of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB).</summary>
</bill>
