<bill session="113" type="s" number="822" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for All Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Effective Administration of Criminal Justice Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect crime victims' rights, to eliminate the substantial backlog of DNA samples collected from crime scenes and convicted offenders, to improve and expand the DNA testing capacity of Federal, State, and local crime laboratories, to increase research and development of new DNA testing technologies, to develop new training programs regarding the collection and use of DNA evidence, to provide post conviction testing of DNA evidence to exonerate the innocent, to improve the performance of counsel in State capital cases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2013-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3033-3034"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3034-3036" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="597"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2013--Introduced.
Justice for All Reauthorization Act of 2013 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) grant crime victims the right to be informed of their rights and of services available to them, (2) expand eligibility for post-conviction DNA testing in criminal proceedings other than death penalty cases, and (3) eliminate the waiver of the right to request DNA testing of biological evidence. Amends the Justice for All Act of 2004 to extend through FY2018 the authorization of appropriations for grant programs for: the enforcement of crime victims' rights; DNA training and education for law enforcement officers; sexual assault forensic exams; DNA research and development; DNA programs of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); identification of missing persons; improving the quality of legal representation for indigent defendants in capital cases; providing incentives to states to establish a reasonable process for resolving claims of actual innocence; and the Kirk Bloodsworth Post-Conviction DNA Testing Grant Program to help states defray the costs of post-conviction DNA testing. Amends the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 to extend through FY2018 grants for notification to crime victims of dates and developments in criminal proceedings. Amends the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 to extend the authorization of appropriations through FY2018 for the Debbie Smith DNA Backlog Grant Program.. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to: (1) extend (until three years after enactment of this Act) the period for compliance by governmental entities with requirements for payment of the full cost of forensic medical exams for victims of sexual assault, and (2) extend (through FY2018) the authorization of appropriations for the Paul Coverdell forensic sciences improvement grant program. Requires the Director of the National Institute of Justice to: (1) establish best practices for evidence retention to focus on the preservation of biological evidence; and (2) assist state, local, and tribal governments in adopting and implementing such best practices. Effective Administration of Criminal Justice Act of 2013 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to require grant applicants under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program to include in grant applications a comprehensive state-wide plan for the improvement of the administration of the criminal justice system. Makes all grants awarded by the Department of Justice (DOJ) under this Act subject to audits beginning in FY2014 to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse of funds by grantees.</summary>
</bill>
