<bill session="109" type="s" number="136" updated="2013-07-19T20:14:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Rancho Corral de Tierra Golden Gate National Recreation Boundary Adjustment Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Rancho Corral de Tierra Golden Gate National Recreation Area Boundary Adjustment Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Redwood National Park Boundary Adjustment Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Rancho Corral de Tierra Golden Gate National Recreation Area Boundary Adjustment Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Rancho Corral de Tierra Golden Gate National Recreation Area Boundary Adjustment Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Redwood National Park Boundary Adjustment Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Rancho Corral de Tierra Golden Gate National Recreation Area Boundary Adjustment Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Redwood National Park Boundary Adjustment Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide supplemental funding and other services that are necessary to assist certain local school districts in the State of California in providing education services for students attending schools located within Yosemite National Park, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to adjust the boundaries of the Golden Gate National Recreation Area.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide supplemental funding and other services that are necessary to assist certain local school districts in the State of California in providing educational services for students attending schools located within Yosemite National Park, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to adjust the boundaries of the Golden Gate National Recreation Area, to adjust the boundaries of Redwood National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S349-350"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S350-351" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-02-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with amendments. With written report No. 109-63.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-04-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="95">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 95.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9018-9052" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9049-9050" label="text of  measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2005-07-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9018-9052" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9049-9051" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T14:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Radanovich moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T14:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11049-11051" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T14:50:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 136.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-12-06T15:01:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11049-11050" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T15:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-12-06">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2005-12-12">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-12-20">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-12-20" type="public" number="109-131">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-131.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Education Reform" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="353"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="353"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Impact aid"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1589"/>
    <amendment number="s1590"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/20/2005--Public Law.
Title I: Yosemite National Park Authorized Payments - (Sec. 101) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to provide funds for FY2006-FY2009 to the Bass Lake Joint Union Elementary School District and the Mariposa Unified School District in California for educational services for students who: (1) are dependents of persons engaged in the administration, operation, and maintenance of Yosemite National Park; or (2) live within or near the Park upon Federal property. Terminates the Secretary's authority to make such payments if the State of California or local education agencies do not continue to provide funding to the schools in those school districts at per student levels that at least equal to the amount provided in FY2005. Sets forth limitations on the use and amount of such funds, including a maximum limit of $400,000 on payments in any fiscal year. Prohibits the use of funds to make payments under this Act from the following sources: (1) any law authorizing the collection or expenditure of entrance or use fees at units of the National Park System; (2) any unexpended receipts collected through the recreational fee demonstration program or the national park passport program; and (3) emergency appropriations for Yosemite flood recovery. Allows the Secretary to use an authorized funding source to make payments only if the funding available to Yosemite National Park from such source (after subtracting any payments to the school districts) is greater than or equal to the amount made available to the Park for the prior fiscal year, or in FY2005, whichever is greater. (Sec. 102) Amends the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 to allow certain facilities to be located outside the boundaries of Yosemite National Park. Title II: Rancho Corral De Tierra Golden Gate National Recreation Area Boundary Adjustment - Rancho Corral de Tierra Golden Gate National Recreation Area Boundary Adjustment Act - (Sec. 202) Modifies the boundaries of the Golden Gate National Recreation Area in California to include specified additional lands. Allows the Secretary of the Interior to acquire certain of those lands only from a willing seller. Title III: Redwood National Park Boundary Adjustment - Redwood National Park Boundary Adjustment Act of 2005 - (Sec. 302) Revises the boundaries of the Redwood National Park in California. Requires that the map of the revised boundaries be placed on file and be available for public inspection in offices of the National Park Service and that such map be provided by the Secretary of the Interior to officers of Del Norte and Humboldt Counties, California. Increases to 133,000 acres the maximum acreage of the Park.</summary>
</bill>
