<bill session="111" type="s" number="3963" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Development, Relief, and Education for Alien Minors Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">DREAM Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the cancellation of removal and adjustment of status of certain alien students who are long-term United States residents and who entered the United States as children and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2010-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7976-7978" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-11-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="645">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 645.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1751"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6327"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6497"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="729"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3827"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3962"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3962"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3992"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2010--Introduced.
Development, Relief, and Education for Alien Minors Act of 2010 or DREAM Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to cancel the removal of, and adjust to conditional permanent resident status, an alien who: (1) entered the United States before his or her 16th birthday and has been present in the United States for at least five years immediately preceding this Act's enactment; (2) is a person of good moral character; (3) is not inadmissible or deportable under specified grounds of the Immigration and Nationality Act; (4) has been admitted to an institution of higher education (IHE) or has earned a high school or equivalent diploma; (5) from the age of 16 and older, has never been under a final order of exclusion, deportation, or removal; and (6) was under age 30 on the date of this Act's enactment. Requires aliens to apply for such adjustment of status within one year of being admitted to an IHE or earning a high school or equivalent diploma. Sets forth conditions for maintaining such status and having its conditional basis removed. Authorizes: (1) the Secretary to adjust the status of an alien who has met such conditions prior to enactment of this Act to conditional permanent resident status; and (2) such alien to petition the Secretary for permanent resident status at the end of the conditional residence period. Provides for: (1) exclusive jurisdiction; (2) penalties for false application statements; (3) confidentiality; (4) higher education assistance; and (5) a Government Accountability Office (GAO) report respecting the number of aliens adjusted under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
