<bill session="110" type="s" number="1766" updated="2013-07-19T22:35:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Low Carbon Economy Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reduce greenhouse gas emissions from the production and use of energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-07-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9022-9023"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10775, S10776"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Emissions trading"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fluorocarbons"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sulphur"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2007--Introduced.
Low Carbon Economy Act of 2007 - Requires specified regulated entities (including certain fuel distributors and owners and operators of coal facilities or nonfuel regulated entities) to submit to the President: (1) the number of allowances or credits equal to the entity's covered greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions; or (2) a payment equal to the amount of the technology accelerator payment (TAP) price in lieu of submission of required allowances. Requires the President to establish a trading system for such allowances and credits.Requires TAP payments to be deposited into the Energy Technology Deployment Fund.Requires the Secretary of Energy to: (1) report on next generation technologies that can reduce and use methane emissions; and (2) use a portion of the Fund to carry out a methane research and development program.Provides for: (1) allowances to industry, carbon-intensive manufacturing facilities, and states; (2) agricultural sequestration allowances; (3) allowances for early reduction projects; (4) bonus allowances to entities that implement geological sequestration projects; and (5) allowances for technology, adaptation, and low-income household assistance.Provides for credits for: (1) activities that take specified GHG precursors (specified fuel, hydrofluorocarbons, perfluorocarbons, sulfur hexafluoride, or nitrous oxide) out of commerce in the United States; (2) carbon dioxide sequestration; and (3) specified offset projects.Establishes: (1) the Energy Technology Deployment Fund for the zero- or low-carbon energy technologies program, the advanced coal and sequestration technologies program, the cellulosic biomass ethanol and municipal solid waste technology deployment programs, and the advanced technology vehicles manufacturing incentive program; (2) the Climate Adaptation Fund for adaptation programs to address climate change impacts and for fish and wildlife conservation programs; and (3) the Energy Assistance Fund for the low-income home energy assistance program, the Weatherization Assistance Program for Low-Income Persons, and the rural energy assistance program. Requires the President to establish an interagency group to review comparable action by foreign countries with respect to GHG emissions and to make recommendations with respect to foreign credits and international offset projects. Authorizes the President to establish a program to distribute credits for the GHG mitigation benefits of offset projects outside the United States. Requires any U.S. importer of certain covered goods, as a condition of importation, to make a written declaration that the goods are accompanied by a sufficient number of international reserve allowances. Authorizes the President to establish a trading system of international reserve allowances for imported goods.</summary>
</bill>
