<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1203" updated="2013-07-19T23:06:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-21T18:29:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-21T18:29:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendments to the bill (H.R. 3590) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the first-time homebuyers credit in the case of members of the Armed Forces and certain other Federal employees, and for other purposes, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4872) to provide for reconciliation pursuant to section 202 of the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2010.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400378"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21T00:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-448, by Ms. Slaughter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21T00:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Also, upon adoption of this resolution, it shall be in order to debate topics addressed by the Senate amendments to H.R. 3590. After debate, it shall be in order to take from the Speaker's table, with the Senate amendments thereto, a single motion offered by the Majority Leader or his designee that the House concur in the Senate amendments to H.R. 3590. If the motion is adopted, it shall be in order to consider H.R. 4872. The amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, modified by the amendment printed in Part B of the report of the Committee on Rules, shall be considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-03-21T00:13:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="178">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 178.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21T14:11:00-04:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Ms. Slaughter called up H.Res. 1203 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Ryan (WI) raised a point of order against the provisions of H.Res. 1203 on the grounds that it violated the Congressional Budget Act. The Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H.Res. 1203. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21T15:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Will the House now consider the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 195 (Roll no. 159).</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1828" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Issa raised a point of order against the provisions of H.Res. 1203 on the grounds that it violates clause 9(b) of rule 21. The Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H.Res. 1203. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21T16:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Will the House now consider the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 230 - 200 (Roll no. 160).</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1833" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21T16:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1824-1851" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21T16:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1203.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21T18:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1852-1854" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by recorded vote: 228 - 202 (Roll no. 162).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1852-1853" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-03-21T18:29:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="163" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 206 (Roll no. 163).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1824-1825" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-21T18:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3590"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="4872"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2010--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendments to the bill (H.R. 3590) to amend the Internal Revenue Code to modify the first-time homebuyers credit in the case of members of the Armed Forces and certain other federal employees, and for other purposes, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4872) to provide for reconciliation pursuant to section 202 of the concurrent resolution on the budget for FY2010. Makes it in order to consider a single motion offered by the Majority Leader or a designee that the House concur in the Senate amendments to H.R. 3590 without intervention of any point of order except those arising under clause 10 of Rule XXI. Provides, upon adoption of the motion to concur in the Senate amendments, for a closed rule for consideration of H.R. 4872. Waives all points of order against consideration of H.R. 4872 except those arising under clause 10 of Rule XXI. Provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the Rules Committee report accompanying this resolution, modified by the amendment printed in part B of the report, shall be considered as adopted and the bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. Waives all points of order against H.R. 4872, as amended. Provides one motion to recommit the bill with or without instructions. Provides that until completion of the proceedings described above: (1) the Chair may decline to entertain any intervening motion, resolution, question, or notice, decline to entertain the question of consideration, and may postpone proceedings to a time designated by the Speaker; (2) the second sentence of clause 1(a) of Rule XIX (regarding 40 minutes of debate on questions not debated) shall not apply; and (3) any proposition admissible under the proceedings described in this resolution shall be considered as read.</summary>
</bill>
