<bill session="109" type="hc" number="459" updated="2013-07-19T20:06:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28T21:28:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-28T21:28:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for an adjournment or recess of the two Houses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28T20:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6038" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28T20:52:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Con. Res. 459, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28T21:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6039-6040" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-07-28T21:28:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="420" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 189 (Roll no. 420).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6038" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28T21:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2006--Passed House without amendment.
Provides for an adjournment of the House of Representatives from July 28 or 29, 2006, until September 6, 2006 (or until another time of reassembly under this concurrent resolution), and a recess or an adjournment of the Senate from August 3, 2006-August 7, 2006, until September 5, 2006 (or until another time of reassembly). Authorizes the Speaker of the House and the Majority Leader of the Senate, or their respective designees, acting jointly after consultation with the Minority Leaders of the House and of the Senate, to notify the Members of the House and the Senate, respectively, to reassemble at such place and time as they may designate whenever, in their opinion, the public interest shall warrant it.</summary>
</bill>
