<bill session="112" type="h" number="1528" updated="2013-07-20T01:23:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Privacy Protection Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect and enhance consumer privacy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2011-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2011-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2860-2861"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2011--Introduced.
Consumer Privacy Protection Act of 2011 - Requires any entity that collects, sells, discloses for consideration, or uses personally identifiable information of more than 5,000 consumers during any consecutive 12-month period to: (1) provide consumers notice (meeting specified requirements) before using personally identifiable information for purposes unrelated to the transaction for which it was collected or upon a material change of the entity's privacy policy; and (2) establish a privacy policy (meeting specified requirements) with respect to the collection, sale, disclosure for consideration, dissemination, use, and security of consumers' personally identifiable information. Authorizes the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to facilitate the development of harmonized, universal wording or logo-based graphics to convey the contents of privacy policy statements. Requires each such entity to: (1) provide a consumer with the opportunity to prevent for up to five years the sale or disclosure for consideration, to any covered entity that is not an information-sharing affiliate of the entity, of the consumer's personally identifiable information that may be used for a purpose other than a transaction with such consumer; (2) give notice of any additional opportunities to limit such entity's practices with respect to collection or use of personally identifiable information; and (3) implement an information security policy that is applicable to the information security practices and treatment of personally identifiable information maintained by such entity and that is designed to prevent the unauthorized disclosure or release of such information. Sets forth provisions concerning compliance with, approval of, and requirements of a self-regulatory program that provides protections for consumers and their personally identifiable information that are equal to or greater than protections provided under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
