<bill session="113" type="h" number="3209" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Boko Haram Terrorist Designation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose sanctions against persons who knowingly provide material support or resources to Boko Haram or its affiliates, associated groups, or agents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412466" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2013-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2013--Introduced.
Boko Haram Terrorist Designation Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress that Boko Haram has met the criteria for designation as a foreign terrorist organization, and the Secretary of State should so designate Boko Haram. Provides that if the Secretary does not designate Boko Haram as a foreign terrorist organization within 60 days the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress that contains the reasons therefor. Directs the President, in concert with applicable Nigerian law, to subject to sanctions any person in the United States or subject to U.S. jurisdiction who knowingly provides material support or resources to Boko Haram or its affiliates, associated groups, or agents. Prohibits the Secretary from issuing any visa to, and directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to deny U.S. entry to, any member or representative of Boko Haram or its affiliates, associated groups, or agents. Requires under certain circumstances, the removal from the United States of any alien who is a member or representative of Boko Haram or its affiliates, associated groups, or agents. Requires any U.S. financial institution that knowingly has possession of or control over funds in which Boko Haram or its affiliates, associated groups, or agents have an interest to: (1) retain possession of or control over the funds, and (2) report the funds to the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury.</summary>
</bill>
