<bill session="112" type="h" number="4041" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-30T19:47:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-05-30T19:47:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Export Promotion Reform Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Export Promotion Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to further enhance the promotion of exports of United States goods and services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2012-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-05-30T19:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Manzullo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-30T19:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3252-3256" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-30T19:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4041.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-05-30T19:47:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3252-3253" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-05-30T19:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2987"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2171"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3347"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3479"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/30/2012--Passed House amended.
Export Promotion Reform Act - Amends the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to revise the duties of the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee (TPCC). Requires the TPCC to review the proposed annual budget of each federal agency, before it is submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and the President, when (as required by current law) assessing the appropriate levels and allocation of resources among such agencies in support of export promotion and export financing. Requires the governmentwide strategic plan for federal trade promotion efforts, in conducting the review of current federal programs designed to promote the sale of U.S. exports and developing a plan to bring such activities into line with specified priorities, to take into account recommendations from a representative number of U.S. exporters, particularly small business and medium-sized businesses, and representatives of U.S. workers. Directs the President to issue an executive order and necessary regulations to provide the TPCC chairperson with the authority to ensure that the TPCC carries out each of its duties and develops and implements the strategic plan. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) conduct at least once every five years a global assessment of overseas markets to determine those with the greatest potential for increasing U.S. exports, and (2) deploy U.S. and Foreign Commercial Service personnel and other resources on the basis of that assessment. Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to require each chief of mission to a foreign country to develop an approved plan for effective diplomacy to remove or reduce obstacles to exports of U.S. goods and services. Requires the Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service to evaluate the commercial effectiveness of diplomacy to promote exports of U.S. goods and services.</summary>
</bill>
