<bill session="112" type="h" number="6363" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Credit Access and Inclusion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to clarify Federal law with respect to reporting positive consumer credit information to consumer reporting agencies by public utility companies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412462"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2012-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/2012--Introduced.
Credit Access and Inclusion Act - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act, with respect to the responsibilities of furnishers of information to consumer reporting agencies, to declare that nothing in the Act or related regulations shall be construed as to prohibit a person from furnishing to a consumer reporting agency certain consumer identifying information, including: (1) consumer's full name, telephone number, mother's maiden name, address, zip code, date of birth, any generational designation, or Social Security number; (2) transactions or experiences between the consumer and the person furnishing the information; and (3) the performance of the consumer's obligations under a real property lease, a subscription agreement, or an account of a public utility service (subject to certain limitations).</summary>
</bill>
