<bill session="110" type="h" number="6735" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">BARREL Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bolster America's Resources through Responsible Exploratory Leasing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To terminate the application of restrictions on exploration, development, and production of oil and gas in areas of the outer Continental Shelf adjacent to Cuba.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400180"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2008-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2008-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2008-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2008--Introduced.
Bolster America's Resources through Responsible Exploratory Leasing Act or the BARREL Act - Declares as having no force or effect federal prohibitions against the expenditure of appropriated funds to conduct oil and gas leasing and preleasing activities for areas of the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) of the United States adjacent to Cuba. Revokes all withdrawals of federal submerged lands of the OCS adjacent to Cuba from leasing for exploration for, and development and production of, oil and natural gas. Terminates certain restrictions under the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2008 on the use of funds for certain offshore leasing and related activities with respect to any location on the OCS adjacent to Cuba. Directs the Secretary of the Interior promptly to conduct lease sales for such locations on the OCS in accordance with the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act and other federal law.</summary>
</bill>
