<bill session="109" type="s" number="1204" updated="2013-07-19T20:23:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Getting Results for Advanced Degrees Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to encourage students to pursue graduate education and to assist students in affording graduate education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2005-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2005-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6235"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6235-6238" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="College teachers"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social sciences"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student housing"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2005--Introduced.
Getting Results for Advanced Degrees Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to revise and reauthorize provisions relating to graduate student assistance. Extends and increases the authorization of appropriations for: (1) Jacob K. Javits Fellowships (Javits Fellows); and (2) graduate assistance in areas of national need. Sets the amount of a stipend under both such programs at the same level as the National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship Program, without regard to financial need. Revises Board membership requirements under the Javits Fellows program. Establishes, and authorizes appropriations for, the Patsy T. Mink Fellowship program of awards to assist highly qualified minorities and women to acquire the doctoral degree, or highest possible degree available, in academic areas in which such individuals are underrepresented, to enable them to enter the higher education professoriate. Revises cost of attendance calculations for graduate students with one or more dependents to include actual living expenses incurred for dependents, including their room, board and health insurance (as well as, currently, dependent care). Increases unsubsidized Stafford loan limits for graduate and professional students. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to treat reasonable room, board, and special needs services allowances as part of permitted higher education expenses, in cases of qualified scholarships or of tuition reduction programs for teaching and research assistants. Amends HEA, as amended by the Taxpayer-Teacher Protection Act of 2004, to provide for further reduction of certain special allowances to lenders and holders of student loans. Directs the Secretary to use any funds made available thereby to carry out programs and activities under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
