<bill session="111" type="h" number="3999" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation to initiate consultations under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 on the Central Valley Project and the California State Water Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2009-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/2009--Introduced.
Requires the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation to initiate (and conclude within 90 days) consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce on the existing and proposed operations of the Central Valley Project and the California State Water Project, including regarding all endangered, threatened, and candidate species listed under the Endangered Species Act affected by such proposed operations. Requires the Secretaries to: (1) identify, analyze, and describe all factors, other than operations of the Projects, affecting the survival and recovery of such species and the effect of invasive species and wastewater discharges on food availability on the survival and recovery of such species; (2) quantify the relative effect of each factor affecting the survival and recovery of the subject species; (3) rank each such factor in the order of its effect on the likelihood of the survival and recovery of the species; and (4) identify the specific, additional incremental effect of existing and proposed discretionary operations of the Projects on the survival and recovery of the species in relation to all other factors affecting such survival and recovery. Requires the Secretaries: (1) to issue a statement setting forth their opinion detailing how existing and proposed operations of such Projects affect such species or their critical habitat; (2) if they include in the statement reasonable and prudent alternatives to discretionary project operations, to describe the increased species abundance they estimate will result from such alternatives and limit the measures required by the alternatives to no more than the proportionate effects of those discretionary project operations in relation to the factors affecting the species; and (3) to identity and recommend actions or measures that are not within the jurisdiction of the Bureau but are necessary to address any factors that are jeopardizing such species or adversely modifying their critical habitat. Declares that any consultation conducted or statement issued before this Act's enactment with respect to the existing and proposed operations shall have no force or effect after the statement is issued under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
