<bill session="111" type="h" number="1554" updated="2013-07-19T23:25:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-30T15:33:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-30T15:33:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fountainhead Property Land Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Fountainhead Property Land Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Fountainhead Property Land Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To take certain property in McIntosh County, Oklahoma, into trust for the benefit of the Muscogee (Creek) Nation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400645"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2010-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-06-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-513.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-06-28T15:20:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="293">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 293.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Boren moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4927-4928" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1554.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T13:26:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5232-5233" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-06-30T15:33:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="411" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 421 - 1 (Roll no. 411).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/29/2010 H4927" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30T15:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2010--Passed House amended.
Fountainhead Property Land Transfer Act - Requires, immediately after completion of a survey required by this Act, receipt of consideration and costs, and satisfaction of all terms specified by the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of the Army, the transfer of administrative jurisdiction over specified federal property in McIntosh County, Oklahoma, within the boundary of the Muscogee (Creek) Nation (the Tribe), from the Secretary of the Army to the Secretary of the Interior, who shall take such land into trust for the benefit of the Tribe. Requires the Tribe to pay: (1) to the Secretary of the Army fair market value for the property; and (2) all costs and administrative expenses associated with the transfer of administrative jurisdiction of the property and the taking of it into trust, including costs of the survey and any environmental remediation. Subjects the transfer of administrative jurisdiction of the property and the taking of it into trust to such other terms and conditions such Secretaries consider appropriate for the protection of U.S. interests, including reservation of flowage easements for the Lake Eufaula project. Prohibits the Tribe from conducting gaming activities on land taken into trust pursuant to this Act: (1) as a matter of claimed inherent authority; or (2) under any federal law, including the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act and any regulations promulgated by the Secretary or the National Indian Gaming Commission pursuant to such Act.</summary>
</bill>
