<bill session="110" type="s" number="957" updated="2013-07-19T22:28:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Amniotic Fluid and Placental Stem Cell Banking Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the collection and maintenance of amniotic fluid and placental stem cells for the treatment of patients and research.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Childbirth"/>
    <term name="Cytology"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Human embryology"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tissue banks"/>
    <term name="Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2007--Introduced.
Amniotic Fluid and Placental Stem Cell Banking Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into one-time contracts with qualified amniotic fluid and placental stem cell banks to assist in the collection and maintenance of 100,000 new units of high-quality amniotic fluid and placental stem cells to be made available for treatment though the C.W. Bill Young Cell Transplantation and Treatment Program. Sets forth provisions relating to requirements for contract recipients, the duration of such contracts, and extensions of funding under such contracts. Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise the Program to provide for amniotic fluid and placental stem cell functions, recruitment, and educational activities.Authorizes appropriations for the Program through FY2012.</summary>
</bill>
