<bill session="111" type="s" number="2764" updated="2013-07-20T00:50:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Satellite Television Extension and Localism Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Satellite Television Extension and Localism Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the Satellite Home Viewer Extension and Reuathorization Act of 2004, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-11-19">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-17">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-12-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="709">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 709.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-22">
      <text>By Senator Rockefeller from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 111-385.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3191"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3333"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/17/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Satellite Television Extension and Localism Act of 2009 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to extend until December 31, 2014 (under current law, until December 31, 2009), the authorization for a multichannel video programming distributor to retransmit the signal of a broadcasting station if the subscriber receiving the signal is outside the station's local market and resides in an unserved household. (Sec. 3) Applies provisions relating to satellite retransmissions of significantly viewed broadcast signals only to retransmissions to subscribers who receive local-into-local service. Allows a satellite carrier to retransmit in high definition (HD) the signal of a significantly viewed station only if the carrier also retransmits in HD (when available) the signal of a station located in the local market of the subscriber and affiliated with the same network. Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to promulgate a rule implementing amendments made by this Act. (Sec. 4) Allows satellite carriers to retransmit local-into-local signals in digital and HD to two separate reception antennas. Revises the rules governing: (1) the reception of distant signals by certain grandfathered and nongrandfathered subscribers; (2) reception predictive models; and (3) on-location reception testing. (Sec. 7) Requires each eligible satellite carrier providing any local-into-local HD secondary transmissions before enactment of this Act to carry the HD signals of qualified noncommercial educational television stations in that local market according to a specified time schedule. Defines "eligible satellite carrier" as any satellite carrier that does not have a carriage contract, in effect at enactment of this Act, with a qualified noncommercial educational television station that governs carriage of more than 30 such stations. (Sec. 8) Requires the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress on the changes to the carriage requirements currently imposed on multichannel video programming distributors under the Communications Act of 1934 and FCC regulations that would be required by or beneficial to consumers if Congress implemented such a phase-out. (Sec. 9) Requires satellite carriers to report to the FCC regarding local market retransmissions. Requires an FCC study and report concerning incentives that would induce a satellite carrier to provide television in certain local markets in which the carrier does not provide service. (Sec. 10) Directs the FCC to require as a condition of any provision, initial authorization, or authorization renewal that a provider of direct broadcast satellite service providing video programming, or a qualified satellite provider providing such programming, reserve a specified portion of its channel capacity for noncommercial programming of an educational or informational nature.</summary>
</bill>
