<bill session="111" type="s" number="3638" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Transportation Safety Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Public Transportation Safety Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">An original bill to establish a national safety plan for public transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Dodd. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-07-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="480">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 480.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>By Senator Dodd from Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs filed written report. Report No. 111-232.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2010--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Public Transportation Safety Act of 2010 - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to create a national public transportation safety plan to improve the safety of all public transportation systems that receive federal assistance. Requires the Secretary to establish a public transportation safety certification training program for federal and state employees, or other designated personnel, who conduct safety audits and examinations of public transportation systems, as well as employees of public transportation agencies responsible for safety oversight. Requires each state or local government, or other public transportation system operator, that receives federal assistance to certify it has established an agency safety plan meeting certain minimum criteria. Prescribes requirements for state safety oversight programs for grant-recipient states with a rail fixed guideway public transportation system (or one in the design or construction phase) that is not subject to Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) regulation. Requires an eligible state, in order to obligate its formula capital grant apportionment, to have an approved state safety oversight program in effect as well as an independent state safety oversight agency. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to eligible states to develop or carry out such a program. Sets the federal share of program costs under a grant at 80%. Grants a state safety oversight agency the authority to request the Secretary to take certain enforcement actions against a rail fixed guideway public transportation system that is not in compliance with federal safety laws. Requires national uniformity of public transportation safety laws, regulations, and orders. Allows a state to adopt or continue in force a public transportation safety law, regulation, or order: (1) until the Secretary promulgates a regulation or issues an order covering public transportation safety; and (2) that is consistent with, and more stringent than, the Secretary's regulation or order and meets certain other criteria. Authorizes appropriations for FY2011- FY2013. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to establish a national transit asset management system requiring fund recipients to develop capital asset inventories and condition assessments. Authorizes appropriations for FY2011- FY2013. (Sec. 5) Authorizes the Secretary to award a public transportation system grant to a recipient only if it reports to the Secretary, for inclusion in the National Transit Database, information relating to: (1) the causes of reportable incidents; and (2) transit asset inventories and condition assessments the recipient has conducted. (Sec. 6) Establishes within the FRA the Office of Safety and Security, to be headed by the Associate Administrator of Safety and Security. Authorizes a recipient to receive an urbanized area formula grant only if it has established a comprehensive public transportation agency safety plan. Requires the Secretary, in prescribing regulations for an alcohol and controlled substances testing program for public transportation employees, to establish an enforcement program that includes the imposition of penalties for noncompliance.</summary>
</bill>
