<bill session="109" type="s" number="3755" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Niagara Falls National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Niagara Falls National Heritage Area in the State of New York, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="6019"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2006--Introduced.
Niagara Falls National Heritage Area Act - Establishes the Niagara Fall National Heritage Area in New York. Designates as the local coordinating entity for the Area: (1) the Niagara Falls National Heritage Area Commission (established by this Act) for a five-year period beginning on the enactment of this Act; and (2) a private nonprofit or governmental organization designated by the Commission on the expiration of such period. Requires the Commission to submit a management plan for the Area. Prohibits the Commission from using federal funds made available to the Commission under this Act to acquire any real property or interest in real property. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to provide technical and financial assistance to the Area for the development and implementation of the management plan. Requires the Secretary to submit a report that includes: (1) an evaluation of the accomplishments and sustainability of the Area; and (2) any recommendations of the Secretary with respect to the future management of the Area.</summary>
</bill>
