<bill session="109" type="s" number="2509" updated="2013-07-19T20:35:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Insurance Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the issuance of charters and licenses for carrying on the sale, solicitation, negotiation, and underwriting of insurance or any other insurance operations, to provide a comprehensive system for the regulation and supervision of National Insurers and National Agencies, to provide for policyholder protections in the event of an insolvency or impairment of a National Insurer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2006-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="6225"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Casualty insurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Corporate governance"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Holding companies"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Insurance agents"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Life insurance"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Property insurance"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/5/2006--Introduced.
National Insurance Act of 2006 - Establishes in the Department of the Treasury an Office of National Insurance (ONI), headed by a Commissioner of National Insurance, with Divisions of Insurance Fraud and of Consumer Affairs, and an Office of the Ombudsman. Authorizes the Commissioner to supervise, regulate, and provide for registration of insurance self-regulatory organizations. Requires the Commissioner to supervise National Insurers and National Agencies, including chartering and licensing. Removes them, as well as federally licensed insurance producers from state oversight of insurance business practices. Authorizes the Commissioner to provide for the organization, operation, and regulation of National Insurance Companies and National Insurance Agencies, including U.S. branches of non-U.S. Insurers. Requires National Insurers to obtain a federal license. Provides for conversion of State Insurers to National Insurers or State Insurance Agencies to National Agencies, and vice versa. Prescribes requirements for National Life Insurer product regulation. Authorizes the Commissioner to: (1) license insurers that are not National Insurers to provide reinsurance; and (2) issue federal insurance producer licenses. Provides for: (1) mergers, consolidations, and acquisitions of National Insurers and National Agencies; and (2) conversion of stock life insurers to National Life Insurer in mutual form, and vice versa. Subjects National Insurers and National Agencies to state taxation. Prohibits states from preventing or restricting National Insurers from engaging in specified insurance business practices. Requires registration with the Commissioner of National Insurers that belong to an insurance holding company system. Authorizes the Commissioner to appoint the ONI as receiver for a National Insurer for rehabilitation or liquidation, as appropriate, in a case of insolvency or one of other specified hazardous financial conditions. Requires National Insurers to join guaranty associations in each state, which may levy assessments on them for purposes of insolvency protection. Establishes a National Insurance Guaranty Corporation to provide benefits to policyholders of a National Life Insurer placed in federal receivership. Applies federal antitrust laws to National Insurers, National Agencies, and federally licensed insurance producers, except regarding standard insurance policy forms. Exempts National Insurers, National Agencies, and federally licensed insurance producers from state regulation, except as expressly provided in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
