<bill session="111" type="hr" number="622" updated="2013-07-19T23:01:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-10T10:58:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-07-10T10:58:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3082) making appropriations for military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2010, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412307"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-195, by Ms. Pingree (ME).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The bill shall be considered as read through page 58, line 6. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI are waived. Notwithstanding clause 11 of rule XVIII, except as provided in section 2, no amendment shall be in order except the amendments printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. All points of order against such amendments are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-07-09T20:00:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="88">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 88.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10T09:15:00-04:00">
      <text>By the direction of the Committee on Rules, Ms. Pingree called up H.Res. 622 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7951-7953" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10T09:18:00-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Flake raised a point of order against the provisions of H.Res. 622 because it violates the Congressional Budget Act. The Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H.Res. 622. The House proceeded with 20 mintues of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10T09:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair put the question on consideration of the resolution.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7953" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10T09:32:00-04:00">
      <text>On question of consideration of the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10T09:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7951-7960" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10T09:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 622.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10T10:50:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 244 - 174 (Roll no. 526).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7959" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-07-10T10:58:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="527" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 241 - 179 (Roll no. 527).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7951" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10T10:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="3082"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3082) making appropriations for military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2010.</summary>
</bill>
