<bill session="112" type="s" number="1711" updated="2013-07-20T02:31:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reciprocal Market Access Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance reciprocal market access for United States domestic producers in the negotiating process of bilateral, regional, and multilateral trade agreements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2011-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6514"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6514-6515" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1749"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/2011--Introduced.
Reciprocal Market Access Act of 2011 - Prohibits the President from agreeing to the reduction or elimination of the existing rate of duty on any product in order to carry out a trade agreement entered into between the United States and a foreign country until the President certifies to Congress that: (1) the United States has obtained the reduction or elimination of tariff and nontariff barriers and policies and practices of such foreign country with respect to U.S. exports of any product that has the same physical characteristics and uses as the product for which the President seeks to modify its rate of duty, and (2) any violation of the trade agreement is immediately enforceable by withdrawal of the modification of the existing duty on such foreign product until the United States Trade Representative (USTR) certifies to Congress that the United States has obtained the reduction or elimination of the tariff or nontariff barrier or policy or practice of such foreign government. Requires the withdrawal of such a modification in specified circumstances until the USTR makes such a certification to Congress. Directs the U.S. International Trade Commission (USITC) to assess and identify the tariff and nontariff barriers and policies and practices for such products that exist in the foreign country as well as expected opportunities for U.S. exports to such country if such barriers and policies and practices are eliminated.</summary>
</bill>
