<bill session="110" type="h" number="1315" updated="2013-07-19T21:15:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-30T16:46:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-07-30T16:46:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Veterans' Benefits Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Veterans' Benefits Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide specially adaptive housing assistance to certain disabled members of the Armed Forces residing temporarily in housing owned by a family member.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the benefits provided to veterans under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400443"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-07-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-07-27T17:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 110-266.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-07-27T17:31:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="168">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 168.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-07-30T16:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Filner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-30T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/31/2007 H8887-8892" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-30T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1315.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-07-30T16:46:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/31/2007 H8887-8888" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-07-30T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-30T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2007--Passed House amended.
Veterans' Benefits Improvement Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide specially adaptive housing assistance for disabled members of the Armed Forces residing temporarily in housing owned by a family member if such military member suffers from a disability which is permanent and total in nature and is the result of an injury incurred or disease contracted or aggravated in the line of duty in active military service. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to carry out the Department of Veterans Affairs Visual Impairment and Orientation and Mobility Professionals Scholarship Program to increase the supply of qualified blind rehabilitation specialists for the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) and the country. Outlines eligibility requirements, including being a full- or part-time student in such fields of education or training. Requires: (1) full-time scholarship recipients to serve full-time in the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) in such field of clinical practice for three years during the six-year period following completion of such education or training; and (2) part-time recipients to serve a proportionately reduced period, but not less than one year. Limits to $15,000 per academic year the maximum scholarship for full-time participants. Requires pro rata repayment for unserved periods of obligated service. (Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary to include, within a currently-required annual report concerning veterans' reemployment rights: (1) the number of cases reviewed by the Secretary of Defense under the National Committee for Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve of the Department of Defense; and (2) an indication of which of the reported cases are disability-related. (Sec. 5) Increases from 15 to 16 the number of members on the Advisory Committee on Veterans Employment, Training, and Employer Outreach.</summary>
</bill>
