<bill session="109" type="s" number="2005" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Flood Mapping Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the reviewing, updating, and maintenance of National Flood Insurance Program rate maps, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2006-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Floodplains"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/14/2005--Introduced.
National Flood Mapping Act of 2005 - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to require the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to cooperate with state and local mapping partners in establishing, updating, and maintaining flood-risk zone data and estimating the rates of loss caused by floods in flood-risk zones. Requires specified federal agency heads to give the highest practicable priority in the allocation of manpower and other resources to the review and updating of maps in coastal areas. Requires flood insurance maps and related information to be made available on the FEMA website and in a format that is digital and geospatial data-compliant. Amends the National Flood Insurance Reform Act of 1994 to direct the Technical Mapping Advisory Council to make recommendations to the Director with respect to: (1) performance metrics and milestones to effectively and efficiently map flood risk areas; and (2) procedures for delegating mapping activities to state and local government mapping partners. Makes the Council permanent. Requires the Under Secretary of Homeland Security for Emergency Preparedness and Response, acting through the Director of FEMA or a successor official, to establish a program for review, updating, and maintenance of National Flood Insurance Program rate maps in accordance with this Act. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security, for purposes of the National Flood Insurance Program, to identify areas that are, or could be, affected by hurricanes. Directs the Comptroller General to review the guidance and regulations issued pursuant to Executive Order 11988 to: (1) determine federal agency compliance with the Order; and (2) make recommendations for restricting federal investment and assistance in floodplains. Directs the Secretary to publish periodically an inventory of levees in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
