<bill session="109" type="h" number="4544" updated="2013-07-19T19:44:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">340B Program Revision and Expansion Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and expand the section 340B program to improve the provision of discounts on drug purchases for certain safety net providers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400350"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental care facilities"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/14/2005--Introduced.
340B Program Revision and Expansion Act of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to include in the discount drug purchasing program those entities that receive funding under the Social Security Act for the provision of maternal and child care services, mental health services, and substance abuse services. Allows otherwise qualified hospitals to purchase discounted drugs through group purchasing agreements and organizations. Allows discounted drugs to be provided in an inpatient setting. (Currently, discounted drugs must be provided only on an outpatient basis.) Allows covered entities to contract with multiple pharmacies to purchase covered drugs. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to prevent abuse and misuse of discounted prices by: (1) developing a system to verify the accuracy of information regarding covered entities that is listed on the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) website; (2) establishing a third-party auditing system to regularly audit covered entities and ensure compliance with requirements of the discounted drug program; (3) conducting supplemental audits and implementing dispute resolution guidelines and other compliance programs; (4) issuing advisory opinions in response to questions by manufacturers or covered entities about the application of this program in specific factual circumstances; and (5) providing covered entities access through HHS's website to the prices for covered drugs.</summary>
</bill>
