<bill session="109" type="h" number="6134" updated="2013-07-19T19:58:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29T19:12:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-29T19:12:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Opportunity Patient Empowerment Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Health Opportunity Patient Empowerment Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand health coverage through the use of high deductible health plans and to encourage the use of health savings accounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="2006-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T19:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 109-704.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-09-29T19:12:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="423">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 423.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Reported to House amended.
Health Opportunity Patient Empowerment Act of 2006 - Amends Internal Revenue Code provisions relating to high deductible health plans and health savings accounts (HSAs). (Sec. 2) Allows a one-time distribution of amounts in a health flexible spending arrangement or a health reimbursement arrangement to an HSA if such distribution takes place before January 1, 2012. Requires distribution amounts to be included in the gross income of any individual (except a deceased or disabled individual) who fails to maintain coverage in a high deductible health plan and imposes an additional 10% penalty tax on such amounts. Allows certain coverage under a flexible spending arrangement for taxable years after December 31, 2006, to be disregarded for purposes of determining eligibility for high deductible health plan coverage. (Sec. 3) Repeals the deductible limitations on tax deductions for contributions to HSAs. (Sec. 4) Requires inflation adjustments to HSA contribution and deductible amounts to be determined at the end of the 12-month period ending on March 31 (currently, August 31). Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to publish inflation adjustments for HSA contribution and deductible amounts by June 1 of each year. (Sec. 5) Allows individuals who establish an HSA after the beginning of a taxable year to make contributions up to the full annual limit. (Sec. 6) Permits employers to make higher contributions to the HSAs of employees who are not highly compensated. (Sec. 7) Allows a one-time tax-free distribution of individual retirement account (IRA) funds to an HSA. Requires distribution amounts to be included in the gross income of any individual (except a deceased or disabled individual) who fails to maintain coverage in a high deductible health plan and imposes an additional 10% penalty tax on such amounts.</summary>
</bill>
