<bill session="110" type="s" number="122" updated="2013-07-19T22:21:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Trade Adjustment Assistance Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Trade Adjustment Assistance Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Trade Adjustment Assistance Equity for Service Workers Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Trade Act of 1974 to extend benefits to service sector workers and firms, enhance certain trade adjustment assistance authorities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-01-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S120-121"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S121-125" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Trade Adjustment Assistance Improvement Act of 2007 - Trade Adjustment Assistance Equity for Service Workers Act of 2007 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to allow the filing of a petition for certification of eligibility to apply for trade adjustment assistance by adversely affected: (1) workers in a service sector firm, its subdivision, or public agency; and (2) service sector firms. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to provide technical assistance to service industries adversely affected by import competition. Requires the Secretary of Labor to: (1) certify as eligible to apply for trade adjustment assistance adversely affected secondary workers in a service sector firm, its subdivision, or a public agency; and (2) upon the request of the President, the U.S. Trade Representative, or resolution of Congress, initiate an investigation to determine the eligibility for trade adjustment assistance for a group of workers or all workers in an occupation (effectively providing another method for petitioning for trade adjustment assistance). Provides for industry-wide certification of workers, including agricultural commodity producers, for trade adjustment assistance where bilateral or other safeguard provisions are invoked or antidumping or countervailing duties have been imposed. Establishes: (1) the Office of the Trade Adjustment Assistance Advisor; and (2) the Office of Trade Adjustment Assistance. Revises alternative trade adjustment assistance program eligibility requirements for older workers. Revises trade readjustment assistance eligibility requirements for adversely affected workers to extend job training enrollment deadlines and the provision of assistance during such training. Extends the trade adjustment assistance program through FY2012. Trade Adjustment Assistance Accountability Act - Requires the Secretary to collect necessary data regarding the trade adjustment assistance program. Makes fishermen who harvest wild stock eligible for trade adjustment assistance. Modifies trade adjustment assistance group eligibility requirements for agricultural commodity producers.</summary>
</bill>
