<bill session="111" type="h" number="2769" updated="2013-07-19T23:36:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commercializing Small Business Research and Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to promote the commercialization of certain small business research and development projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412267"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Contracting and Technology .</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSM23" subcommittee="Contracting and Technology" name="House Small Business"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2009--Introduced.
Commercializing Small Business Research and Development Act - Amends the Small Business Act to state as the policy of Congress that Small Business Administration (SBA) research and development (R&amp;D) programs should focus on promoting R&amp;D of projects governed by commercial business plans which have significant potential to produce products or services for the marketplace or for acquisition by federal agencies. Includes energy-related and rare disease-related research topics as deserving special consideration under Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Program research topics. Includes nanotechnology-related topics within authorized research topics under the SBIR Program and Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) Program. Requires each federal agency that is required to have an SBIR program and that awards annually $5 billion or more in procurement contracts to establish, for FY2010 and thereafter, annual goals for the commercialization of projects funded by SBIR awards. Directs each federal agency required to conduct an SBIR program to establish a commercialization program that supports the progress of SBIR awardees to the third (final) phase. Provides funding for such commercialization programs.</summary>
</bill>
