<bill session="110" type="h" number="3056" updated="2013-07-19T21:30:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-10T17:50:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-10-10T17:50:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tax Collection Responsibility Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Tax Collection Responsibility Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Tax Collection Responsibility Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the authority of the Internal Revenue Service to use private debt collection companies, to delay implementation of withholding taxes on government contractors, to revise the tax rules on expatriation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-07-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 18.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-07-31T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 110-281.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-07-31T16:43:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="182">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 182.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-10-09T19:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 719 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3056 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 or rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T12:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 719 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T15:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 719.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11400-11410, H11446-11464" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11400" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T15:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3056 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 or rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3056.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11462" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hulshof moved to recommit with instructions to Ways and Means.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11462-11464" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hulshof motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment adding a new section making the estate tax repeal permanent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11463" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T17:42:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 196 - 212 (Roll no. 959).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-10-10T17:50:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="960" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 232 - 173 (Roll no. 960).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11449-11452" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="719"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Expatriation"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Inheritance tax"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h851"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/10/2007--Passed House amended.
Tax Collection Responsibility Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Repeals the authority of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to enter into private debt collection contracts. Exempts contracts entered into before July 18, 2007, if such contracts are not renewed or extended after such date. Nullifies any contract entered into, extended, or renewed on or after July 18, 2007.(Sec. 3) Delays until 2012 the requirement for federal, state, and local agencies to withhold 3% of payments for goods and services provided to such agencies.Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to report to the House Committee on Ways and Means and the Senate Committee on Finance on issues relating to the administration of the withholding requirement.(Sec. 4) Treats income tax returns filed with the U.S. Virgin Islands by an individual claiming to be a bona fide resident of the Virgin Islands during the entire taxable year as filed with the United States for tax administration purposes. (Sec. 5) Sets forth additional rules for the tax treatment of high-income individuals who relinquish U.S. citizenship or residency to avoid U.S. taxation (expatriates). Treats all property of expatriates as sold for its fair market value on the day before the expatriation date and includes gain (over $600,000) or loss from such sale in the gross income of such expatriates. Allows expatriates to elect to defer payment of any tax resulting from expatriation if adequate security for payment of such tax is given.Requires 30% withholding of tax for certain items of deferred compensation payable to expatriates.Imposes a separate tax on gifts and bequests from expatriates exceeding $10,000, payable by the recipient of such gift or bequest.(Sec. 6) Repeals provisions providing for a 36-month suspension of interest and penalties on tax underpayments for taxpayers who had not been notified of a tax deficiency by the IRS. (Sec. 7) Increases penalties for failing to file correct information returns, failing to furnish correct payee statements, and failing to comply with other information reporting requirements.(Sec. 8) Increases to 115.25% the rate for estimated tax payments for certain large corporations in the third quarter of 2012.</summary>
</bill>
