<bill session="111" type="s" number="1018" updated="2013-07-20T00:32:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Park Service and Northwestern State University Collections Conservation Center Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">National Park Service and Northwestern State University Collections Conservation Center Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with Northwestern State University in Natchitoches, Louisiana, to construct a curatorial center for the use of Cane River Creole National Historical Park, the National Center for Preservation Technology and Training, and the University, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5330"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5331" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-476.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments. With written report No. 111-254.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-08-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="524">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 524.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2384"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
National Park Service and Northwestern State University Collections Conservation Center Act - Amends the Cane River Creole National Historical Park and National Heritage Area Act (the Act) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with Northwestern State University in Natchitoches, Louisiana, to construct a facility on land owned by the University to be used for: (1) housing the museum collection of the Historical Park; (2) providing additional space for use by the National Center for Preservation Technology and Training; and (3) providing space to the University for educational purposes related to the Williamson Museum collection if the University pays an appropriate rental fee to the National Park Service (NPS), as determined in such agreement. Requires the proceeds from the rental fees collected pursuant to this Act to be made available for the Historical Park. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into a lease for a term of not more than 40-years with the University if the land made available is leased to the Secretary at a nominal cost.</summary>
</bill>
