<bill session="112" type="h" number="806" updated="2013-07-20T01:17:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">End Veteran Homelessness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the services provided for homeless veterans under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2011-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2011-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1060"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/18/2011--Introduced.
End Veteran Homelessness Act of 2011 - Extends through FY2011, and increases the amount of, the authorization of appropriations for Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) comprehensive service programs for homeless veterans. Revises provisions concerning payments for providing services for homeless veterans to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to annually adjust the rate of such payment to reflect anticipated changes in the cost of furnishing services and to take into account the cost of providing services in a particular geographic area. Directs the Secretary to make such payments quarterly, while requiring quarterly statements from recipients on amounts expended. Requires the Secretary to ensure that each VA medical center that provides treatment and services under the supported housing program of the United States Housing Act of 1937 employs or provides one or more specialists to handle program issues and to conduct outreach to landlords to encourage and facilitate program participation. Directs the Secretary to coordinate with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to provide assistance to homeless veterans in accessing HUD's Homelessness Prevention and Rapid Re-Housing Program. Authorizes appropriations for FY2012 and thereafter for VA financial assistance for supportive services for very low-income veteran families occupying permanent housing. Authorizes, in connection with VA authority to advertise in the national media concerning available VA benefits, a special emphasis to be placed on promoting awareness of assistance for homeless women veterans and homeless veterans with children.</summary>
</bill>
