<bill session="111" type="s" number="3701" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural America Preservation Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to restore integrity to and strengthen payment limitation rules for commodity payments and benefits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2010-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2010-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/2010--Introduced.
Rural America Preservation Act of 2010 - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to cap maximum annual direct and counter-cyclical payments to an individual (for covered commodities and peanuts) at $20,000 and $30,000, respectively. Revises limitation provisions for marketing loan gains, loan deficiency payments, and commodity certificate transactions, and establishes an annual combined limitation of $75,000 for such payments. Doubles payment limitations for single farming operations. Limits an individual or a legal entity to a combined annual payment of $250,000. Sets forth attribution of payment provisions for: (1) individuals; (2) legal entities; and (3) embedded legal entities. Revises provisions respecting limitation of benefits to active farmers. Makes a person who commits fraud in connection with a scheme or device to evade certain program limitations ineligible for farm benefits for six years. Makes foreign individuals and foreign entities ineligible for agricultural program benefits.</summary>
</bill>
