<bill session="111" type="hr" number="846" updated="2013-07-19T23:03:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-22T12:12:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-10-22T12:12:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3585) to guide and provide for United States research, development, and demonstration of solar energy technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412308"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-20T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-304, by Mr. Polis (CO).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-20T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Science and Technology shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment. All points of order against consideration of he bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The Chair may entertain a motion that the Committee rise only if offered by the chair of the Committee on Science and Technology or his designee. The Chair may not entertain a motion to strike out the enacting words of the bill (as described in clause 9 of rule XVIII).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-10-20T18:53:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="122">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 122.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22T10:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11587-11595" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22T10:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 846.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22T12:04:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 176 (Roll no. 798).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11592-11594" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-10-22T12:12:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="799" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 178 (Roll no. 799).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11587" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22T12:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="3585"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3585) to guide and provide for United States research, development, and demonstration of solar energy technologies.</summary>
</bill>
