<bill session="111" type="s" number="1540" updated="2013-07-20T00:37:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Resolution Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for enhanced authority of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation to act as receiver for certain affiliates of depository institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2009-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8559-8561" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2009--Introduced.
Resolution Reform Act of 2009 - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to make it the responsibility of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) and its Board of Directors, using the powers and authorities conferred by this Act, to resolve depository institution holding companies of failed or failing insured depository institutions (including their affiliates and subsidiaries). Requires the FDIC to accept appointment and act as receiver of a covered depository institution holding company if it determines, in its sole discretion, that such appointment will reduce the cost to the Deposit Insurance Fund, and that specified grounds exist. Sets forth conditions for appointment of the FDIC as receiver. Permits the FDIC to decline to accept appointment for a covered depository institution holding company, when, in its sole discretion, it determines that resolution of the company would be better accomplished under either federal bankruptcy law or state insurance law. Shields the FDIC from direction or supervision of any other federal or state agency when in its status as receiver it exercises its rights, powers, and privileges. States that: (1) appointment of the FDIC as receiver terminates any proceeding under either federal bankruptcy law or state insolvency law with respect to the subject holding company; and (2) no case or proceeding may be commenced against such holding company while the FDIC acts as receiver without the written agreement of the FDIC. Permits judicial review regarding appointment of the FDIC as receiver. Sets forth the powers and duties of the FDIC as receiver. Authorizes the FDIC to make a determination of troubled condition for any covered company that does not have an appropriate federal banking agency. Authorizes the FDIC to cooperate and coordinate with foreign courts, foreign representatives, and foreign regulatory or supervisory authorities.</summary>
</bill>
