<bill session="111" type="h" number="3345" updated="2013-07-19T23:42:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Guard Technician Equity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles 5, 10, and 32, United States Code, to eliminate inequities in the treatment of National Guard technicians, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2010-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2009--Introduced.
National Guard Technician Equity Act - Authorizes the employment of a person as a non-dual status technician if: (1) the technician position has been designated to be filled only by a non-dual status technician; or (2) the person occupying the technician position has at least 20 years of service as a dual status military technician. Repeals: (1) the permanent limitation on the number of non-dual status technicians; and (2) the prohibition against overtime pay for National Guard technicians. Provides for: (1) up to 12 months of continued compensation for a military technician who was hired as a dual status technician but who is no longer a member of the Selected Reserve; (2) an extended deployment bonus for military technicians; (3) certain enlistment, reinlistment, and student loan benefits for military technicians. Reduces the eligibility age for retired pay to 55 years old. Makes a dual status military technician eligible for early retirement if separating from the Selected Reserve or ceasing to hold a specified military grade after: (1) completing 25 years of technician service; or (2) becoming 50 years old and completing 20 years of such service. Increases annual paid employment leave to 30 days for Reserve or National Guard duty. Revises specified provisions regarding employer health plan contributions for members of a reserve component of the Armed Forces.</summary>
</bill>
