<bill session="112" type="s" number="1234" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Partners for Stable Families and Foster Youth Affected by Methamphetamine or Other Substance Abuse Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend part B of title IV of the Social Security Act to reauthorize grants to assist children affected by methamphetamine or other substance abuse under the promoting safe and stable families program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3930-3931"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2883"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1542"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2011--Introduced.
Partners for Stable Families and Foster Youth Affected by Metamphetamine or Other Substance Abuse Act - Amends part B (Child and Family Services) of title IV of the Social Security Act to reauthorize grants to assist children affected by methamphetamine or other substance abuse. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to renew a five-year grant for up to an additional two years. Specifies the federal share of services or activities covered by such a grant for the sixth and seventh fiscal year. Directs the Secretary to reserve a certain portion of appropriations for awarding grants for each of FY2012-FY2016 to regional partnerships that have not been awarded such a grant in any of FY2007-FY2011. Limits the amount of funds reserved for awarding such grants that may be used for the Secretary's administrative expenses. Requires the Secretary to evaluate the effectiveness of such grants awarded to regional partnerships and report the results on the HHS website.</summary>
</bill>
