<bill session="111" type="sr" number="437" updated="2013-07-20T00:20:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-04">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the positive effect of the upcoming Iraqi parliamentary elections on Iraq's political reconciliation and democratic institutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2010-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-03-04" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1129-1131" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="S1130-1131" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1183-1184" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2010--Passed Senate without amendment.
Reaffirms the commitment of the United States to building a long-term partnership with Iraq that strengthens Iraq's security, stability, economy, and democracy. Urges the Administration to: (1) devote continued support for the people and government of Iraq, especially during the critical months after the elections of March 7, 2010; and (2) work with the international community to provide support for the Iraqi elections. Calls upon all parties in Iraq to ensure that the elections are free, without intimidation, and to not inflame communal tensions. Urges the surrounding countries to: (1) refrain from exercising destabilizing interference in Iraq's internal affairs; and (B) allow the Iraqi people to determine their own future. Calls for the timely formation of an inclusive post-election Iraqi government. Expresses gratitude to the men and women of the U.S. Armed Forces, the Foreign Service, and other federal government agencies for their service and heroism in Iraq. Commends the Iraqi people for their courage, sacrifice, and hard-won gains in fighting terrorism and building a peaceful democracy.</summary>
</bill>
