<bill session="112" type="s" number="1221" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">GEDI Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gestational Diabetes Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide grants to better understand and reduce gestational diabetes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2194"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2474"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2011--Introduced.
Gestational Diabetes Act of 2011 or the GEDI Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to develop a multisite gestational diabetes research project within the diabetes program of the CDC to expand and enhance surveillance data and public health research on gestational diabetes.&#160; Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to expand and intensify public health research on gestational diabetes, including; (1) developing and testing novel approaches for improving postpartum testing or screening and for preventing type 2 diabetes in women with a history of gestational diabetes; and (2) conducting research to&#160;further understanding of the&#160;factors and health systems that influence the risk&#160;of gestational diabetes and the development of type 2 diabetes in women with a history of gestational diabetes. Requires the Director to: (1) award grants for demonstration projects to reduce the incidence of gestational diabetes, the recurrence of such disease in subsequent pregnancies, and the development of type 2 diabetes in women with a history of gestational diabetes; and (2) work with state and Indian tribal-based diabetes prevention and control programs assisted by the CDC to encourage postpartum follow-up after gestational diabetes to reduce the incidence of gestational diabetes and its recurrence, the development of type 2 diabetes in at-risk women, and&#160;related complications.</summary>
</bill>
