<bill session="109" type="s" number="1302" updated="2013-07-19T20:24:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop the Raid on Social Security Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to stop the Congress from spending Social Security surpluses on other Government programs by dedicating those surpluses to personal accounts that can only be used to pay Social Security benefits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300069" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2005-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7303"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7303-7308" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12829-12830"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Retirement income"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2005--Introduced.
Stop the Raid on Social Security Act of 2005 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to establish a Social Security Personal Retirement Accounts Program, to be administered by a Social Security Personal Savings Board established within the Social Security Administration. Authorizes any individual credited with wages paid after December 31, 2005, or self-employment income derived in any taxable year ending after such date, who is born on or after January 1, 1950, and who has not filed an election to renounce such individual's status as a participating individual, to participate in the Program. Directs the Board to establish a social security personal retirement account for each participating individual upon initial receipt of a transfer from amounts held in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to make necessary transfers from the general fund of the Treasury to maintain a 100 percent ratio of assets of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund to the annual amount required to pay the full amount of benefits payable for each year up to 2041. Requires designation of a certified account manager by or on behalf of each participating individual to hold the individual's account assets for investment, including in broad-based index funds similar to the index fund investment options available within the Thrift Savings Fund. Prescribes requirements for withdrawal from such accounts, annuitization, and related matters. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) make all social security personal retirement accounts exempt from income taxation; but (2) subject distributions from closed accounts to taxation as social security benefits. Exempts assets of Social Security Personal Retirement Accounts from the estate tax.</summary>
</bill>
