<bill session="112" type="hr" number="455" updated="2013-07-20T01:06:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-04T10:56:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-11-04T10:56:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2838) to authorize appropriations for the Coast Guard for fiscal years 2012 through 2015, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412410"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-267, by Mr. Webster.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution makes in order as original text for the purpose of amendment an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of the Rules Committee Print of H.R. 2838 dated October 21, 2011. All points of order against the amendment in the nature of a substiture made in order as original text are waived. At any time on the legislative day of November 4, 2011, it shall be in order for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules relating to a measure addressing the applicability of the coastwise trade laws.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-11-03T19:03:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="86">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 86.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04T09:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7337-7340" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04T09:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 455.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04T09:34:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 455, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Slaughter demanded the yeas and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04T10:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7340-7342" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04T10:47:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 177 (Roll no. 829).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7339-7340, H7340-7341" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7339-7340" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-11-04T10:56:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="830" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 245 - 166 (Roll no. 830).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7337" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="2838"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/2011--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2838) to authorize appropriations for the Coast Guard for fiscal years 2012 through 2015.</summary>
</bill>
