<bill session="109" type="s" number="3055" updated="2013-07-19T20:40:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family-Based Meth Treatment Access Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act regarding residential treatment programs for pregnant and parenting women, a program to reduce substance abuse among nonviolent offenders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300096"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="5493"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug addiction"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and women"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Mortality"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Prison alternatives"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2006--Introduced.
Family-Based Meth Treatment Access Act of 2006 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to expand the grant program to provide residential substance abuse treatment to pregnant and postpartum women to include: (1) parenting women substance abuse treatment (including treatment for addiction to methamphetamine); and (2) outpatient treatment services. Requires that such treatment programs be accessible to pregnant and parenting women in health disparity populations. Gives priority in awarding grants to any entity that agrees to use the award for programs serving: (1) an area that is a rural area, an area with a shortage of mental health professionals, or an area with a shortage of family-based substance abuse treatment options; or (2) an area that has high rates of addiction to methamphetamine or other drugs. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to award grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts for the purpose of assisting local jails and detention facilities in providing comprehensive, family-based substance abuse treatment services to pregnant and parenting adults who are considered nonviolent offenders. Sets forth criteria that must be met if such a grant is used for a family drug treatment program that is an alternative to incarceration.</summary>
</bill>
