<bill session="110" type="s" number="1834" updated="2013-07-19T22:36:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HEALTH Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Help End Addiction to Lethal Tobacco Habits Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the health of Americans through the gradual elimination of tobacco products.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-07-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9622-9623"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nicotine"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tobacco industry"/>
    <term name="Tobacco tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2007--Introduced.
Help End Addiction to Lethal Tobacco Habits Act or the HEALTH Act - Amends the Federal Cigarette Labeling and Advertising Act and the Smokeless Tobacco Health Education Act of 1986 to make changes to annual reporting requirements relating to ingredients added to tobacco in the manufacture of cigarettes and smokeless tobacco.Requires the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, to develop standards and best practices for: (1) the sampling of tobacco, smokeless tobacco, and tobacco products; and (2) accurate measurement and analysis of tobacco constituents.Makes changes to the Surgeon General's Warning on the packages of cigarettes and smokeless tobacco, including the content, size, and location of such warnings.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) to conduct a survey on the usage of tobacco products.Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish an allowance system to reduce the sale of U.S. tobacco products. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to make changes to the excise tax on cigarettes, cigars, and smokeless tobacco. Establishes a classification system for tobacco products based on their level of health risks. Requires the Secretary to establish the Tobacco Risk Classification Panel to make recommendations concerning such classification.Authorizes the Secretary to prohibit the introduction into interstate commerce of any product that contains nicotine if such product has no health benefits.Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to carry out a campaign of counter-advertising with respect to tobacco use.Provides for coverage of tobacco cessation products and programs.</summary>
</bill>
