<bill session="111" type="sr" number="171" updated="2013-07-20T00:17:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-08">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution commending the people who have sacrificed their personal freedoms to bring about democratic change in the People's Republic of China and expressing sympathy for the families of the people who were killed, wounded, or imprisoned, on the occasion of the 20th anniversary of the Tiananmen Square Massacre in Beijing, China from June 3 through 4, 1989.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2009-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-06-08" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6316-6317" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6317" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6273" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="sr" number="167"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2009--Passed Senate without amendment.
Commends the people who demonstrated at Tiananmen Square and elsewhere in the People's Republic of China (PRC) in 1989, many of whom sacrificed their lives and freedom to bring about democratic change and gain freedom of expression, assembly, association, and religion for the people of China. Expresses sympathy for the families of those who were killed, wounded, or imprisoned due to their involvement in the peaceful protests in Tiananmen Square. Condemns the ongoing human rights abuses by the PRC. Calls on the Government of the PRC to: (1) release all Tiananmen Square prisoners; (2) allow freedom of speech; and (3) cease intimidation and imprisonment of religious monitories and those who disagree with PRC policies. Supports efforts by free speech activists in China and elsewhere. Urges the President to support peaceful advocates of free speech around the world.</summary>
</bill>
