<bill session="111" type="s" number="1092" updated="2013-07-20T00:33:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reenergize America Loan Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a program to provide loans for use in carrying out residential, commercial, industrial, and transportation energy efficiency and renewable generation projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5704-5706"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5707-5708" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2009--Introduced.
Reenergize America Loan Program Act of 2009 - Establishes: (1) within the Department of Energy (DOE) the Reenergize America Loan Program, under which the Secretary of Energy shall allocate funds to states for use in providing zero-interest loans to qualified persons to carry out residential, commercial, industrial, and transportation energy efficiency and renewable generation projects contained in approved state energy conservation plans; and (2) the Reenergize America Loan Program Fund. Requires the Secretary, in allocating funds, to consider: (1) the likely energy savings and renewable energy potential of the plans; (2) regional energy needs; and (3) the equitable distribution of funds among regions. Requires states that seek to receive allocations to: (1) submit to the Secretary a five-year plan for the administration and distribution of funds; (2) agree to annual audits; and (3) reapply for a subsequent allocation at the end of the five-year period. Limits the amount of a loan provided by a state to $5 million and the term of a loan to four years. Authorizes states that receive allocations to: (1) impose on loan recipients a fee to cover the costs incurred by the state in administering the loan; and (2) retain the return of principal from loans for the purpose of making additional loans.</summary>
</bill>
