<bill session="110" type="h" number="6498" updated="2013-07-19T22:00:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Genomics and Personalized Medicine Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To secure the promise of personalized medicine for all Americans by expanding and accelerating genomics research and initiatives to improve the accuracy of disease diagnosis, increase the safety of drugs, and identify novel treatments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="976"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Genetic counseling"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Hereditary diseases"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2008--Introduced.
Genomics and Personalized Medicine Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) establish the Genomics and Personalized Medicine Interagency Working Group (IWG) to facilitate collaboration, coordination, and integration of activities among federal agencies relating to genomic research and initiatives; (2) expand and accelerate research and programs to collect genetic and genomic data that will advance the field of genomics and personalized medicine; (3) establish a national biobanking distributed database for the collection and integration of genomic data and associated environmental and clinical health information; (4) establish a grant program for academic medical centers and other entities to develop or expand biobanking initiatives; (5) improve genetics and genomics training for diagnosis, treatment, and counseling of adults and children for both rare and common disorders; (6) establish a registry on the analytical and clinical validity of laboratory-developed genetic tests; (7) contract with the National Academy of Sciences to study incentives to encourage companion diagnostic test development; and (8) make information available on the safety and efficacy of genetic tests and commission a study for improving federal oversight and regulation of such tests. Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to: (1) conduct an analysis of the public health impact of direct-to-consumer marketing of genetic tests; and (2) expand efforts to educate the public about genomics and its health applications.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish a companion diagnostic tax credit for qualified diagnostic tests designed to provide information that can be used to increase the safety or effectiveness of a drug.</summary>
</bill>
