<bill session="111" type="h" number="4955" updated="2013-07-19T23:57:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transforming Undergraduate STEM Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the National Science Foundation to provide grants for implementing or expanding research-based reforms in undergraduate STEM education for the purpose of increasing the number and quality of students studying toward and completing baccalaureate degrees in STEM.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Science Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Research and Science Education" name="House Science and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4968"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2010--Introduced.
Transforming Undergraduate STEM Education Act - Amends the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002 to make changes to the program requiring the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) to expand previously implemented reforms of undergraduate science, mathematics, engineering, or technology (STEM) education. Expands grant uses to allow their use in: (1) implementing, rather that just expanding, research-based reforms in undergraduate STEM education; (2) creating multidisciplinary or interdisciplinary STEM courses or programs; (3) expanding undergraduate STEM research opportunities to include interdisciplinary research and research in industry, at federal labs, and at international research institutions or research sites; (4) implementing or expanding bridge, cohort, tutoring, or mentoring programs that enhance student recruitment or persistence; (5) implementing STEM faculty development programs; (6) supporting the participation of graduate students and postdoctoral fellows in instructional or assessment activities at primarily undergraduate IHEs; and (7) researching STEM teaching and learning at the undergraduate level related to the proposed reform effort. Gives priority, among proposals that expand existing reform efforts beyond a single academic unit, to proposals for which a senior institutional administrator serves as the principal investigator.</summary>
</bill>
