<bill session="111" type="h" number="1507" updated="2013-07-19T23:25:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 23 of title 5, United States Code, relating to disclosures of information protected from prohibited personnel practices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400415"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2009-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2009-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2009-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="372"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2009--Introduced.
Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act of 2009 - Amends federal personnel law relating to whistleblower protections to expand the concept of protected disclosure to include lawful disclosures without restriction to time, place, form, motive, context, forum, or prior disclosure, including a disclosure made in the ordinary course of an employee's duties. Defines evidentiary standards applicable to whistleblower disclosures. Includes as a prohibited personnel practice against whistleblowers the implementation or enforcement of any nondisclosure policy, form, or agreement, a suspension or revocation of a security clearance, and an investigation of a whistleblower. Directs the Comptroller General to conduct a study of security clearance revocations of federal employees at a select sample of executive branch agencies and report to Congress on such study. Provides for expedited review of Merit Systems Protection Board (MSPB) decisions interpreting whistleblower protections in U.S. district court. Grants authority to MSPB to determine whether whistleblower security clearances were properly suspended or revoked. Expands whistleblower protection to employees or former employees of a national security agency. Prohibits reprisals against such employees, including revocations of their security clearances, for making disclosures. Extends whistleblower protections to contractors, employees of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA), and individuals who disclose censorship related to federal research or technical information.</summary>
</bill>
