<bill session="111" type="s" number="623" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pre-existing Condition Patient Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, title XXVII of the Public Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prohibit preexisting condition exclusions in group health plans and in health insurance coverage in the group and individual markets.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3183"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3183-3185" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1558"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2009--Introduced.
Pre-existing Condition Patient Protection Act of 2009 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code to prohibit a group health plan from: (1) imposing any preexisting condition exclusion; or (2) providing for an affiliation period for coverage offered by a health maintenance organization (HMO). Defines an "affiliation period" as a period of time before health insurance coverage becomes effective. Requires each health insurance issuer offering coverage in the group market in a state to accept every employer in the state that applies for such coverage. Revises provisions governing individual health insurance coverage to apply certain prohibitions related to denying coverage and preexisting condition exclusions to coverage offered in an area (currently, a state). Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to report to Congress concerning the occurrence of adverse selection as a result of this Act. Requires health insurance issuers to which this Act applies to submit to the Secretary specified information on enrollees and claims. Directs the Secretary to require that group health plans and health insurance issuers provide data to the Secretary for compliance purposes. Sets forth civil penalties for violations. Directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to report to the Secretary on: (1) the impact of this Act and other relevant federal laws; and (2) this Act's effect on the affordability of health insurance coverage and on the expansion of coverage and reductions in the number of uninsured and underinsured.</summary>
</bill>
