<bill session="112" type="hr" number="233" updated="2013-07-20T01:05:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Welcoming the new state of Southern Sudan, encouraging Sudan and Southern Sudan to resolve separation issues and the future of the Abyei region, and urging the Governments of Sudan and Southern Sudan to abide by the principles of peace, democracy, and human rights.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E746-747"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2011--Introduced.
Congratulates the people of Southern Sudan for exercising their right to self determination. Welcomes the new nation of Southern Sudan. Pledges that the United States will work with the governments of Sudan and Southern Sudan to ensure a peaceful transition to independence. Calls on: (1) the government of Southern Sudan to create democratic institutions, build infrastructures, and ensure the well-being of its citizens; and (2) the U.S. government to appoint an Ambassador to Southern Sudan. Urges the government of Sudan to put an end to repression and violence in the region and abide by democratic principles. Encourages other nations to welcome the new state of Southern Sudan and assist with the transition process.</summary>
</bill>
