<bill session="110" type="h" number="2603" updated="2013-07-19T21:26:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">High Threat Helicopter Flight Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to designate high threat helicopter flight areas and to provide special rules for screening of passengers and property to be transported on passenger helicopters operating to or from such areas and for helicopters flights in such areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400426"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/2007--Introduced.
High Threat Helicopter Flight Area Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) to designate an area at high risk for an attack by one or more terrorists as a high threat helicopter flight area. Directs the Secretary to provide screening of all passengers and property transported from a high threat flight helicopter area on a passenger helicopter equivalent to that provided for passengers and property carried aboard a domestic passenger aircraft. Requires the Secretary to develop a plan for acquiring and training personnel, including acquiring equipment, to provide such screening. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to take necessary action to ensure that: (1) no passenger helicopter flies in a high threat flight area, except on approach for landing, or departure after takeoff, in such area; (2) a passenger helicopter when flying in such area, to the maximum extent practicable, flies over water; and (3) a helicopter pilot when in flight over such area remains in contact with the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) regarding its flight path, irrespective of its altitude. Exempts from such requirement helicopters carrying out military, police, medical, or other operations as the Secretary of Transportation deems appropriate.</summary>
</bill>
