<bill session="109" type="s" number="3653" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Law Enforcement Pension Adjustment Equity Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Law Enforcement Pay Equity Act of 2000 to permit certain annuitants of the retirement programs of the United States Park Police and United States Secret Service Uniformed Division to receive the adjustments in pension benefits to which such annuitants would otherwise be entitled as a result of the conversion of members of the United States Park Police and United States Secret Service Uniformed Division to a new salary schedule under the amendments made by such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300004" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2006-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="2006-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce,  and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="960"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2006--Introduced.
Federal Law Enforcement Pension Adjustment Equity Act of 2006 - Amends the Law Enforcement Pay Equity Act of 2000 to apply a prohibition against treatment as an increase in salary, for purposes of increased annuitant pension benefits, of the conversion of positions and members of the U.S. Park Police and the Secret Service Uniformed Division to a new salary schedule, and the associated initial adjustments in basic pay rates, with respect to any payment made prior to January 1, 2006. (Thus permits cost-of-living adjustments in pension benefits for annuitants of the U.S. Park Police and the U.S. Secret Service Uniformed Division for payments made in 2006 and in subsequent years.)</summary>
</bill>
