<bill session="112" type="s" number="300" updated="2013-07-20T02:19:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-10-05">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prevent abuse of Government charge cards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2011-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2011-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S629-630"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-07-18">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with amendments. With written report No. 112-37.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-07-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="104">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 104.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2011-07-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4850-4852" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4850-4852" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-07-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-25T12:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-01-27T14:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 112-376, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-27T14:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-01-27T14:57:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="257">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 257.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5411-5414" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 300.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mrs. Maloney objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5599" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE" datetime="2012-08-01T18:34:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/31/2012 H5411-5412" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-22">
      <text>Senate agreed to the House amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/21/2012 S6672" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2012-09-25">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2012-10-05">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2012-10-05" type="public" number="112-194">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-194.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/2012--Public Law.
Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2012 - (Sec. 2) Requires the head of each executive agency that issues and uses purchase cards and convenience checks, other than the Department of Defense (DOD), to establish and maintain safeguards and internal controls to ensure that: (1) records are kept of each holder of a purchase card and the applicable transaction limits; (2) each purchase card and convenience check holder is assigned an approving official; (3) the card holder and approving official perform a reconciliation of card charges with receipts and other supporting documentation and forward a summary report to a certifying official in a timely manner; (4) disputed charges are resolved in an appropriate manner; (5) payments on purchase card accounts are made promptly to avoid interest penalties; (6) rebates and refunds earned by the use of such cards are reviewed for accuracy; (7) records of each purchase card transaction are retained in accordance with standard government policies on disposition of records; (8) periodic reviews are performed to determine whether each purchase card holder has a need for such card; (9) the agency provides appropriate training to purchase card holders and supervising officials; (10) the agency has specific policies regarding the number of purchase cards issued, the authorized credit limits, and the categories of employees eligible for purchase cards; (11) effective systems, techniques, and technologies are used to prevent or identify illegal, improper, or erroneous purchases; (12) purchase cards of terminated or transferred employees are invalidated upon termination or transfer; and (13) steps are taken to recover the cost of erroneous, improper, or illegal purchases made with a purchase card or convenience check through salary offsets. Imposes similar safeguards and controls for the use of purchase cards and convenience checks by DOD personnel. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to review existing guidance for the use of purchase cards and convenience checks and prescribe additional necessary guidance for the implementation of safeguards and internal controls for such use. Requires agency heads to: (1) provide for appropriate adverse personnel actions, including dismissal, for employees who violate requirements for the use of purchase cards or convenience checks; and (2) report to the Director of OMB on violations if the agency incurs more than $10 million in purchase card spending annually. Requires agency Inspectors General to: (1) report to the Director of OMB semiannually on violations of this Act; and (2) conduct periodic assessments and audits of purchase card or convenience check programs to identify and analyze risks of illegal, improper, or erroneous uses of purchase cards or convenience checks. (Sec. 3) Amends the Travel and Transportation Reform Act of 1998 to require agency heads that issue travel charge cards for official government travel to establish and maintain internal control activities, including: (1) maintaining a record of each holder of a travel card and of limitations on the use of such card; (2) monitoring for accuracy rebates and refunds based on prompt payment, sales volume, or other actions on card accounts; (3) conducting periodic reviews to determine whether each cardholder has a need for the card; (4) providing appropriate training to holders of such cards and supervising officials; (5) ensuring that the agency has specific policies on the number of purchase cards issued, the authorized credit limits, and the categories of employees eligible for purchase cards; (6) checking the creditworthiness of individuals to whom such a card is issued; (7) ensuring that each agency uses effective systems, techniques, and technologies to prevent or identify illegal, improper, or erroneous purchases; and (8) ensuring that the travel charge cards of employees who are terminated are invalidated immediately upon termination of employment. Requires the Director of OMB to review existing guidance for travel cards and prescribe additional guidance for implementing internal controls for such cards. Requires each executive agency to provide for appropriate adverse personnel actions, including removal from employment, for employees who fail to comply with applicable travel charge card terms or who commit fraud with respect to a travel card. Requires the Inspector General of each executive agency with more than $10 million in travel card spending to conduct periodic audits or reviews of travel card programs to analyze the risks of illegal, improper, or erroneous purchases and payments and to report the findings of such audits or reviews to the Director of OMB. (Sec. 4) Requires an agency head who issues travel charge cards that are billed directly to the federal government to establish and maintain internal control activities to: (1) ensure that officials with the authority to approve official travel verify that centrally-billed account charges are not reimbursed to an employee, (2) dispute unallowable and erroneous charges and track the status of disputed transactions to ensure resolution, and (3) submit requests to servicing airlines for refunds of fully or partially unused tickets and track the status of unused tickets to ensure resolution. Directs the Director of OMB to review existing guidance and prescribe additional guidance for implementing internal controls of centrally-billed accounts. (Sec. 6) Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to: (1) excuse an agency head from responsibilities relating to executive agency accounting and responsibilities under the Improper Payments Information Act of 2002, or (2) require the disclosure of personally identifying information that is otherwise protected from disclosure under the Privacy Act.</summary>
</bill>
