<bill session="111" type="s" number="1299" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Worker Infection Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect health care workers and first responders, including police, firefighters, emergency medical personnel, and other workers at risk of workplace exposure to infectious agents and drug resistant infections, such as MRSA.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2009-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2009--Introduced.
Worker Infection Protection Act - Directs the Secretaries of Labor and of Health and Human Services (HHS) to jointly develop and issue workplace standards, recommendations, and plans to protect health care workers and first responders and other workers at risk of workplace exposure to infectious agents and drug resistant infections, such as Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA). Directs the Secretary of Labor to develop and issue an emergency temporary standard and, not later than 180 days after such issuance, a permanent standard for the protection of workers at risk of exposure, to prevent occupational exposure to infectious agents and toxins. Sets forth minimum requirements for such standards concerning: (1) an infectious agent control plan in settings where health care is delivered; (2) personal protective equipment; (3) training and information, including providing job-specific training and education regarding the prevention of transmission of infectious agents and providing instructional materials for patients and visitors; and (4) medical surveillance for exposed workers.</summary>
</bill>
