<bill session="110" type="s" number="2654" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Citizen Soldier and Military Veteran Travel Reimbursement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for enhanced reimbursement of servicemembers and veterans for certain travel expenses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2008-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2008-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2008--Introduced.
Citizen Soldier and Military Veteran Travel Reimbursement Act of 2008 - Repeals the requirement that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs adjust the amount (similar to a copay or deductible) charged to a member who is reimbursed by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for travel expenses connected with the receipt of vocational rehabilitation, counseling, or required medical care. Requires the Secretary, in determining the amount of the allowance or reimbursement, to use the reimbursement rate for the use of privately-owned vehicles by government employees on official business. Authorizes the Secretary of the military department concerned to reimburse a member of the reserves for expenses incurred in connection with round-trip travel in excess of 100 miles to an inactive duty training location, requiring the same reimbursement rate as above.</summary>
</bill>
