<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1180" updated="2013-07-19T21:00:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-04T14:02:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-06-04T14:02:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing the efforts and contributions of outstanding women scientists, technologists, engineers, and mathematicians in the United States and around the world on Mother's Day, 2008.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">Resolution recognizing the efforts and contributions of outstanding women scientists, technologists, engineers, and mathematicians in the United States and around the world.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400660"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2008-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2008-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2008-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2008-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-04T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Johnson, E. B. moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-04T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4918-4919" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-04T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1180.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-06-04T14:02:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-06-04T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-04T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mothers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Special days"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/2008--Passed House amended.
Recognizes the important contributions of women to science, technology, engineering, mathematics, and the health of many industries that have created new jobs, boosted economic growth, and improved the nation's competitiveness and standard of living.Recognizes the need to increase the number of women participating in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.Supports the role of women in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics. Encourages the people of the United States to use this Mother's Day to give appropriate recognition not only to our mothers but also to women scientists, technologists, engineers, and mathematicians who have made important contributions to our everyday lives.</summary>
</bill>
