<bill session="109" type="h" number="1975" updated="2013-07-19T19:21:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Virginia Ridge and Valley Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate additional National Forest System lands in the State of Virginia as wilderness, to establish the Seng Mountain and Bear Creek Scenic Areas, to provide for the development of trail plans for the wilderness areas and scenic areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2006-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2005-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Dairy, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="942"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="942"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National scenic areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Old growth forests"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2005--Introduced.
Virginia Ridge and Valley Act of 2005 - Designates certain lands in the Jefferson National Forest, Virginia (Brush Mountain and Brush Mountain East, Seng Mountain and Raccoon Branch, Stone Mountain, Hunting Camp Creek and Garden Mountain, Lynn Camp Creek, Mountain Lake Additions, Lewis Fork Addition and Little Wilson Creek Additions, Shawvers Run Additions, Peters Mountain Addition, and Kimberling Creek Additions) as wilderness. Designates Seng Mountain and Raccoon Branch, and Bear Creek, as National Scenic Areas (Areas). Establishes such Areas for purposes of: (1) ensuring the protection and preservation of scenic quality, water quality, natural characteristics, and water resources; (2) protecting wildlife and fish habitat; (3) protecting areas that may develop characteristics of old-growth forests; and (4) providing a variety of recreation opportunities. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) administer such Areas in accordance with this Act and the laws and regulations generally applicable to the National Forest System (NFS); (2) develop a management plan for such Areas; and (3) establish a trail for NFS lands to develop hiking and equestrian trails within the wilderness areas and non-motorized recreation trails within the Areas. Sets forth provisions regarding roads, vegetation management, motorized travel, fire, insects and disease, water, and mining and geothermal leasing.</summary>
</bill>
