<bill session="113" type="h" number="1128" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting U.S. Missile Defense Information Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the effectiveness of the missile defense system of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412395"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400004" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400038" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412567" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412394" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2013-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS29" subcommittee="Strategic Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2013--Introduced.
Protecting U.S. Missile Defense Information Act of 2013 - Directs the President to report semiannually to the congressional defense and appropriations committees on: (1) any discussions on missile defense between the U.S. government and the Russian Federation during the preceding six months, and (2) meetings held by the National Disclosure Policy Committee with respect to declassifying documents containing information on U.S. missile defense systems. Requires briefings to such committees in connection with the latter reports. Prohibits Department of Defense (DOD) funds for FY2014 or thereafter from being used to provide the Russian Federation with access to: (1) U.S. missile defense hit-to-kill technology, or (2) telemetry data with respect to missile defense interceptors or target vehicles. Declares that the United States shall not be bound by the terms of any executive agreement relating to U.S. missile defense capabilities, including basing, locations, and numbers of missiles. Prohibits DOD funds for FY2014 or thereafter from being used to: (1) negotiate or implement any executive agreement relating to such capabilities, or (2) implement rules of engagement or guidance for employment of forces relating to such an agreement. Provides an exception with respect to any country with which the United States has entered into a treaty of alliance or a security guarantee. Directs the President to: (1) seek to encourage the Russian Federation to disclose any support provided for the ballistic missile programs of China, Syria, Iran, or North Korea; and (2) submit to the above committees a semiannual report on any such support.</summary>
</bill>
