<bill session="109" type="s" number="3476" updated="2013-07-19T20:43:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeland Security Professional Development Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish employee professional development programs at the Department of Homeland Security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5602-5603"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5603-5604" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2006--Introduced.
Homeland Security Professional Development Act of 2006 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish: (1) the Homeland Security Mentoring Program for DHS employees, the goals of which shall include addressing critical human capital deficiencies, recruitment and retention efforts, and succession planning and promoting cross-disciplinary mentoring and training opportunities; and (2) the Homeland Security Rotation Program to provide middle level DHS employees the opportunity to broaden their knowledge through exposure to other DHS components. Requires such programs to be: (1) established in accordance with DHS's Human Capital Strategic Plan; and (2) administered by the Training Leaders Council (established by the Chief Human Capital Officer). Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to report annually to specified congressional committees on the training, mentoring, and succession plans and programs of federal agencies.</summary>
</bill>
