<bill session="109" type="h" number="5881" updated="2013-07-19T19:56:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disabled Veterans Tax Termination Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to eliminate the offset between military retired pay and veterans service-connected disability compensation for certain retired members of the Armed Forces who have a service-connected disability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400254"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2006-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2006--Introduced.
Disabled Veterans Tax Termination Act - Amends federal military retired pay provisions to: (1) permit veterans with a service-connected disability of less than 50% to claim both retired pay and disability compensation; (2) eliminate provisions requiring a phase in between January 1, 2004, and December 31, 2013, of concurrent receipt of retired pay and disability compensation; (3) eliminate the four-year phase in of concurrent receipt of retired pay and disability compensation for disabled veterans determined to be individually unemployable; (4) permit certain veterans with combat-related disabilities (Chapter 61 retirees) to claim both retired pay and disability compensation; and (5) extend combat-related special compensation to certain veterans with less than 20 years of service who have a combat-related disability (TERA retirees).</summary>
</bill>
