<bill session="109" type="s" number="1299" updated="2013-07-19T20:24:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community College Partnership Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to encourage partnerships between community colleges and 4-year institutions of higher education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1031"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="College entrance requirements"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Community colleges"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student enrollment"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2005--Introduced.
Community College Partnership Act of 2005 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a community college opportunity program to help students at community or technical colleges to transfer to four-year institutions and complete bachelor's degrees. Directs the Secretary of Education to award program grants to eligible partnerships that include one or more community or technical colleges that award associate's degrees and one or more institutions of higher education that offer a baccalaureate or postbaccalaureate degree not awarded by the partner colleges (or to statewide boards or partnerships with jurisdiction over such educational entities). Requires funds from such grants to be used for: (1) development of policies to expand opportunities for community or technical college students to earn bachelor's degrees, including transfer of academic credits between institutions and expanded articulation and guaranteed transfer agreements; (2) support services to students participating in the program, including tutoring, mentoring, academic and personal counseling, and transition facilitation; (3) academic program enhancements at the community or technical college that increase program quality and the number of student participants in the dual degree program offered in conjunction with a baccalaureate degree-granting institution; and (4) programs to identify barriers that inhibit student transfers.</summary>
</bill>
