<bill session="112" type="h" number="803" updated="2013-07-20T01:17:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Equity for Injured Veterans Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to increase vocational rehabilitation and employment assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/18/2011--Introduced.
Equity for Injured Veterans Act of 2011 - Extends the period of eligibility for training and rehabilitation through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for veterans with service-connected disabilities until the end of the 15 (under current law, 12) year period after the veteran's discharge from active-duty service. Allows a service-disabled veteran a subsistence allowance for six (under current law, two) months of full-time employment training following completion of a vocational rehabilitation program. Allows such a veteran who has unused VA educational assistance entitlement to use such assistance to pursue a program of education as part of a vocational rehabilitation program, as long as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs approves the educational, professional, or vocational objective chosen by the veteran. Directs the Secretary to provide reimbursement for the actual cost of child care provided by a licensed provider to a veteran who is participating in a vocational rehabilitation program, is the sole caretaker of a child, and would not otherwise be able to afford such care. Requires the Secretary to include in annual budget materials submitted to Congress information on veterans receiving vocational rehabilitation assistance who: (1) became employed, and (2) achieved independence in daily living.</summary>
</bill>
