<bill session="111" type="h" number="5371" updated="2013-07-20T00:00:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">William Shemin Jewish World War I Veterans Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Army and the Secretary of the Navy to conduct a review of military service records of Jewish American veterans of World War I, including those previously awarded a military decoration, to determine whether any of the veterans should be posthumously awarded the Medal of Honor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400060" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2010-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2010-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2010--Introduced.
William Shemin Jewish World War I Veterans Act - Directs the Secretaries of the Army and the Navy to: (1) review the service records of certain Jewish-American World War I veterans to determine whether that veteran should be posthumously awarded the Medal of Honor; and (2) upon a positive determination, submit a recommendation to the President that the President make such award. Makes eligible for such review and award each Jewish-American World War I veteran: (1) who was previously awarded the Distinguished Service Cross, Navy Cross, or other military decoration for service during World War I; or (2) whose name is submitted to either Secretary by the Jewish War Veterans of the United States of America within one year after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
