<bill session="112" type="hr" number="786" updated="2013-07-20T01:09:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-19T14:46:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-19T14:46:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Honoring the four United States public servants who died in Libya and condemning the attacks on United States diplomatic facilities in Libya, Egypt, and Yemen.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400036"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400060" joined="2012-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2012-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="2012-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Ros-Lehtinen moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6076-6079" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 786.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-09-19T14:46:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6076-6077" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T14:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2012--Passed House without amendment.
Recognizes the selfless commitment to U.S. national security and to Libya's transitional democracy by the brave U.S. citizens who lost their lives in the unjustified attack on the U.S. consulate in Benghazi, Libya. Expresses deepest condolences to the families and loved ones of those U.S. public servants killed in Benghazi, Libya. Condemns the terrorists who planned and conducted the attack on the U.S. consulate in Benghazi, Libya, and those who vandalized the U.S. embassies in Cairo, Egypt, and Sana'a, Yemen. Expresses concern about the security situation in Libya, Egypt, and Yemen, and with the threat posed to the region and U.S. interests by extremists and terrorists. Expresses appreciation for the actions of those who sought to protect the U.S. diplomats and diplomatic facilities. Calls upon all governments to continue to work closely with the Department of State to: (1) ensure security of diplomatic facilities, (2) secure their borders, and (3) combat terrorists and extremists who operate within their sovereign territory. Calls upon the governments of Libya, Egypt, and Yemen, in full cooperation with the U.S. government, to bring the perpetrators of these attacks to justice. Reiterates the commitment of the United States to promoting its core values, including support for democracy, human rights, individual and religious freedom, and respect for human dignity.</summary>
</bill>
