<bill session="109" type="s" number="2750" updated="2013-07-19T20:37:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Access to Emergency Medical Services Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve access to emergency medical services through medical liability reform and additional Medicare payments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2006-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2006-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2006-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2006-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4073"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2729"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3875"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care fraud"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2006--Introduced.
Access to Emergency Medical Services Act of 2006 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to deem hospitals, emergency rooms, physicians (including on-call physicians), and physicians groups that provide emergency care to uninsured individuals to be employees of the Public Health Service for purposes of any civil action that may arise due to items and services furnished. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide additional payments from the Federal Supplementary Insurance Trust Fund for physicians' services in the emergency department of a hospital or critical access hospital to a Medicare recipient. Provides for incentive payments to hospitals that certify to the Secretary that they meet established standards for prompt admission by a hospital of individuals presenting to the emergency department that need inpatient hospital services. Requires the Comptroller General to submit to the relevant congressional committees a report that evaluates whether such standards will achieve the stated objectives and recommends any changes. Sets forth civil monetary penalties for filing a false certification and engaging in a pattern or practice of failing to meet established standards.</summary>
</bill>
