<bill session="112" type="h" number="1266" updated="2013-07-20T01:21:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fraudulent Prescription Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to improve detection of the fraudulent abuse of prescriptions to obtain controlled substances in schedule II or III, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412451"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2011-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2011--Introduced.
Fraudulent Prescription Prevention Act of 2011 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to prohibit the Attorney General from registering a practitioner to dispense or conduct research with a schedule II or III controlled substance unless the practitioner agrees to comply with this Act's requirements. Requires a practitioner, at the time of prescribing such substances to submit to the Attorney General by means of a web portal: (1) the patient's name, date of birth, and address; (2) the date and time of the prescription; (3) the name and amount of the substance prescribed; (4) the practitioner's Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) registration number and contact information; and (5) the prescription pad number. Makes exceptions if the practitioner is prescribing a controlled substance in a medical emergency situation or does not have access to the web portal (in which case the practitioner may make the required submissions within seven days). Requires a practitioner to submit the same information before dispensing such a controlled substance, as well as whether the dispensing constitutes a refill of a prescription. Requires a practitioner who declines to dispense such a controlled substance to submit information that would have been required to be reported if the substance had been dispensed and any reason to suspect that the individual attempting to purchase the substance was acting pursuant to fraud. Directs the Attorney General to establish and maintain a web portal and database that allows a practitioner to submit such information and that communicates an alert to the practitioner if circumstances exist that indicate the patient or purchaser is attempting to unlawfully divert or misuse a controlled substance. Limits disclosure of database information.</summary>
</bill>
