<bill session="111" type="s" number="3995" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Wi-Net Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Administrator of the General Services Administration to install Wi-Fi hotspots and wireless neutral host systems in all Federal buildings in order to improve in-building wireless communications coverage and commercial network capacity by offloading wireless traffic onto wireless broadband networks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2010-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-12-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8350"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/1/2010--Introduced.
Federal Wi-Net Act - Requires the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) to: (1) install or retrofit wireless Internet connections in federal buildings; and (2) allow eligible carriers, upon request, to install wireless neutral host systems in all publicly accessible federal buildings. Authorizes the executive agency controlling a federal government building to grant an easement or rights-of-way, for the installation, construction, and maintenance of wireless transmitters and backhaul transmission, to an executive agency, state, or individual applicant. Requires the Administrator to establish a fee for awarding such easement or rights-of-way that is based on fair market prices, subject to certain exceptions. Requires any fees collected to be used by the relevant agency for construction and maintenance of Wi-Fi hotspots and wireless neutral host systems. Directs the Administrator to develop one or more master contracts to govern the placement of wireless transmitters on federal government buildings.</summary>
</bill>
