<bill session="109" type="sr" number="468" updated="2013-07-19T20:10:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-03">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution supporting the continued administration of Channel Islands National Park, including Santa Rosa Island, in accordance with the laws (including regulations) and policies of the National Park Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2006-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4077-4078"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4077" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-547.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici without amendment. With written report No. 109-310.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-07-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="553">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 553.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-08-03" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8900" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8900" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2006--Passed Senate without amendment.
States that: (1) Channel Islands National Park, including Santa Rosa Island, should continue to be administered by the National Park Service (NPS); (2) the NPS should manage Santa Rosa Island in a manner that ensures that the natural, scenic, and cultural resources of the Island are properly protected, restored, and interpreted for the public and that visitors to the Park are provided with a safe and enjoyable Park experience; and (3) the NPS should not be directed to manage Santa Rosa Island in a manner that would result in the public being denied access to significant parts of the Island or that is inconsistent with the responsibility of NPS to protect native resources within the Park, including threatened and endangered species.</summary>
</bill>
