<bill session="112" type="h" number="6664" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to the State of California all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to certain National Forest System land to facilitate the relocation of the South Operations Coordination Center, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2012--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to convey to the state of California a parcel of approximately 12.55 acres of National Forest System land in the Pacific Southwest Region to permit the state to use such land to relocate the South Operations Coordination Center. Defines "South Operations Coordination Center" as the state facility that is jointly operated by the state and the Forest Service and is used for providing emergency support for wildland fires and other emergencies. Requires the state, as consideration for the conveyance of the land, to pay an amount equal to the fair market value of the conveyed land. Requires the state to cover the costs to be incurred by the Secretary, or to reimburse the Secretary for the costs incurred in carrying out such conveyance. Subjects such conveyance to valid existing rights.</summary>
</bill>
