<bill session="113" type="h" number="3148" updated="2013-11-02T06:45:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect America's Credit Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to apply the debt limit only to debt held by the public and to adjust the debt limit for increases in the gross domestic product.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412523"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2013-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2013--Introduced.
Protect America's Credit Act of 2013 - Modifies public debt limit requirements to specify that the debt limit amount applies only to debt held by the public. Reduces the public debt limit by the excess of: (1) the face amount of obligations issued under the federal government's borrowing authority and the face amount of obligations whose principal and interest are guaranteed by the federal government (except guaranteed obligations held by the Secretary of the Treasury), over (2) the face amount of obligations issued under such borrowing authority to the public and the face amount of obligations issued to the public whose principal and interest are guaranteed by the federal government. Requires an increase in the public debt limit each year by an amount equal to the product of such amount as in effect as of the close of the preceding calendar year multiplied by the percentage, if any, by which the Current-Dollar GDP for the third quarter of the preceding calendar year exceeds the Current-Dollar GDP for the third quarter of the second preceding calendar year. Defines "Current-Dollar GDP" as the current-dollar gross domestic product as computed and published by the Department of Commerce. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress annually regarding the increase in the debt limit that will take effect the next calendar year, including a description of how each increase in the statutory limit compares to the actual increase in debt.</summary>
</bill>
