<bill session="109" type="h" number="6001" updated="2013-07-19T19:57:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to establish an identity verification system that ensures that disaster assistance payments are paid only to qualified individuals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400634"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2006--Introduced.
Requires the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to establish a system that verifies applicant identity in near-real time to ensure that disaster assistance payments are paid only to qualified individuals. Requires the Director, in order to determine if an individual is qualified and ensure that the system is efficient, to: (1) establish registration criteria that provides simple but specific instructions to registrants regarding the required information; (2) require registrants to provide their name exactly as it appears on their social security card; (3) test the system prior to implementation; (4) ensure that call center employees give prompt feedback regarding whether the registrant's identity has been validated; and (5) establish an expeditious appeal and alternative verification process for a registrant who is rejected.</summary>
</bill>
