<bill session="112" type="h" number="6666" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Communities through Helping to Offer Incentives and Choices to Everyone in Society Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a comprehensive approach to preventing and treating obesity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400218"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Natural Resources, Education and the Workforce, Transportation and Infrastructure, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2012--Introduced.
Healthy Communities through Helping to Offer Incentives and Choices to Everyone in Society Act - Expands coverage of obesity treatment under titles XVIII (Medicare), including part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program), and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act. Sets forth requirements to expand training of health professionals and the community on treating and preventing obesity. Requires activities to encourage physical activity, including the development of assessment tools on barriers in communities to physical activity, planning and implementing model communities of play that increase physical activity, the development of state and national strategies to encourage Americans to be physically active outdoors, and dissemination of best practices to encourage physical activity outdoors. Sets forth requirements to address physical education in schools, including to: (1) issue guidelines for physical education in elementary and secondary schools; (2) revise the definition of &#8220;core academic subject&#8221; to include physical education; (3) issue physical activity guidelines for preschool children and recommend that each Head Start agency implement such guidelines; (4) promote healthy, active lifestyles by students within specified educational grant programs; and (5) revise the professional development program for teachers and principals to include training for physical and health education teachers and training on improving students' health habits and participation in physical activities. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from the gross income of employees: (1) the value of any on-premises employer-provided athletic facility; and (2) fees, dues, or membership expenses paid to an athletic or fitness facility by an employer for its employees. Allows employers a tax deduction for fees, dues, or membership expenses paid to an athletic or fitness facility. Allows a medical care tax deduction for qualified sports and fitness expenses. Revives a grant program for the administration of national or regional programs to provide instructional activities on a variety of sports for low-income youth. Expands activities to educate consumers about nutrition, physical activity, and healthy lifestyles and to improve eating and physical habits. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to award grants to expand, establish, or maintain urban community gardens. Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to make grants to assist local planning decisions and policies that increase the access of individuals to physical activity. Establishes a program to award grants for costs related to allowing the use of a school&#8217;s facilities and equipment by people other than the school&#8217;s students or staff. Authorizes the collection and analysis of data on fitness, activity levels and nutrition.</summary>
</bill>
