<bill session="111" type="s" number="1538" updated="2013-07-20T00:37:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Black Carbon and Other Aerosols Research Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a black carbon and other aerosols research program in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that supports observations, monitoring, modeling, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8276"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8276-8277" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1562"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2009--Introduced.
Black Carbon and Other Aerosols Research Act of 2009 - Directs the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to: (1) develop an observation, monitoring, modeling, and research plan for black carbon and other aerosols that contribute to climate-forcing and climate change, which shall analyze research gaps, identify federal research priorities, include a framework for modeling effects on climate, identify sources, monitor atmospheric concentrations, and provide for assets necessary to develop a monitoring and research program; and (2) establish a Black Carbon and Other Aerosols Advisory Panel to assist in development and implementation of such plan. Directs the Administrator to establish a black carbon and other aerosols monitoring and research program that combines observations, research, monitoring, modeling, and other activities within NOAA, consistent with such plan, and that includes: (1) coordinated monitoring and research activities to improve understanding of specified factors that influence the contribution of such substances to climate change processes; (2) strategic modeling activities to improve understanding of the transportation and transformation of such substances, their distributions and climate-forcing properties, and their roles in climate change and air quality; (3) educational opportunities that encourage an interdisciplinary and international approach to exploring such substances' associated sources and impacts; (4) public outreach activities; and (5) coordination of monitoring research with various agencies and entities. Directs the Administrator to establish a program to provide grants for critical research and projects that improve the ability to measure, monitor, model, and assess such substances with respect to atmospheric concentrations and deposited forms, including research that supports means of reducing their impacts on climate.</summary>
</bill>
