<bill session="111" type="sr" number="108" updated="2013-07-20T00:17:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-22">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution commending Captain Richard Phillips, the crew of the "Maersk Alabama", and the United States Armed Forces, recognizing the growing problem of piracy off Somalia's coast, and urging the development of a comprehensive strategy to address piracy and its root causes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-04-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4596-4597" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4597" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4586" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Somalia"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/2009--Passed Senate without amendment.
Declares the sense of the Senate that: (1) Captain Richard Phillips of the Maersk Alabama deserves the respect and admiration of all people of the United States for his brave conduct under life-threatening circumstances; (2) the Senate shares the sense of relief and gratitude felt by the family and shipmates of Captain Phillips; (3) all members of the U.S. Armed Forces involved in the rescue operation, in particular members of the Navy and Navy SEAL teams who rescued Captain Phillips, the officials of other federal government departments and agencies who contributed, and the crew of the Maersk Alabama, are to be commended for their exceptional efforts and devotion to duty; and (4) the President should work with the international community and the transitional government of Somalia to develop a comprehensive strategy to address both the burgeoning problem of piracy and its root causes.</summary>
</bill>
