<bill session="110" type="h" number="307" updated="2013-07-19T21:06:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To impose limitations on the authority of the Secretary of the Interior to claim title or other rights to water absent specific direction of law or to abrogate, injure, or otherwise impair any right to the use of any quantity of water.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court decisions"/>
    <term name="Water allocation (Policy)"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2007--Introduced.
Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior from claiming title or other rights to water in a state, other than for Indian reservation lands, absent specific direction of law, or from exercising authority so as to abrogate, injure, or otherwise impair any right to the use of any quantity of water: (1) that has been allocated in accordance with provisions of the Department of Justice Appropriations Act relating to suits for the adjudication of water rights by or pursuant to interstate compact and by a decision of the United States Supreme Court; (2) by requiring a change in the nature of use or the transfer of any right to use water or creating a limitation on the exercise of any right to use water; or (3) by modifying the delivery, diversion, nondiversion, allocation, or storage of any water to be delivered by contract.</summary>
</bill>
