<bill session="113" type="h" number="823" updated="2013-11-02T06:25:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Space Leadership Preservation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To preserve American space leadership, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400089"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2013-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-26">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-26">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/2013--Introduced.
Space Leadership Preservation Act of 2013 - Establishes a six-year term of office for the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA). Prohibits the Deputy Administrator from acting for, and exercising the powers of, the Administrator for a period exceeding 45 days. Requires the Associate Administrator, after such a 45 day period, to exercise the powers of the Administrator until a new Administrator is appointed and confirmed by the Senate. Establishes a Board of Directors for NASA. Sets forth Board membership and appointment criteria. Allows the President to appoint the Administrator and Deputy Administrator from among a list of nominees provided by the Board. Requires the Board to provide: (1) NASA's proposed annual budget; (2) annual reports on spaceflight infrastructure, unique space capabilities, and the workforce necessary to maintain such infrastructure and capabilities; (3) reports on specific policy matters; and (4) quadrennial reviews of current space programs and a vision for future space exploration. Authorizes the Administrator to enter into contracts for rocket propulsion systems and manned and unmanned space transportation vehicles and payloads.</summary>
</bill>
