<bill session="113" type="s" number="441" updated="2013-11-02T06:55:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Professional Development for Educators Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 by establishing a program to provide professional development activities for educators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2013--Introduced.
Professional Development for Educators Act of 2013 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to direct the Secretary of Education to allot grants to states and, through them, award or allot subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to provide professional development to educators. Makes each state's allotment equivalent to its share of school improvement funds under part A of title I of the ESEA. Requires states to use a portion of their allotment to: establish the criteria for quality professional development activities, which must include the requirement that those activities are regularly assessed on the basis of their impact on teacher effectiveness and student achievement; design and implement methods for evaluating quality professional development activities; make recommendations for improving those activities; design and maintain an electronic, searchable, statewide registry of quality professional development activities; hire regional professional development coordinators to work as liaisons between the state and LEAs regarding those activities; evaluate professional development activities; and submit annual reports to the Secretary regarding the progress they make under the grant program. Requires LEAs to use their subgrant to: (1) inform their states of quality professional development activities that are available for inclusion in the statewide registry; and (2) dedicate at least 25% of each subgrant to quality professional development activities that involve science, technology, engineering, mathematics, and career and technical education.</summary>
</bill>
