<bill session="112" type="s" number="1502" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Rivers Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to restore public trust in pipeline safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2011-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2011--Introduced.
Clean Rivers Act of 2011 - Directs the Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration (PHMSA) to review the adequacy of PHMSA regulations with respect to PHMSA-regulated pipelines that cross rivers with a width of at least 100 feet from high water mark to high water mark. Requires the Administrator to establish on a publicly available PHMSA website: (1) a database of all pipeline water crossings in the United States, (2) a listing of national and state statistics on pipeline safety, and (3) certain information regarding pipeline operator hazardous liquid pipeline response plans. Directs the Administrator to review: (1) the need for performance standards for leak detection systems used by hazardous liquid pipeline facility operators, and (2) the adequacy of PHMSA regulations in cases where a hazardous liquid pipeline facility operator must use an emergency flow restricting device. Requires the Administrator to review and report to Congress on all onshore gas and hazardous liquid gathering lines not regulated by PHMSA. Requires revision of the National Contingency Plan for removal of oil and hazardous substances to provide greater involvement of local authorities in the basic framework for the response management structure.</summary>
</bill>
