<bill session="111" type="s" number="3374" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cleanfields Investment Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Cleanfields Investment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to establish a grant program to revitalize brownfield sites for the purpose of locating renewable electricity generation facilities on those sites.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2010-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-06-18">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer with amendments and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 111-210. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-06-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="434">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 434.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Cleanfields Investment Act - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a program to provide grants for: (1) inventorying, characterizing, assessing, and conducting planning relating to brownfield sites for the purpose of locating renewable electricity generation facilities or renewable energy manufacturing facilities on such sites; and (2) remediating brownfield sites for the purpose of locating such facilities on such sites. Authorizes such grants to be made to: (1) eligible entities to be used for capitalization of revolving loan funds to provide such assistance; or (2) eligible entities or nonprofits to be used directly for such activities. Requires the Administrator to issue: (1) guidance describing the considerations to be used in determining whether a grant is warranted; and (2) ranking criteria to be used in determining whether a grant is warranted. Defines a "renewable electricity generation facility" to mean a facility that generates renewable electricity from wind energy, solar energy, or geothermal energy. Defines a "renewable energy manufacturing facility" to mean a facility that manufactures components or systems for use in generating renewable electricity from such energy. Authorizes of appropriations for such grants for FY2011-FY2016.</summary>
</bill>
