<bill session="112" type="hr" number="412" updated="2013-07-20T01:06:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-22T23:18:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-09-22T23:18:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 2608) to provide for an additional temporary extension of programs under the Small Business Act and the Small Business Investment Act of 1958, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-09-22T21:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-215, by Mr. Dreier.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-22T21:41:00-04:00">
      <text>It shall be in order to take from the Speaker's table H.R. 2608 with the Senate amendment thereto and to consider in the House, without any intervention of any point of order, a motion offered by the Chair of the Committee on Appropriations or his designee that the House concur in the Senate amendment with the amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution modified by the amendment printed in part B of such report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-09-22T21:41:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="76">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 76.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-09-22T21:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6389-6399" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-22T21:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 412.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-22T23:11:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 235 - 177 (Roll no. 725).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6398" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6398" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-09-22T23:18:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="726" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 238 - 176 (Roll no. 726).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6389" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-09-22T23:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="2608"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2011--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 2608) to provide for an additional temporary extension of programs under the Small Business Act and the Small Business Investment Act of 1958.</summary>
</bill>
