<bill session="111" type="s" number="2907" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Land Avalanche Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Federal Land Avalanche Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a coordinated avalanche protection program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2009-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13459-13460"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-565.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-266.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-08-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="536">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 536.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="4407"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Federal Land Avalanche Protection Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, to establish an avalanche protection program to provide information and assistance to users of avalanche-prone National Forest System lands. Includes as objectives of the program: (1) informing and educating the public about the risks posed by avalanches; (2) providing avalanche forecasts for avalanche-prone areas of the National Forest System that are frequented by recreational or other users; (3) providing oversight of activities relating to the prevention and control of avalanches by ski area and other special use permit holders on National Forest System land, including the procurement, control, and use of artillery; and (4) facilitating research on the program's objectives, including research on the development of alternatives to military artillery. Requires the Secretary to: (1) use the resources of the Forest Service's National Avalanche Center and other partners; and (2) work with the Avalanche Artillery Users of North America Committee and other partners to improve coordination among the users of artillery used to prevent and control avalanches. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to further the program's objectives and requires giving priority to grants that enhance public safety. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
