<bill session="111" type="h" number="1427" updated="2013-07-19T23:24:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Promoting Innovation and Access to Life-Saving Medicine Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the licensing of biosimilar and biogeneric biological products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400425"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412224" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2009-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="2009-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2009-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400242" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2009-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2009-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2009-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2009-03-18" withdrawn="2009-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="726"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2009--Introduced.
Promoting Innovation and Access to Life-Saving Medicine Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to provide for the licensing of biosimilar and interchangeable biological products. Defines "biosimilar" and "interchangeability" for purposes of this Act. Allows any person to file an abbreviated biological product application with the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Requires such applications to include information demonstrating a high degree of similarity or interchangeability between the biological product and the licensed biological product (reference product). Requires the Secretary to: (1) approve an application and issue a license for a biosimilar product unless the Secretary finds and informs the applicant that the information in the application fails to demonstrate biosimilarity between the biological product and the reference product or the safety, purity, and potency of the biological product; and (2) establish requirements for the efficient review, approval, suspension, and revocation of abbreviated biological product applications. Allows an applicant to request the Secretary to make a determination as to the interchangeability of a product and its reference product based on whether a product can be expected to produce the same clinical result as the reference product in any given patient. Grants market exclusivity to any biological product that is determined to be interchangeable for a specified period. Sets forth provisions governing patent infringement claims involving comparable biological products and legal remedies to expedite the adjudication of patent infringement disputes. Extends the period for approval of biological products to allow for studies of the use of new biological products in the pediatric population.</summary>
</bill>
