<bill session="113" type="s" number="1274" updated="2013-11-02T07:03:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend assistance to certain private nonprofit facilities following a disaster, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412597" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2013-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="592"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to include community centers and houses of worship as "private nonprofit facilities" that provide essential services of a governmental nature to the general public for purposes of disaster relief and emergency assistance eligibility under such Act. Makes a church, synagogue, mosque, temple, or other house of worship and an otherwise eligible private nonprofit facility operated by a religious organization eligible for federal contributions for the repair, restoration, and replacement of facilities damaged or destroyed by a major disaster, without regard to the religious character of the facility or the primary religious use of the facility. Requires that, in spaces used primarily for religious worship services, such contributions only be used to cover costs of purchasing or replacing, without limitation, the building structure, building enclosure components, building envelope, vertical and horizontal circulation, physical plant support spaces, electrical, plumbing, and mechanical systems (including heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and fire and life safety systems), and related site improvements. Makes this Act applicable to the provision of assistance in response to a major disaster or emergency declared on or after October 28, 2012.</summary>
</bill>
