<bill session="112" type="h" number="2420" updated="2013-07-20T01:31:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate certain lands in the State of Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400101"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2922"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/6/2011--Introduced.
Colorado Wilderness Act of 2011 - Amends the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 to add specified lands in Colorado managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) (proposed as the Powderhorn Wilderness Addition) to the Powderhorn Wilderness. Designates specified lands in Colorado managed by the BLM or the U.S. Forest Service as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System (NWPS). Designates specified lands in Colorado administered by the BLM, Forest Service, and Bureau of Reclamation as wilderness and as components of the NWPS. Incorporates such lands into the West Elk Wilderness. Authorizes the Colorado Army National Guard, through the High-Altitude Army National Guard Aviation Training Site, to conduct aerial navigation training maneuver exercises over the wilderness areas designated by this Act. Allows the Secretary to continue authorizing competitive running events currently permitted in the Redcloud Peak Wilderness and Handies Peak Wilderness Areas. Provides for the securing, adjudication, and use of U.S. water rights for certain of the wilderness areas designated by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
