<bill session="112" type="s" number="971" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Digital Goods and Services Tax Fairness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote neutrality, simplicity, and fairness in the taxation of digital goods and digital services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2011-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2012-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2941"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1860"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2011--Introduced.
Digital Goods and Services Tax Fairness Act of 2011 - Prohibits a state or local jurisdiction from imposing multiple or discriminatory taxes on or with respect to the sale or use of digital goods or services delivered or transferred electronically to a customer. Excludes from the definition of "digital service" telecommunications service, Internet access service, or audio or video programming service. Restricts taxation of digital goods and services to the retail sale of such goods and services and by the jurisdiction encompassing a customer's tax address. Prohibits the use of existing regulations or administrative rulings relating to the taxation of tangible personal property or other services to impose any tax on the sale or use of digital goods or services. Grants jurisdiction to federal district courts to prevent a violation of this Act, without regard to the amount in controversy or the citizenship of the parties. Expresses the sense of Congress that each state shall take reasonable steps to prevent multiple taxation of digital goods and services where a foreign country has imposed a tax on such goods and services.</summary>
</bill>
