<bill session="111" type="s" number="792" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improvement of the National Program of Cancer Registries Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve the National Program of Cancer Registries by expanding data collection and allowing data sharing for public health objectives, while preserving the confidentiality of patients, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
Improvement of the National Program of Cancer Registries Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise requirements for statewide cancer registries and require the inclusion in such registries of information on: (1) the highest level of education attained by adults with cancer; (2) sources of payment by individuals for the costs of cancer diagnosis and treatment; and (3) the history of alcohol and tobacco use by individuals with cancer. Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) develop standards for collection of data elements for state cancer registries; (2) develop inter-operability and security standards for data exchange and integration between state cancer registries and any cancer registry and another federal registry for non-cancer diseases; and (3) provide a basic electronic collection tool to facilitate standardized data collection. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to facilitate coordination of the National Program of Cancer Registries with other federally-supported registry programs, including infectious disease registries, environmental disease registries, and other non-cancer, chronic disease registries.</summary>
</bill>
