<bill session="109" type="h" number="974" updated="2013-07-19T19:12:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Corporate Subsidy Reform Commission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Corporate Subsidy Reform Commission to review inequitable Federal subsidies and make recommendations for termination, modification, or retention of such subsidies, and to state the sense of the Congress that the Congress should promptly consider legislation that would make the changes in law necessary to implement the recommendations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2005-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="2005-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2005-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2005-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="2005-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2005-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2005-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2005-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2006-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2005-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Tax preferences"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2005--Introduced.
Corporate Subsidy Reform Commission Act - Establishes an independent Corporate Subsidy Reform Commission to: (1) identify Federal programs and laws that provide inequitable Federal subsidies; (2) review such subsidies; (3) conduct public hearings on agency recommendations regarding inequitable subsidies; and (4) report to Congress recommendations for termination, modification, or retention of each subsidy reviewed. Requires each Federal agency to include in budget documents submitted in FY 2007 a list of programs or laws within that agency that provide inequitable Federal subsidies, together with recommendations for appropriate action. Expresses the sense of Congress that, following submission of the Commission's report, the House of Representatives and the Senate should promptly consider legislation that would enact changes in Federal statutes necessary to implement the Commission's recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
