<bill session="109" type="s" number="177" updated="2013-07-19T20:14:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Salt Cedar and Russian Olive Control Demonstration Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Salt Cedar and Russian Olive Control Demonstration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to further the purposes of the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992 by directing the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to carry out an assessment and demonstration program to control salt cedar and Russian olive, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300036"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300003" joined="2005-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2005-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2005-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2005-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S588"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S588-589" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-03-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici without amendment. With written report No. 109-15.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-03-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="26">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 26.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2720"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="2720"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aquatic pests"/>
    <term name="Aquatic plants"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Droughts"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Exotic plants"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fibers"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Revegetation"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="West (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/2005--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Salt Cedar and Russian Olive Control Demonstration Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary), acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation and in cooperation with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Defense, to carry out a salt cedar (Tamarix spp) and Russian olive (Elaeagnus angustifolia) assessment and demonstration program to: (1) assess the extent of the infestation by salt cedar and Russian olive trees in the western United States; (2) demonstrate strategic solutions for the long-term management of such trees and the reestablishment of native vegetation; and (3) assess economic means to dispose of biomass created as a result of removal of those trees. Requires the Secretary to: (1) complete an assessment of the extent of the infestation on public and private land; (2) identify and document long-term management and funding strategies that could be implemented by Federal, State, and private land managers in addressing the infestation and that should be tested as components of specified demonstration projects; and (3) establish a program that selects and funds at least five projects proposed by and implemented in collaboration with Federal agencies, State and local governments, national laboratories, Indian tribes, institutions of higher education, individuals, organizations, or soil and water conservation districts to demonstrate and evaluate the most effective methods of controlling salt cedar and Russian olive trees. Directs the Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Agriculture, to complete an analysis of economic means to use or dispose of biomass created as a result of removal of salt cedar and Russian olive trees. Sets forth requirements regarding cost limitations and cost-sharing. Requires the Secretary to: (1) subject to independent review the assessment, identification and documentation of long-term management strategies, demonstration projects, and analysis; and (2) report annually to Congress. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2006 and beyond.</summary>
</bill>
