<bill session="112" type="s" number="2183" updated="2013-07-20T02:35:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bringing Fugitives to Justice Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide funding for the Fugitive Extradition and Apprehension Trust Fund.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1577-1578"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1578-1579" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2012--Introduced.
Bringing Fugitives to Justice Act - Creates in the Treasury a Fugitive Extradition and Apprehension Trust Fund (FEATF), into which shall be deposited the proceeds of forfeited appearance bonds, bail bonds, and collateral collected for failure to appear in court as required by the conditions of release or to surrender for service of sentence pursuant to a court order. (Amends the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 to repeal a provision requiring such proceeds to be deposited in the Crime Victims Fund.) Requires FEATF funds to be obligated and expended by the Attorney General for: (1) the United States Marshals Service to enhance efforts to investigate and apprehend fugitives, (2) the Offices of the United States Attorneys to enhance efforts to investigate and prosecute fugitives, and (3) the Office of International Affairs of the Department of Justice (DOJ) to coordinate the investigation and extradition or other legal rendition of international fugitives.</summary>
</bill>
