<bill session="113" type="h" number="913" updated="2013-11-02T06:26:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Everglades for the Next Generation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Water Resources Development Act of 2000 to provide for expedited project implementation relating to the comprehensive Everglades restoration plan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412529" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400439" joined="2013-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E230-231"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="414"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="414"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Everglades"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2013--Introduced.
Everglades for the Next Generation Act - Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 2000 to authorize the Secretary of the Army, after completing a project implementation report prepared for a project under the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan and without any further congressional authorization, to carry out projects for: (1) the Caloosahatchee River (C-43) West Basin Storage Reservoir; (2) the Biscayne Bay coastal wetland; (3) Broward County water preserve areas; (4) the C-111 Spreader Canal; (5) any other project identified in the Plan for which a project implementation report is completed that is in accordance with an integrated delivery schedule approved by the Chief of Engineers and the South Florida Water Management District, provided that the report is completed not later than five years after this Act's enactment; and (6) any group of projects under the Plan that the Secretary determines will provide regional or watershed ecosystem or water supply benefits if the group of projects is constructed in accordance with a project implementation report approved by the Chief and the District within that time frame.</summary>
</bill>
