<bill session="111" type="s" number="3613" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey certain Federally owned land located in Story County, Iowa.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2010-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5669"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2010--Introduced.
Requires conveyance of approximately 44 acres of federally owned land administered by the Agricultural Research Service which comprises part of the National Animal Disease Center (the property) in the city of Ames, Iowa, to the city of Ames and its assigns. Requires the city: (1) to pay to the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) the market value of the property, to be determined by an appraisal; and (2) at closing, to pay or reimburse the reasonable transaction and administrative costs associated with the conveyance incurred by the Secretary. Requires the city and the Secretary to bear their own attorneys fees. Requires the Secretary to meet disclosure requirements for hazardous substances, but to otherwise not be required to remediate or abate such substances or any other hazardous pollutants, contaminants, or waste that might be present on the property at the time of closing.</summary>
</bill>
