<bill session="109" type="h" number="4816" updated="2013-07-19T19:46:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 27 of title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the unauthorized construction of tunnels between the United States and another country.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400173"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="2006-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="2006-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4830"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2355"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2652"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3948"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tunnels"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2006--Introduced.
Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit the construction or financing of an unauthorized tunnel or subterranean passage that crosses the international border between the United States and another country. Imposes a 20-year prison term for such offense. Imposes a 20-year prison term on any person who knowingly permits the construction or use of such a tunnel or passage on land that such person owns or controls. Doubles penalties for persons who use such a tunnel or passage to unlawfully smuggle an alien, illegal goods, controlled substances, weapons of mass destruction, or members of a terrorist organization. Subjects to forfeiture any property involved in, or traceable to, the construction or financing of such a tunnel or passage. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to promulgate or amend sentencing guidelines to provide for increased penalties for persons convicted of criminal offenses related to the construction or financing of such a tunnel or passage.</summary>
</bill>
