<bill session="113" type="hc" number="51" updated="2013-11-02T06:49:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Immediate Establishment of Syrian War Crimes Tribunal Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress regarding the need for investigation and prosecution of war crimes, crimes against humanity, and genocide, whether committed by officials of the Government of Syria, or members of other groups involved in civil war in Syria, and calling on the President to direct the United States representative to the United Nations to use the voice and vote of the United States to immediately promote the establishment of a Syrian war crimes tribunal, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412553" joined="2013-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412483" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2013-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1324-1325"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/2013--Introduced.
Immediate Establishment of Syrian War Crimes Tribunal Resolution - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the United States should urge the government of Syria and other groups involved in the civil war in Syria to implement an immediate cease fire and engage in negotiations to end the bloodshed; (2) the United States should declare that it is a requirement of basic justice that war crimes, crimes against humanity, and genocide, whether committed by officials of the government of Syria or members of other groups involved in the civil war in Syria, should be investigated and prosecuted; (3) the President should direct the U.S. representative to the United Nations (U.N.) to promote the establishment of a Syrian war crimes tribunal; (4) in working with other countries to establish a Syrian war crimes tribunal the United States should promote judicial procedures that enable the prosecution of the most culpable persons guilty of directing such crimes; (5) the United States should make an immediate priority the collection of information for use as evidence to support the indictment and trial of any person responsible for war crimes, crimes against humanity, or genocide in Syria; and (6) the United States should urge other interested states to apprehend and deliver into the custody of a Syrian war crimes tribunal persons indicted for war crimes, crimes against humanity, or genocide in Syria, and urge such states to provide relevant information to the tribunal.</summary>
</bill>
