<bill session="111" type="s" number="3944" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Law Enforcement Officers Retirement Equity Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the definition of a law enforcement officer under subchapter III of chapter 83 and chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code, respectively, to ensure the inclusion of certain positions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300073"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="673"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2010--Introduced.
Law Enforcement Officers Retirement Equity Act of 2010 - Redefines the term "law enforcement officer" under provisions of the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) and the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) to include: (1) federal employees not otherwise covered by such term whose duties include the investigation or apprehension of suspected or convicted individuals and who are authorized to carry a firearm; and (2) such employees of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) whose duties are primarily the collection of delinquent taxes and the securing of delinquent tax returns. Requires that service performed by an incumbent law enforcement officer be treated: (1) for all purposes, as service performed as a law enforcement officer, irrespective of how such service is treated for retirement purposes; and (2) for retirement purposes, as service performed as such an officer, but only if an appropriate written election is submitted to the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) five years after the enactment of this Act or before separation from government service, whichever is earlier.</summary>
</bill>
