<bill session="109" type="s" number="2781" updated="2013-07-19T20:37:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wastewater Treatment Works Security Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Wastewater Treatment Works Security Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to enhance the security of wastewater treatment works.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2006-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2006-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4340-4341"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-345. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="625">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 625.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10445-10446"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1995"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Sewerage"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2006--Reported to Senate amended.
Wastewater Treatment Works Security Act of 2006 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to provide grants to any state or local agency or privately owned utility that principally treats municipal wastewater for: (1) a vulnerability assessment of publicly owned treatment works; (2) implementation of security enhancements to reduce identified vulnerabilities; (3) the development, expansion, or upgrading of emergency response plans and site security plans; and (4) the voluntary creation of, or participation in, a mutual aid and emergency network preparedness agreements developed in accordance with the National Incident Management System. Authorizes the Administrator, upon certification that a vulnerability assessment has been completed and that assistance is sought for a security enhancement, to provide grants for: (1) equipment and activities relating to access control, intrusion prevention and delay, and detection of intruders and hazardous or dangerous substances; (2) an activity to improve security for electronic, computer, or other automated systems and remote security systems; (3) security training; and (4) security screening of employees or contractor support services. Prohibits: (1) a grant from being used for personnel costs or for the operation or maintenance of facilities, equipment, or systems; and (2) the Administrator from requiring an applicant to provide the Administrator with a copy of a vulnerability assessment, except to view. Provides for the protection of vulnerability assessment information from unauthorized disclosure. Limits: (1) the federal share of the cost of grant-funded activities for vulnerability assessments and security enhancements to 50%; and (2) the total amount of such grants for publicly owned treatment works to $100,000. Authorizes the Administrator to: (1) provide technical guidance to small publicly owned treatment works (serving fewer than 10,000 individuals) for a vulnerability assessment, emergency response plan, or site security plan and for implementing security enhancements; and (2) make grants to nonprofit organizations to improve assessment methodologies for publicly owned treatment works and to implement a comprehensive training program for treatment works or privately owned utilities that principally treat municipal wastewater. (Sec. 3) Requires the Administrator to research and review: (1) means of providing alternative processes to convey, treat, and dispose of wastewater if a disruption of service event occurs; (2) means by which a collection system of a treatment works could be used to convey hazardous substances and secured in response to an intentional harmful act; (3) methods for monitoring a collection system for hazardous substances and unauthorized entry; and (4) treatment technologies. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
