<bill session="112" type="h" number="1635" updated="2013-07-20T01:24:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ponzi Scheme Victims' Tax Relief Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide special rules for investments lost in a fraudulent Ponzi-type scheme.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400038" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2011-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2012-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2011-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400280" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2011-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2011--Introduced.
Ponzi Scheme Victims' Tax Relief Act of 2011- Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) a special theft loss tax deduction for qualified fraudulent investment losses and for such losses in connection with assets held in an individual retirement account (IRA); (2) a carryback of net operating losses which are qualified fraudulent investment losses for up to 10 years; (3) withdrawals from tax-exempt retirement plans for a 10-year period without penalty to replace qualified fraudulent investment losses; (4) catch-up contributions to retirement plans to compensate for fraudulent investment losses; and (5) an extension of the limitation period for filing refund claims for overpayments of tax in connection with gifts and bequests of an interest in an investment for which there is a qualified fraudulent investment loss. Defines "qualified fraudulent investment loss" as a loss discovered in 2008 or 2009 resulting from a fraudulent arrangement in which a person receives cash or property from investors, purports to earn income for investors, reports partially or wholly fictitious income to such investors, makes payments to some investors from payments made by other investors, and appropriates some or all of the investors' cash or property. Waives for a one-year period after the enactment of this Act the application of any law or rule of law (including res judicata) which prevents any credit or refund otherwise allowed by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
