<bill session="111" type="h" number="4053" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Kids Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Office of Childhood Overweight and Obesity Prevention and Treatment within the Office of Public Health and Science of the Department of Health and Human Services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2009-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2748-2749"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/6/2009--Introduced.
Healthy Kids Act - Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate rules that define advertising, promoting, and marketing directed at children and that specify categories of foods and beverages for which advertising, promotion, or marketing directed at children shall be an abusive, unfair, or deceptive act or practice in or affecting commerce. Repeals the restriction on FTC rulemaking authority relating to children's advertising. Amends the Children's Television Act of 1990 to direct the FTC to revise its regulations with respect to children's television programming to limit the amount of time devoted to advertising foods and beverages of low nutritional value. Amends the Public Health Service Act to: (1) establish within the Office of Public Health and Science of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) the Office of Childhood Overweight and Obesity Prevention and Treatment (Office); and (2) direct the Secretary to establish and carry out a matching grant program to assist the Office in gathering data on childhood obesity and to carry out demonstration programs to reduce the incidence of childhood obesity. Amends the Childhood Nutrition and WIC Reauthorization Act of 2004 to include the Office in providing technical assistance to schools and educational agencies for developing and implementing local wellness policy. Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to require the Secretary to prescribe regulations for identifying healthy and unhealthy foods and beverages for children in schools and service institutions. Amends titles XIX (Medicaid) and XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program) (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP) of the Social Security Act to include in early and periodic screening, diagnostic, and treatment services obesity prevention, nutritional counseling, and other services for obesity.</summary>
</bill>
