<bill session="110" type="h" number="5154" updated="2013-07-19T21:49:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To condition further increases in the minimum wage applicable to American Samoa and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands on a determination by the Secretary of Labor that such increases will not have an adverse impact on the economies of American Samoa and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400128"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-01-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economic research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Standard of living"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/29/2008--Introduced.
Amends the U.S. Troop Readiness, Veterans' Care, Katrina Recovery, and Iraq Accountability Appropriations Act, 2007 to condition further increases in the federal minimum wage applicable to the Commonwealth of Northern Mariana Islands and American Samoa on a determination by the Secretary of Labor that such increases will not have an adverse impact on any further increases on living standards and rates of employment in the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands and American Samoa. Requires the Secretary to make the determinations each year 60 days before the scheduled increase in such minimum wage and to publish it in the Federal Register. Directs the Secretary to study and report to Congress biennially (currently, within eight months after the enactment of such Act) on the impact of: (1) such minimum wage increases; and (2) any further increases on living standards and rates of employment in the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands and American Samoa.</summary>
</bill>
