<bill session="109" type="h" number="5019" updated="2013-07-19T19:48:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wallowa Lake Dam Rehabilitation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Bureau of Reclamation to participate in the rehabilitation of the Wallowa Lake Dam in Oregon, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400419"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-05">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="231"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/28/2006--Introduced.
Wallowa Lake Dam Rehabilitation Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to provide grants to, or enter into cooperative or other agreements with, tribal, state, and local governmental entities and the Associated Ditch Companies, Incorporated (ADC) (nonprofit corporation that operates the Wallowa Lake Dam) to plan, design, and construct facilities needed to implement the Wallowa Lake Dam Rehabilitation Program. Directs the Secretary, as a condition of providing funds, to ensure that: (1) the Rehabilitation Program meets the standards of the dam safety program of Oregon; (2) ADC agrees to assume liability for any work performed or supervised with federal funds provided to it under this Act; and (3) the United States shall not be liable for damages arising out of any act relating to a facility rehabilitated or constructed with federal funds provided under this Act, both while and after activities are conducted using such funds. Limits the federal share of the cost of activities authorized under this Act to 50%. Prohibits the federal government from holding title to, or being responsible for the operation and maintenance of, any facility rehabilitated or constructed under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
