<bill session="109" type="h" number="5609" updated="2013-07-19T19:53:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require automobile dealers to disclose to consumers the presence of event data recorders, or "black boxes", on new automobiles, and to require manufacturers to provide the consumer with the option to enable and disable such devices on future automobiles.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2006-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronics"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/2006--Introduced.
Requires automobile dealers to disclose to each consumer at the time of purchase of a new automobile, and to include in the automobile's owner's manual, information on: (1) the presence and location of an event data recorder (EDR) in such automobile; and (2) the type of information recorded by the EDR, how such information is recorded, and the possible use of such information in law enforcement proceedings. Requires the EDR and any data recorded to be considered the property of the vehicle owner. Prohibits the retrieval of EDR data by anyone other than the vehicle owner, except : (1) with the owner's consent; (2) in response to a court order; (3) by a vehicle dealer or an automotive technician for servicing the vehicle; or (4) for improving vehicle safety, provided the identity of the registered owner or driver is not disclosed. Prohibits persons from manufacturing automobiles for sale in the United States after 2008 (bearing a model year of 2009 or later) that are equipped with EDRs, unless those EDRs can be disabled by the consumer. Treats a violation of EDR requirements of this Act as an unfair or deceptive act or practice under the Federal Trade Commission Act.</summary>
</bill>
