<bill session="111" type="h" number="2669" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Better Oversight of Secondary Sales and Accountability in Concert Ticketing Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Federal Trade Commission to prescribe rules to protect consumers from unfair and deceptive acts and practices in connection with primary and secondary ticket sales.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2009-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2010-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2009-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2009-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/2/2009--Introduced.
Better Oversight of Secondary Sales and Accountability in Concert Ticketing Act of 2009 - Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate rules regarding the primary sale, distribution, and pricing of tickets, including regarding: (1) disclosing the number of tickets and the distribution method; (2) printing the date and time of sale on each ticket; (3) disclosure on the seller's website or in promotional material of all ancillary charges; and (4) inclusion of all ancillary charges in any refund. Requires the FTC to promulgate rules regarding the secondary sale, distribution, and pricing of tickets, including regarding: (1) disclosure if the secondary seller does not possess the ticket at the time of the sale; (2) purchase by a secondary seller during the first 48 hours of ticket availability; (3) disclosure of the distribution method, the face value of each ticket, and the location of the seat or space involved; (4) disclosure that an online marketplace is for secondary sale; (5) resale for a price higher than face value; and (6) disclosure by an online marketplace when the secondary seller is the primary seller, venue, or artist involved. Requires secondary sellers and online resale marketplaces to register with the FTC. Treats a violation as an unfair or deceptive act or practice under of the Federal Trade Commission Act and requires the FTC to enforce this Act. Allows states to bring civil enforcement actions. Allows state and local laws that provide equal or greater protection to consumers.</summary>
</bill>
