<bill session="113" type="s" number="1124" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BPA in Food Packaging Right to Know Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish requirements with respect to bisphenol A.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2013-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2013--Introduced.
BPA in Food Packaging Right to Know Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) issue a revised safety assessment for food containers composed of bisphenol A (BPA), taking into consideration different types of such containers and the use of such containers with respect to different foods; and (2) determine whether there is a reasonable certainty that no harm will result from aggregate exposure to BPA through food containers or other items composed of BPA, taking into consideration potential adverse effects from low-dose exposure and the effects of exposure on vulnerable populations, including pregnant women, infants, children, the elderly, and populations with high exposure to BPA. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to deem a food to be misbranded if its container is composed in whole or in part of BPA, unless the label includes the following statement: "This food packaging contains BPA, an endocrine-disrupting chemical."</summary>
</bill>
