<bill session="110" type="s" number="3020" updated="2013-07-19T22:47:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Food and Drug Administration Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to the postmarket surveillance of devices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2008--Introduced.
Food and Drug Administration Accountability and Transparency Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to publish in the Federal Register postmarket surveillance plans for medical devices, unless such information is exempted under the Freedom of Information Act. Subjects medical device manufacturers that fail to comply with postmarket surveillance requirements to civil monetary penalties. Requires the Secretary to take into consideration whether the manufacturer is making efforts toward correcting the violation in determining the amount of the civil penalty. Authorizes the Secretary to order notification of health personnel and other relevant persons if a violation of postmarket surveillance requirements of a device presents an unreasonable risk of substantial harm to the public health, such notification is necessary to eliminate such risk, and no more practicable means is available to eliminate such risk.</summary>
</bill>
