<bill session="109" type="s" number="526" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Care Quality Incentive Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to provide incentive grants to improve the quality of child care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2037-2038"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2038-2039" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2005--Introduced.
Child Care Quality Incentive Act of 2005 - Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to revise requirements relating to child care payment rates. Requires States to conduct market rate surveys, at least once every two years, to determine their child care payment rates under the block grant program, including cost-of-living adjustments and consideration of variations in localities, children's ages, and types of services. Establishes a program of incentive grants to States and Indian tribes to improve the quality of, and access to, child care by increasing child care payment rates. Makes separate appropriations for such incentive grants in specified amounts for FY 2006 through FY 2010 (prohibiting use of block grant funds for such incentive grants). Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make an annual incentive grant payment to an eligible State only if the State has conducted a statistically valid survey of the market rates for child care services in the State within the two years before it submits an application containing information on such survey and the State's plans to increase its child care payment rates. Requires an eligible State that receives such a grant to make priority use of its funds to increase significantly (up to the 100th percentile of the market rate survey) the rate of reimbursement to providers for subsidized child care (with any remaining funds to be used to improve the quality of child care services). Requires a State matching contribution of at least 20 percent of incentive grant program activity costs.</summary>
</bill>
