<bill session="111" type="h" number="6502" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Beneficiary Preservation of Choice Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To preserve Medicare beneficiary choice by restoring and expanding the Medicare open enrollment and disenrollment opportunities repealed by section 3204(a) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400152"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400657" joined="2010-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="4040"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2010--Introduced.
Medicare Beneficiary Preservation of Choice Act of 2010 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to repeal the allowance for disenrollment, between January 1 and March 15 of each year, only from an MedicareAdvantage plan to elect enrollment in the original Medicare fee-for-service program. Restores the option under previous law to elect to change from a MedicareAdvantage to the original Medicare fee-for-service plan, or from the original Medicare fee-for-service to a MedicareAdvantage plan, once a year during the first three months.</summary>
</bill>
