<bill session="113" type="s" number="841" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hermosa Creek Watershed Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain Federal land in the San Juan National Forest in the State of Colorado as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2013-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1839"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2013--Introduced.
Hermosa Creek Watershed Protection Act of 2013 - Designates specified federal lands in San Juan National Forest in Colorado as: (1) the Hermosa Creek Watershed and Protection Area, and (2) the Hermosa Creek Special Management Area. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to develop a management plan for the long-term protection and management of the Special Management Area. Designates specified land within the Protection Area as the Hermosa Creek Wilderness. Directs the Secretary of the Interior, upon the expiration of a specified permit, to convey to La Plata County, Colorado, identified land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in the Tres Rios District in Colorado. Requires such land to be used only for public purposes consistent with the uses allowed under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act. Requires the County to: (1) pay all survey costs and other administrative costs necessary for preparing and completing patents for, and transfers of title to, such land; and (2) agree in writing to pay administrative costs associated with such conveyance, including the costs of environmental, wildlife, cultural, or historical resources studies. Releases the West Needles Contiguous Wilderness Study Area in San Juan County, Colorado, from further study for designation as wilderness.</summary>
</bill>
