<bill session="111" type="h" number="4483" updated="2013-07-19T23:52:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Taxpayers from Excessive Compensation Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit compensation for any officer or employee of the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, during any conservatorship or receivership of such enterprise, in an amount exceeding the compensation provided to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff of the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412202"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/20/2010--Introduced.
Protecting Taxpayers from Excessive Compensation Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 to direct the Federal Housing Finance Agency, in its capacity as conservator or receiver of a government-sponsored enterprise (Federal National Mortgage Association [Fannie Mae] or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation [Freddie Mac]), to prohibit the provision of compensation to any employee, officer, or executive officer of such enterprise, for any period during such conservatorship or receivership, in an amount exceeding the rate of basic pay at such time for the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff of the Armed Forces.</summary>
</bill>
