<bill session="111" type="h" number="6363" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Supporting Law Enforcement through Lessons of the Holocaust Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Attorney General to establish a competitive grant program for State and local law enforcement agencies to carry out training programs based on lessons from the Holocaust.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="World history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Supporting Law Enforcement through Lessons of the Holocaust Act - Directs the Attorney General to establish a competitive grant program for state and local law enforcement agencies to carry out training programs on the implications of the Holocaust for modern day law enforcement professionals. Requires any training program funded by this Act to examine: (1) the implications of the history of the Holocaust for individuals who are active law enforcement professionals on or after the enactment of this Act; (2) the relationship of law enforcement professionals to their communities; (3) the role and responsibility of law enforcement officials as protectors of the Constitution and civil liberties; (4) the procedures and practices that prevent abuse of the roles of law enforcement professionals; and (5) the core values of law enforcement and the connection of those values to Constitutional principles.</summary>
</bill>
