<bill session="111" type="h" number="3781" updated="2013-07-19T23:46:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Target Practice and Marksmanship Training Support Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act to facilitate the establishment of additional or expanded public target ranges in certain States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412234" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412262" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2009-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400096" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412188" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2010-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2009-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412300" joined="2009-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412332" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412301" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400620" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412316" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2010-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1702"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2009--Introduced.
Target Practice and Marksmanship Training Support Act - Amends the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act to: (1) authorize a state to pay up to 90% of the costs of acquiring land for, expanding, or constructing a public target range; (2) authorize a state to elect to allocate 10% of a specified amount apportioned to it from the federal aid to wildlife restoration fund for such costs; (3) limit the federal share of such costs under such Act to 90%; and (4) require amounts provided for such costs under such Act to remain available for expenditure and obligation for five fiscal years. Shields the United States from any civil action or claim for money damages for injury to or loss of property, personal injury, or death caused by an activity occurring at a public target range that is funded by the federal government pursuant to such Act or located on federal land, except to the extent provided under the Federal Tort Claims Act with respect to the exercise or performance of a discretionary function. Urges the Chief of the Forest Service and the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to cooperate with state and local authorities and other entities to carry out waste removal and other activities on any federal land used as a public target range in order to encourage its continued use for target practice or marksmanship training.</summary>
</bill>
