<bill session="111" type="h" number="1649" updated="2013-07-19T23:26:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">High-Quality Education Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Education to make grants to reduce the size of core curriculum classes in public elementary and secondary schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400270"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2009--Introduced.
High-Quality Education Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award matching grants to states, or local educational agencies (LEAs) in states that do not receive such grants, to reduce the size of core curriculum classes in public elementary and secondary schools. Requires such grants to be provided only to states or LEAs serving schools whose average core curriculum class size is greater than 18 students in kindergarten through grade 3, 22 students in grades 4 through 8, and 25 students in grades 9 through 12. Requires grant funds to be used for: (1) constructing new classroom space; (2) hiring additional teachers; and (3) purchasing portable structures to replace administrative offices that are converted into classrooms. Permits the Secretary to give grant priority to states or LEAs serving schools: (1) where over 17% of the students between age 4 and 18 are from impoverished families; or (2) whose average core curriculum class size is higher than the average core curriculum class size of schools served by other applicants.</summary>
</bill>
