<bill session="111" type="hr" number="489" updated="2013-07-19T23:00:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-02T19:21:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-06-02T19:21:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing the twentieth anniversary of the suppression of protesters and citizens in and around Tiananmen Square in Beijing, People's Republic of China, on June 3 and 4, 1989 and expressing sympathy to the families of those killed, tortured, and imprisoned in connection with the democracy protests in Tiananmen Square and other parts of China on June 3 and 4, 1989 and thereafter.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400238"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412300" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2009-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02T17:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Levin moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02T17:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6040-6049" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02T17:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 489.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6050-6051" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-06-02T19:21:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="294" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 396 - 1 (Roll no. 294).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6040-6041" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02T19:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/2/2009--Passed House without amendment.
Expresses sympathy to the families of those killed, tortured, and imprisoned as a result of their participation in the democracy protests in Tiananmen Square and elsewhere in China on June 3 and 4, 1989, and to those persons who have suffered for their peaceful efforts to keep that struggle alive during the last two decades. Calls on the People's Republic of China (PRC) to: (1) invite independent investigations into the Tiananmen Square crackdown; (2) end its harassment and detention against those who were involved in the 1989 protests and against those who continue to advocate peacefully for political reform such as Mr. Liu Xiaobo and his wife, Liu Xia; and (3) allow protest participants who escaped to or are living in exile in the United States and other countries to return to China without risk of retribution. Calls on the legal authorities of the PRC to review immediately the cases of those still imprisoned for participating in the 1989 protests and to release those individuals imprisoned solely for peacefully exercising their internationally-recognized rights. Calls on the Administration and Congress to mark the 20th anniversary of Tiananmen Square by meeting with participants in the demonstrations who are living in the United States or elsewhere outside of China, supporting those in China who demand an accounting of the June 1989 events, and supporting those advocating for democratic governance in China.</summary>
</bill>
