<bill session="111" type="s" number="1257" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Project 2020: Building on the Promise of Home and Community-Based Services Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Social Security Act to build on the aging network to establish long-term services and supports through single-entry point systems, evidence based disease prevention and health promotion programs, and enhanced nursing home diversion programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2009-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6564"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6564-6568" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2852"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2009--Introduced.
Project 2020: Building on the Promise of Home and Community-Based Services Act of 2009 - Amends the Social Security Act (SSA) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a single-entry point system of grants to states for their own single-entry point systems providing information and counseling about public and private long-term services and supports. Directs the Secretary to establish a healthy living program, with grants to state agencies for the federal share of the cost of carrying out evidence-based disease prevention and health promotion programs. Directs the Secretary to establish a diversion program of grants to states for the federal share of the cost of carrying out enhanced nursing home diversion programs enabling individuals ineligible for medical assistance under SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to avoid admission into nursing homes by helping them to obtain alternative home and community-based long-term services and supports.</summary>
</bill>
