<bill session="110" type="h" number="792" updated="2013-07-19T21:10:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Growing Responsible Energy and Environment Nationally through Federal Energy Decisions Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to direct the head of each Federal agency to ensure that, in areas in which ethanol-blended gasoline is reasonably available at a generally competitive price, the Federal agency purchases ethanol-blended gasoline containing at least 10 percent ethanol rather than nonethanol-blended gasoline, for use in vehicles used by the agency that use gasoline.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400429"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E238"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO24" subcommittee="Government Management, Organization, and Procurement" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Agricultural wastes"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Energy crops"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Oils and fats"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2007--Introduced.
Growing Responsible Energy and Environment Nationally through Federal Energy Decisions Act - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to repeal a certain lease charge reduction incentive program for encouraging federal agencies to use alternative fueled vehicles. Requires the head of each federal agency to ensure that, in areas in which ethanol-blended gasoline or biodiesel-blended diesel fuel is reasonably available at a generally competitive price, the agency purchases for use in appropriate vehicles: (1) ethanol-blended gasoline containing at least 10% ethanol rather than nonethanol-blended gasoline; and (2) biodiesel-blended diesel fuel containing at least 2% biodiesel within five years, and 20% biodiesel within 10 years.</summary>
</bill>
