<bill session="113" type="h" number="1883" updated="2013-11-02T06:34:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Firearms Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a deduction for the purchase of secure gun storage or safety device for the securing of firearms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400657" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2013-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2013-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2013--Introduced.
Secure Firearms Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow individual taxpayers a deduction, up to $1,200 in any taxable year, for the cost of secure gun storage or safety devices for the securing of firearms. Defines "secure gun storage or safety device" as: (1) a device that, when installed on a firearm, is designed to prevent the firearm from being operated; or (2) a safe, gun safe, gun case, lock box, or other device used to store a firearm that can only be unlocked by a key, a combination, or other similar means. Terminates such deduction after 2014. Requires that an amount equal to all amounts allowed as a deduction by this Act be rescinded each year from the Department of Justice (DOJ) Assets Forfeiture Fund.</summary>
</bill>
