<bill session="110" type="h" number="6038" updated="2013-07-19T21:56:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to direct the President to modernize the integrated public alert and warning system of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2008-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2008-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="2008-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6392"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2008--Introduced.
Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2008 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to direct the President, acting through the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), to: (1) modernize and implement the integrated U.S. public alert and warning system to ensure that the President can alert governmental authorities and the civilian population in areas endangered by disasters under all conditions; (2) assign to the National Continuity Programs Directorate responsibility for advising on system modernization and implementation; (3) establish or adopt common alerting and warning protocols, standards, terminology, and operating procedures; (4) include in such system the capability to adapt the distribution and content of communications on the basis of geographic location, risks, or personal user preferences and to alert individuals with disabilities or limited English proficiency; and (5) ensure the conduct of training, tests, and exercises.Requires the system to: (1) incorporate multiple communications technologies; (2) be designed to adapt to and incorporate future technologies for communicating directly with the public; (3) be designed to provide alerts to the largest portion of the affected population feasible and improve the ability of remote areas to receive alerts; (4) promote local and regional partnerships to enhance community preparedness and response; and (5) provide redundant alert mechanisms.Requires the Director to conduct pilot programs to demonstrate the feasibility of using a variety of methods for achieving system requirements.</summary>
</bill>
