<bill session="109" type="h" number="4253" updated="2013-07-19T19:41:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Illegal Alien Transport and Removal Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to transport and remove aliens unlawfully present in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2005-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2005-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2005-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-08">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Border Security, and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/2005--Introduced.
Illegal Alien Transport and Removal Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to contract with private entities to provide secure domestic transport of aliens who are apprehended at or along the international land or maritime borders from Border Patrol custody to detention facilities and other locations as necessary. States that the extension of removal period provision under the Immigration and Nationality Act shall not be construed as preventing the Secretary from removing an alien from the United States if the alien has failed or refused to make timely application in good faith for travel or other documents necessary to the alien's departure or conspires or acts to prevent the alien's removal subject to an order of removal.</summary>
</bill>
