<bill session="109" type="h" number="3649" updated="2013-07-19T19:36:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-29">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sportfishing and Recreational Boating Safety Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Sportfishing and Recreational Boating Safety Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Sportfishing and Recreational Boating Safety Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Sportfishing and Recreational Boating Safety Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure funding for sportfishing and boating safety programs funded out of the Highway Trust Fund through the end of fiscal year 2005, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2005-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-06">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-13T14:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Shuster moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-13T14:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7823-7825" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-13T14:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3649.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-13T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-13T18:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7833-7834" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-09-13T19:03:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="466" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 401 - 1 (Roll no. 466).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7823-7824" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-13T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10067" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2005-09-15" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-20T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Boustany moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8116-8117" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-20T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 3649.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-09-20T15:30:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H8116-8117" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-20T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-09-20">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-09-29">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-09-29" type="public" number="109-74">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-74.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Sewage disposal"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1723"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/29/2005--Public Law.
Sportfishing and Recreational Boating Safety Amendments Act of 2005 - Title I: Corrections to the Sportfishing and Recreational Boating Safety Act of 2005 - (Sec. 101) Amends the Sportfishing and Recreational Boating Safety Act of 2005 (SRBA) to make October 1, 2005, the effective date of such Act in its entirety, not just its amendments to the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act. Preserves until the end of FY2005, as though unamended, certain provisions of law otherwise amended by SRBA. (Sec. 102) Increases the authorization of appropriations from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) to the Secretary of Transportation for payment of expenses of the Coast Guard for personnel and activities directly related to coordinating and carrying out the national recreational boating safety program. Decreases the amount of authorized appropriations available to the Secretary for activities to ensure compliance with safety standards for recreational vessels. (Sec. 103) Revises requirements for the apportionment of the remaining balance in the Boat Safety Account for FY2006-FY2010. Title II: Extension of Recreational Boating Funding Through the End of Fiscal Year 2005 - (Sec. 201) Amends the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act to extend through FY2005 the authorization of appropriations from the HTF for: (1) the national outreach and communications program; and (2) qualified projects under the Clean Vessel Act of 1992. (Sec. 203) Conforms the authorization of appropriations to the Coast Guard for the national recreational boating safety program with the increase under title I of this Act. Title III: Extension of Authorization For Use of Funds In Boat Safety Account - (Sec. 301) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend through FY2005 the authorization of expenditures from the Boat Safety Account to carry out state recreational boating safety programs. (Sec. 302) Declares that the obligation authority for funds made available under the Transportation, Treasury, Independent Agencies, and General Government Appropriations Act, 2005 (the Act) for expenses necessary to discharge the functions of the Secretary of Transportation with respect to traffic and highway safety shall be available in an amount equal to the funds provided. Requires the additional obligation authority needed to meet such requirement to be withdrawn from the obligation authority previously distributed to other surface transportation programs, projects, and activities funded from an amount (of up to 4.1%) deducted from various transportation programs under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
