<bill session="109" type="h" number="1722" updated="2013-07-19T19:19:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Education to revise regulations to increase the percentage of proficient and advanced level scores based on alternate assessments and alternate achievement standards for purposes of calculating adequate yearly progress, to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to decrease the percentage of students who meet or exceed the proficient level of academic achievement on State assessments required to calculate adequate yearly progress, to direct the Secretary of Education to expand to two years the exclusion for second year limited English proficiency students from adequate yearly progress calculations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400045"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2005-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2005-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Education Reform" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Immigrant education"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/20/2005--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Education to revise certain regulations to increase, from one to three percent, the number of proficient and advanced level scores based on alternate assessments and alternate achievement standards for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities that may be counted in calculating adequate yearly progress (AYP) for schools, local educational agencies, and States, under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 as amended by the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001 (ESEA-NCLBA). Amends ESEA-NCLBA to lower from ten to seven percent the amount of the decrease, in the percentage in a school year from the preceding school year, of students in any of specified groups who did not meet or exceed the proficient level of academic achievement on the State assessments, which is required under certain conditions for a school to be considered to have made AYP. Requires the Secretary to issue policy guidance directing that the assessment results of first-year and second-year limited English proficiency students who are recently resettled refugees and who take the reading-language arts assessment are not required to be included in AYP determinations, even if such students have been enrolled in the school or district for one or two full academic years.</summary>
</bill>
