<bill session="111" type="h" number="5562" updated="2013-07-20T00:02:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeland Security Grant Management Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Homeland Security Grant Management Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to prohibit requiring the use of a specified percentage of a grant under the Urban Area Security Initiative and State Homeland Security Grant Program for specific purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2010-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-11-30T15:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 111-663.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-11-30T15:45:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="395">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 395.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/30/2010--Reported to House without amendment.
Homeland Security Grant Management Improvement Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to prohibit the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) from requiring the recipient of a grant under the Urban Area Security Initiative or the State Homeland Security Grant Program to use a specified percentage of such grant for any one of the specified permitted uses.Directs the Administrator to: (1) study the use of grant funds for administrative expenses; (2) determine whether 3% of the grant amount is adequate to ensure proper oversight, management, and administration of the grant; and (3) report recommendations on whether such percentage should be adjusted to better reflect administrative costs to grant recipients. Requires the Administrator to study the feasibility, advantages, and disadvantages of issuing multiyear program guidance for such grants.</summary>
</bill>
