<bill session="109" type="h" number="5303" updated="2013-07-19T19:51:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Depleted Uranium Munitions Suspension and Study Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the suspension of the use, sale, development, production, testing, and export of depleted uranium munitions pending the outcome of certain studies of the health effects of such munitions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400513"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman .</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Ordnance"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Plutonium"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smoke"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2006--Introduced.
Depleted Uranium Munitions Suspension and Study Act of 2006 - Requires the Secretary of Defense to direct that all elements of the Department of Defense (DOD) suspend use of depleted uranium munitions until the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) certifies to certain congressional committees that use of such munitions in future conflicts: (1) will not pose a likely long-term or residual threat to the health of U.S. or NATO military personnel; and (2) will not jeopardize the health of civilian populations in the area of such use. Suspends federal approval of the foreign sale or export of munitions containing depleted uranium until the Secretary of HHS has made such certification. Limits future exports to stocks certified free of transuranic matter by the Secretary of Defense. Requires the Comptroller General to investigate and report to Congress on the contamination of stocks of depleted uranium munitions with transuranic elements. Requires the Director of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention jointly to conduct a comprehensive study of the health effects of exposure to depleted uranium munitions on veterans and on their children born after their respective exposures to uranium. Directs the Secretary of Defense to provide to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (Administrator) a list and maps of all sites in the United States where depleted uranium munitions have been used or produced. Requires the Administrator to study and report to Congress and the Secretary of Defense on the possible depleted uranium contamination of the soil, air, water, and vegetation of each listed site. Directs the Secretary of Defense to develop a plan for mitigation and cleanup at each site.</summary>
</bill>
