<bill session="111" type="s" number="3810" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gulf Security and Iran Sanctions Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to restrict participation in offshore oil and gas leasing by a person who engages in any activity for which sanctions may be imposed under section 5 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996, to require the lessee under an offshore oil and gas lease to disclose any participation by the lessee in certain energy-related joint ventures, investments, or partnerships located outside Iran, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2010-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6043"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2010--Introduced.
Gulf Security and Iran Sanctions Enforcement Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to include in each lease issued after enactment of this Act that authorizes oil and gas drilling on the Outer Continental Shelf a provision that requires: (1) the lessee to certify annually to the Secretary that it does not engage in any activity for which sanctions may be imposed under the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996; and (2) the Secretary to cancel the lease if the lessee fails to make such a certification or makes a false one. Requires such a lease also to require the lessee to disclose to the Secretary any participation in any energy-related joint venture, investment, or partnership located outside Iran that involves: (1) any person whose property and property interests are blocked pursuant to Executive Orders 13224 (for transacting business with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism) or 13382 (because they are weapons of mass destruction proliferators or their supporters); or (2) any entity on a specified list relating to Iranian Transactions Regulations. Requires cancellation of any lease whose lessee has failed to make such a disclosure or makes a false disclosure. Allows a national interest waiver of these requirements.</summary>
</bill>
