<bill session="112" type="h" number="4116" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regulatory Accountability and Economic Freedom Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for regulatory accountability and for the revision of economically burdensome regulations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400234"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, the Budget, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="10"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6333"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="299"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2012--Introduced.
Regulatory Accountability and Economic Freedom Act of 2012 - Revises criteria for the federal agency rule making process. Requires federal agencies proposing a rule to make all preliminary and final factual determinations based on evidence and to consider: (1) the legal authority under which a rule may be proposed, (2) the specific nature and significance of the problem the agency may address with a rule, (3) any reasonable alternatives for a new rule, and (4) the potential costs and benefits associated with potential alternative rules. Requires agencies to publish in the Federal Register advance notice of proposed rule making for major rules, high-impact rules, and rules involving novel legal or policy issues. Defines "major rule" as any rule that is likely to impose: (1) an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more, adjusted annually for inflation; (2) a major increase in costs or prices; (3) significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or U.S. competitiveness; or (4) significant impacts on multiple sectors of the economy. Defines "high-impact rule" as any rule that is likely to impose an annual cost on the economy of $1 billion or more, adjusted annually for inflation. Rewrites provisions for congressional review of agency rule making to require congressional approval of major rules before they may take effect (currently, major rules take effect unless Congress passes and the President signs a joint resolution disapproving them). Sets forth House and Senate procedures for enacting joint resolutions approving major rules and disapproving non-major rules. Establishes the United States Red Tape Reduction Commission to advise federal agencies on the modification, consolidation, or elimination of federal regulatory requirements to reduce direct or indirect burdens on U.S. businesses.</summary>
</bill>
