<bill session="113" type="s" number="810" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jacob Sexton Military Suicide Prevention Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a pilot program on an online computerized assessment to enhance detection of behaviors indicating a risk of suicide and other mental health conditions in members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2013-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3031-3032"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2013--Introduced.
Jacob Sexton Military Suicide Prevention Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress that, as the United States draws down combat operations in Afghanistan, the Department of Defense (DOD) should continue to seek to assist in the identification of behavior indicating a risk of suicide in members of the Armed Forces (members). Directs the Secretary of Defense to carry out a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of using an online computerized assessment to assist DOD in detecting behaviors in members that indicate a risk of suicide or other mental health conditions. Requires: (1) 1,000 members of each regular component and 500 members of each reserve and National Guard component to be used in the pilot program, and (2) each participating member to complete two assessments. Requires the first superior officer of each participating member to also complete a computerized assessment on the behavior of that member as it relates to the risk of suicide or other mental health conditions. Requires each member determined under the pilot program to have behavior indicating a risk of suicide or other mental health conditions to be referred to an appropriate mental health care provider for further assessment, care, and services. Directs the Secretary to establish one or more control groups whose behavior permit comparison with the behavior and experiences of the participants. Provides for the privacy of any medical or other information obtained under the pilot program. Prohibits information obtained from being used in determining the promotion or advancement of the member. Excludes the use of participant personally identifiable information in any required report.</summary>
</bill>
