<bill session="112" type="h" number="4056" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Science and Technology Regulatory Relief Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prevent a State or political subdivision thereof from conducting or requiring duplicative inspections of establishments in which a drug or device is manufactured, processed, packed, or held by a manufacturer or wholesale distributor of the drug or device.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2012-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2012--Introduced.
Science and Technology Regulatory Relief Act of 2012 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prohibit a state or political subdivision from conducting or requiring an inspection of a factory, warehouse, or establishment in which a drug or device is manufactured, processed, packed, or held by a manufacturer or wholesale distributor for introduction into interstate commerce, or after such introduction, for purposes of verifying compliance with such Act, Public Health Service Act requirements regarding the regulation of biological products, or any similar requirements established pursuant to state law. Makes exceptions for such an inspection if: (1) the state or subdivision makes a determination that a drug or device presents a threat of serious adverse health consequences or death; (2) the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) orders a recall of a drug, biological product, or device manufactured, processed, packed, or held at the factory, warehouse, or establishment; or (3) the Secretary requests or authorizes the state to conduct or require the inspection.</summary>
</bill>
