<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1320" updated="2013-07-19T23:07:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-05T14:20:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-05-05T14:20:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing support for the vigilance and prompt response of the citizens of New York City, the New York Police Department, the New York Police Department Bomb Squad, the Fire Department of New York, other first responders, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, United States Customs and Border Protection, the United States Attorney's Office for the Southern District of New York, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Justice, the New York Joint Terrorism Task Force, the Bridgeport Police Department, Detective Bureau, Patrol Division, and other law enforcement agencies in Connecticut to the attempted terrorist attack in Times Square on May 1, 2010, their exceptional professionalism and investigative work following the attempted attack, and their consistent commitment to preparedness for and collective response to terrorism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412296"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412264" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412224" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412291" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412297" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412332" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2010-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T11:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pascrell moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T11:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3140-3144" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T11:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1320.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T11:33:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3166-3167" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-05-05T14:20:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="246" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 418 - 0 (Roll no. 246).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3140" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2010--Passed House amended.
Commends Lance Orton and Duane Jackson for promptly alerting authorities about the suspicious vehicle involved in the attempted terrorist attack at Times Square on May 1, 2010. Urges: (1) all Americans to remain vigilant about potential terrorist or suspicious activity within their communities and to report such activity to the appropriate authorities; and (2) all federal agencies to continue to work with state, local, and tribal partners to bolster preparedness for and prevention of terrorism. Recognizes the New York City Police Department and its bomb squad, the Fire Department of New York, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), the United States Customs and Border Protection, the United States Attorney's Office for the Southern District of New York, the Departments of Justice (DOJ) and Homeland Security (DHS), the New York Joint Terrorism Task Force, the Bridgeport Police Department, Detective Bureau, Patrol Division, and other Connecticut law enforcement agencies for their commitment in responding to terrorism and their work in apprehending a suspect only 53 hours after the attempted bombing.</summary>
</bill>
