<bill session="111" type="h" number="5931" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Renewable Energy Incentive Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for the development of solar energy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412188" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412187" joined="2010-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2010-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3136"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5252"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2899"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2010--Introduced.
Renewable Energy Incentive Act - Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to: (1) extend the grant program for investment in renewable energy property, including renewable resources used to produce electricity, and fuel cell, solar, wind, geothermal, and microturbine property, in lieu of tax credits, by extending the placed-in-service deadline for such property through 2012; and (2) expand eligibility for such grants to certain state power utilities and tax-exempt mutual or cooperative electric companies. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow an energy tax credit for investment in qualified solar manufacturing project property; (2) allow a tax credit for the purchase, consolidation, and use of contiguous high solarity disturbed private land to produce solar energy for use in a trade or business; and (3) limit the energy tax credit for solar energy equipment used to generate electricity or heat or cool a structure, as applied to swimming pools, to exclude those located at single-family residences. Defines "qualified solar manufacturing project property" as any tangible personal property purchased to re-equip, expand, or establish a manufacturing facility for producing solar energy equipment to generate electricity.</summary>
</bill>
