<bill session="109" type="h" number="3731" updated="2013-07-19T19:37:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhance and Protect Local Community Radio Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To implement the recommendations of the Federal Communications Commission report to the Congress regarding low-power FM service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400069" joined="2005-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2005-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2005-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2005-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2005-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2005-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Public broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Public interest"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Radio programs"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2005--Introduced.
Enhance and Protect Local Community Radio Act of 2005 - Repeals provisions in the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001, that required the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to: (1) modify rules authorizing the operation of low-power FM radio stations to prescribe minimum distance separations for third-adjacent channels; (2) prohibit applicants who have engaged in the unlicensed operation of any station from obtaining a low-power FM license; and (3) conduct a program to test whether low-power FM radio stations will result in harmful interference to existing FM radio stations if minimum distance separations for third-adjacent channels are not required. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require the FCC to modify its rules to eliminate third-adjacent minimum distance separation requirements between: (1) low-power FM stations; and (2) full-service FM stations, FM translator stations, and FM booster stations. Directs the FCC to: (1) ensure the availability of spectrum for low-power FM stations; (2) establish a schedule for low-power station licensing opportunities; (3) explore the public interest obligations of FM and AM digital terrestrial radio licenses; (4) ensure that low-power FM stations will not be displaced by the granting of licenses to full-power FM stations; and (5) prohibit the future voluntary transfers of construction permits for FM translator stations or FM booster stations.</summary>
</bill>
