<bill session="111" type="s" number="1593" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Investment and Economic Development for the Americas Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the establishment of a Social Investment and Economic Development for the Americas Fund to reduce poverty, expand the middle class, and foster increased economic opportunity in that region, to promote engagement on the use of renewable fuel sources and on climate change in the Americas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4368"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/2009--Introduced.
Social Investment and Economic Development for the Americas Act of 2010 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to direct the President, acting through the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) and working with governments and civil society in the Americas (all the countries of North America, Central America, South America, and the Caribbean), to provide assistance to reduce poverty, expand the middle class, and foster increased economic opportunity by promoting education, improving health and disease prevention, increasing access to income generating activities, reducing crime, generating rural development, reducing poverty and inequality, eliminating the exclusion of marginalized populations, and strengthening the rule of law, governance, and democracy through the establishment of independent judiciaries, efficient processes to adjudicate claims, and effective law enforcement institutions. Authorizes appropriations for debt and equity financing for a Microfinance Growth Fund for the Americas. Directs the Secretary of State to: (1) establish an advisory group on the feasibility of establishing a new public-private Fund for Social and Economic Development in the Americas; (2) conduct a joint study to determine the best strategy for increasing the use of renewable energy sources in the Americas; and (3) work with interested governments in Central America, South America, the Caribbean, and Mexico (the Region) to study mechanisms to facilitate regional and hemispheric carbon trading. Authorizes appropriations to USAID: (1) for labor and environmental capacity building activities relating to the implementation of trade promotion agreements; (2) for programs in the Americas to reduce global warming; (3) to support activities in the Region involving adaptation to, and reduction in the negative impact of, environmental changes brought about by global warming and activities promoting sustainable forest management and reduction of deforestation. Expresses support for the establishment of an Energy and Climate Partnership of the Americas.</summary>
</bill>
