<bill session="110" type="h" number="6319" updated="2013-07-19T21:59:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commission on Affordable Health Care Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Commission on Affordable Health Care to study and provide recommendations for establishing a health care system to provide affordable health care to all citizens of the United States and for the roles of certain health care entities in providing such services under such system, and to provide for expedited Congressional consideration of such recommendations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400177"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2008--Introduced.
Commission on Affordable Health Care Act of 2008 - Establishes in the legislative branch the Commission on Affordable Health Care to: (1) conduct a comprehensive study of potential models for a health care system to provide affordable and quality health care to all U.S. citizens; and (2) make recommendations for implementing such a system. Requires the Commission to report to Congress on the study and include a legislative proposal that provides for a health care system based on the recommendations of the Commission. Provides for expedited congressional consideration of such a proposal.</summary>
</bill>
