<bill session="111" type="h" number="920" updated="2013-07-19T23:20:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor Act of 1988 regarding the local coordinating entity of the Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2009-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412233" joined="2009-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor Act of 1988 to make the Delaware &amp; Lehigh National Heritage Corridor Incorporated (the Corporation) the local coordinating entity for the Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor, assuming the Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor Commission's duties in implementing the Cultural Heritage and Corridor Management Plan for the Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor. Extends the authorization of appropriations to implement the management action plan created by the Commission through FY2012. Terminates the Secretary's authority to provide assistance under such Act five years after this Act's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
