<bill session="110" type="h" number="6468" updated="2013-07-19T22:00:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Putting the Brakes on Human Smuggling Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To disqualify any individual who engages in or is convicted of human smuggling from operating a commercial motor vehicle or holding a commercial driver's license and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400657"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3250"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Truck drivers"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2008--Introduced.
Putting the Brakes on Human Smuggling Act - Disqualifies from operating a commercial motor vehicle any individual who uses a commercial motor vehicle to assist in the entry of illegal aliens into the United States. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to impose a lifetime disqualification from operating such a vehicle on any individual convicted under federal criminal law of assisting in such entry or in the harboring of illegal aliens. Revises content requirements of the commercial driver's license information system to include whether a commercial motor vehicle operator has been temporarily or permanently disqualified from operating a commercial motor vehicle for violation of this Act. Requires a state to notify the Secretary of Transportation or the operator of the information system of disqualifications, revocations, suspensions, or cancellations of licenses to operate a commercial motor vehicle because of such a violation.</summary>
</bill>
