<bill session="112" type="h" number="4625" updated="2013-07-20T01:50:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Yucca Utilization to Control Contamination Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to require the President to certify that the Yucca Mountain site remains the designated site for the development of a repository for the disposal of high-level radioactive waste, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400433"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412473" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2012-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2144"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2176"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2012--Introduced.
Yucca Utilization to Control Contamination Act - Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to direct the President to publish in the Federal Register a notice certifying that the Yucca Mountain site (Nevada) is the selected site for the development of a repository for the disposal of high-level radioactive radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel. Declares that, if the President fails to publish the certification or revokes it, each entity: (1) that is required to make a payment to the Nuclear Waste Fund shall not be required to make any additional payment; and (2) that has made a payment shall receive a refund, 75% of which shall be used for rebates to the entity's ratepayers, and 25% shall be used to carry out upgrades to the entity's nuclear power facilities to enhance the storage and security of materials used to generate nuclear power. Requires the Secretary of Energy to initiate by January 1, 2017, the transportation to the Yucca Mountain site of defense waste from each state in which it is located. Imposes penalties on the Secretary for failure to initiate such transportation.</summary>
</bill>
