<bill session="113" type="h" number="3146" updated="2013-11-02T06:45:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAVE II Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Savings, Accountability, Value, and Efficiency II Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To take steps to reduce the deficit of the Federal Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412527"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412509" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, Foreign Affairs, the Judiciary, Financial Services, House Administration, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2013--Introduced.
Savings, Accountability, Value, and Efficiency II Act or SAVE II Act - Requires the Unmanned Aircraft Systems (UAS) Task Force to conduct an examination of the entire UAS portfolio of the Department of Defense (DOD), including UAS requirements, platforms, payloads, and ground control stations, to develop strategies for improved interoperability of existing systems. Directs the Secretary of Defense to: (1) identify areas in which commonality with other unmanned aircraft systems across the UAS portfolio will be achieved, (2) request a federally-funded research and development center to conduct an independent study on UAS interoperability and overlap issues, (3) report to Congress on the examination of the UAS portfolio and the UAS independent study, and (4) issue revised excess inventory management guidance and report to Congress on such guidance. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for the denial, revocation, or limitation of a passport or passport card for individuals with a seriously delinquent tax debt in excess of $50,000. Prohibits the Secretary of State from issuing a passport to an individual with a seriously delinquent tax debt and requires the Secretary to revoke the passport of such an individual, with an exception for emergency circumstances or humanitarian reasons. Allows disclosure of tax return information to the Secretary for purposes of processing passports of individuals with a seriously delinquent tax debt. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to report on the merits and feasibility of converting from a retrospective antidumping and countervailing duty collection system to a prospective one, including an estimate of costs and cost savings resulting from such a conversion. Requires the Inspector General of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to report on the effectiveness of each USAID foreign assistance program and project. Directs the Attorney General to convert by 2015 all X-ray systems in federal prisons from analog, film-based systems to digital, filmless systems. Prohibits the Secretary of the Treasury from minting or issuing any coin, or engraving or printing any U.S. currency, that costs more to produce than the denomination of such coin or currency. Requires the Public Printer of the Government Printing Office (GPO) to make any document of the House of Representatives or Senate available only in an electronic format accessible through the Internet and prohibits the printing or distribution of a printed copy of any such document, with a limited exception for requests by any person for whom the Public Printer would have been required to provide a printed copy.</summary>
</bill>
