<bill session="112" type="s" number="1611" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reducing the Size of the Federal Government Through Attrition Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reduce the size of the Federal workforce through attrition, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412496"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2114"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3029"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3487"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3494"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6474"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1476"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1611"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1936"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2011--Introduced.
Reducing the Size of the Federal Government Through Attrition Act of 2011 - Requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to take appropriate measures to ensure that: (1) the total number of federal employees, beginning in FY2015, does not exceed 90% of the total number of such employees as of September 30, 2011; (2) agencies do not appoint, until the end of FY 2014, more than one employee for every three employees retiring or otherwise separating from government service; and (3) there is no increase in the procurement of service contracts due to this Act unless a cost comparison demonstrates that such contracts would be financially advantageous to the federal government. Requires OMB to continuously monitor all agencies and make a determination whether the total number of federal employees exceeds the limitation imposed by this Act. Prohibits a federal agency from filling any vacancy unless OMB provides written notice to the President and Congress that the number of federal employees does not exceed the limitation established by this Act. Allows the President to waive the workforce limitations imposed by this Act if the President determines that the existence of a state of war or other national security concern or the existence of an extraordinary emergency threatening life, health, public safety, property, or the environment so requires. Allows the President additional discretion to waive such workforce limitations if the President determines that the efficiency of a federal agency or the performance of its critical mission so requires.</summary>
</bill>
