<bill session="110" type="s" number="2773" updated="2013-07-19T22:45:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pediatric Research Consortia Establishment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title IV of the Public Health Service Act to provide for the establishment of pediatric research consortia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2008-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="2008-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="6089"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2008--Introduced.
Pediatric Research Consortia Establishment Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), acting through the Director of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, to award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements for planning, establishing, and providing basic operating support for up to 20 national pediatric research consortia. Requires each such consortium to: (1) supplement, but not replace, the establishment of a comprehensive pediatric research portfolio; (2) conduct basic, clinical, behavioral, social, and translational research; and (3) conduct training and demonstration of advanced diagnostic and treatment methods relating to pediatrics.Requires the Director of NIH to provide for the coordination of information and ensure regular communication between consortia.</summary>
</bill>
