<bill session="109" type="sr" number="629" updated="2013-07-19T20:12:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-12-07">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution establishing a procedure for affixing and removing permanent artwork and semi-permanent artwork in the Senate wing of the Capitol and in the Senate office buildings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300045"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2006-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-12-07" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11545" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11545" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11506" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Artists"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Capitol (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional office buildings"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Painting"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/7/2006--Passed Senate without amendment.
Prescribes requirements for affixing permanent or semi-permanent artwork to, or removing it from, the public spaces and committee rooms of the Senate wing of the Capitol and the Senate office buildings. Requires the Senate Commission on Art to recommend the affixation, in an appropriate location, or removal. Requires that at least 25 years have passed since: (1) the death of any subject in a portrait included in the artwork; or (2) the commemorative event that is to be portrayed in it. Requires also that the Senate has passed a Senate resolution approving the Commission's recommendation. Declares that it is the sense of the Senate that the Commission consider specified factors before making an affixation recommendation. Requires the Commission, if a request meets the requirements of this Act, to select the artist and supervise the creation of the artwork and its application to the selected surface.</summary>
</bill>
