<bill session="109" type="h" number="4468" updated="2013-07-19T19:43:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhancing America's Guard and Reserve Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve certain compensation, health care, and education benefits for individuals who serve in a reserve component of the uniformed services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400379"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Government Reform, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-07">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-07">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Military transportation"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telecommuting"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/7/2005--Introduced.
Enhancing America's Guard and Reserve Act - Entitles a Federal employee who is a member of a reserve component to receive the difference in pay between military compensation and civilian compensation during periods of active duty exceeding 30 days. Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned to reimburse States or local governments for 50 percent of the civilian compensation paid by such governments to equalize military and civilian pay. Increases the reimbursement rate to 100 percent if active duty extends beyond nine months. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish an active-duty reserve component employee credit for employers who provide compensation to employees on active duty. Modifies age and service requirements for receipt of retired pay for non-regular service. Removes certain service commencement and continuation requirements for the receipt by members of the Selected Reserve of benefits under the TRICARE program (a Department of Defense (DOD) managed care program). Increases the amount of basic educational assistance for members of reserve components under the Montgomery GI Bill. Prohibits the termination of educational assistance for a member's failure to participate satisfactorily in required training due solely to a call to active duty. Authorizes the limited use of telecommuting to satisfy inactive-duty training. Requires the Secretary of Defense to give Selected Reserve members eligibility for travel on DOD aircraft on a space-available basis.</summary>
</bill>
