<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1503" updated="2013-07-19T21:03:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-26T15:11:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-26T15:11:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25T19:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-888, by Ms. Castor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25T19:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Waives clause 6(a) of rule XIII (requiring a two-thirds vote to consider a rule on the same day it is reported from the Rules Committee) against certain resolutions reported from the Rules Committee. The rule applies the waiver to any resolution reported on the legislative day of September 26, 2008, providing for consideration or disposition of a measure making supplemental appropriations for job creation and preservation, infrastructure investment, and economic and energy assistance for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2009, and for other purposes.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-09-25T19:38:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="279">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 279.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T13:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10050-10058" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T13:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1503.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T15:01:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 222 - 198 (Roll no. 654).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10056-10057" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-09-26T15:11:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="655" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 216 - 203 (Roll no. 655).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10050" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2008--Introduced.
Waives a specified requirement of Rule XIII (Calendar and Committee Reports) to allow consideration or disposition of a measure (making FY2009 supplemental appropriations for job creation and preservation, infrastructure investment, and economic and energy assistance) on the same day it is presented to the House.</summary>
</bill>
