<bill session="113" type="s" number="1054" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gold Butte National Conservation Area Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish Gold Butte National Conservation Area in Clark County, Nevada in order to conserve, protect, and enhance the cultural, archaeological, natural, wilderness, scientific, geological, historical, biological, wildlife, educational, and scenic resources of the area, to designate wilderness areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3852-3853"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3853-3857" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2276"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Gold Butte National Conservation Area Act - Establishes the Gold Butte National Conservation Area in Nevada. Establishes the Gold Butte National Conservation Area Advisory Council. Designates specified wilderness areas administered by the National Park Service (NPS) or the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in Clark County, Nevada, as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Authorizes the Secretary, through the BLM, to establish a visitor center and field office in Mesquite, Nevada, to assist in fulfilling the purposes of the Lake Mead National Recreation Area, the Grand Canyon-Parashant National Monument, and the Conservation Area. States that the withdrawal of specified parcels of BLM lands for use by the Bureau of Reclamation is terminated. Requires the Conservation Area and the wilderness areas designated by this Act to be administered as components of the National Landscape Conservation System.</summary>
</bill>
