<bill session="109" type="s" number="2664" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">PhAIm bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pharmacy Access Improvement (PhAIm) Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve access to pharmacies under part D.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2006-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2006-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2006-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3710"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5182"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5307"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2563"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2723"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Generic drugs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Mail-order business"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2006--Introduced.
Pharmacy Access Improvement (PhAIm) Act of 2006 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program ) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) with respect to participating pharmacies and standards for access to them. Requires that such standards ensure that enrollees residing in long-term care facilities have access to a long-term care network pharmacy. Requires prompt payment of clean claims to pharmacies by prescription drug plans (PDPs) and Medicare Advantage prescription drug plans (MA-PD Plans) Defines prompt payment as within 14 days from submission for claims submitted electronically, and within 30 days for claims submitted otherwise. Requires payment of interest, also, if a payment is not issued, mailed, or otherwise transmitted within the applicable number of calendar days. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a 24-hour toll-free telephone number dedicated to providing Medicare prescription drug benefit information to pharmacists and pharmacy staff. Amends SSA title XVIII to require PDP sponsors to establish toll-free pharmacy and physician and provider hotlines. Requires a PDP sponsor to utilize standardized technology for any communication or transaction occurring between the PDP and a participating pharmacy. Prohibits a Medicare prescription drug card issued by a PDP sponsor from displaying the name, brand, logo, or trademark (co-branding) of any pharmacy. Provides for submission of claims by pharmacies located in or contracting with long-term care facilities. Requires the Secretary to establish reasonable dispensing fees for covered Medicare part D drugs dispensed through participating pharmacies. Requires a PDP sponsor to encourage generic utilization by paying an increased dispensing fee for generic drugs.</summary>
</bill>
