<bill session="110" type="hr" number="734" updated="2013-07-19T20:56:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-16T15:20:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-10-16T15:20:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the withholding of information relating to corruption in Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400425"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2007-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2007-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2007-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2007-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2007-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-15T20:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 741 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 734 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-16T13:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 741 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-16T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 741.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11576-11586" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-16T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 734 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-16T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 734.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-16T13:50:00-04:00">
      <text>During the course of debate, exception was taken to certain words used in debate. Subsequently, unanimous consent was granted to withdraw the words in question and debate continued under regular order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-16T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11585" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2007-10-16T15:20:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="969" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 395 - 21 (Roll no. 969).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11576-11577" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-10-16T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="741"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/16/2007--Passed House without amendment.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) as Congress considers the President's request for over $150 billion more for the war in Iraq it is essential that Congress and the people of the United States know the extent of corruption in the Iraqi government and whether corruption is fueling the insurgency; (2) it was wrong to retroactively classify portions of the report titled "Stabilizing and Rebuilding Iraq: U.S. Ministry Capacity Development Efforts Need an Overall Integrated Strategy to Guide Efforts and Manage Risk" which was released October 4, 2007, and other statements that do not meet the criteria for classification; (3) it is an abuse of the classification process to withhold from Congress and the people of the United States broad assessments of the extent of corruption in the Iraqi government; and (4) a directive that prohibits federal officials from providing Congress and the people of the United States with broad assessments which characterize the quality of Iraqi governance should be rescinded.</summary>
</bill>
