<bill session="110" type="s" number="763" updated="2013-07-19T22:26:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Transportation Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Public Transportation Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">An original bill to provide the resources to protect public transportation from terrorism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-05">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Dodd. With written report No. 110-32.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-03-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="69">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 69.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-03-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3048"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-13">
      <text>Star Print ordered on the report to accompany the bill (Report 110-32).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1401"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1401"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Public Transportation Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007 - Requires the Department of Transportation's (DOT) Federal Transit Administration, within 30 days of enactment, to submit all public transportation security assessments to the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) to review and augment such assessments, not later than July 31, 2007. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish and annually update security improvement priorities (improvement priorities), by September 30, 2007, that are consistent with relevant State Homeland Security Plans; (2) annually update the assessments and annually conduct assessments of all public transportation agencies considered to be at greatest risk of a terrorist attack; (3) by July 31, 2007, conduct security assessments of local bus-only public transportation systems and of selected transportation systems receiving grants as other than urbanized areas; and (4) use information collected from the assessments to develop security guidelines for public transportation security and design a security improvement strategy. Directs the Secretary, consistent with relevant State Homeland Security Plans, to award grants to public transportation agencies for allowable capital and operational security improvements based on the improvement priorities. Defines allowable. Requires congressional notification before the award of any grant. Sets forth public transportation agency requirements for receiving a grant. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop and issue regulations for a public transportation worker security training program; (2) ensure that DOT receives timely notification of all credible terrorist threats against U.S. public transportation assets; (3) provide assistance for the reasonable costs of the Information Sharing and Analysis Center (ISAC) for Public Transportation to protect critical infrastructure; and (4) award grants or contracts for research and the demonstration of technologies and methods to reduce and deter terrorist threats or mitigate damages resulting from terrorist attacks. Requires public transportation agencies determined to be at significant risk of terrorist attack to participate in the ISAC and encourages all other public transportation agencies to participate in the ISAC. Prohibits charging a fee to any public transportation agency for participating in the ISAC. Sets forth reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations through FY2010. Terminates grant authority on October 1, 2011.</summary>
</bill>
