<bill session="109" type="s" number="34" updated="2013-07-19T20:13:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Tsunami Detection and Warning System Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the development of a global tsunami detection and warning system, to improve existing communication of tsunami warnings to all potentially affected nations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S225"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S225-226" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="499"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Computer simulation"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Facsimile transmission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Landslides"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seismology"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Tsunamis"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Volcanoes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2005--Introduced.
Global Tsunami Detection and Warning System Act of 2005 - Requires the Secretary of Commerce, working with other specified Federal agency heads, to: (1) identify and eliminate (with international cooperation) deficiencies in existing systems of worldwide seismic stations that can identify in real or near real time potentially tsunamigenic earthquakes; (2) identify tsunami sensors that can be deployed to detect potential tsunamis generated by any type of disturbance and the number and location of such sensors that must be deployed to provide complete global coverage; (3) procure and deploy such sensors; (4) establish systems and infrastructure to process sensor signals; and (5) disseminate tsunami forecasts and warnings to potentially affected nations. Calls on the President to convene an international conference on global tsunami detection and warning unless a satisfactory international agreement has been reached. Requires the Secretary of State to implement a comprehensive strategy to: (1) identify coastal nations that have the potential to be affected by tsunamis; (2) identify appropriate contacts within the governments of those nations for disseminating tsunami warnings; (3) develop a structure for a Global Tsunami Warning System (GTWS) and an appropriate chain of command structure for GTWS warnings; (4) implement a tsunami forecasting system that includes specified technological capabilities for real-time forecasting; (5) use such forecasts to form and rapidly disseminate warnings; (6) develop a warning communications system; (7) work in partnership with specified nations to provide appropriate educational and response planning partnerships; and (8) seek funding assistance from participating nations. Requires reports to Congress on the measures mandated by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
