<bill session="110" type="h" number="6669" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-29T14:58:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-29T14:58:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that claims of the United States to certain documents relating to Franklin Delano Roosevelt shall be treated as waived and relinquished in certain circumstances.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Clay moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10205-10206" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6669.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Davis, Tom objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-29T14:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10631" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-09-29T14:58:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/27/2008 H10205" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-29T14:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3350"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Presidential records"/>
    <term name="Roosevelt Administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2008--Passed House without amendment.
Declares that any claim of the United States to certain property relating to Franklin Delano Roosevelt, his family, or staff shall be treated as having been waived and relinquished on the day before any person makes a gift of such property to the National Archives and Records Administration. Specifies such property as any part of the collection of documents, papers, and memorabilia relating to Roosevelt, or any member of his family or staff, which was originally in the possession of Grace Tully and retained by her at the time of her death, and included in her estate.</summary>
</bill>
