<bill session="110" type="h" number="1267" updated="2013-07-19T21:14:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Carbon Dioxide Storage Capacity Assessment Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To develop a methodology for, and complete, a national assessment of geological storage capacity for carbon dioxide, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400155"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2007-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2007-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2007-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400633" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2007-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2007-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2007-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400281" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412229" joined="2007-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2007-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2007-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="731"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="731"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary recovery of gas"/>
    <term name="Secondary recovery of oil"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2007--Introduced.
National Carbon Dioxide Storage Capacity Assessment Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary), acting through the Director of the U.S. Geological Survey, to develop a methodology for conducting a national assessment of the geological storage capacity for carbon dioxide. Sets forth elements for the Secretary to consider in developing the methodology. Requires the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to cooperate with the Secretary to ensure the usefulness and success of the assessment. Requires the Secretary to: (1) provide the heads of stakeholder federal agencies, the heads of state land management agencies, industry stakeholders, and the public with an opportunity to review and comment on the proposed methodology; (2) convene a committee of subject matter experts to review the methodology for capacity and risk estimation; (3) publish a description of the final methodology and issue a public report that responds to the comments received and the methodology review; (4) complete a national assessment of geological storage capacity for carbon dioxide using the methodology; (5) establish a database on the Internet accessible to the public that provides the results of the assessment and includes the data necessary to rank potential storage sites for capacity and risk; and (6) report to Congress on the findings of the assessment.</summary>
</bill>
