<bill session="110" type="h" number="81" updated="2013-07-19T21:04:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bartlett Montgomery GI Bill Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide that members of the Armed Forces and Selected Reserve may transfer certain educational assistance benefits to dependents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400017"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2007-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2008-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2007-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="2007-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412201" joined="2008-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2008-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Bartlett Montgomery GI Bill Act - Amends the Montgomery GI Bill educational assistance program to allow an individual who has completed six years of service in the Armed Forces and enters into an agreement to serve at least four more years to transfer their educational assistance entitlement to their spouse, child, or a combination thereof. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide a percentage annual increase in the rates of such educational assistance based on the average monthly costs of higher education. Authorizes reimbursement of reductions in basic pay for educational assistance coverage in the case of extended active-duty service. Provides similar eligibility for the transfer of educational assistance for members of the Selected Reserve who have completed at least six years of service and enter into an agreement to remain a member of such Reserve for at least four more years. Provides educational assistance eligibility credit for cumulative active-duty service in the Selected Reserve. Increases the rates of educational assistance under the Reserve Montgomery GI Bill. Applies an annual adjustment to the rates of survivors' and dependents' educational assistance.</summary>
</bill>
