<bill session="110" type="h" number="6589" updated="2013-07-19T22:01:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Charles H.W. Meehan Law Library Improvement and Modernization Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Charles H.W. Meehan Law Library Improvement and Modernization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide financial support for the operation of the law library of the Library of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400245"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2008-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House House Administration"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House House Administration"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T11:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 110-896, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T11:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-27T11:09:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="578">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 578.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal libraries"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law libraries"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2008--Reported to House amended.
Charles H.W. Meehan Law Library Improvement and Modernization Act - Authorizes appropriations to the Librarian of Congress, in addition to any other amounts made available, for maintaining and administering the operations of the law library of the Library of Congress, including the cataloguing of its collections. Requires the Law Librarian of Congress, to the extent practicable in using such funds, to catalog and archive nonproprietary material in the collections of the Law Library electronically in a nonproprietary and nondiscriminatory format.Requires the Librarian of Congress, in preparing the annual budget for the Library of Congress, to ensure that all amounts attributable to salaries and expenses of the law library are set forth separately as a separate line item. Directs the Librarian, acting through the Law Librarian of Congress, to establish and operate a program to be known as the Charles H.W. Meehan Law Library Support Program, to provide enhanced or special services and programs for the Law Library and otherwise support the mission of the Law Library. Allows acceptance of donations of private funds, in-kind contributions, and voluntary services in support of the Program.Establishes a separate account in the Treasury for use solely by the Librarian to carry out the Program. Requires an annual report to Congress, the American Bar Association, and the American Association of Law Libraries on Program funding and activities. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
