<bill session="110" type="h" number="733" updated="2013-07-19T21:10:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Budget Autonomy Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to eliminate all Federally-imposed mandates over the local budget process and financial management of the District of Columbia and the borrowing of money by the District of Columbia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2007-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E360-361"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal mandates"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Local budgets"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Municipal home rule"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/30/2007--Introduced.
District of Columbia Budget Autonomy Act of 2007 - Amends the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to eliminate, with respect to each fiscal year that is not a control year, all federally-imposed mandates over the District of Columbia's: (1) local budget process, financial management, audits, and accountability requirements; and (2) short-term borrowing of money, with specified exceptions. Declares that the process by which the District develops and enacts the District government's budget for a fiscal year, the activities carried out regarding financial management of the District government, and the process and rules by which the District issues bonds or otherwise borrows money shall be established under laws enacted by the District. Provides that Acts adopting the District government's annual budget for FY2008 and succeeding non-control fiscal years shall take effect upon their prescribed dates. (Thus eliminates congressional review of such Acts). Repeals the federal cap on amounts the District may borrow (other than in a control year).</summary>
</bill>
