<bill session="111" type="h" number="2076" updated="2013-07-19T23:30:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Border Security and Responsibility Act 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of a border protection strategy for the international land borders of the United States, to address the ecological and environmental impacts of border security infrastructure, measures, and activities along the international land borders of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400302" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2009-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Unconventional Threats and Capabilities.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS26" subcommittee="Terrorism, Unconventional Threats and Capabilities" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/2009--Introduced.
Border Security and Responsibility Act 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary), the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with tribal, state, and local officials, to submit to Congress a border protection strategy for the international land borders of the United States. Specifies strategy elements. Amends the the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to revise international land border security provisions, including: (1) eliminating existing southwest border fencing requirements; (2) requiring that border control actions be in accordance with the border strategy required under this Act; and (3) giving priority to the use of remote cameras, sensors, removal of nonnative vegetation, incorporation of natural barriers, additional manpower, unmanned aerial vehicles, or other low impact border enforcement techniques. Prohibits construction of border fencing, physical barriers, roads, lighting, cameras, sensors, or other tactical infrastructure prior to 90 days after such border strategy's submission to Congress. Directs the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of appropriate state and tribal wildlife agencies, to implement a comprehensive monitoring and mitigation plan to address the ecological and environmental impacts of security infrastructure and activities along the international land borders of the United States. Specifies plan requirements.</summary>
</bill>
