<bill session="111" type="h" number="2309" updated="2013-07-19T23:32:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Credit and Debt Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide authority to the Federal Trade Commission to expedite rulemakings concerning consumer credit or debt and to direct the Commission to examine and promulgate rules with regard to debt settlement and automobile sales, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400350"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2009-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 16 - 9 .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2009--Introduced.
Consumer Credit and Debt Protection Act - Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to give the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) authority to expedite rulemakings concerning consumer credit or debt. Directs the FTC to examine the practices of providers of debt settlement services and prescribe rules necessary to prevent unfair and deceptive acts or practices by such providers. Directs the FTC to examine the practices of automobile dealers with respect to credit and lending and prescribe rules necessary to prevent unfair and deceptive dealer acts or practices. Gives the FTC authority to commence a civil action to recover a civil penalty in a U.S. district court against any person, partnership, or corporation which engages in any unfair or deceptive acts or practices in connection with consumer credit or debt with actual knowledge or knowledge fairly implied on the basis of objective circumstances that such act is unfair or deceptive. Authorizes enforcement of this Act by state attorneys general.</summary>
</bill>
