<bill session="113" type="h" number="2354" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROMPT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Proper Replacement Of Medals and Performance Tracking Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to require the prompt replacement of military decorations upon the request of the recipients of the decorations or their immediate next of kin.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412446" joined="2013-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/13/2013--Introduced.
Proper Replacement Of Medals and Performance Tracking Act or the PROMPT Act - Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned, when recipients of certain military decorations or medals (or in some cases when the recipient's immediate next of kin) requests a replacement of such decoration (e.g., when the original medal is lost, stolen, or destroyed), to ensure that: (1) all actions to be taken with respect to the request, including verification of the service record of the recipient, are completed within one year; and (2) the replacement is mailed to the person making the request within a specified period after such verification. Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to submit to Congress: (1) an annual report regarding compliance by the military departments with such replacement performance standards; and (2) a plan to implement such standards, including an estimate of FY2015 funds necessary to meet or exceed such standards.</summary>
</bill>
