<bill session="110" type="s" number="2215" updated="2013-07-19T22:40:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Supporting America's Protective Security Advisor Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish the Protective Security Advisor Program Office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2007-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2007-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2008-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2007-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2007-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13200"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13201-13202" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/22/2007--Introduced.
Supporting America's Protective Security Advisor Act of 2007 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish the Protective Security Advisor Program Office within the Protective Security Coordination Division of the Office of Infrastructure Protection of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). Requires the Office to have primary responsibility within DHS for: (1) encouraging state, local, and tribal governments and private sector owners and operators of critical infrastructure and key resources to participate and collaborate within the risk management framework of the National Infrastructure Protection Plan; (2) coordinating national and intergovernmental critical infrastructure and key resource activities with such governments, owners, and operators; (3) facilitating and conducting requirements, capabilities, and risk assessment analyses that enhance critical infrastructure and key resources preparedness; (4) promoting information sharing and security awareness; (5) assisting such governments in developing multijurisdictional security plans; (6) helping to ensure coordination among such governments, such owners and operators, emergency response providers, and related agencies; (7) serving as infrastructure liaison officials when a joint field office is activated in response to a natural disaster or terrorist event; and (8) facilitating and coordinating interaction with international security partners.Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to develop a plan for the assignment and distribution of protective security advisors that takes into account baseline requirements and anticipated growth to: (1) ensure that protective security advisors are located across the United States and provide appropriate coverage and coordinated support, especially in high-risk regions; and (2) assign protective security advisors and support staff based on risk.</summary>
</bill>
