<bill session="111" type="h" number="4819" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Expanding Opportunities for Older Americans Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to expand the Senior Community Service Employment Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2010-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2010-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2010-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2010--Introduced.
Expanding Opportunities for Older Americans Act of 2010 - Amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 to expand the Senior Community Service Employment (SCSE) Program. Lowers the age of eligibility from 55 to 52. Repeals the requirement that the eligible individual be unemployed. Increases from 125% to 200% of the poverty line the maximum income for eligibility. Excludes from the counting of an eligible individual's income any income received by another member of the eligible individual's household. Prohibits any limit of fewer than 40 hours per week on the number of hours per week a grant recipient may permit a participant to work in a job assisted under the grant. Declares the sense of Congress that not less than $700 million should be appropriated to carry out the SCSE Program in each of FY2011-FY2016.</summary>
</bill>
