<bill session="111" type="h" number="2002" updated="2013-07-19T23:29:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Patient IVIG Access Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve access of Medicare beneficiaries to intravenous immune globulins (IVIG).</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2009-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412288" joined="2009-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400635" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2009-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2009-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412313" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2009-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2009-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400439" joined="2009-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="701"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Drug and radiation therapy"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Immunology"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2009--Introduced.
Medicare Patient IVIG Access Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to collect data on the differences, if any, between: (1) payments to physicians for immune globulins using average sales price payment methodology; and (2) costs incurred by physicians for furnishing these products. Requires the Secretary also to review data on the access of eligible individuals to immune globulins. Requires the Secretary, after completion of the review, to provide, if appropriate, an additional payment to such physicians for all items related to the furnishing of immune globulins as part of hospital outpatient services. Provides for Medicare coverage of and payment for intravenous immune globulin (IVIG) administered in the home. Directs the Secretary to contract for the collection of data on the practice of IVIG infusion if the Secretary determines that collection of additional data is necessary. Directs the Secretary to review data collected under such a contract as well as data submitted by members of the medical community related to the current infusion payment codes under part B (SupplementaryMedical Insurance) of SSA title XVIII. Requires the Secretary, upon completion of any data collection and review, to: (1) notify the appropriate Medicare administrative contractors regarding which existing infusion codes shall be used for purposes of part B IVIG reimbursement; or (2) report to Congress and the RBRVS Update Committee (RUC) on why an additional infusion payment code is necessary. Extends the meaning of durable medical equipment to include a disposable pump prescribed, instead of a non-disposable external infusion pump, for administration of a drug used as part of a chemotherapy regimen for treatment of colorectal cancer, if a non-disposable external infusion pump would have been covered to administer the same drug for the same indication as of July 1, 2008.</summary>
</bill>
