<bill session="113" type="h" number="1170" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Land Management and the Bureau of Reclamation, to convey, by quitclaim deed, to the City of Fernley, Nevada, all right, title, and interest of the United States, to any Federal land within that city that is under the jurisdiction of either of those agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412500"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2013--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior, if the Secretary receives an offer from the city of Fernley, Nevada, to purchase identified federal land within the city, through the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and the Bureau of Reclamation, to convey to the city all interest of the United States in such land in exchange for consideration in an amount equal to the fair market value of the land. Permits the city and the Bureau of Reclamation to retain easements or rights-of-way on the federal land to be conveyed, including easements or rights-of-way that are necessary to carry out the operation and maintenance of the Truckee Canal Irrigation District Canal or the Newlands Project. Requires the city to pay or reimburse the Secretary, as appropriate, for reasonable transaction and administrative personnel costs associated with such conveyance. Releases the United States from all liabilities or claims of any kind or nature arising from the presence, release, or threat of release of any hazardous substance, pollutant, contaminant, petroleum product (or derivative of a petroleum product), solid waste, mine materials, or mining related features existing on the federal land.</summary>
</bill>
