<bill session="113" type="s" number="1200" updated="2013-11-02T07:02:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Residential Energy Savings Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to promote energy efficiency and energy savings in residential buildings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2013-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Energy. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG01" subcommittee="Energy" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2013--Introduced.
Residential Energy Savings Act of 2013 - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to require the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to establish a voluntary loan program to provide support to states, U.S. territories, and Indian tribal governments (eligible entities) in establishing or expanding programs that provide to residential property owners or tenants financing for energy efficiency upgrades of residential buildings. Authorizes assistance provided by eligible entities to be in the form of a: (1) revolving loan fund; (2) credit enhancement structure designed to mitigate the effects of default; or (3) program that adopts other approaches for providing financing for upgrades producing significant energy efficiency gains, produces a high-leverage ratio of non-federal funds, and incorporates measures for making the loan repayment system for recipients of financing consumer-friendly. Requires the Secretary to establish a performance incentive providing a repayment discount in an amount equal to no more than the value of the interest accrued on the loan provided, based on performance as evaluated in accordance with specified factors. Makes an authorization of appropriations under this Act effective for a fiscal year only to the extent and in the amounts provided in advance in appropriations Acts.</summary>
</bill>
