<bill session="112" type="h" number="522" updated="2013-07-20T01:14:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Worker Protection Against Combustible Dust Explosions and Fires Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Labor to issue an interim occupational safety and health standard regarding worker exposure to combustible dust, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2011-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2011-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2011--Introduced.
Worker Protection Against Combustible Dust Explosions and Fires Act of 2011 - Requires the Secretary of Labor to promulgate an interim final standard regulating occupational exposure to combustible dust hazards, which shall apply to manufacturing, processing, blending, conveying, repackaging, and handling of combustible particulate solids and their dusts (including organic dusts, plastics, sulfur, wood, rubber, furniture, textiles, pesticides, pharmaceuticals, fibers, dyes, coal, metals, and fossil fuels), but shall not apply to processes already covered by the occupational safety and health standard on grain facilities. Requires such standard to be based on portions of the National Fire Protection Association Standards in effect upon enactment of this Act that: (1) apply to existing facilities; or (2) call for source and dust emission control technologies. Requires such standard also to provide requirements for: (1) a hazard assessment to identify, evaluate, and control combustible dust hazards; (2) a written program that includes provisions for hazardous dust inspection, testing, hot work, ignition control, and housekeeping; (3) engineering controls, administrative controls, and operating procedures; (4) workplace inspection and housekeeping to prevent accumulation of combustible dust in places of employment in depths that can present explosion, deflagration, or other fire hazards, including safe methods of dust removal; (5) participation of employees and their representatives in hazard assessment, development of and compliance with the written program, incident investigation, and other elements of hazard management; and (6) providing safety and health information and annual training to managers and employees and their representatives. Requires the interim final standard to take effect 30 days after its issuance, and remain in effect until a final standard becomes effective, except that it may include a reasonable phase-in period for implementation of required engineering controls. Requires the Secretary to issue: (1) a proposed rule for regulating combustible dust explosions that includes the major elements contained in the interim final standard, and (2) a final rule three years after issuance of a proposed rule.</summary>
</bill>
