<bill session="110" type="s" number="2105" updated="2013-07-19T22:38:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Health Care Board Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the establishment of the Federal Health Care Board.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2007--Introduced.
Federal Health Care Board Act of 2007 - Establishes the Federal Health Care Board as an independent agency in the executive branch.Requires the Board to: (1) ensure that Americans have access to health insurance and are provided certain basic facts about health care services prior to receiving care; (2) ensure that providers are delivering safe, evidence-based, high quality care and are transparent about pricing through disclosure of actual costs; (3) demand transparency for disclosure of actual costs and pricing from providers and payers through an information clearinghouse; (4) establish a national standard for a basic health insurance plan (including a basic minimum policy and the regional cost for such policy), a national protocol and standard for secure, universal, and individual electronic medical records, a national standard for public health services (including safety net providers), loan forgiveness and scholarship programs for health care providers who serve in underserved areas, and model dispute resolution procedures for malpractice claims that states may adopt; and (5) monitor progress toward those objectives.Directs the Board's Board of Governors to establish 12 regions of the United States. Establishes in each region a Regional Board, based in a major city, to provide the Board of Governors with considerations that are relevant to their region's population.</summary>
</bill>
