<bill session="109" type="s" number="2486" updated="2013-07-19T20:35:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chemical Security and Safety Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that adequate actions are taken to detect, prevent, and minimize the consequences of chemical releases that result from terrorist attacks and other criminal activity that may cause substantial harm to public health and safety and the environment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2006-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2006-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2006-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2606"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2606-2611" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2006--Introduced.
Chemical Security and Safety Act of 2006 - Establishes a general duty by each owner and operator of a stationary source (as defined under the Clean Air Act) that produces, processes, handles, or stores any substance of concern to: (1) identify hazards that may result from a criminal release; (2) take necessary actions to prevent criminal releases; and (3) eliminate or significantly reduce the consequences of any such release. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to promulgate regulations to: (1) designate certain stationary sources and substances of concern as high priority; and (2) require each owner or operator of a high priority stationary source to detect, prevent, and eliminate or significantly reduce the consequences of criminal releases that may harm public health or safety. Requires each such owner or operator to: (1) report to the Secretary with a vulnerability assessment and a prevention, preparedness, and response plan; (2) establish a safety and security committee for that source if it has 15 or more full-time equivalent employees; and (3) annually provide each employee with four hours of training regarding requirements of this Act. Directs the Secretary and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a program to conduct regular inspections of stationary sources. Authorizes the Secretary to issue orders directing compliance with this Act and sets penalties for noncompliance. Requires the Secretary and the Administrator to promulgate regulations requiring high priority stationary sources to participate in emergency preparedness exercises. Directs the Secretary to establish an information clearinghouse to assist stationary sources in complying with this Act. Prohibits discrimination against employees who disclose violations of this Act or threats to public health or safety relating to chemical security or improper releases.</summary>
</bill>
