<bill session="109" type="h" number="168" updated="2013-07-19T19:05:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Goods Movement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 23, United States Code, to establish a goods movement program to improve the productivity, security, and safety of freight transportation gateways.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400275"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Car pools"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Gross national product"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Terminals (Transportation)"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2005--Introduced.
Goods Movement Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish a goods movement program to improve the productivity, security, and safety of freight transportation gateways, while mitigating congestion and community impacts in the area of such gateways. Declares that the purposes of the program shall be to: (1) facilitate and support multimodal freight transportation initiatives at the State, regional, and local levels to improve freight transportation gateways and mitigate congestion in the area of such gateways; (2) provide capital funding to address infrastructure and freight operational needs at freight transportation corridors and gateways; (3) encourage adoption of new financing strategies to leverage State, local, and private investment in freight transportation gateways; and (4) support military mobilization and readiness. Qualifies for funding under this Act intermodal freight transportation projects that provide community and highway benefits by addressing economic, congestion, security, safety, and environmental issues associated with freight transportation corridors and gateways, subject to specified limitations. Sets forth project selection and grant approval criteria. Requires a recipient of Federal financial assistance for a project with an estimated total cost of $100 million or more to submit to the Secretary an annual financial plan for the project. Repeals National Corridor Planning and Development Program provisions of the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century.</summary>
</bill>
