<bill session="111" type="h" number="6017" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gulf Coast Health Monitoring and Research Program Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to ensure that the Federal Government has independent, peer-reviewed scientific data and information to assess short-term and long-term direct and indirect impacts on the health of oil spill clean-up workers and vulnerable residents resulting from the Deepwater Horizon oil spill, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2010-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2010-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Immunology"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
Gulf Coast Health Monitoring and Research Program Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a short-term and long-term comprehensive health screening, monitoring, and research program of: (1) oil spill workers and vulnerable residents; and (2) food safety affected by the oil spill in the Gulf of Mexico. Directs the Secretary to appoint the Gulf Coast Health Research Advisory Committee in order to: (1) offer high-quality scientific research advice to the program established under this Act, including proactive advice regarding each federal agency's long-term monitoring and research objectives relating to workers and vulnerable residents at risk from the Deepwater Horizon disaster and other oil spills; and (2) provide a forum for ensuring that health concerns of workers and the public are considered in determining the priorities for scientific research. Requires the Secretary to ensure that members of the Advisory Committee do not have any conflicts of interest. Requires the Advisory Committee to: (1) provide advice on the development and implementation of the health research program; (2) respond to requests for advice from the appropriate federal official on matters within the Advisory Committee's expertise; and (3) as appropriate, review reports or other documents submitted to the appropriate federal officials pursuant to this Act to obtain information on protecting the health and safety of cleanup workers and vulnerable communities. Authorizes the Secretary to compel BP PLC to provide health-related data and information collected by or on behalf of BP PLC, except to the extent such data or information is protected from disclosure under federal law.</summary>
</bill>
