<bill session="111" type="s" number="3409" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make certain adjustments to the price analysis of propane prepared by the Secretary of Commerce.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2010-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2010-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2010-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="3716"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2010--Introduced.
Amends the Propane Education and Research Act of 1996 to revise requirements for the annual report by the Secretary of Commerce to the Propane Education and Research Council, the Secretary of Energy, and the public analyzing changes in the price of propane relative to other energy sources. Requires the analysis to compare indexed changes in the average price of consumer grade propane to all end users to an equally weighted composite of indexed changes in the price of residential electricity, residential natural gas, and refiner price to end users of No. 2 fuel oil on an annual national average basis. (Currently, the comparison is to be made of indexed changes in the price of consumer grade propane to a composite of indexed changes in the price of residential electricity, residential natural gas, and refiner price.) Directs the Secretary of Commerce, within 60 days after enactment of this Act, to prepare and make available to the public an updated propane price analysis reflecting the amendment made by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
