<bill session="110" type="h" number="5650" updated="2013-07-19T21:53:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to limit the repair, restoration, reconstruction, or replacement of certain property and to discontinue large in-lieu contributions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400279"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2008--Introduced.
Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to: (1) prohibit the President from contributing federal funds to a state or local government or private nonprofit organization for the repair, restoration, reconstruction, or replacement of donated real property that the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) determines is not critical to the public welfare; and (2) repeal a provision authorizing a state or local government to elect to receive in lieu of such public facility funds a contribution equal to 90% of the federal share of the estimated cost of repairing, restoring, reconstructing, or replacing a facility and of management expenses if such government determines that conducting such activity would not best serve the public welfare.</summary>
</bill>
