<bill session="112" type="s" number="205" updated="2013-07-20T02:18:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Alaska Adjacent Zone Safe Oil Transport and Revenue Sharing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to require that oil produced from Federal leases in certain Arctic waters be transported by pipeline to onshore facilities and to provide for the sharing of certain Outer Continental Shelf revenues from areas in the Alaska Adjacent Zone.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2011--Introduced.
Alaska Adjacent Zone Safe Oil Transport and Revenue Sharing Act - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) to direct the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) require oil produced from federal leases in certain Arctic waters, except in preproduction phases (including explorations), to be transported by pipeline to onshore facilities; and (2) provide for, and issue appropriate permits for, the transportation of oil from such leases in preproduction phases (including exploration) by means other than pipeline. Requires that the state of Alaska receive 37.5% of: (1) any bonus bid paid for leasing rights for any area in the Alaska Adjacent Zone; and (2) specified post-leasing revenues including lease rental payments and lease royalty payments, as well as royalty proceeds from a sale of royalties taken in kind. Sets forth an allocation scheme under which the Secretary of the Interior is directed to pay: (1) 20% of any allocable state share directly to coastal political subdivisions, (2) 33% of any allocable state share to certain Regional Corporations, and (3) 7% of any allocable state share directly to Indian tribes. Instructs the Secretary to distribute 6.25% of certain federal royalty revenues into: (1) a specified land and water conservation fund to provide financial assistance to states, and (2) direct federal deficit reduction.</summary>
</bill>
