<bill session="111" type="h" number="2569" updated="2013-07-19T23:34:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize surface transportation research, development, and technology transfer activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Directs the Administrator of the Research and Innovative Technology Administration (RITA) within the Department of Transportation (DOT) to: (1) develop a strategic plan annually to guide DOT surface transportation research, development, and technology transfer activities for the following three years; (2) develop and execute a review process to assess the performance of university transportation centers (UTCs); and (3) report to Congress on how best to strengthen the transfer of transportation-related technology, including through the establishment of transportation technology extension centers at UTCs. Authorizes the Administrator, in order to expand the workforce of transportation professionals, to establish a grant program to fund internships for students participating in the UTC program. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish a visiting committee on surface transportation research. Moves the Office of Climate Change and Environment into RITA and requires it to coordinate research, development, and technology transfer activities: (1) that focus on transportation-related emissions and energy reduction strategies; and (2) on the impacts of climate change on surface transportation infrastructure. Revises the surface transportation, research, development, and technology program to direct the Administrator to make grants to institutions of higher education (including consortia) to establish regional UTCs to carry out research, development, and technology transfer activities in the field of green transportation infrastructure (i.e., infrastructure that preserves and restores natural processes, utilizes natural design techniques, and minimizes energy consumption and pollution). Directs the Administrator to: (1) contract with the National Research Council to review the research, development, and technology transfer activities at the Turner Fairbank Highway Research facility; and (2) establish a pavement research, deployment, and education program. Reauthorizes: (1) the surface transportation research, development, and technology program; and (2) university transportation research.</summary>
</bill>
