<bill session="110" type="s" number="3502" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Children's Environmental Health and Safety Risk Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the establishment of a task force to address the environmental health and safety risks posed to children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2008--Introduced.
Children's Environmental Health and Safety Risk Reduction Act - Establishes the Task Force on Environmental Health and Safety Risks to Children to: (1) recommend to the President federal strategies for children's environmental health and safety; and (2) develop a proposed plan for use in ensuring that researchers and federal research agencies have access to information on federal research that relates to adverse health risk in children resulting from exposure to environmental health and safety risks.Directs each federal agency, for each regulatory action submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for review that may concern an environmental health risk or safety risk that may disproportionately affect children, to provide: (1) an evaluation of the environmental health and safety effects of the planned regulation; and (2) an explanation of why the planned regulation is preferable to other potentially effective and reasonable feasible alternatives considered by the agency. Requires agencies to comply with such requirements to the maximum extent practicable in emergency situations.Requires the Director of OMB to convene the Forum on Child and Family Statistics to: (1) publish an annual report that describes the most important indicators of the well-being of U.S. children; (2) provide an ongoing review of federal collection and dissemination of data on children and families; and (3) make recommendations to improve the coverage and coordination of data collection and to reduce duplication and overlap.Applies this Act only to the executive branch.</summary>
</bill>
