<bill session="112" type="h" number="2281" updated="2013-07-20T01:30:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Next Generation Wireless Disclosure Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require accurate disclosures to consumers of the terms and conditions of 4G service and other advanced wireless mobile broadband service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400124"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2011-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2011-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2011-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1695"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2011--Introduced.
Next Generation Wireless Disclosure Act - Requires a person selling advanced wireless mobile broadband service (4G service or a successor technology) directly to a consumer to prominently, clearly, and accurately disclose service terms and conditions in marketing materials and upon sale. Excludes from such requirements transactions in which the consumer receives a device allowing access to a specified quantity of prepaid advanced wireless mobile broadband service when the average consumer would not expect the selling agents to have expertise regarding the terms and conditions. Directs a person: (1) packaging such prepaid service for ultimate sale to consumers to accurately and clearly display the terms and conditions on all marketing materials and packaging; and (2) selling wholesale service to another person for ultimate sale to consumers to disclose the information necessary to permit such other person to comply with this Act. Sets forth required disclosures including: (1) the guaranteed minimum transmit and receive data rates for Internet protocol packets, (2) reliability ratings, (3) service-based pricing, (4) network management policies, (5) utilized technology services, and (6) a website showing complete terms of service and coverage area maps. Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to: (1) promulgate implementing regulations, (2) set minimum signal strength and data rates for a location to be within the coverage area of such service, and (3) enforce this Act as if it were a part of the Communications Act of 1934. Directs the FCC to complete an annual study evaluating the speed and pricing of advanced wireless mobile broadband service offered in the United States by the 10 largest service providers.</summary>
</bill>
