<bill session="109" type="h" number="4783" updated="2013-07-19T19:46:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Permanent Protection for Florida Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit offshore drilling on the outer Continental Shelf off the State of Florida, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2006-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="2239"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Ocean mining"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Submarine oil well drilling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2006--Introduced.
Permanent Protection for Florida Act of 2006 - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to prohibit the Secretary of the Interior from issuing a lease for the exploration, development, or production of oil, natural gas, or any other mineral in the Florida exclusion zone. Expresses the sense of Congress that states are encouraged not to issue a permit or lease for new oil and natural gas slant, directional, or offshore drilling in or under any of the Great Lakes. Declares this Act applicable to non-producing leases. Withdraws the Florida exclusion zone from: (1) any Outer Continental Shelf protraction diagram prepared by the Minerals Management Service; and (2) consideration for inclusion in any five-year Outer Continental Shelf leasing program of the Department of the Interior. Declares that any non-producing or similar lease that is suspended as of the enactment of this Act in the Eastern planning area of the Gulf of Mexico (with a specified exception), and that is also active, non-producing, or in suspension as of such date, is relinquished and abandoned in exchange for royalty forgiveness for revenue streams owed by oil and gas lessees producing on that date in the Central and Western planning areas of the Gulf of Mexico. Specifies the characteristics of any relinquished and abandoned lease whose lessee is ineligible for royalty forgiveness. Extends until June 30, 2020, the expiration date for the withdrawal of areas of the Outer Continental Shelf described in a specified Memorandum.</summary>
</bill>
