<bill session="109" type="s" number="1198" updated="2013-07-19T20:23:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Solid Waste Importation and Management Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize States to restrict receipt of foreign municipal solid waste, to implement the Agreement Concerning the Transboundary Movement of Hazardous Waste between the United States and Canada, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2005-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6232"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6232-6234" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2491"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="2780"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2005--Introduced.
International Solid Waste Importation and Management Act of 2005 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize states to enact laws restricting the receipt and disposal of foreign municipal solid waste within their borders until the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) promulgates regulations implementing and enforcing the Agreement Concerning the Transboundary Movement of Hazardous Waste between the United States and Canada (Agreement). Defines the authority of the Administrator with respect to the importation and exportation of municipal solid waste under the Agreement. Requires the Administrator to give substantial weight to the views of affected states and local governments before consenting to the importation of foreign municipal solid waste into the United States under the Agreement, and to consider the impact of such importation on: (1) the continued public support for state and local recyling programs; (2) landfill capacities; (3) air emissions and road deterioration from increased vehicular traffic; and (4) homeland security, public health, and the environment. Authorizes the Administrator to assess civil penalties for any past or current violations of this Act or to commence a civil action in the U.S. district court.</summary>
</bill>
