<bill session="113" type="s" number="236" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Patient Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a Medicare payment option for patients and physicians or practitioners to freely contract, without penalty, for Medicare fee-for-service items and services, while allowing Medicare beneficiaries to use their Medicare benefits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2013-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2013-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2013-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1310"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2300"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2013--Introduced.
Medicare Patient Empowerment Act - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to allow any Medicare beneficiary to enter into a contract with a non-participating (as well as with a participating) physician or practitioner for any item or service covered by Medicare. Allows such beneficiaries to submit a claim for Medicare payment in the amount that would otherwise apply if the claim had been filed by a participating physician or practitioner in the payment area where the physician or practitioner covered by the contract resides. Requires a Medicare beneficiary to agree in writing in such a contract to: (1) pay the physician or practitioner for a Medicare-covered item or service; and (2) submit (in lieu of the physician or practitioner) a claim for Medicare payment. Allows a beneficiary, however, to negotiate, as a term of the contract, for the physician or practitioner to file such claims on the beneficiary's behalf. Preempts state laws from limiting the amount of charges for physician and practitioner services for which Medicare payment is made.</summary>
</bill>
