<bill session="112" type="s" number="3469" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Waste Administration Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a new organization to manage nuclear waste, provide a consensual process for siting nuclear waste facilities, ensure adequate funding for managing nuclear waste, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5873-5874"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5874-5880" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-598.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2012--Introduced.
Nuclear Waste Administration Act of 2012 - Establishes as an independent agency in the executive branch: (1) the Nuclear Waste Administration (NWA) to provide for the permanent disposal of nuclear waste, including the siting, construction, and operation of additional repositories, a test and evaluation facility, and additional storage facilities; and (2) the Nuclear Waste Oversight Board. Transfers to the NWA Administrator specified functions of the Secretary of Energy. Prescribes guidelines for nuclear waste facilities and for the identification and suitability of candidate sites. Directs the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to adopt generally applicable standards to protect the environment from offsite releases from radioactive material in geological repositories. Directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to amend its regulations governing the licensing of geological repositories to make them consistent with comparable EPA standards. Prohibits the Administrator, before ratification of a consent agreement with a state, local, or tribal government, from possessing, taking title to, or storing more than 10,000 metric tons of spent nuclear repository fuel at a storage facility licensed under this Act. Requires the Secretary to arrange for the Administrator to dispose of defense wastes in a repository developed under this Act. Confers upon the Administrator responsibility for transporting nuclear waste under this Act. Establishes in the Treasury the Nuclear Waste Administration Working Capital Fund. Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to reflect the amendments made by this Act. Authorizes the Administrator to proceed with siting and licensing consolidated storage facilities pursuant to a certain cooperative agreement entered into before the date of enactment of this Act. Terminates those authorities of the Secretary regarding siting, construction, and operation of repositories, storage facilities, or test and evaluation facilities which were not transferred to the Administrator under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
