<bill session="111" type="h" number="824" updated="2013-07-19T23:19:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family and Medical Leave Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 and title 5, United States Code, to allow employees to take, as additional leave, parental involvement leave to participate in or attend their children's and grandchildren's educational and extracurricular activities, and to clarify that leave may be taken for routine family medical needs and to assist elderly relatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2009-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2009-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2009-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2009-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2009-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2009-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2009-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E187"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/2009--Introduced.
Family and Medical Leave Enhancement Act of 2009 - Amends the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (FMLA) to cover employees at worksites that employ fewer than 50 employees, but not fewer than 25 employees. Continues to exempt from FMLA coverage employees at worksites that employ fewer than 25 employees (currently 50), if the total number of employees employed by that employer within 75 miles of that worksite is fewer than 25 (currently 50). Allows an employee covered by FMLA to take up to 4 hours during any 30-day period, and up to 24 hours during any 12-month period, of parental involvement leave to participate in or attend activities that are sponsored by a school or community organization; and (2) relate to a program of the school or organization that is attended by the employee's child or grandchild. Permits the use of such parental involvement leave to meet routine family medical care needs, including: (1) such employee's medical and dental appointments, or their spouse, child, or grandchild; and (2) the care needs of their related elderly individuals, including visits to nursing homes and group homes. Allows an employee to elect, or an employer to require, substitution of any of the paid or family leave or paid medical or sick leave of the employee for any leave provided under this Act. Declares that nothing in this Act shall require an employer to provide paid sick leave or paid medical leave in situations where such employer would not normally provide any such paid leave. Imposes on the employee requesting leave certain notification requirements. Allows an employer to require certification supporting such requests. Applies the parental involvement and family wellness leave allowance to federal employees.</summary>
</bill>
