<bill session="111" type="s" number="3627" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HIV/AIDS Save Lives First Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that United States global HIV/AIDS assistance prioritizes saving lives by focusing on access to treatment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400576"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6085-6086"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2010--Introduced.
HIV/AIDS Save Lives First Act of 2010 - Amends the United States Leadership Against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria Act of 2003 regarding allocation of bilateral global HIV/AIDS assistance to: (1) make such allocation permanent; (2) increase the treatment allocation to 75%; and (3) allocate amounts to expand the use of rapid HIV/AIDS testing, with a set-aside for assistance to countries with a national policy of universal rapid HIV/AIDS diagnosis of all patients of publicly funded facilities, including pregnant women and newborns. Revises provisions concerning treatment, prevention, and care goals to require that by the end of FY2013: (1) antiretroviral treatment for HIV/AIDS and associated opportunistic infections or medical monitoring of HIV-seropositive people not in clinical need of retroviral treatment has been provided to at least 5 million people living in recipient countries; (2) at least 1 billion rapid tests for HIV/AIDS have been conducted on people living in such countries; and (3) every available intervention is provided to ensure that 100% of infants born to HIV-infected women in such countries are born uninfected and remain uninfected for at least the first year after birth. Sets forth administrative and per-patient funding limitations.</summary>
</bill>
