<bill session="110" type="s" number="283" updated="2013-07-19T22:22:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Compacts of Free Association Amendments Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Compacts of Free Association Amendments Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Compact of Free Association Amendments Act of 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S510"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S510-511" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-01-31">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-02-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-17.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-02-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="42">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 42.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2705"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="2705"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Palau Islands"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Compacts of Free Association Amendments Act of 2007 - Amends the Compact of Free Association Amendments Act of 2003 with respect to the provision of emergency and disaster assistance through the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) and the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to the Federated States of Micronesia and the Republic of the Marshall Islands. Provides with respect to the Republic of Palau that: (1) students from Micronesia and the Marshall Islands attending universities or colleges in Palau shall remain eligible for specified higher education assistance; and (2) government, institutions, and people of Palau shall be eligible for education assistance through FY2009 that they were eligible for in FY2003. Provides for the continuation of legal services to the citizens of Micronesia, Palau, and the Marshall Islands legally residing in the United States (including territories and possessions). Authorizes Micronesia, Palau, and the Marshall Islands to transmit videotaped programming. Authorizes the government of Palau to deposit the payment otherwise payable to the U.S. government under P.L. 101-219 (a law concerning the implementation of the Palau Compact of Free Association and insular area matters) into a trust fund if: (1) trust fund earnings are expended solely for maintenance of the road system constructed pursuant to the Compact of Free Association between the U.S. government and the government of Palau; and (2) the trust fund is established and operated pursuant to an agreement between the U.S. government and the government of Palau. Provides that in the U.S.-RMI Compact (Marshall Islands), the U.S.-FSM Compact (Micronesia), and their respective trust fund subsidiary agreements, for the purposes of taxation by the United States or its subsidiary jurisdictions, the term "state" means state, territory, or the District of Columbia.</summary>
</bill>
