<bill session="110" type="s" number="1583" updated="2013-07-19T22:34:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coral Reef Ecosystem Conservation Amendments Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000, and for other coral conservation purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7380-7385" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1580"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Coral reefs"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Oceanography"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2007--Introduced.
Coral Reef Ecosystem Conservation Amendments Act of 2007 - Amends the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 to direct the Secretary of Commerce to make grants for projects for the conservation of coral reef ecosystems (under current law, conservation of coral reefs). Modifies various requirements of the grant program. Authorizes the Secretary to make agreements with nonprofit organizations (under current law, an agreement with a nonprofit organization) for public-private partnerships promoting coral reef ecosystem conservation. Authorizes the Secretary, in cooperation with the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), to provide assistance to any state, local, or territorial government agency for any unforeseen or disaster-related circumstance regarding coral reef ecosystems. (Current law does not mention FEMA.) Authorizes the Secretary to conduct activities, including with local, regional, or international programs and partners, to conserve coral reef ecosystems. (Current law does not mention local, regional, or international programs and partners.) Directs the Secretary to provide for the long-term stewardship of environmental data, products, and information. Directs the Secretary to establish the Emergency Response, Stabilization, and Restoration Account in the existing Damage Assessment Restoration Revolving Fund. Authorizes the Secretary to issue permits for activities that would otherwise be prohibited by the Act. Amends the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act to include coral reef ecosystems in the definition of "wildlife" and "wildlife resources." Requires construing the Acts commonly known as the Fish and Wildlife Act of 1956 and the Fish and Wildlife Improvement Act of 1978 to include coral reef ecosystems in those terms. Amends the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide technical and financial assistance to states, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands, for management and conservation of coral reef ecosystems.</summary>
</bill>
