<bill session="113" type="s" number="1409" updated="2013-11-02T07:04:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Better Education and Skills Training for America's Workforce Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit for employer-provided job training, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2013--Introduced.
Better Education and Skills Training for America's Workforce Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow tax credits for: (1) the qualified training expenses of job trainees who have been unemployed for at least 90 days before enrolling in a training program, that are paid by U.S.-based employers; and (2) investment in a qualified job training partnership between a private business and an institution of higher education or a labor organization. Defines "qualifying training expenses" as an eligible trainee's qualified tuition costs, which may include costs for books and enrollment in a training program at an institution of higher education that may include a single course, multiple courses, or a combination of work training and study and that is reasonably necessary for employment. Terminates the credit for qualified training expenses of job trainees after December 31, 2016. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a Qualified Job Training Partnership program to consider and award certifications for qualified investments eligible for credits to qualified job training partnerships. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to individuals who make an investment in a qualified job training partnership, in lieu of a tax credit.</summary>
</bill>
