<bill session="112" type="h" number="3796" updated="2013-07-20T01:42:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-01T20:46:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-08-01T20:46:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Adam Walsh Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Adam Walsh Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Adam Walsh Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize certain programs established by the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412265" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412473" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2012-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2012-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2012-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2012-01-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-07-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T14:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 112-637.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-07-31T14:59:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="458">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 458.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5450-5452" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3796.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T19:36:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Scott (VA) objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01T20:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5618-5619" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-08-01T20:46:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/31/2012 H5451" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01T20:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2870"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2012--Passed House amended.
Adam Walsh Reauthorization Act of 2012 - Amends the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (Adam Walsh Act) to authorize appropriations through FY2017 for: (1) the Sex Offender Management Assistance (SOMA) program, (2) the Jessica Lunsford Address Verification Grant Program, and (3) federal assistance to states in locating and apprehending sex offenders who violate sex offender registration requirements. Requires a tier III sex offender to maintain a clean record for 15 (currently, 25) years to qualify for a reduction in the period for which such offender must keep a sex offender registration current. Allows a jurisdiction to exempt from disclosure through the Internet any information about a sex offender for whom the offense giving rise to the duty to register was one for which the offender was adjudicated delinquent (or otherwise convicted) as a juvenile. Modifies penalty provisions applicable to states that fail to substantially implement sex offender registration and notification requirements under the Adam Walsh Act to require such states to return to the Attorney General for reallocation to other jurisdictions (including local governments) 10% of amounts allocable to those states under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program. Directs the National Institute of Justice to report on the public safety impact, recidivism, and collateral consequences of long-term registration of juvenile sex offenders. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize appropriations through FY2017 for juvenile sex offender treatment grants.</summary>
</bill>
