<bill session="109" type="sr" number="442" updated="2013-07-19T20:10:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the deep disappointment of the Senate with respect to the election of Iran to a leadership position in the United Nations Disarmament Commission and requesting the President to withhold funding to the United Nations unless credible reforms are made.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2006-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2006-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2006-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2006-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="2006-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3515-3516"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3515" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="786"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations delegations"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
    <term name="United Nations structure"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2006--Introduced.
Expresses disappointment at the failure of the Asia group members of the United Nations Disarmament Commission to stop Iran's election as vice chair of that body. Asserts that the Commission has no credibility on disarmament issues due to Iran's participation, particularly in light of Iran's defiance in disregarding International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) and the Security Council Presidential Statement resolutions relating to its nuclear program. Calls on the United States to reject all Commission resolutions. Condemns Iran's continued intransigence with respect to its nuclear program, treatment of Israel, and sponsorship of terror. States that the Senate shall work to ensure that U.S. funding is withheld from: (1) the regular budget of the United Nations in the amount directed towards the Commission; and (2) any U.N. commission in which the worst violators of the principles it claims to promote are included in its membership. Calls on the United Nations to deny Iranian participation in any U.N. commission until it: (1) complies with Non-Proliferation Treaty and IAEA resolutions; (2) halts all uranium enrichment activities and its calls for Israel's destruction; and (3) withdraws terrorist support. Calls on the President to monitor U.N. reform and withhold funding unless credible reforms are made prior to biannual budget discussions.</summary>
</bill>
