<bill session="109" type="s" number="3834" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to address online pharmacies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2006-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8848"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2006--Introduced.
Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act of 2006 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to impose registration and reporting requirements on pharmacies that seek to deliver, distribute, or dispense over the Internet a controlled substance or prescription drug (online pharmacies). Exempts pharmacies that merely advertise on the Internet. Prohibits the delivery, distribution, or dispensing of a controlled substance or prescription drug over the Internet without a valid prescription issued pursuant to a medical evaluation conducted in the presence of a registered medical practitioner. Requires an online pharmacy to include on its website: (1) a statement that it complies with the requirements of this Act; (2) identifying information, including its physical address, phone numbers, and email address; (3) the qualifications of its pharmacist-in-charge and the practitioners who prescribe controlled substances or prescription drugs; and (4) a list of states in which it is licensed. Increases criminal penalties for certain controlled substances offenses. Imposes criminal penalties for the unlawful delivery, distribution, or dispensing of controlled substances or prescription drugs over the Internet. Authorizes a state attorney general to apply for injunctions or obtain damages and other civil remedies against an online pharmacy that poses a threat to the residents of such state.</summary>
</bill>
