<bill session="111" type="s" number="657" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sunshine in the Courtroom Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Sunshine in the Courtroom Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for media coverage of Federal court proceedings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2009-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-04-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="361">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 361.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3054"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2010--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Sunshine in the Courtroom Act of 2009 - Authorizes the presiding judge of a U.S. appellate court or U.S. district court to permit the photographing, electronic recording, broadcasting, or televising to the public of court proceedings over which that judge presides, except when such action would constitute a violation of the due process rights of any party. Directs: (1) a district court, upon the request of any witness in a trial proceeding other than a party, to order the face and voice of the witness to be disguised or otherwise obscured to render the witness unrecognizable to the broadcast audience of the trial proceeding; and (2) the presiding judge in a trial proceeding to inform each witness who is not a party of the right to make such request. Authorizes the Judicial Conference of the United States to promulgate advisory guidelines to which a presiding judge may refer in making decisions regarding the management and administration of photographing, recording, broadcasting, or televising described in this Act. Requires the Judicial Conference of the United States to promulgate mandatory guidelines which a presiding judge must follow for obscuring certain vulnerable witnesses. Prohibits broadcast of conferences between attorneys and clients.</summary>
</bill>
