<bill session="111" type="s" number="2963" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cathedral Rock and Horse Heaven Wilderness Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to designate certain land in the State of Oregon as wilderness, to provide for the exchange of certain Federal land and non-Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S343-344"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S344-345" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-566.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/28/2010--Introduced.
Cathedral Rock and Horse Heaven Wilderness Act of 2010 - Designates specified Bureau of Land Management (BLM) land in Oregon, to be known as the Cathedral Rock Wilderness and the Horse Heaven Wilderness, as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Sets forth requirements for the administration of the wilderness areas, including with respect to the incorporation of acquired land and interests, domestic livestock grazing, access to non-federal land, state water laws, and tribal rights. Withdraws federal land within the wilderness areas from all forms of: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials. Authorizes certain land exchanges with specified landowners. Requires appraisals to be conducted of the federal and non-federal land to be exchanged.</summary>
</bill>
