<bill session="109" type="s" number="297" updated="2013-07-19T20:15:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Montserrat Immigration Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for adjustment of immigration status for certain aliens granted temporary protected status in the United States because of conditions in Montserrat, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="342"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Montserrat"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2005--Introduced.
Montserrat Immigration Fairness Act - Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) to grant lawful permanent resident status to certain nationals of Montserrat previously granted temporary protected status in the United States (and specified family members). Authorizes aliens previously ordered excluded, deported, or removed, or ordered to depart voluntarily, to apply for adjustment of status under this Act. Requires the Secretary to provide work authorization and related documentation to principal aliens seeking the benefits of this Act. Directs the Secretary to provide specified administrative review procedures for such aliens and their qualifying family members. States that the granting of adjustment of status for principal aliens under this Act shall not reduce the number of available immigrant visas.</summary>
</bill>
