<bill session="110" type="hr" number="363" updated="2013-07-19T20:53:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-02T23:45:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-05-02T23:45:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to clarify certain matters relating to official conduct.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400316"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2007-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02T23:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Standards of Official Conduct discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02T23:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Jones (OH) asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02T23:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4411-4412" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2007-05-02T23:45:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H45411-4412" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02T23:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government aircraft"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Private aviation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/2007--Passed House without amendment.
Amends Rule XXIII (Code of Official Conduct) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to authorize a Member of Congress to use personal, official, or campaign funds for a flight on an aircraft that is operated: (1) by an air carrier or commercial operator certificated by the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), and the flight is required to be conducted under air carrier safety rules; or (2) in the case of travel abroad, by an air carrier or commercial operator certificated by an appropriate foreign civil aviation authority, and the flight is similarly required to be conducted under air carrier safety rules. Allows the use of such funds also if the aircraft: (1) is owned or leased by the Member or a family member (including a privately owned aircraft in which such Member or family member has an ownership interest, and the Member does not use the aircraft any more than the proportionate share of ownership allows); or (3) is operated by a state or federal entity. Allows the use of such funds also for a flight that consists of the personal use of an aircraft supplied to a Member by an individual on the basis of personal friendship.</summary>
</bill>
