<bill session="112" type="s" number="2103" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Pain-Capable Unborn Child Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to protect pain-capable unborn children in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412495"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2012-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2012-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2012-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2012-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2012-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2012-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2012-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2012-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2012-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2012-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2012-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-13">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="3803"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2012--Introduced.
District of Columbia Pain-Capable Unborn Child Protection Act - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit any person from performing or attempting to perform an abortion within the District of Columbia except in conformity with this Act's requirements. Requires the physician to first make a determination of the probable post-fertilization age of the unborn child, or reasonably rely upon such a determination made by another physician, by making inquiries of the pregnant woman and performing such medical examinations and tests as a reasonably prudent physician would consider necessary. Prohibits the abortion from being performed if the probable post-fertilization age of the unborn child is 20 weeks or greater. Makes an exception where necessary to save the life of a pregnant woman whose life is endangered by a physical disorder, illness, or injury, excluding psychological or emotional conditions or any claim or diagnosis that the woman will engage in conduct intended to result in her death. Permits a physician to terminate a pregnancy under such exception only in the manner which provides the best opportunity for the unborn child to survive, unless termination of the pregnancy in that manner would pose a greater risk of the death or substantial and irreversible physical impairment of a major bodily function, not including psychological or emotional conditions, of the pregnant woman than would other available methods. Prescribes penalties for violations. Bars prosecution of a woman upon whom an abortion is performed in violation of this Act, but authorizes such a woman or the father or maternal grandparent of the unborn child to obtain appropriate relief through a civil action. Provides for injunctive relief to prevent violations. Sets forth specified privacy protections in court proceedings for the woman upon whom an abortion has been performed. Requires any physician who performs an abortion within the District to report it to the Department of Health of the District of Columbia, which shall issue annual public reports.</summary>
</bill>
