<bill session="111" type="h" number="1144" updated="2013-07-19T23:22:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fulfilling the Potential of Women in Academic Science and Engineering Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase awareness of the existence of and to overcome gender bias in academic science and engineering through research and training, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2009-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412273" joined="2009-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2009-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2009-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412288" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400280" joined="2009-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2009-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2009-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Science Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Research and Science Education" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/24/2009--Introduced.
Fulfilling the Potential of Women in Academic Science and Engineering Act - Requires the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to develop a policy for federal science agencies to carry out a program of workshops that educate specified federally funded researchers about methods that minimize the effects of gender bias in the evaluation of federal research grants and in the related academic advancement of the recipients of these grants. Requires the support of at least one workshop every two years among the federal science agencies in the major science and engineering disciplines.Authorizes federal science agencies to carry out such program by making grants to eligible organizations as described in this Act. Requires the Director to transmit a report evaluating such program's impact in reducing gender bias towards women engaged in research funded by the federal government. Requires the Director to develop a policy to extend research grant support and provide interim technical support for federally funded researchers who are caregivers. Requires transmission of a copy of such policy to specified congressional committees. Requires federal science agencies to collect specified standardized annual data for all applications for research and development grants to institutions of higher education and to submit the data collected to the National Science Foundation (NSF). Makes the NSF responsible for storing and publishing all such grant data. Requires annual publication of a list of the institutions of higher education science and engineering departments represented by individuals who attend the workshops described above.</summary>
</bill>
