<bill session="112" type="h" number="6313" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote peaceful and collaborative resolution of maritime territorial disputes in the South China Sea and its environs and other maritime areas adjacent to the East Asian mainland.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2012-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-09-12">
      <text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="352"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="ASEAN countries"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State should: (1) reaffirm U.S. support for the peaceful resolution of maritime territorial disputes in the South China Sea, the East China Sea, the Taiwan Strait, and the Yellow Sea; (2) condemn the use of force by China in the South China and East China Seas and by China's North Korean ally in the Yellow Sea; (3) call on all parties to these territorial disputes to refrain from threatening force or using force to assert territorial claims; (4) welcome the diplomatic efforts of Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and U.S. allies and partners in Taiwan, Japan, and the Republic of Korea to resolve these outstanding disputes; and (5) support U.S. Armed Forces operations in support of freedom of navigation rights in international waters and air space in the South China Sea, the East China Sea, the Taiwan Strait, and the Yellow Sea.</summary>
</bill>
