<bill session="109" type="h" number="2099" updated="2013-07-19T19:22:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-19T01:03:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-19T01:03:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Illinois and Michigan Canal National Heritage Corridor Act Amendments of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400513"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400254" joined="2005-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2005-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-19T01:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Resources discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-19T01:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Pombo asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-19T01:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12218-12224" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H12219-12220" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-12-19T01:03:00-05:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-19T01:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="2297"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="200"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="203"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Architecture"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Mountains"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h675"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/19/2005--Passed House amended.
Title I: Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area - Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area Act - (Sec. 104) Establishes the Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area in Georgia. (Sec. 105) Designates the Arabia Mountain Heritage Area Alliance as the local coordinating entity for the Area. Allows the entity, for developing and implementing the management plan, to use federal funds to make grants to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, states and their political subdivisions, and private organizations. Prohibits the entity from using federal funds to acquire real property or an interest in real property. (Sec. 106) Requires the entity to submit a management plan for the Area to the Secretary of the Interior that incorporates an integrated and cooperative approach to protect, interpret, and enhance the natural, cultural, historical, scenic, and recreational resources of the Area. Requires the plan to be based on the preferred concept in the document entitled "Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area Feasibility Study." Authorizes the Secretary to provide financial and technical assistance to develop and implement the plan. (Sec. 108) Specifies the effect of this title on certain authorities for occupational safety, conservation, and environmental regulations and land use regulations. (Sec. 109) Authorizes appropriations of $10 million. Limits: (1) the funding that may be authorized to be appropriated for any fiscal year to $1 million; and (2) the federal share of the cost of any project or activity to 50%. (Sec. 110) Terminates the authority of the Secretary to provide assistance under this title 15 years after enactment. (Sec. 111) Sets forth requirements concerning: (1) the preservation, conservation, or promotion of privately owned property by the plan; and (2) the withdrawal of private property from inclusion within the boundary of the Area. Specifies private property protections. Title II: Illinois and Michigan Canal National Heritage Corridor Act Amendments - Illinois and Michigan Canal National Heritage Corridor Act Amendments of 2005 - (Sec. 202) Amends the Illinois and Michigan Canal National Heritage Corridor Act of 1984 to designate, upon the termination of the Illinois and Michigan Canal National Heritage Corridor Commission, the Canal Corridor Association to be the local coordinating entity for the Illinois and Michigan Canal National Heritage Corridor. Allows the Association, for preparing and implementing the management plan, to use federal funds to make grants to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, states and their political subdivisions, private organizations, or any person. Prohibits the Association from using federal funds to acquire real property or an interest in real property. Requires the Association to develop and submit a proposed management plan for the Corridor. Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical and financial assistance to the Association for the development and implementation of the management plan. Authorizes appropriations of $10 million. Limits: (1) the funding that may be authorized to be appropriated for any fiscal year to $1 million; and (2) the federal share of the cost of any project or activity to 50%. Terminates the authority of the Secretary to provide assistance under this title 15 years after enactment. (Sec. 203) Sets forth requirements concerning: (1) the preservation, conservation, or promotion of privately owned property by the plan; and (2) the withdrawal of private property from inclusion within the boundary of the Area. Specifies private property protections.</summary>
</bill>
