<bill session="109" type="h" number="4292" updated="2013-07-19T19:42:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend Public Law 107-153 to further encourage the negotiated settlement of tribal claims.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400322"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2005-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06T15:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-324.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-12-06T15:52:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="178">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 178.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1892"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/6/2005--Reported to House without amendment.
Amends specified federal law with respect to the negotiated settlement of tribal claims. Extends from December 31, 1999, to December 31, 2005, the earliest date on which an Indian tribe shall be deemed to have received a certain reconciliation report for purposes of calculating the statute of limitations on claims against the United States for the mismanagement of tribal trust assets. (The reconciliation report, required by the American Indian Trust Fund Management Reform Act of 1994 (AITFMRA), is a report by the Secretary of the Interior to specified congressional committees identifying for each tribal trust fund account for which the Secretary is responsible a balance reconciled as of September 30, 1995. The stated intent of AITFMRA is to provide recipients of reconciliation reports with the opportunity to postpone the filing of claims, or to facilitate the voluntary dismissal of claims, to encourage settlement negotiations with the United States.)</summary>
</bill>
