<bill session="112" type="s" number="3197" updated="2013-07-20T02:44:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Women's Small Business Ownership Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the women's business center program of the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2012-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2012-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3281-3282"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3283-3286" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3442"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3572"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2012--Introduced.
Women's Small Business Ownership Act of 2012 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Office of Women's Business Ownership within the Small Business Administration (SBA) to address issues concerning the management, operations, manufacturing, technology, finance, retail and product sales, international trade, government contracting, and other disciplines required for starting, operating, and increasing the business of a small business. Authorizes the SBA Administrator to provide annual training for women's business ownership representatives to enable them to carry out such responsibilities. Authorizes the Administrator to provide financial assistance to qualifying entities to conduct projects designed to provide training and counseling meeting the needs of women business owners, especially socially and economically disadvantaged women business owners. Provides assistance amounts of at least $100,000 and up to $150,000 per year. Directs the Administrator to consult with each association of women's business centers to develop: (1) a training program for the staff of such centers, and (2) recommendations to improve the policies and procedures for governing the general operations and administration of the women's business center program. Outlines application and other requirements for entities to receive assistance to conduct such projects. Directs the Administrator to solicit applications and award grants for the first fiscal year beginning after the enactment of this Act, and every third fiscal year thereafter. Provides for the review and approval of grant applications, as well as conditions for continued funding. Allows for multiple awards to the same entities. Directs the Comptroller General (CG) to study and report to Congress on: (1) the unique economic issues facing women's business centers located in predominately rural, urban, or insular areas; and (2) SBA oversight of women's business centers.</summary>
</bill>
