<bill session="109" type="h" number="3462" updated="2013-07-19T19:34:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-10T14:22:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-10T14:22:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the conveyance of the Bureau of Land Management parcels known as the White Acre and Gambel Oak properties and related real property to Park City, Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-04-25T16:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-418.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-04-25T16:50:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="227">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 227.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Radanovich moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4923-4924" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3462.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-07-10T14:22:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4923" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2006--Passed House amended.
(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on April 25, 2006. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to Park City, Utah, two parcels of property located in Park City that are currently under the management jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and known as the White Acre and Gambel Oak properties. Requires such conveyance to be made by a deed or deeds containing a restriction requiring that the lands be maintained as open space and used only for public recreation purposes or other purposes consistent with their maintenance as open space. Prohibits interpreting this restriction as prohibiting the construction or maintenance of recreational facilities, utilities, or other structures that are consistent with the maintenance of such lands as open space or its use for public recreation purposes. Requires Park City to pay to the Secretary an amount consistent with conveyances to governmental entities for recreational purposes under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act. Directs the Secretary to offer for sale two specified parcels of property located in Park City that are currently under the management jurisdiction of the BLM. Requires such land sale to be consistent with specified provisions under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 through a competitive bidding process and for not less than fair market value. Sets forth requirements for the disposition and use of the proceeds derived from such sale, including providing for the use of such proceeds for environmental restoration projects on BLM-administered lands within the BLM Salt Lake City Field Office.</summary>
</bill>
