<bill session="109" type="s" number="240" updated="2013-07-19T20:15:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Military Reservist Tax Credit Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow small business employers a credit against income tax with respect to employees who participate in the military reserve components and are called to active duty and with respect to replacement employees and to allow a comparable credit for activated military reservists who are self-employed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2005-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2005-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2005-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2005-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S747-749"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Replacement workers"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2005--Introduced.
Small Business Military Reservist Tax Credit Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) certain small business employers (50 or fewer employees) and small manufacturers (100 or fewer employees) a tax credit for a percentage of the differential between the average daily civilian compensation and average daily military pay and allowances of their military reservist employees who are called to active duty; (2) such employers a tax credit for the hiring of temporary replacement employees; and (3) self-employed military reservists a comparable tax credit for a percentage of the differential between their average daily self-employment income and their average daily military pay and allowances. Denies a tax credit: (1) to employers who fail to comply with employment or reemployment rights of military reservists; and (2) for employees who are called to active duty for training.</summary>
</bill>
