<bill session="111" type="h" number="5936" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Restoring Assistance for Families' and Seniors' Health Expenses Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal limitations imposed by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act on health-related tax benefits under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and to treat high deductible health plans as qualified health plans under such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400660"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412300" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2010-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5126"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2010--Introduced.
Restoring Assistance for Families' and Seniors' Health Expenses Act of 2010 - Repeals provisions of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) that: (1) increase from 7.5% to 10% the adjusted gross income threshold for claiming the tax deduction for medical expenses; (2) restrict payments from health savings accounts, medical savings accounts, and health flexible spending arrangements for medications solely to prescription drugs or insulin; (3) increase to 20% the penalty for distributions from a health savings or Archer medical savings account not used for qualified medical expenses; and (4) limit to $2,500 the annual salary reduction contribution to a health flexible spending arrangement under a cafeteria plan. Amends PPACA to treat a high deductible health plan as a qualified health plan under such Act.</summary>
</bill>
