<bill session="111" type="h" number="4380" updated="2013-07-19T23:51:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-11">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Miscellaneous Trade and Technical Corrections Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">United States Manufacturing Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">United States Manufacturing Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">United States Manufacturing Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to modify temporarily certain rates of duty, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400238"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2009-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Levin moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5825-5852" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4380.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21T11:16:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21T14:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5884" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-07-21T14:16:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="456" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 378 - 43 (Roll no. 456).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5825-5846" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-07-27" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6341" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-08-11">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-08-11" type="public" number="111-227">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-227.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2010--Public Law.
United States Manufacturing Enhancement Act of 2010 - Title I: New Duty Suspensions and Reductions - (Sec. 1004) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to provide for duty suspensions and reductions through December 31, 2012, for specified chemicals and other products. Title II: Existing Duty Suspensions and Reductions - (Sec. 2001) Extends existing suspensions and reductions of duties through December 31, 2012, for other specified chemicals and products. Imposes, suspends, and increases and/or decreases the duty on certain chemicals through December 31, 2012. Extends, through December 31, 2012, the suspension of duty on certain products. Imposes, through December 31, 2012, a duty on: (1) brakes designed for bicycles; and (2) certain 12V lead-acid storage batteries. Suspends, through December 31, 2012, the duty on: (1) certain catalytic converter mats of ceramic fibers; and (2) certain herbicides. Extends the duty on aspirin through December 31, 2012. Title III: Additional Existing Duty Suspensions and Reductions - (Sec. 3001) Extends existing suspensions and reductions of duties through December 31, 2012, for certain additional chemicals and products. Imposes, suspends, and increases and/or decreases the duty on certain chemicals and products through December 31, 2012. (Sec. 3002) Directs the U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to liquidate or reliquidate entries of articles (as amended by titles II and III) which were made on or after January 1, 2010, and before the 15th day after enactment of this Act, and with respect to which there would have been no duty or a reduced duty if the amendments applied to such entries, as though the entries had been made on the 15th day after enactment of this Act. Title IV: Customs User Fees; Time for Payment of Corporate Estimated Taxes; PAYGO Compliance - (Sec. 4001) Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (COBRA) to extend certain customs fees for the processing of merchandise entered into the United States through December 10, 2018, and November 30, 2018, respectively. (Sec. 4002) Amends the Hiring Incentives to Restore Employment Act to increase required estimated tax payments of corporations with at least $1 billion in assets in the third quarter of 2015 by 0.5% to 122.0% of such amount.</summary>
</bill>
