<bill session="112" type="h" number="2109" updated="2013-07-20T01:28:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Savings Account for Every American Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for each American the opportunity to provide for his or her retirement through a S.A.F.E. account, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2011-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2011-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2011-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2011-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2011-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2011-06-03" withdrawn="2011-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2011--Introduced.
Savings Account for Every American Act of 2011 - Allows employees and self-employed individuals with a Social Security number to elect to participate in a S.A.F.E. account. Defines such an account as a trust created exclusively for the benefit of an individual or his or her beneficiaries. Requires: (1) employers of electing employees to establish a payroll deduction program to make employee contributions (6.2% of wages) to such accounts, and (2) employer matching contributions after a participating employee has maintained an account for 15 years. Imposes penalties on employers who fail to make required payroll deductions or pay deducted wages to S.A.F.E. accounts. Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to study how to extend S.A.F.E. Accounts to federal civilian and military employees. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exempt S.A.F.E. Accounts from income taxation. Allows a tax deduction from gross income for cash contributions to such an account. Includes distributions from such an account in employee gross income, with specified exceptions for distributions after the Social Security retirement age or death, for purchase of certain insurance contracts, and for rollovers. Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code to exempt S.A.F.E. Account participants from Social Security taxes and exclude such participants from OASDI coverage.</summary>
</bill>
