<bill session="110" type="hr" number="794" updated="2013-07-19T20:57:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-06T21:15:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-11-06T21:15:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 3043) making appropriations for the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-05T21:25:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-427, by Mr. Hastings (FL).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-05T21:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 3043.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-11-05T21:25:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="146">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 146.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06T18:55:00-05:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Mr. Hastings (FL) called up H. Res. 794 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06T18:57:00-05:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Flake raised a point of order against the provisions of H. Res. 794 because it waived all points of order against the conference report to accompany H.R. 3043. The Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H. Res. 794. The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06T19:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Will the House now consider the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 203 - 178 (Roll no. 1044).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06T19:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12802-12805, H12806-12814" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06T19:49:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 794.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06T21:07:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 218 - 183 (Roll no. 1047).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12812-12813" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06T21:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2007-11-06T21:15:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="1048" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 216 - 182 (Roll no. 1048).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12802" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="110" type="h" number="3043"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/6/2007--Passed House without amendment.
Waives points of order against consideration of the conference report on H.R. 3043 (Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008). Makes a motion to proceed to consideration of H.R. 3688 (United States-Peru Trade Promotion Agreement Implementation Act) in order only if offered by the Majority Leader or his designee.</summary>
</bill>
