<bill session="110" type="s" number="612" updated="2013-07-19T22:25:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Women's Health Office Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the health of women through the establishment of Offices of Women's Health within the Department of Health and Human Services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="1072"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2007--Introduced.
Women's Health Office Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish an Office on Women's Health within the Office of the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Office, to establish: (1) a Department of Health and Human Services Coordinating Committee on Women's Health; and (2) a National Women's Health Information Center. Transfers the functions of the Office on Women's Health of the Public of Health Service to the Office on Women's Health within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). Amends the Public Health Service Act, the Social Security Act, and the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish separate Offices of Women's Health within the Office of the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), the Office of the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), and the Office of the Commissioner of the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), and an Office of Women's Health and Gender-Based Research within the Office of the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ). Directs the lead officers of each Office of Women's Health to establish goals, provide information on women's health activities, and establish a Coordinating Committee on Women's Health within their respective agencies. Prohibits termination, reorganization, or transfers of powers and duties of any federal office of women's health or appointive position with primary responsibility over women's health issues without congressional approval.</summary>
</bill>
