<bill session="113" type="s" number="1271" updated="2013-11-02T07:02:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the President to establish guidelines for the United States foreign assistance programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412491"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2013-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2638"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2013--Introduced.
Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013 - Directs the President to establish guidelines for the establishment of measurable goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans for U.S. foreign assistance. Requires: (1) each appropriate federal department or agency to begin using such guidelines within one year after their establishment, and (2) the President to submit a related report to Congress within 18 months. Directs the President to require the Secretary of State to revise the Department of State's Internet website, ForeignAssistance.gov, to make publicly available comprehensive and accessible information on U.S. foreign assistance programs on a country-by-country and program-by program basis. Expresses the sense of Congress that Congress shall take into account certain Government Accountability Office (GAO) reports required by this Act when making decisions regarding the appropriation of funds for each department or agency that administers U.S. foreign assistance. Authorizes a department or agency to use up to 5% of its foreign development assistance funds for activities under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
