<bill session="112" type="s" number="2179" updated="2013-07-20T02:35:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military and Veterans Educational Reform Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve oversight of educational assistance provided under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412249"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2012-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2012-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2012-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2012-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2012-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2012-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2012-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2012-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2012-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2012-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1541-1542"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-567.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2012--Introduced.
Military and Veterans Educational Reform Act of 2012 - Allows the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) or a state approving agency (SAA) to approve, for purposes of veterans' educational assistance provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), a course that leads to an associate or higher degree only when such course is an eligible program offered by an institution of higher education that has entered into and is complying with a program approved by the Secretary of Education under the Higher Education Act of 1965. Provides conditions under which the Secretary or a SAA may approve a course that does not lead to an associate or higher degree. Prohibits the approval of a non-degree course of education unless, among other things, the course is determined to further the purposes of the VA program. Provides additional requirements for the VA approval of nonaccredited courses. Requires additional requirements imposed by SAAs to be approved by the Secretary prior to use under the VA program. Provides additional requirements for the approval of programs of educational assistance for persons enlisting for active duty. Requires educational institutions to inform participants on matters relating to accreditation and educational outcomes as a condition of approval under educational assistance programs offered by the VA and Department of Defense (DOD). Directs an educational institution with 20 or more VA program participants enrolled, prior to approval, to provide adequate academic and student support services, including remediation, tutoring, and job placement counseling. Requires each SAA, as a condition of receiving VA reimbursement for program approval activities, to conduct education and outreach activities to assist participants in making well-informed choices about their education and successful transition into an educational environment. Requires SAAs to conduct annual audits of institutions that have VA program participants. Directs the Secretary to conduct mandatory annual compliance reviews of such institutions. Directs the Secretary to provide individualized, one-on-one counseling to veterans and members of the Armed Forces who are considering a program of education with assistance through the VA or DOD. Requires the Secretaries of VA and DOD to each establish a process whereby individuals are able to submit complaints regarding educational institutions relevant to the provision of educational assistance, including complaints regarding misrepresentation, fraud, waste, and abuse.</summary>
</bill>
