<bill session="112" type="h" number="974" updated="2013-07-20T01:18:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">True Cost of War Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the President to submit to Congress a report on the long-term costs of Operation Iraqi Freedom, Operation New Dawn, and Operation Enduring Freedom in Iraq and Afghanistan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2012-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2012-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2011-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2011--Introduced.
True Cost of War Act of 2011 - Directs the President, with contributions from the Secretary of Defense (DOD), the Secretary of State, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA), to report to Congress an estimate of the long-term costs of Operation New Dawn (the successor contingency operation to Operation Iraqi Freedom) and Operation Enduring Freedom under three specified scenarios based on the number of U.S. troops deployed in such operations, as well as contingency operation and withdrawal plans. Requires the President, in preparing such report, to make estimates and projections through at least FY2020, and to take into account specified cost factors, including: (1) the deployment of U.S. military personnel, contractors, and private security firms; (2) the number of veterans in need of medical or mental health care due to injuries and illnesses; (3) pending veterans' disability compensation claims; (4) total casualties and injuries; (5) current and future operational expenses and related costs; and (6) the amount of money borrowed to pay for such operations, the sources of that money, and the interest on the money borrowed.</summary>
</bill>
