<bill session="110" type="h" number="6028" updated="2013-07-19T21:56:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-10T13:31:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-06-10T13:31:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Merida Initiative to Combat Illicit Narcotics and Reduce Organized Crime Authorization Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Merida Initiative to Combat Illicit Narcotics and Reduce Organized Crime Authorization Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Merida Initiative to Combat Illicit Narcotics and Reduce Organized Crime Authorization Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize law enforcement and security assistance, and assistance to enhance the rule of law and strengthen civilian institutions, for Mexico and the countries of Central America, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400657" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-05-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T22:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Foreign Affairs. H. Rept. 110-673, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T22:12:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 6, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-06T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-06-06T12:37:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="445">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 445.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10T11:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Berman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10T11:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5126-5139" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10T11:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6028.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10T12:29:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10T13:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5142-5143" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-06-10T13:31:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="393" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 311 - 106 (Roll no. 393).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5126-5132" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10T13:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Cameras"/>
    <term name="Central America"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Guatemala"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Patrol aircraft"/>
    <term name="Patrol ships"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Polygraphs"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's shelters"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2008--Passed House amended.
Merida Initiative to Combat Illicit Narcotics and Reduce Organized Crime Authorization Act of 2008 - Title I: Assistance for Mexico - Subtitle A: Law Enforcement and Security Assistance - (Sec. 112) Authorizes the President to provide assistance for Mexico for: (1) counternarcotics and countertrafficking; (2) port, airport, and related security to assist in controlling the Mexico-U.S. and Mexico-Central America borders; (3) intelligence gathering operational technology; and (4) public security and law enforcement, including assistance to the National Council Against Addiction (CONADIC). (Sec. 114) Prohibits assistance to any armed forces of Mexico or law enforcement unit of Mexico if the Secretary of State determines that there is credible evidence that such unit has committed gross human rights violations. Makes such prohibition inapplicable if the Secretary reports to the appropriate congressional committees that the government of Mexico is taking effective measures to bring the responsible unit members to justice. (Sec. 115) Authorizes FY2008-FY2010 appropriations to carry out this subtitle, with not more that specified amounts allocated to the armed forces for each of FY2008-2010. Prohibits FY2009 funds from being provided to the Mexican Secretariat of Public Security until the President determines that the Mexican National Registry of Police Personnel (Registro Nacional de Personal Policial) is operational at the federal, state, and local levels. Subtitle B: Assistance to Enhance the Rule of Law and Strengthen Civilian Institutions - (Sec. 122) Authorizes the President to provide assistance to Mexico for: (1) institution building and the rule of law, including support for the Mexican Office of the Attorney General and for enhancing police professionalization; (2) anti-corruption, transparency, and human rights; (3) activities to prevent narcotics-related violence; and (4) employment and rural development programs. (Sec. 124) Authorizes FY2008-FY2010 appropriations to carry out this subtitle. Title II: Assistance for Countries of Central America - Subtitle A: Law Enforcement and Security Assistance - (Sec. 212) Authorizes the President to provide assistance to the countries of Central America (Belize, Costa Rica, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras, Nicaragua, Panama, Haiti, and the Dominican Republic) for: (1) counternarcotics, countertrafficking, and related security to combat narcotics trafficking and bulk currency smuggling; and (2) public security and law enforcement to combat transnational gangs. (Sec. 214) Prohibits providing assistance to any armed forces or law enforcement unit of a Central American country if the Secretary determines that there is credible evidence that such unit has committed gross human rights violations. Makes such prohibition inapplicable if the Secretary reports to the appropriate congressional committees that the government of the relevant Central American country is taking effective measures to bring the responsible unit members to justice. Authorizes FY2008-FY2010 appropriations to carry out this subtitle, including a set-aside for youth gang prevention activities. Subtitle B: Assistance to Enhance the Rule of Law and Strengthen Civilian Institutions - (Sec. 221) Authorizes the President to provide assistance to the countries of Central America to build the capacity of justice systems and to reduce high impunity rates. Authorizes FY2008-FY2010 appropriations. Title III: Administrative Provisions - (Sec. 301) Prohibits the President from providing assistance under title I or title II of this Act for a fiscal year until the end of a 15-day period beginning on the date that the President transmits to the appropriate congressional committees a determination that specified requirements have been met. (Sec. 302) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) activities undertaken under titles I and II should be performed by employees and officers of the recipient country; and (2) the United States should limit the number of U.S. contractors. Caps: (1) at 50 the number of U.S. citizens or foreign nationals that may be retained as contractors to carry out title I (Mexico); and (2) at 100 the number of U.S. citizens or foreign nationals that may be retained as contractors to carry out Title II (Central America). Prohibits funds under this Act from being made available for budget support or cash payments. Provides for a national interest waiver. (Sec. 303) Prohibits, as of October 1, 2009, transfer of surveillance-related equipment to a recipient country unless the President determines that such country has cooperated with the United States to ensure that such equipment will be used principally for the purposes for which it is provided. (Sec. 304) Authorizes the President, notwithstanding a specified prohibition, to provide assistance under title I or title II to the police forces of recipient countries. (Sec. 305) States that authority to provide assistance under titles I and II is in addition to any other authority to provide assistance for Mexico and the countries of Central America. (Sec. 306) States that the Arms Export Control Act applies to all transfers of equipment under this Act unless otherwise specified. Title IV: Support Activities in the United States - (Sec. 401) Directs the President to report to the appropriate congressional committees concerning measures taken to reduce U.S. drug demand. (Sec. 402) Directs the Attorney General to: (1) expand resources for the Project Gunrunner initiative of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF) to identify, investigate, and prosecute firearms trafficking across the U.S.- Mexico border; and (2) provide ATF agents, equipment, and training to assist Mexican law enforcement officers in combating firearms trafficking and other criminal enterprises. Authorizes FY2008-FY2010 appropriations. (Sec. 404) Directs the President to report to the appropriate congressional committees regarding measures taken to stop the flow of illegal precursor chemicals and bulk cash into Mexico. Title V: Miscellaneous Provisions - (Sec. 501) Directs the President to establish within the Department of State a Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Implement the Merida Initiative (with the rank of ambassador). (Sec. 502) Directs the President to: (1) develop metrics to identify and manage the progress of activities under this Act; and (2) use such metrics for resource allocations to combat narcotics and organized crime activities. (Sec. 503) Directs the President to report to the appropriate congressional committees regarding programs and activities carried out under this Act during the preceding fiscal year. (Sec. 504) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the U.S. government requires an effective public diplomacy strategy to explain the Merida Initiative's purposes; and (2) the Secretary shall design and implement a public diplomacy campaign regarding the Merida Initiative. (Sec. 505) Sunsets this Act after September 30, 2010.</summary>
</bill>
