<bill session="111" type="s" number="1801" updated="2013-07-20T00:39:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">First State National Historical Park Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the First State National Historical Park in the State of Delaware, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2009-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10571-10572"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-645.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="3893"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/2009--Introduced.
First State National Historical Park Act - Establishes the First State National Historical Park in Delaware as a unit of the National Park System. Specifies that the purpose of the Park is the preservation, protection, and interpretation of the historic and cultural resources associated with Dutch, Swedish, and English settlement in Delaware and the resources associated with the role of the state of Delaware as the first state to ratify the Constitution. Requires the preparation of a general management plan for the Park. Requires completion of a study regarding the preservation and interpretation of additional properties in Delaware that relate to the Park's purposes, including an assessment of: (1) the potential for designating them as National Historic Landmarks; and (2) options for maintaining their historic integrity.</summary>
</bill>
