<bill session="113" type="h" number="1557" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Plain Regulations Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure clarity of regulations to improve the effectiveness of Federal regulatory programs while decreasing burdens on the regulated public.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412537" joined="2013-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="807"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2013--Introduced.
Plain Regulations Act of 2013 - Requires the head of each executive agency to: (1) implement a program for using plain language in writing new and revised regulations, and (2) certify to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) that each proposed or final rule is in plain language. Requires the Director to: (1) publish agency certifications of compliance with plain language requirements on OMB's website, and (2) return proposed agency regulations that fail to meet such requirements to be redrafted and resubmitted for approval. Denies jurisdiction to any court to review compliance or noncompliance with any provision of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
