<bill session="113" type="h" number="2659" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Opportunities for Success Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program to issue grants to institutions of higher education to support student internships.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412501"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2013--Introduced.
Opportunities for Success Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Education to award grants to institutions of higher education for use in providing their students with financial support to engage in internships reasonably associated with their studies. Requires support recipients to be full-time or half-time students who are eligible for Federal Pell Grants. Sets the student support level for unpaid internships at: (1) the higher of the federal or state minimum wage for each hour of the internship, if the internship occurs while the student is enrolled in classes; and (2) the student's reasonable cost of living expenses, if the internship occurs while the student is not enrolled in classes. Sets the support level for paid internships by reducing the amount the student would receive for an unpaid internship by the amount the paid internship provides to the student. Caps the total support a student may receive for full-time and part-time internships. Makes that support nontaxable and excludes it from the calculation of a student's need or eligibility for financial assistance under title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</summary>
</bill>
