<bill session="113" type="h" number="2243" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Air Force to make competitive grants to support research and development, education, and training to produce a bio-based aviation fuel for use by the Air Force.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412535"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3125"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/2013--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Air Force to make a competitive grant to an existing biofuels research center in the United States to conduct pilot-scale research, development, and testing of bio-based fuels for use by the Air Force as aviation fuel for jet aircraft. Permits a recipient to use grant funds to train military and civilian personnel in the new technologies and to conduct a study regarding the economic feasibility of a full-scale bio-based aviation fuel production facility. Directs the Secretary to give preference to a center that: (1) has the capacity and expertise necessary to quickly and efficiently conduct such research, development, and testing; and (2) is located in close proximity to specified raw materials, a military installation with responsibility for military air transportation, and a private or commercial airport with capacity to host a research and pilot production facility.</summary>
</bill>
