<bill session="111" type="s" number="1170" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Alaska Omnibus Aviation Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve aviation safety in Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2009--Introduced.
Alaska Omnibus Aviation Improvement Act - Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to promulgate regulations to: (1) exempt Iditarod Air Force pilots, for a minimum five-year period, from certain federal regulations restricting private pilot and commercial pilot operation of passenger aircraft for compensation to allow them to accept nonmonetary compensation for costs for flying in support of the Iditarod Sled Dog Race; and (2) develop, implement, and submit to Congress a plan for the future of Alaska flight service stations. Makes authorizations for FY2009-FY2012 for: (1) the Medallion Foundation Program in Alaska; and (2) the Alaska aviation safety project. Authorizes the use of airport improvement program grants received by Alaskan airports for on-the-job trainee positions to the same extent as such positions are authorized for federal-aid highway projects.</summary>
</bill>
