<bill session="112" type="sr" number="227" updated="2013-07-20T02:12:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution calling for the protection of the Mekong River Basin and increased United States support for delaying the construction of mainstream dams along the Mekong River.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412249"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4454" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-11-29">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-12-01">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-12-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="249">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 249.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Laos"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Thailand"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/1/2011--Reported to Senate amended.
Calls on: (1) the U.S. government to recognize different national circumstances of riparian states along the Mekong River, (2) U.S. representatives at multilateral development banks to oppose financial assistance to Mekong River hydropower dam projects that have not been regionally coordinated, and (3) the U.S. government in leading the Lower Mekong Initiative to devote greater attention to energy and water infrastructure projects. Encourages greater U.S. engagement with the Mekong River countries through the Lower Mekong Initiative. Applauds the government of Laos' decision to temporarily suspend work on the Xayaburi Dam. Supports delay of the construction of mainstream hydropower dams along the Mekong River until environmental assessments have been completed. Calls on: (1) riparian states along the Mekong River, including China, to respect the rights of other River basin countries; and (2) the governments of Burma and China to improve cooperation with the Mekong River Commission. Supports assistance to the Lower Mekong River riparian states to analyze the impacts of proposed development.</summary>
</bill>
