<bill session="112" type="s" number="1439" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ready Schools Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 regarding ready school needs reviews.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2011-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5067"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2011--Introduced.
Ready Schools Act of 2011 - Amends part A of title I (Improving the Academic Achievement of the Disadvantaged) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require local educational agencies to describe how they will assist each of their elementary schools that receive school improvement funds in conducting a ready school needs review at least once every three years. Requires schools to use that review in developing and implementing policies and procedures that create a school environment and classroom practices that: (1) help each child reach state and grade level expectations, including state academic content and achievement standards; and (2) support successful transitions for children. Requires the review to assess a school's needs for: (1) developmentally appropriate curricula, classroom materials, teaching practices, instructional assessments, and accommodations; (2) services and supports for disabled and limited English proficient children; (3) family and community engagement policies and practices; (4) building and maintaining a school climate that supports positive development and learning; (5) school staff leadership and support; and (6) outreach to, and collaboration with, early childhood education and service providers.</summary>
</bill>
