<bill session="111" type="s" number="2786" updated="2013-07-20T00:50:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhanced Restitution Enforcement and Equitable Retirement Treatment Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend titles 18 and 28 of the United States Code to provide incentives for the prompt payments of debts owed to the United States and the victims of crime by imposing late fees on unpaid judgments owed to the United States and to the victims of crime, to provide for offsets on amounts collected by the Department of Justice for Federal agencies, to increase the amount of special assessments imposed upon convicted persons, to establish an Enhanced Financial Recovery Fund to enhance, supplement, and improve the debt collection activities of the Department of Justice, to amend title 5, United States Code, to provide to assistant United States attorneys the same retirement benefits as are afforded to Federal law enforcement officers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2010-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2009-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11434"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11434-11437" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4091"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2009--Introduced.
Enhanced Restitution Enforcement and Equitable Retirement Treatment Act of 2009 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) impose a late fee on unpaid criminal fines or restitution obligations of $2,500 or more; (2) revise requirements for the modification or remission of unpaid criminal fines, restitution obligations, or special assessments; (3) require the Attorney General to establish guidelines for the enforcement of all criminal and civil obligations owed to the United States; and (4) increase special assessments on persons convicted of federal misdemeanors and felonies. Amends the federal judicial code to impose a late fee on unpaid money judgments owed to the United States. Establishes in the Treasury the Department of Justice (DOJ) Enhanced Financial Recovery Fund to support DOJ debt collection activities. Requires current federal agency share contributions for personnel benefits incurred as a result of this Act to be paid from such Fund. Requires assistant U.S. attorneys to be treated in the same manner as federal law enforcement officers for purposes of federal employee retirement benefit provisions.</summary>
</bill>
