<bill session="112" type="s" number="468" updated="2013-07-20T02:20:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mining Jobs Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to clarify the authority of the Administrator to disapprove specifications of disposal sites for the discharge of, dredged or fill material, and to clarify the procedure under which a higher review of specifications may be requested.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2011-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2011-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1221"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1221-1222" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="960"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="960"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2011--Introduced.
Mining Jobs Protection Act - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to repeal provisions that require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to consult with the Secretary of the Army before denying or restricting the use of specified areas as disposal sites for discharges of dredged or fill material into waters of the United States. Requires the Administrator to provide, within specified timeframes, to: (1) the Secretary notice of any concerns with respect to a specification for a disposal site proposed to be issued under a permit to discharge into navigable waters; and (2) the Secretary and permit applicants the reasons for any disapproval of permits. Removes the Administrator's authority to prohibit the specification of any defined area as a disposal site: (1) 60 days after the Administrator receives the proposed specification from the Secretary for review; and (2) once the Secretary has issued a permit for dredged or fill material. Authorizes the Secretary to reevaluate and reissue, or to elect not to reissue, a specification in any case in which, before the enactment of this Act, the Administrator disproved of a specification after it was issued by the Secretary. Sets forth requirements that must be met before the Administrator or the head of another agency requests that a proposed permit for dredged or fill material receive a higher level of review by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
