<bill session="111" type="h" number="129" updated="2013-07-19T23:12:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-16T12:31:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-07-16T12:31:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the conveyance of certain National Forest System lands in the Los Padres National Forest in California.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10T13:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-197.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-07-10T13:07:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="104">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 104.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-14T15:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-14T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8056-8057" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-14T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 129.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-14T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-16T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8201" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-07-16T12:31:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="549" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 422 - 0 (Roll no. 549).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/14/2009 H8056" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-16T12:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-270.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-08-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="540">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 540.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture, if the White Lotus Foundation in Santa Barbara, California, offers to convey to the Secretary a parcel of non-federal land that is acceptable to the Secretary and the Secretary accepts the offer, to convey approximately five acres of certain identified National Forest System land (the federal land) in Santa Barbara County to the Foundation. Subjects the land exchange to provisions under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 related to exchanges of public lands and interests therein within the National Forest System. Expresses the intent of Congress that the land exchange be completed within two years of enactment of this Act. Allows the Secretary to offer to sell to the White Lotus Foundation the federal land for fair market value if such exchange is not completed by such time. Makes the land exchange subject to specified additional terms and conditions, including to valid existing rights and the White Lotus Foundation paying the reasonable costs of surveys, appraisals, and other administrative costs associated with the exchange or sale. Requires land conveyed by exchange or sale under this Act to be appraised by an independent appraiser selected by the Secretary and such an appraisal to be conducted in accordance with nationally recognized appraisal standards. Requires any proceeds received by the Secretary from any cash equalization payment or sale under this Act to be deposited in a special account in the Treasury and to be made available for the acquisition of land or interests in the Los Padres National Forest.</summary>
</bill>
