<bill session="113" type="h" number="1191" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep American Natural Gas Here Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that the Secretary of the Interior may accept bids on any new oil and gas leases of Federal lands (including submerged lands) only from bidders certifying that all natural gas produced pursuant to such leases shall be offered for sale only in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1190"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2013--Introduced.
Keep American Natural Gas Here Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to accept bids on any new oil and gas leases of federal lands (including submerged lands) under the Mineral Leasing Act or the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act only from bidders certifying that all natural gas produced pursuant to such leases will be offered for sale only in the United States. Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to prohibit granting a new right-of-way for a natural gas pipeline unless the right-of-way applicant certifies that all natural gas transported via such pipeline will be offered for sale only in the United States. Declares this Act without force or effect 10 years after enactment of this Act. Instructs the Secretary of the Interior and the Comptroller General to report separately to Congress on the impact of this Act upon: (1) natural gas production on federal lands, (2) consumption of natural gas in the United States, and (3) prices and markets for natural gas in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
