<bill session="109" type="h" number="1670" updated="2013-07-19T19:19:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Egyptian Counterterrorism and Political Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit United States military assistance for Egypt and to express the sense of Congress that the amount of military assistance that would have been provided for Egypt for a fiscal year should be provided in the form of economic support fund assistance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400426"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2005-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2005-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and Central Asia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA13" subcommittee="Middle East and Central Asia" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2005--Introduced.
Egyptian Counterterrorism and Political Reform Act - Prohibits military assistance to Egypt beginning in FY 2006 unless the President determines and certifies to Congress that it is in the national security interests to provide assistance for a given fiscal year. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) funds that would have been provided for military assistance should be given in the form of economic support fund assistance and not used by the armed forces of Egypt; (2) the President should certify the establishment of procedures to ensure access by the Comptroller General to appropriate financial information in order to review the use of these funds; and (3) the agreement among the United States, Egypt, and Israel to decrease the overall amount of U.S. foreign assistance for both countries should continue.</summary>
</bill>
