<bill session="109" type="h" number="5029" updated="2013-07-19T19:48:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prevention of Nuclear Terrorism Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish in the Department of Homeland Security a Domestic Nuclear Detection Office to improve the ability of the United States to detect and prevent acts of nuclear and radiological terrorism and to enhance coordination of such efforts across Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400375" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2006-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fissionable materials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Radioactivity"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/28/2006--Introduced.
Prevention of Nuclear Terrorism Act of 2006 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for the establishment within the Department of Homeland Security of a Domestic Nuclear Detection Office. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to vest in the Office's Director the primary responsibility for: (1) administering the Department's nuclear and radiological detection and prevention functions and assets; and (2) coordinating such administration with other federal detection and prevention activities. Requires the Director to: (1) coordinate the government's implementation of a global nuclear detection architecture; (2) carry out a research and development program and a program to test and evaluate technology; (3) develop and execute a strategy for the acquisition and deployment of detection systems; (4) continuously monitor detection information received from foreign and domestic detection systems to maintain a situational awareness of all nuclear threats; (5) gather and archive detection data measurements taken of benign activities; (6) coordinate with other agencies to ensure that the detection of unauthorized nuclear explosive devices or radiological material is promptly reported; (7) assess nuclear threats communicated by federal, state, tribal, or local officials and provide adequate capability for swift and effective incident resolution; (8) develop and implement security standards for the protection of classified or sensitive information; (9) perform research, development, and acquisition activities pertaining to forensic analysis and attribution of nuclear and radiological attacks; and (10) utilize classified and unclassified threat assessments in designing the architecture. Establishes within the Office an Advisory Council on Nuclear Detection. Requires the Director to establish an interagency coordination council.</summary>
</bill>
