<bill session="111" type="h" number="5436" updated="2013-07-20T00:01:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the Minerals Management Service from issuing permits or environmental or safety waivers for any deepwater drilling rig in the Gulf of Mexico until the discharge of oil from the last Deepwater Horizon well has stopped and a congressional committee has issued a report finding the cause of the explosion on and sinking of the Deepwater Horizon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/2010--Introduced.
Prohibits the Minerals Management Service of the Department of the Interior from issuing any permit or granting any waiver of any environmental or safety requirement or restriction under any federal law for any deepwater drilling rig in the Gulf of Mexico before the date on which: (1) the discharge of oil from the last well drilled by the semi-submersible drilling rig Deepwater Horizon has stopped; and (2) a Committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate has issued a report that includes a finding of the cause of the explosion on and sinking of that drilling rig.</summary>
</bill>
