<bill session="111" type="s" number="3059" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Energy Efficiency Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve energy efficiency of appliances, lighting, and buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2010-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2010-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2010-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2010-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S946-947, S954"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S947-954" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 111-402.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2010--Introduced.
National Energy Efficiency Enhancement Act of 2010 - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to set forth provisions concerning establishing standards for: (1) a minimum level of energy efficiency or a maximum quantity of water use for clothes washers and dishwashers; (2) the seasonal energy efficiency ratio of central air conditioners and central air conditioning heat pumps manufactured on or after January 1, 2015; (3) the annual fuel utilization efficiency of non-weatherized furnaces manufactured on or after May 1, 2013; (4) the energy conservation of heat pump pool heaters; and (5) the energy efficiency of pole-mounted outdoor luminaires and high light output double-ended quartz halogen lamps. Revises provisions concerning prescribing new or amended standards. Sets forth provisions concerning establishing regional energy efficiency standards for such: (1) central air conditioners and their heat pumps; and (2) non-weatherized furnaces. Requires the Secretary of Energy to publish rules that determine whether the Secretary should: (1) establish standards for through-the-wall central air conditioners, through-the-wall central air conditioning heat pumps, and small duct, high velocity systems; and (2) amend standards for weatherized furnaces. Amends the Energy Conservation Program for Consumer Products Other Than Automobiles to: (1) revise exceptions from preemption requirements for certain building code requirements; (2) provide that No-Load Mode energy efficiency standards do not apply to specified external power supplies manufactured before July 1, 2017; and (3) revise labeling rules for "covered products." Prohibits the manufacture of general purpose mercury vapor lamps on or after January 1, 2016. Provides that state energy conservation standards that are adopted by January 1, 2015, pursuant to statutory requirements to adopt efficiency standards for reducing outdoor lighting energy use enacted prior to January 31, 2008, will not be preempted by federal standards. Authorizes the Secretary to incorporate smart grid technologies or capabilities into energy conservation standards. Requires sates to give notice to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) about a state or local public comment period with respect to local laws prohibiting, limiting, or restricting the use of alternative refrigerants for specific end uses.</summary>
</bill>
