<bill session="111" type="s" number="930" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Ferry Systems Investment Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote secure ferry transportation and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2009-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2172"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2172"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2009--Introduced.
United States Ferry Systems Investment Act of 2009 - Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of Transportation for FY2010-FY2015 for construction of ferry vessels and ferry terminal facilities. Revises general requirements and the formula for the allocation of such funds to ferry systems and public entities responsible for developing ferries. Includes ferries within the federal clean fuels program. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish within the Department of Transportation a Ferry Joint Program Office to: (1) coordinate federal programs affecting ferry vessel and ferry facility construction, maintenance, operations, and security; and (2) promote ferry service as a component of the U.S. transportation system. Requires the Secretary to: (1) ensure that the national ferry database is consistent with the national transit database maintained by the Federal Transit Administration; and (2) award a grant to a college to establish a National Ferry Transportation Institute for research, development, and training programs relating to U.S. ferry transportation systems.</summary>
</bill>
