<bill session="112" type="s" number="537" updated="2013-07-20T02:21:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mekong River Protection Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the United States Executive Directors of the World Bank and the Asian Development Bank to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose the provision of any loan or financial or technical assistance for a project for the construction of hydroelectric dams or electricity transmission systems in the Mekong River Basin unless the Secretary makes certain assurances with respect to the project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412249"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Laos"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Thailand"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2011--Introduced.
Mekong River Protection Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the United States Executive Directors of the World Bank and the Asian Development Bank to oppose the provision of any loan or financial or technical assistance for the construction of hydroelectric dams or electricity transmission systems in the Mekong River Basin unless the Secretary submits a related report providing certain assurances with respect environmental protection, public health, economic effect, and resettlement concerns to Congress. Defines "World Bank" as the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development and the International Development Association.</summary>
</bill>
