<bill session="112" type="s" number="1387" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Airport and Airway Extension Act of 2011, Part IV</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the funding and expenditure authority of the Airport and Airway Trust Fund, to amend title 49, United States Code, to extend the airport improvement program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2011-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2011-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4775-4776"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1034"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1079"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1893"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2279"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2553"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2644"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2887"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="340"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2011--Introduced.
Airport and Airway Extension Act of 2011, Part IV - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend through September 16, 2011, increased excise taxes on aviation fuels, the excise tax on air transportation of persons and property, and the expenditure authority for the Airport and Airway Trust Fund. Extends through September 16, 2011: (1) the authorization of appropriations for airport planning and development and noise compatibility planning projects (known as airport improvement projects [AIPs]), and (2) the authority of the Secretary of Transportation to make new AIP grants. Extends until September 17, 2011: (1) the pilot program for passenger facility fee authorizations at non-hub airports, and (2) disclosure requirements for large and medium hub airports applying for AIP grants. Directs the Secretary to extend through September 16, 2011, the termination date of insurance coverage for domestic or foreign-flag aircraft. Grants the Secretary discretionary authority to further extend such coverage through December 31, 2011. Extends through December 31, 2011, the authority of the Secretary to limit air carrier liability for claims arising out of acts of terrorism. Extends through September 16, 2011: (1) grant eligibility for airports located in the Marshall Islands, Micronesia, and Palau; (2) grants to state and local governments for land use compatibility AIPs; and (3) authority for approving an application of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority for an airport development grant or for permission to impose a passenger facility fee. Amends the Vision 100 - Century of Aviation Reauthorization Act to extend through September 16, 2011: (1) the temporary increase to 95% of the federal government's share of certain AIP costs, and (2) funding for airport development at Midway Island Airport.</summary>
</bill>
