<bill session="109" type="hr" number="1064" updated="2013-07-19T19:03:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29T22:19:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-29T22:19:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving points of order against the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 4954) to improve maritime and cargo security through enhanced layered defenses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T21:30:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Dreier asked unanimous consent that it be in order at any time for the Chairman of the Committee on Rules or his designee, without intervention of any point of order, to call up H. Res. 1064; that the resolution be considered as read; and that the resolution be debatable for 20 minutes equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T21:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sessions asked unanimous consent to consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T21:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8021-8024" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T21:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on H. Res. 1064.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T21:39:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T22:19:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 189 (Roll no. 512).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8023-8024" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8023-8024" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-09-29T22:19:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8021" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T22:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4954"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="109" type="h" number="4954"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Passed House without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Waives points of order against consideration of the conference report on H.R. 4954 (Security and Accountability For Every Port Act or the SAFE Port Act).</summary>
</bill>
