<bill session="110" type="hc" number="6" updated="2013-07-19T22:08:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress that the Supreme Court misinterpreted the First Amendment to the Constitution in the case of Buckley v. Valeo.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11302"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court decisions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the Supreme Court misinterpreted the First Amendment to the Constitution in the case of Buckley v. Valeo because the decision failed to recognize: (1) that the unlimited spending of large amounts of money on elections has a corrosive effect on the electoral process not simply because of direct transactions between those who give large amounts of money and candidates and elected officials but because the presence of unlimited amounts of money corrupts the process on a more fundamental level; and (2) other legitimate state interests which justify limiting money in campaigns, including the need to preserve the integrity of our republican form of government, restore public confidence in government, and ensure all citizens a more equal opportunity to participate in the political process.</summary>
</bill>
