<bill session="112" type="s" number="677" updated="2013-07-20T02:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 13, United States Code, to provide for the more accurate and complete enumeration of certain overseas Americans in the decennial census, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="868"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Political representation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2011--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of Commerce, beginning with the 2020 decennial census of population, to take measures in tabulating total population by state for purposes of apportionment of Representatives in Congress to ensure that all U.S. citizens temporarily living abroad on the census date are fully and accurately counted and properly attributed to the last state in which they were domiciled before leaving the United States. Requires such measures to include methods: (1) by which administrative records of a nongovernmental organization may be used to enumerate organization members residing overseas if such records satisfy the Secretary's criteria, (2) under which an international "Be Counted" form may be completed at a U.S. embassy by U.S. citizens residing overseas, and (3) under which voter registration rolls may be used to establish usual residence by confirming the state in which U.S. citizens living abroad usually reside.</summary>
</bill>
