<bill session="112" type="h" number="6500" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Detroit Economic Competitiveness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Detroit Jobs Trust Fund and to temporarily provide a zero percent capital gains rate for certain new investments in Detroit, Michigan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
Detroit Economic Competitiveness Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish the Detroit Jobs Trust Fund to finance economic development in Detroit, Michigan. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to make annual distributions from such Fund to the city of Detroit for payment of debt obligations and for job development, public safety, education, and business and public infrastructure. Prohibits any distributions unless the city of Detroit: (1) does not impose an income tax during a period of distribution, (2) has made specified reductions in aggregate property taxes, (3) has used prior distributions as required under this Act, (4) has provided required information to the Comptroller General (GAO), and (5) has implemented a five-year plan describing development goals for Detroit and detailing how distributions from the Trust Fund will be spent. Terminates such Fund five years after enactment of this Act. Requires GAO to submit annual reports to Congress describing the use of distributions from the Trust Fund, the extent to which progress has been made in meeting the plan's development goals, and Comptroller General recommendations for improving the program established under this Act. Excludes from gross income capital gain from the sale or exchange of investment property used in trade or business in Detroit.</summary>
</bill>
