<bill session="112" type="h" number="776" updated="2013-07-20T01:17:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Guaranteed 3% COLA for Seniors Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the establishment of a Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers to compute cost-of-living increases for Social Security benefits under title II of the Social Security Act and to provide, in the case of elderly beneficiaries under such title, for an annual cost-of-living increase which is not less than 3 percent.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2011-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1876"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2011--Introduced.
Guaranteed 3% COLA for Seniors Act of 2011 - Directs the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor to prepare and publish a monthly Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers that indicates changes over time in expenditures for consumption which are typical for individuals in the United States who are age 62 or older. Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to: (1) require the use of such index to compute cost-of-living increases for Social Security benefits; and (2) provide, in the case of individuals who have attained age 62, for an annual cost-of-living increase of at least 3%.</summary>
</bill>
