<bill session="112" type="h" number="2976" updated="2013-07-20T01:35:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Help Emergency Responders Operate Emergency Systems Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HEROES Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance public safety by making more spectrum available to public safety agencies, to facilitate the development of a wireless public safety broadband network, to provide standards for the spectrum needs of public safety agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400346"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2011-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2011--Introduced.
Help Emergency Responders Operate Emergency Systems Act of 2011 or the HEROES Act of 2011 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to increase the electromagnetic spectrum allocation for public safety services by 10 megahertz within a specified range and reduce such allocation for commercial use by the same amount. Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to license certain paired bands to the public safety broadband licensee (PSBL). Directs the FCC to establish rules to: (1) permit the PSBL to authorize public safety services providers to construct and operate a wireless public safety broadband network in the PSBL's spectrum, and (2) authorize the shared use of public safety broadband spectrum and network infrastructure by non-public safety services and the use of public safety broadband spectrum by emergency response providers. Requires: (1) the FCC to develop a public safety agency statement of requirements enabling nationwide interoperability and roaming across communications systems, and (2) the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish standards for meeting such requirements. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a grant program (a maximum 80% federal share of the costs for each project) to assist public safety entities in constructing a nationwide interoperable broadband network in the 700 megahertz band; (2) administer a program to reimburse up to 50% of network maintenance, operation, and improvement expenses; and (3) establish a narrowbanding compliance assistance program. Requires: (1) the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to reallocate for commercial use spectrum from a specified range, and (2) the FCC to establish rules for pairing spectrum within specified ranges and to auction licenses for such paired spectrum. Extends to September 30, 2020, the FCC's authority to grant a license or permit under applicable competitive bidding provisions. Prohibits a bidder from being deemed ineligible for or excluded from an auction on account of its size or the amount of its other spectrum holdings.</summary>
</bill>
