<bill session="113" type="h" number="1649" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Offshore Oil and Gas Worker Whistleblower Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide whistleblower protections to certain workers in the offshore oil and gas industry.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2013-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/2013--Introduced.
Offshore Oil and Gas Worker Whistleblower Protection Act of 2013 - Prohibits an employer from discharging, discriminating, or engaging in retaliatory actions against specified employees who report to a government official any violation or unsafe condition under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act. Sets forth procedures for the filing, investigation, and adjudication of a complaint regarding such retaliation. Requires employers to: (1) post a notice approved by the Secretary of Labor explaining employee rights and remedies under this Act in a conspicuous location in the place of employment where employees frequent; (2) provide training to employees about their rights under this Act within 30 days of employment, and at least once every 12 months thereafter; and (3) provide employees with a card containing a toll free telephone number at the Department of Labor to get information or file a complaint under this Act. Directs the Secretary of Labor, within 30 days after enactment of this Act, to designate agency officials to receive, investigate, and adjudicate complaints concerning violations under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
