<bill session="110" type="h" number="5687" updated="2013-07-19T21:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-24T21:21:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-06-24T21:21:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Advisory Committee Act Amendments of 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Federal Advisory Committee Act Amendments of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Federal Advisory Committee Act Amendments of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Advisory Committee Act to increase the transparency and accountability of Federal advisory committees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400074"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-04-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-05-15T17:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government. H. Rept. 110-650.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-05-15T17:40:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="411">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 411.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-24T21:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Clay moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-24T21:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5994-5997" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-24T21:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5687.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-06-24T21:21:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5994-5995" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-06-24T21:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2008--Passed House amended.
Federal Advisory Committee Act Amendments of 2008 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Federal Advisory Committee Act to require appointments to advisory committees to be made without regard to political affiliation or activity, unless otherwise required by federal statute. Directs each agency head to: (1) ensure that no individual who has a conflict of interest is appointed unless the need for the individual's services outweighs the potential impacts of the conflict; (2) require that each individual to be appointed inform the agency of any actual or potential conflict that exists before the appointment or that arises while the individual is serving; and (3) ensure that advisory committee reports are the result of the committee's judgment, independent from the agency. Declares that: (1) this Act is not intended to preclude agency heads from requiring the recusal of individuals with conflicts from particular aspects of the committee's work; and (2) an individual representative's association with the entity whose views are being represented shall not itself be considered to be a conflict of interest.Requires: (1) the public disclosure of any conflict of interest; (2) the Director of the Office of Government Ethics to promulgate regulations defining "conflict of interest" and identifying the method for disclosure and the period back in time an interest is considered a conflict; and (3) the Administrator of General Services to promulgate regulations to implement the Federal Advisory Committee Act.(Sec. 3) Regards an individual who is not a full-time or permanent part-time officer or employee of the federal government as a member of a committee if the individual regularly attends and participates in committee meetings as if the individual were a member, even if the individual does not have the right to vote or veto the committee's advice or recommendations.(Sec. 4) Requires public disclosure of: (1) any communication between an interagency advisory committee established by the President or the Vice President and a person who is not a federal officer or employee; (2) charters of advisory committees; (3) the process used to establish and appoint committee members; (4) specified information about current members; (5) each committee's decision-making process; (6) transcripts or recordings of committee meetings; (7) determinations to close meetings; and (8) notices of future committee meetings. Requires agency heads to make such information available electronically 15 days before each meeting (or 30 days after for meeting transcripts or recordings). Authorizes an agency to withhold from disclosure any information that would be exempt from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act. Requires the Administrator of General Services to provide electronic access to such information on the General Services Administration's (GSA's) Internet site.Requires committee charters to include: (1) the authority under which the committee is established; (2) the estimated number of members and a description of the expertise needed to carry out the committee's objectives; (3) a description of whether the committee will be composed of special government employees, representatives, or members from both categories; and (4) whether the committee has the authority to create subcommittees and, if so, the agency official authorized to exercise such authority. (Sec. 5) Requires the Comptroller General to review and report on agency compliance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act, including whether agencies are appropriately appointing advisory committee members as either special government employees or representatives.</summary>
</bill>
