<bill session="109" type="h" number="4068" updated="2013-07-19T19:40:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center Lease Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to lease a portion of a visitor center to be constructed outside the boundary of the Indiana Dunes National Lakeshore in Porter County, Indiana, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400417"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1913"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="National lakeshores"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/17/2005--Introduced.
Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center Lease Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a memorandum of understanding to establish a joint partnership with the Porter County Convention, Recreation and Visitor Commission and, after entering into such a memorandum, lease space in the Dorothy Buell Memorial Visitor Center for use as a visitor center for the Indiana Dunes National Lakeshore. Allows the Secretary to: (1) plan, design, construct, and install exhibits in the leased space related to the use and management of the resources at the Lakeshore, at a cost under $1.2 million; and (2) utilize park staff from the Lakeshore in the leased space to provide visitor information and education.</summary>
</bill>
