<bill session="112" type="s" number="207" updated="2013-07-20T02:18:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">COPS Improvements Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to enhance the COPS ON THE BEAT grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2012-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S287-288"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S288-289" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1896"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2011--Introduced.
COPS Improvements Act of 2011 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to modify the public safety and community policing grant program (COPS ON THE BEAT grant program) to: (1) establish within the Department of Justice (DOJ), under the general authority of the Attorney General, the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services to be headed by a Director; and (2) authorize the Attorney General to carry out more than one such program. Repeals provisions authorizing: (1) the Attorney General to give preferential consideration to applications for hiring and rehiring additional career law enforcement officers that involve a non-federal contribution exceeding a 25% minimum; and (2) the use of such grants to develop and implement either innovative programs to permit members of the community to assist state, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies in the prevention of crime in the community or new administrative and managerial systems to facilitate the adoption of community-oriented policing as an organization-wide philosophy. Authorizes the use of such grants to: (1) hire school resource officers and establish local partnerships to combat crime, gangs, drug activities, and other problems in elementary and secondary schools; (2) establish and implement innovative programs to reduce and prevent illegal drug manufacturing, distribution, and use; (3) meet emerging law enforcement needs; (4) hire former members of the Armed Forces to serve as career law enforcement officers for deployment in community-oriented policing; (5) pay for additional community prosecuting programs to handle cases from specific geographic areas and to address counter-terrorism problems and violent crime in local communities; and (6) develop new technologies to assist state and local law enforcement agencies in crime prevention and training. Directs the Attorney General to ensure that the same percentage of the total number of eligible applicants in each state receive a grant. Authorizes the Attorney General to extend grant periods and to renew grants if the grant recipient can demonstrate significant progress in achieving the objectives of the initial grant application. Includes officers for the Amtrak Police Department within the definition of "career law enforcement officer" for purposes of such grant program. Increases and extends the authorization of appropriations for the program for FY2012-FY2017.</summary>
</bill>
