<bill session="111" type="h" number="4796" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Secondary Payer Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act with respect to the application of Medicare secondary payer rules for certain claims.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412233"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412264" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2010-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412188" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2010-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2010-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412291" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412190" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2010-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400328" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2010-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2010-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2010--Introduced.
Medicare Secondary Payer Enhancement Act of 2010 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with respect to any settlement, judgment, award, or other payment between a Medicare claimant and an applicable plan involving a payment made for items and services by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS). Prescribes requirements for a voluntary calculation and direct reimbursement by a Medicare claimant and an applicable plan to the Hospital Insurance Trust Fund or the Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund, as appropriate, of a conditional payment of Medicare secondary payer claims for settlement purposes. Grants the Secretary the right to contest the amount of any such reimbursement, and the right of the claimant and plan to request a final recovery demand for reimbursement. Declares that requirements to reimburse the appropriate Trust Fund for any payment made by the Secretary with respect to an item or service shall not apply with respect to any settlement, judgment, award, or other payment by an applicable plan: (1) constituting a total payment obligation to a claimant of not more than $5,000; or (2) involving the ongoing responsibility for other medical payments of not more than $5,000. Changes from mandatory to discretionary the current civil money penalty for failure of an applicable plan to submit certain information to the Secretary with respect to any claimant. Prescribes requirements for the creation of safe harbors from such sanctions. Directs the Secretary to modify reporting requirements for liability insurance (including self-insurance), no fault insurance, and workers' compensation laws and plans so that entities responsible for reporting information are not required to access or report to the Secretary beneficiary Social Security numbers or health identification numbers. Sets a statute of limitations with respect to the recovery of payments by the United States. Establishes $30 user fees, adjusted annually for inflation, for requests submitted to the Secretary for direct conditional payment reimbursement and for final demand of a conditional payment.</summary>
</bill>
