<bill session="110" type="s" number="3708" updated="2013-07-19T22:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Professions and Primary Care Reinvestment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to health professions education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-11-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10671-10674"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-11-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="7302"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Dentistry"/>
    <term name="Dentists"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Psychologists"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2008--Introduced.
Health Professions and Primary Care Reinvestment Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise provisions related to: (1) addressing workforce shortages for primary care health professions; and (2) assisting underrepresented minorities or disadvantaged students to enter health professions.Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) make grants for the training of primary care physicians teaching in community-based settings; (2) provide for programs that improve clinical teaching and research in primary care; (3) provide for community health needs assessments; (4) provide for the establishment of Primary Care Training Institutes within academic health centers; and (5) provide for approved professional training programs in the field of general or pediatric dentistry.Revises provisions governing area health education centers, including to require the Secretary to make awards to improve the effectiveness and capabilities of existing programs.Authorizes the Secretary to provide for the development and implementation of interdisciplinary training of psychology graduate students to provide behavioral and mental health services.Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish the National Center for Health Workforce Analysis; (2) designate regional workforce analysis centers; (3) award grants or contracts to regional centers for research on high-priority workforce questions; (4) provide for monitoring of the supply, need for, and diversity and distribution of health professionals; and (5) establish the Advisory Committee on Health Workforce Information, Evaluation, and Assessment.Requires the Secretary, acting in conjunction with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to award competitive grants to establish Academic Health Departments to provide for collaboration between the academic and practice aspects of public health.</summary>
</bill>
