<bill session="109" type="h" number="4914" updated="2013-07-19T19:47:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Choice of Representation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to remove certain limitations on attorney representation of claimants for veterans benefits in administrative proceedings before the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2006-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2006-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2006-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2006-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2006-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="2006-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-06">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received from Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2006--Introduced.
Veterans' Choice of Representation Act - Amends federal law concerning a veteran's representation by an agent or attorney to allow the payment of attorney fees from the date the claimant files a Notice of Disagreement in the case. (Currently, such fees may not be paid before the Board of Veterans' Appeals first makes a final decision in the case.) Repeals the requirement that, in order to be paid, an attorney must be retained within a one-year period after the case has begun. Authorizes: (1) the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to review an attorney's fee agreement and order a reduction if the Secretary finds that the fee is excessive or unreasonable; and (2) judicial review of such findings. Requires (currently, authorizes) the Secretary to direct the payment of attorney fees out of any past-due benefits awarded to a veteran in a proceeding.</summary>
</bill>
