<bill session="110" type="h" number="2543" updated="2013-07-19T21:25:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Commissions Revision Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to revise the definition of unlawful enemy combatant for purposes of laws administered by the Secretary of Defense relating to military commissions, to establish a statutory right of habeas corpus for individuals detained at the detention facility at Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400356"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="267"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1189"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1416"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2826"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="185"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Courts-martial and courts of inquiry"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Police questioning"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2007--Introduced.
Military Commissions Revision Act of 2007 - Amends federal law concerning powers and procedures of military commissions (commissions) to redefine the term "unlawful enemy combatant" as a person who has engaged in, attempted, or conspired to engage in acts of armed hostilities or terrorism against the United States or its co-belligerents, and who is not a lawful enemy combatant. Repeals the requirement that a finding by a combatant status review tribunal that a person is an unlawful enemy combatant be dispositive for purposes of jurisdiction for trial by a commission. Allows statements obtained by a degree of coercion less than torture to be admitted only if the military judge finds that: (1) the totality of the circumstances indicates that the statement possesses probative value; (2) the interests of justice would best be served by admitting the statement; and (3) the interrogation methods used do not amount to cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment. Prohibits a court or judge jurisdiction to hear or consider an application for a writ of habeas corpus filed by an alien enemy combatant detained by the United States who has been determined by a combatant status review panel to have been properly detained, unless two years has elapsed since the date of detention, and no criminal charges are pending against the detainee at the time the writ is filed.</summary>
</bill>
