<bill session="110" type="s" number="1725" updated="2013-07-19T22:35:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Restoring Pension Promises to Workers Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and title 5, United States Code, to improve the protection of pension benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2007--Introduced.
Restoring Pension Promises to Workers Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require the inclusion in gross income of all income previously deferred under a nonqualified deferred compensation plan if an employer maintaining such a plan fails to meet certain participation, vesting, and minimum benefit requirements. Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to: (1) deny ERISA pension plan administrators the right to recover overpayments made to plan participants and beneficiaries in cases of hardship or insignificant amounts; (2) impose a three-year limitation period for bringing any action to recover an overpayment; (3) prohibit the elimination of accrued pension plan benefits during corporate mergers and acquisitions; and (4) establish in the Department of Labor an Office of Pension Participant Advocacy to protect pension plan participants.Amends federal employee personnel provisions to: (1) entitle former spouses of federal employees who die before establishing a valid claim for an annuity to 55% of such deferred annuity or a lump-sum payment; (2) permit divorced spouses of federal employees to collect court-awarded retirement benefits when such employees are first eligible to retire (currently, only available at the time the employee actually retires); (3) entitle certain former spouses of retired federal employees divorced prior to September 14, 1978, to a survivor annuity; and (4) give priority to a surviving spouse of a federal employee in the distribution of balances in a Thrift Savings account, unless such spouse consents to the designation of another beneficiary.</summary>
</bill>
