<bill session="109" type="h" number="532" updated="2013-07-19T19:08:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Playwrights Licensing Antitrust Initiative Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the application of the antitrust laws to permit collective development and implementation of a standard contract form for playwrights for the licensing of their plays.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2005-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2005-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="2005-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Theater"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2005--Introduced.
Playwrights Licensing Antitrust Initiative Act of 2005 - Provides that the antitrust laws shall not apply to: (1) any joint discussion, consideration, review, action, or agreement between or among playwrights for the express purpose of developing a standard form contract containing minimum terms of artistic protection and levels of compensation for playwrights or any joint or collective voluntary actions for the limited purposes of developing a standard form contract by playwrights or their representatives; and (2) any joint discussion, consideration, review, or action for the express purpose of reaching a collective agreement among playwrights adopting a standard form contract as the sole and exclusive means by which participating playwrights shall license their plays to producers. Makes a standard form of contract developed and implemented under this Act subject to amendment by individual playwrights and producers consistent with its terms.</summary>
</bill>
