<bill session="111" type="s" number="636" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to conform the definition of renewable biomass to the definition given the term in the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2009-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4572"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3381"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Clean Air Act to redefine "renewable biomass" as: (1) materials, pre-commercial thinnings, or invasive species from certain National Forest System land and public lands that are byproducts of preventive treatments that are removed to reduce hazardous fuels, reduce or contain disease or insect infestation, or restore ecosystem health, that would not otherwise be used for higher-value products, and that are harvested in accordance with specified requirements for old-growth forests and large tree retention; or (2) any organic matter that is available on a renewable or recurring basis from nonfederal land or land belonging to an Indian or Indian tribe that is held in trust by the United States or subject to a restriction against alienation imposed by the United States, including specified renewable plant material and waste material.</summary>
</bill>
