<bill session="112" type="h" number="6130" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Treasure Promotion and Investment Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require priority visa processing for visitors to National Heritage Areas or National Parks, to invest in communities hosting these national treasures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412497"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration Policy and Enforcement" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2012--Introduced.
National Treasure Promotion and Investment Act of 2012 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the maintenance of infrastructure in communities hosting national parks and national heritage areas is important to the safety of residents and visitors; and (2) visa issuance fees should be invested in such maintenance in these communities, which draw visitors from across the globe. Requires consular officers, in issuing visas to applicants seeking to visit the United States temporarily for pleasure, to give priority to those intending to visit a national heritage area or national park. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to make grants to support infrastructure projects: (1) in communities hosting such heritage areas or parks, (2) that have been prioritized for completion by an applicable metropolitan planning organization, and (3) that are determined beneficial to the upkeep of roads or bridges used by international visitors to these regions.</summary>
</bill>
