<bill session="110" type="h" number="6280" updated="2013-07-19T21:58:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">America's Affordable Health Care Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the offering of Health Benefit Plans to individuals, to increase funding for State high risk health insurance pools, and to promote best practice protocols for State high risk pools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400640"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400131" joined="2008-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2008--Introduced.
America's Affordable Health Care Act of 2008 - Authorizes a health insurance issuer to apply to the Secretary of Health and Human Services to certify health insurance coverage policies offered in the individual market in any state as Health Benefit Plans. Allows certified plans to be offered to individuals in all states without regard to state and local laws respecting mandates for benefits. Requires such plans to cover inpatient hospital services and physicians' surgical and medical services. Requires the Secretary to review the impact of this Act on the availability and purchase of health insurance coverage. Amends the Public Health Service Act to increase the authorization of appropriations for FY2009-FY2013 for grants to states for the creation and operation of qualified high risk health insurance pools. Conditions eligibility for receiving an operating grant on a state submitting to the Secretary evidence-based information on the operation of such pool for purposes of creating best practice guidelines. Requires the Secretary to: (1) recommend and publicly post a list of best practices on the operation of qualified high risk pools; and (2) give a bonus grant to states that demonstrate that their pool was operated in accordance with such best practices.</summary>
</bill>
