<bill session="111" type="hr" number="645" updated="2013-07-19T23:01:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-15T12:28:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-07-15T12:28:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3183) making appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2010, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400663"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-14T20:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-209, by Ms. Matsui.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-14T20:46:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI are waived. The Chair may entertain a motion that the Committee rise only if offered by the chair of the Committee on Appropriations or his designee. The Chair may not entertain a motion to strike out the eneacting words of the bill. During consideration of the bill, the Chair may reduce to two minutes the minmum time for electronic voting under clause 6 of rule XVIII and clauses 8 and 9 of rule XX. House Resolution 618 is laid on the table</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-07-14T20:46:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="90">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 90.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15T10:58:00-04:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Ms. Matsui called up H.Res. 645 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15T11:02:00-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Flake raised a point of order against the provisions of H.Res. 645 because it violates the Congressional Budget Act. The Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H.Res. 645. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15T11:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The Chair put the question of consideration of the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15T11:17:00-04:00">
      <text>On question of consideration Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15T11:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8107-8115" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15T11:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 645.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15T12:19:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 237 - 177 (Roll no. 538).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8113-8114" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8113" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-07-15T12:28:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="539" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 238 - 185 (Roll no. 539).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8107" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15T12:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="618"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="3183"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3183) making appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2010.</summary>
</bill>
