<bill session="113" type="h" number="1280" updated="2013-11-02T06:29:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Voter Fraud Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to increase the penalties imposed for intimidating, threatening, or coercing any person from engaging in voter registration activities or for procuring, submitting, or casting false voter registration applications or ballots, to require election officials to transmit voter registration cards and absentee ballots to voters in elections for Federal office through the use of the automated tagging and tracing services provided by the United States Postal Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412302"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2013--Introduced.
Voter Fraud Prevention Act - Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to: (1) increase from 5 to 10 years the length of imprisonment for criminal activities involving intimidation or fraud in connection with voter registration and voting, (2) prohibit an individual involved in such activities from voting in subsequent federal elections; and (3) require use of automated tagging and tracking services for voter registration cards and absentee ballots. Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require use of automated tagging and tracking services for absentee ballots.</summary>
</bill>
