<bill session="109" type="h" number="3263" updated="2013-07-19T19:33:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Efficiency Cornerstone Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce the growth of energy use in the United States, to limit the impact of growing energy use on the economy, environment, and national security of the United States through reductions in energy demand, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400421"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="2005-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2005-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2006-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400434" joined="2005-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air conditioning"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Cogeneration of electric power and heat"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Condominium (Housing)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Cooperative housing"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric appliances"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Gas companies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Heat pumps"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Industrial buildings"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lighting"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Mobile homes"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Natural gas vehicles"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Prefabricated buildings"/>
    <term name="Refrigeration"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Traffic signs and signals"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2005--Introduced.
Energy Efficiency Cornerstone Act of 2005 - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (EPCA) to expand the scope of products encompassed within the Energy Conservation Program for Consumer Products Other Than Automobiles, including testing requirements and energy conservation standards for additional consumer and commercial products. Amends the Energy Conservation and Production Act (ECPA) to set forth additional funding incentives for state building energy efficiency codes. Amends the National Manufacturing Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 to subject its energy conservation standards to the most recent version of the International Energy Conservation Code. Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to subject energy efficiency standards and a model energy code to the 2004 International Energy Conservation Code. Amends EPCA to establish within the Department of Energy and the Environmental Protection Agency a voluntary program to identify and promote energy-efficient products and buildings through voluntary labeling of, or other forms of communication about, products and buildings that meet the highest energy efficiency standards. Amends the ECPA to: (1) subject federal building performance standards to the 2004 International Energy Conservation Code; and (2) require all housing constructed under the military housing privatization initiative of the Department of Defense to be Energy Star qualified and equipped with Energy Star appliances and FEMP designated appliances, including Energy Star lighting. Amends EPCA and the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to modify compliance requirements governing alternative fuel use by light duty federal vehicles. Amends federal transportation law to modify standards for executive agency automobiles. Directs the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) to enter into voluntary agreements with entities in industrial sectors that consume significant quantities of primary energy for each unit of physical output to reduce the energy intensity of their production activities. Instructs the Secretary to establish a financial assistance pilot program for state implementation of pilot projects for energy efficiency programs and reduction of consumption of electricity or natural gas. Amends the Public Utilities Regulatory Policy Act of 1978 to require a state regulatory authority or non-regulated utility to implement an energy efficiency resource program to reduce consumer electricity or gas consumption. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to set forth business related credits for: (1) construction of new energy efficient homes; (2) energy efficiency improvements to existing homes; and (3) energy efficient appliances. Allows as a deduction from gross income: (1) an amount equal to the cost of energy efficient commercial building property placed in service during the taxable year; and (2) certain energy efficient property used in business and residential rental property. Establishes a tax credit for: (1) energy efficient building property expenditures; (2) installation of qualified fuel cells; and (3) qualified fuel cell motor vehicles and hybrid motor vehicle. Revises requirements for the energy credit for combined heat and power system property.</summary>
</bill>
