<bill session="109" type="h" number="2364" updated="2013-07-19T19:25:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-23T19:04:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-06-23T19:04:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a Science and Technology Scholarship Program to award scholarships to recruit and prepare students for careers in the National Weather Service and in National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration marine research, atmospheric research, and satellite programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Technology, and Standards.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-23T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 109-151.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-06-23T19:04:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="91">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 91.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Environment, Technology, and Standards" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Atmosphere"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Earth resources satellites"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Meteorological research"/>
    <term name="Meteorological satellites"/>
    <term name="Meteorology"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in government"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oceanography"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in government"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2005--Reported to House amended.
Authorizes the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to establish a Science and Technology Scholarship Program to award scholarships to students at institutions of higher education to recruit and prepare them for careers in the National Weather Service and in NOAA marine research, atmospheric research, and satellite programs. Sets forth provisions governing such Program. Requires individuals to be selected to receive scholarships under this Act through a competitive process primarily based on academic merit, with consideration given to financial need and to the goal of promoting the participation of of certain individuals identified under the Science and Engineering Equal Opportunities Act, including those from historically black colleges and universities and institutions serving a large proportion of minorities or other underrepresented populations. Requires the Administrator to enter into contractual agreements with selected individuals under which such individuals, in exchange for receiving a scholarship, agree to serve as full-time employees of NOAA, for a 24-month period of obligated service for each academic year for which a scholarship is provided in positions needed by NOAA in marine research, atmospheric research, and satellite programs. Instructs the Administrator to make publicly available a list of academic programs and fields of study for which scholarships may be utilized in marine research, atmospheric research, and satellite programs and to update such list as necessary. Prohibits: (1) an individual from receiving a scholarship for more than four academic years, unless the Administrator grants a waiver; and (2) the amount of a scholarship from exceeding the cost of attendance. Permits a scholarship to be used for tuition, fees, and other authorized uses as established by the Administrator by regulation. Allows the Administrator to enter into a contractual agreement with an institution of higher education under which the amounts provided for a scholarship for tuition, fees, and other authorized expenses are paid directly to the institution with respect to which the scholarship is provided. Sets forth penalties for specified breaches of scholarship agreements.</summary>
</bill>
