<bill session="109" type="h" number="3447" updated="2013-07-19T19:34:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Highway Claims Resolution Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a means of resolving claims regarding the continued existence of rights-of-way under former section 2477 of the Revised Statutes, for the benefit of private landowners, State and local governments, and the public.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1622-1624"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2005--Introduced.
Highway Claims Resolution Act of 2005 - Permits, for a four-year period following the enactment of this Act, the filing of claims asserting the existence and validity of right-of-ways, pursuant to a repealed section of the Revised Statutes (R.S. 2477), to build highways across public land not reserved for public uses. Deems a failure to make and prove such claim a relinquishment of all right-of-way rights. Requires claimants to submit evidence in support of a claim within six years of the claim filing. Declares that claimants shall have the burden of proof that the grant of a right-of-way was validly accepted. Directs an authorized officer (designated by the Secretary of the Interior) to review evidence submitted and determine whether the claim is presumptively valid. Subjects to judicial review the administrative record of the final decision of an authorized officer. Prohibits charging a state, county, or local government a fee for the filing of a claim. Allows the United States to retain exclusive possession or control of federal conservation, tribal, or defense lands traversed by a valid right-of-way, upon payment to the claimant of an amount set by the relevant district court. Requires the recording of recognized claims. Recognizes the prior adjudication of claimed rights-of-way by courts of competent jurisdiction. States that nothing in this Act shall be construed to alter provisions of the: (1) Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 regarding rights-of-way with respect to public lands and National Forest System lands; or (2) Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act regarding Alaska's transportation and utility network.</summary>
</bill>
