<bill session="110" type="s" number="2365" updated="2013-07-19T22:41:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Parents' Rights Empowerment and Protection Act (PREP Act)</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require educational institutions that receive Federal funds to obtain the affirmative, informed, written consent of a parent before providing a student information regarding sex, to provide parents the opportunity to review such information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2007-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational surveys"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sex"/>
    <term name="Sex education"/>
    <term name="Students' rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2007--Introduced.
Parents' Rights Empowerment and Protection Act (PREP Act) - Requires each preschool and elementary and secondary school that receives federal funds to obtain the affirmative, informed, written consent of a child's parent before requesting information from, or conveying information to, such child on topics relating to sex or sexuality.Requires parents, upon their request, to be given an opportunity to review such information as well as a description of the context of, and need for, its request or conveyance.Subjects individuals and schools to civil liability and fines for violating these consent and disclosure requirements. Makes noncompliant schools ineligible for federal funds for one year following a violation.Amends the General Education Provisions Act to direct administrators of surveys, analyses, or evaluations that require students to reveal certain personal or familial information to obtain the prior consent of adult or emancipated students and prior written consent of minor students' parents.</summary>
</bill>
