<bill session="109" type="s" number="3798" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to exclude and defer from the pooled reimbursable costs of the Central Valley Project the reimbursable capital costs of the unused capacity of the Folsom South Canal, Auburn-Folsom South Unit, Central Valley Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8812-8813"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8813" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-781.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="5796"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2006--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) exclude and defer from the pooled reimbursable costs of the Central Valley Project the reimbursable capital costs of the unused capacity of the Folsom South Canal, Auburn-Folsom South Unit, of such Project; and (2) calculate the amount to be assigned to deferred use, which shall be reflected in future years' water rates. Sets forth a formula for calculating such excluded reimbursable cost. Provides that as long as an entity that is allocated and that pays capital, interest, and operation and maintenance costs associated with an amount of Project water historically assigned to the Canal does not use the Canal for the conveyance of Project water, that entity shall be entitled to convey an equivalent amount of non-Project water through the Canal without additional cost.</summary>
</bill>
