<bill session="110" type="s" number="2232" updated="2013-07-19T22:40:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Aid Lessons for Domestic Economic Assistance Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish a demonstration program to adapt the lessons of providing foreign aid to underdeveloped economies to the provision of Federal economic development assistance to certain similarly situated individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13449-13450"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 110-368.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/25/2007--Introduced.
Foreign Aid Lessons for Domestic Economic Assistance Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish and implement the Native American Millennium Challenge Demonstration Project through which federal economic development assistance may be provided for certain Native American communities. Authorizes the Secretary to provide such assistance to consortia of Alaska Native nonprofit organizations, Native Hawaiian community organizations, and other Indian tribes that enter into Native American Challenge Compacts. Requires such Compacts to establish a multiyear plan for achieving certain development objectives, including promoting economic growth and the elimination of poverty, strengthening good governance, entrepreneurship, and investment in Native American communities, and building the capacity of Native people to deal with rapid change and uncertainty due to climate change.</summary>
</bill>
