<bill session="112" type="s" number="862" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Gulf of Mexico Recovery, Restoration, and Resiliency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for a comprehensive Gulf of Mexico restoration plan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2536"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2536-2539" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2011--Introduced.
Comprehensive Gulf of Mexico Recovery, Restoration, and Resiliency Act - Establishes the Gulf of Mexico Recovery Council, which shall be composed of members of the Gulf Coast Ecosystem Restoration Task Force. Requires the Council, in coordination with the natural resource trustees designated with respect to natural resource damages relating to the Gulf oil spill in connection with the blowout and explosion of the mobile offshore drilling unit Deepwater Horizon on April 20, 2010, to: (1) develop the Comprehensive Gulf of Mexico Recovery Plan to restore, revitalize, and increase the resiliency of the Gulf of Mexico ecosystem; (2) provide grants to local political subdivisions affected by the oil spill for activities relating to Gulf coast&#160;economic development, ecosystem restoration, and public health rehabilitation; (3) establish the Gulf of Mexico Observation System, which shall be implemented through a Gulf of Mexico Exploration Research Center, to observe, monitor, and map the Gulf in a comprehensive manner; (4) establish a Fishery Endowment to ensure the long-term sustainability of fish stocks and the recreational, commercial, and charter fishing industry in the Gulf; and (5) administer the Gulf of Mexico Recovery Fund established by this Act for activities relating to economic development, ecosystem restoration, and public rehabilitation. Establishes the Citizens' Advisory Committee to report on: (1) the achievement of safe operations in the Gulf of oil and gas activities; (2) unresolved problems and concerns with operations, activities, and plans; and (3) the operations and expenditures, needs, issues, and recommendations of such Committee. Establishes the Scientific Advisory Committee to: (1)&#160;provide advice to the Council regarding the science behind the Plan and the long-term monitoring and restoration of the Gulf Coast ecosystem; and (2) report to the Council on the science regarding the impacts to the Gulf and the Gulf coast from the oil spill; (3) the progress of restoration activities; and (4) the Plan's implementation.</summary>
</bill>
