<bill session="110" type="s" number="3526" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-18">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drug Trafficking Vessel Interdiction Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance drug trafficking interdiction by creating a Federal felony relating to operating or embarking in a submersible or semi-submersible vessel without nationality and on an international voyage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2008-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-11-18">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1116 under authority of the order of the Senate of 11/17/2008.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6295"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="7099"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3198"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3351"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3598"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Submarines"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2008--Introduced.
Drug Trafficking Vessel Interdiction Act of 2008 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose a fine and/or prison term of up to 15 years for knowingly operating or embarking in any submersible or semisubmersible vessel that is without nationality and that is navigating in, or has navigated into, through, or from, waters beyond the outer limit of the territorial sea of a single country or a lateral limit of that country's territorial sea with an adjacent country, with the intent to evade detection. Grants extraterritorial federal jurisdiction over violations of this Act.Makes it an affirmative defense to a prosecution under this Act that a vessel operated at the time of a violation was: (1) a vessel of the Untied States or lawfully registered in a foreign nation; (2) classed by and designated in accordance with the rules of a classification society; (3) lawfully operated in a government-regulated or licensed activity; or (4) equipped with and using an operable automatic identification system, vessel monitoring system, or a long range identification and tracking system. Specifies the documents required to conclusively prove an affirmative defense. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to promulgate or amend existing guidelines to provide adequate penalties for violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
