<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1354" updated="2013-07-19T21:02:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Reprsentatives to require a vote each year on whether to increase Members' pay.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2008--Introduced.
Amends Rule XXI (Restrictions on Certain Bills) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to declare that during consideration in the Committee of the Whole of a bill making appropriations for the Department of the Treasury for any fiscal year, before consideration of any other amendment, it shall be in order to consider an amendment only proposing to bar the automatic annual cost-of-living pay adjustment of Members of Congress that would otherwise take effect in such fiscal year. Declares that, during consideration of legislation between the two chambers making or continuing appropriations to the end of a fiscal year that includes appropriations for such Department for that fiscal year, it shall not be in order to consider such measure unless: (1) it includes a provision to bar such pay adjustment; or (2) the rule providing for its consideration allows a vote proposing such bar.</summary>
</bill>
