<bill session="111" type="h" number="2424" updated="2013-07-19T23:33:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Reserve Credit Facility Review Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 31, United States Code, to authorize reviews by the Comptroller General of the United States of any credit facility established by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or any Federal reserve bank during the current financial crisis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400227"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412226" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2009-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1457"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2009--Introduced.
Federal Reserve Credit Facility Review Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Comptroller General to conduct reviews, including onsite examinations, of any credit facility established by the Federal Reserve Board or any federal reserve bank, and of its establishment as the lender of last resort, including when it provides temporary assistance to private institutions as the lender of last restort. Specifies the credit facilities to which this Act applies. Terminates such authorization five years after the enactment of this Act. Grants the Comptroller General access to all records and property of any such credit facility, as well as to its officers, employees, contractors, and other agents and representatives.</summary>
</bill>
