<bill session="112" type="s" number="489" updated="2013-07-20T02:20:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preserving Homes and Communities Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require certain mortgagees to evaluate loans for modifications, to establish a grant program for State and local government mediation programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2012-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2011-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2011-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1232-1233"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1233-1235" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1477"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2011--Introduced.
Preserving Homes and Communities Act of 2011 - Prohibits a covered mortgagee from initiating either a nonjudicial or a judicial foreclosure against a covered mortgagor that is otherwise authorized under state law unless the covered mortgagee has: (1) used its best efforts to determine whether the mortgagor is eligible for a qualified loan modification, and to offer one if the mortgagor is eligible; and (2) made available to an ineligible mortgagor certain documentation of a loan modification calculation or net present value calculation, the loan origination, any pooling and servicing agreement, the mortgagor's payment history, and the specific alternatives to foreclosure considered by the mortgagee, including qualified loan modifications, workout agreements, and short sales. Requires a covered mortgagee to use its best efforts to suspend any foreclosure proceeding initiated before enactment of this Act, and to toll any deadlines limiting the mortgagor's rights. Prohibits any sale of the property under the mortgage or the entry of judgment against the mortgagor. Requires the mortgagee to reevaluate an eligible mortgagee's application for a qualified loan modification and offer one. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection (CFPB) Director to ensure that any home loan modification protocol includes a dispute resolution procedure to resolve any application disputes. Declares any sale of property in violation of this Act void. Makes failure to comply with this Act a bar to foreclosure under state law. Prohibits loan modification fees and sets forth rules governing foreclosure-related fees. Directs the Secretary of HUD to: (1) establish a grant program to make competitive grants to state and local governments to establish mediation programs that assist mortgagors facing foreclosure, and (2) develop and implement a plan to monitor conditions and trends in home ownership and the mortgage industry and the effectiveness of public and private efforts to reduce mortgage defaults and foreclosures. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, out of funds received or to be received from the sale of warrants under the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008, to transfer and credit $1 billion to the Housing Trust Fund established under the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992.</summary>
</bill>
