<bill session="112" type="h" number="5344" updated="2013-07-20T01:56:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent and respond to hazing incidents involving members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2012--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) (Secretary) to: (1) assess and develop a uniform definition of hazing, applicable to members of the Armed Forces (members), for inclusion in the Uniform Code of Military Justice (UCMJ); and (2) submit such definition to Congress. Expresses the sense of Congress that such definition should cover, at a minimum, any situation in which a member suffers or is exposed to any cruelty, indignity, humiliation, hardship, harm, harassment, or oppression, or the deprivation or abridgment of any right, by another member. Requires the Secretary to develop and implement a comprehensive policy on the prevention of and response to hazing involving members. Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to develop and implement a centralized, case-level database for the collection and maintenance of information regarding hazing, including incidents occurring at officer candidate schools, military academies and their preparatory schools, and basic training and professional schools for enlisted members. Requires such Secretaries to: (1) submit to Congress a plan to implement the database, and (2) complete implementation within 15 months after the enactment of this Act. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress: (1) a description of the current status of the Defense Incident-Based Reporting System, and (2) an explanation of how such System will relate to the database. Requires annual reports from each Secretary on the hazing incidents involving members. Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to report to Congress on the policies to prevent hazing and the systems initiated to track incidents of hazing in each of the military departments.</summary>
</bill>
