<bill session="113" type="h" number="2451" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Entrepreneurs' Economic Development Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish and carry out a direct lending program for small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2013-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2013--Introduced.
Strengthening Entrepreneurs' Economic Development Act of 2013 - Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish and carry out a direct lending program for small businesses (businesses with fewer than 20 employees). Sets forth provisions governing the amount and repayment period of, and interest rate on, such a loan. Authorizes the Administrator to collect a fee from the borrower. Directs the Administrator to: (1) issue guidance regarding prudent underwriting standards for such loans; (2) establish a process of making each loan application available to lenders for the purpose of originating, underwriting, closing, and servicing the loan; (3) first give priority to lenders within 50 miles of the principal office of the applicant, then make such applications available to lenders in the Preferred Lenders Program, and then consider such a loan for origination, underwriting, closing, and servicing by the Administrator; (4) offer to sell loans made under the program through the semi-annual public solicitation of offers to purchase; and (5) maintain and service loans that are not sold through asset sales. Amends the Small Business Act to require the SBA, for each small business loan in excess of $2 million that is approved under such Act, to collect a fee not to exceed a certain percentage of the outstanding balance of the deferred participation share of the loan as necessary to reduce to zero the cost to the SBA of making such loan.</summary>
</bill>
