<bill session="111" type="h" number="2108" updated="2013-07-19T23:30:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Predatory Mortgage Lending Practices Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Consumer Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect home buyers from predatory lending practices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412327"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2009--Introduced.
Predatory Mortgage Lending Practices Reduction Act - Amends the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 to prohibit any person, in connection with a subprime federally related mortgage loan, from providing mortgage lending services or mortgage brokerage services unless such person is certified by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development as having been adequately trained with regard to subprime lending. Amends the Truth in Lending Act to require lenders to establish a best practices plan, meeting certain criteria, to ensure compliance with such Act for high cost mortgages. Proscribes unfair or deceptive acts or practices in providing: (1) mortgage lending services for either a subprime federally related mortgage loan; (2) mortgage brokerage services for such a loan; and (3) appraisal of a property offered as security for repayment of the loan.Sets forth civil penalties for violations. Consumer Fairness Act - Amends the Consumer Credit Protection Act to declare unenforceable a written provision in any consumer contract or transaction which requires binding arbitration to resolve any controversy arising out of such transaction or contract, or the refusal to perform all or any part of the transaction. (Permits post-controversy arbitration agreements.) Amends the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 to authorize the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund to make grants to nonprofit community development corporations to educate and train borrowers and community groups regarding illegal and inappropriate predatory lending practices.</summary>
</bill>
