<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1769" updated="2013-07-19T23:11:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that in order to undermine the Taliban and their terrorist allies, the policy of the United States should support the recognition of Afghanistan's ethnic diversity, promoting mutual respect between various communities and regions of the country and bringing democracy closer to the people of Afghanistan by supporting constitutional change that recognizes and enables a democratic, decentralized, federal structure to replace the present failed centralized system of government, providing a political structure that reflects the diversity of the country and that builds trust and goodwill among Afghanistan's many communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2010-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2010-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Militias and paramilitary groups"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2010--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) the U.S. government should broaden the regional dialogue on Afghanistan, support constitutional reform, oppose the inclusion of the Taliban in the government of Afghanistan, and support the establishment of trained regional militias as well as a national army to fight the Taliban insurgency; and (2) the United States should abandon its support for the present failed centralized system of government in Afghanistan.</summary>
</bill>
