<bill session="110" type="s" number="2889" updated="2013-07-19T22:46:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Health Care Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve veterans' health care benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3160, S3161"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3160-3161" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Brain"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Dentists"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Head injuries"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Terminal care"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2008--Introduced.
Veterans Health Care Act of 2008 - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to contract to provide specialized residential care and rehabilitation services to a veteran of Operation Enduring Freedom or Operation Iraqi Freedom who suffers from a traumatic brain injury, has an accumulation of deficits in activities of daily living and instrumental activities of daily living and, because of these deficits, would otherwise require nursing home admission even though such care would generally exceed the veteran's nursing needs. Directs the Secretary to provide full-time board-certified physicians and dentists the opportunity to continue their professional education through VA sponsored continuing education programs. Authorizes (currently, directs) the Secretary to reimburse such physicians or dentists up to $1,000 per year for continuing professional education not available through VA sources. Exempts hospice care from requirements to pay a copayment in connection with hospital or nursing home care or medical services. Repeals a provision that prohibits the Secretary from performing widespread human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) testing but does allow voluntary testing of certain individuals. Authorizes the Secretary to disclose the name and address of present or former Armed Forces members and their dependents to collect charges for care or services provided for a non-service-connected disability. Removes provisions ending, on September 30, 2008, the Secretary's authority to obtain information from the Secretary of the Treasury or the Commissioner of Social Security under specified provisions of the Internal Revenue Code. Directs the Secretary to increase certain disability compensation and dependency and indemnity compensation amounts.</summary>
</bill>
