<bill session="111" type="s" number="259" updated="2013-07-20T00:25:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vision Care for Kids Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a grant program to provide vision care to children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2009-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2009-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2009-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2009-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2009-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2010-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="577"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/15/2009--Introduced.
Vision Care for Kids Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to award matching grants to states to complement existing state efforts to: (1) provide comprehensive eye examinations from a licensed optometrist or ophthalmologist for children who have been previously identified through a vision screening or eye examination by a licensed health care provider or vision screener as needing such services, who do not otherwise have coverage for vision services, and who are low-income children, with priority given to children who are under the age of nine years; (2) provide treatment or services as necessary to correct identified vision problems; and (3) develop and disseminate to parents, teachers, and health care practitioners educational materials on recognizing signs of visual impairment in children.Requires the Secretary to develop criteria: (1) governing the operation of the grant program; and (2) for the collection of data related to vision assessment and the utilization of follow-up services.Requires the Secretary to coordinate the program under this Act with other federal or state programs that provide services to children.</summary>
</bill>
