<bill session="112" type="h" number="6427" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Capitalizing Workforce Development Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title IV of the Social Security Act to create a competitive self-sustainable social services grant program to provide workforce development opportunities and training to people with barriers to employment under the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400379"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2012--Introduced.
Capitalizing Workforce Development Act of 2012 - Amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award competitive grants to support the purchase, renovation, construction, or lease and improvement of real property to be used by qualified self-sustaining job programs that provide job training, job placement, or other employment-related services to individuals with employment challenges.</summary>
</bill>
