<bill session="112" type="s" number="3323" updated="2013-07-20T02:45:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Family Home Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to improve the protections for servicemembers against mortgage foreclosures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2012-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4372-4373"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4310"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="5747"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/2012--Introduced.
Military Family Home Protection Act - Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to allow a court, in an action to enforce an obligation on real or personal property secured by a mortgage against a servicemember on active duty, a totally disabled veteran, or the surviving spouse of a member who died during military service, to either: (1) stay the proceedings for a period of time as justice and equity require, or (2) adjust the obligation to preserve the interests of all parties. Prohibits the sale, foreclosure, or seizure of the subject property for the service period, as well as the 12-month period after: (1) the servicemember is discharged or redeployed from a contingency operation, (2) the veteran is retired, or (3) the death of the servicemember (in the case of a surviving spouse). Increases the civil penalties for violations of the sale or foreclosure prohibitions. Prohibits an individual from being denied or refused credit solely by reason of eligibility for relief under this Act. Requires each lending institution acting as a creditor to such servicemember, veteran, or surviving spouse to designate an employee responsible for ensuring the institution's compliance with the requirements of this Act. Requires any such institution that had prior annual assets of $10 billion or more to maintain on its primary website a toll-free number for information with respect to the protections afforded under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
