<bill session="112" type="sr" number="24" updated="2013-07-20T02:10:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-25">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution to propose a standing order to govern extended debate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2011-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Over, Under the Rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S245-246" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sr" number="21"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2011--Introduced.
Establishes a standing order applicable to extended debate (filibuster) on a measure, motion, or other matter in the Senate. States that, if a question to close debate (cloture) on a measure, motion, or other matter is decided in the negative and a majority of Senators present and voting have voted to invoke cloture, the filibuster procedures under this Act shall be in order at any time if that measure, motion or other matter has continued as the only pending business subsequent to the vote against cloture. Makes it in order for the Majority Leader or his designee to move to invoke cloture on the pending measure, motion, or other matter on the grounds that no Senator seeks recognition to debate the matter. Requires the Presiding Officer: (1) immediately after the motion is made and before putting forth the question, to inquire whether any Senator seeks recognition to debate the measure, motion or other matter; (2) if a Senator seeks such recognition, to announce that the Senate is proceeding under filibuster; and (3) to recognize such Senator. Prohibits the entertainment of any dilatory motions, motions to suspend any rule or any such part, or dilatory quorum calls if the Senate enters into a filibuster. Requires the Senate, if during filibuster specified proceedings occur, and unless the Majority Leader or his designee withdraws the cloture motion, to proceed immediately to vote on the motion or to vote at a time designated by the Majority Leader or his designee within the next four calendar days of Senate session. Requires only a majority of Senators to decide such a motion to end the filibuster. Requires the Presiding Officer, if the Majority Leader's cloture motion is agreed to by a majority of Senators, to announce that: (1) the filibuster is ended; (2) the measure, motion, or other matter pending before the Senate shall be the unfinished business to the exclusion of all other business until disposed of; and (3) further proceedings on the measure, motion, or other matter shall occur as if the Senate had decided to invoke cloture.</summary>
</bill>
