<bill session="111" type="h" number="1811" updated="2013-07-19T23:28:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Getting Resources Efficiently and Effectively Now Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">GREEN Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the President to review and approve oil and gas exploration, development, and production projects under existing Federal oil and gas leases, both onshore and offshore, and to limit administrative and judicial proceedings with respect to such projects, upon finding that such a project complies with all applicable Federal laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412216"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/2009--Introduced.
Getting Resources Efficiently and Effectively Now Act or the GREEN Act - Directs the President (or a designee) to review all projects for the exploration, development, or production of oil and gas resources under federal leases for lands (or submerged lands) located onshore or offshore to determine whether the projects comply with federal laws. Requires the projects to be approved and authorized to proceed upon a written finding by the President (or the designee) that they serve the public interest in responsible domestic oil and gas development and comply with federal laws. Shields decisions of the President from further administrative or judicial review, stay, or injunction, except with respect to an appeal filed by the applicant or permittee. Declares that the President's (or designee's) determinations pre-empt any state law.</summary>
</bill>
