<bill session="109" type="h" number="1265" updated="2013-07-19T19:15:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Abandoned Hardrock Mines Reclamation Funding Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a source of funding for the reclamation of abandoned hardrock mines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2005-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E430-432"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Land subsidence"/>
    <term name="Mine wastes"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining engineering"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Revegetation"/>
    <term name="Sediment control"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/2005--Introduced.
Abandoned Hardrock Mines Reclamation Funding Act - Requires any person producing hardrock minerals from a mine within an unpatented mining claim or a mine on land that was patented under the general mining laws to pay a reclamation fee to the Secretary of the Interior. Requires the fee amount to be equal to a percentage of the net proceeds derived from the mine, with the percentage based upon the ratio of the net proceeds to the gross proceeds related to mineral production in accordance with a specified table. Exempts gross proceeds of less than $500,000 from minerals produced in any calendar year from the fee for that year if such proceeds are from mines located in a single patented claim or on two or more contiguous patented claims. Requires the Secretary to: (1) deposit amounts received into the Abandoned Minerals Mine Reclamation Fund (established by this Act); and (2) reduce a fee required by this Act by an amount equal to a royalty paid pursuant to an Act of Congress that provides for crediting to the Fund royalties paid to the Secretary regarding hardrock mineral production. Lists permissible uses of the Fund, including: (1) the reclamation and restoration of abandoned surface mined areas; (2) the planting of land adversely affected by past mining to prevent erosion and sedimentation; (3) the prevention, abatement, treatment, and control of water pollution created by abandoned mine drainage; and (4) the control of surface subsidence due to abandoned deep mines.</summary>
</bill>
