<bill session="111" type="s" number="3694" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Great Ape Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit the conducting of invasive research on great apes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2010-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2010-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2010-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6652-6653"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1326"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research ethics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2010--Introduced.
Great Ape Protection Act of 2010 - Prohibits: (1) conducting invasive research on great apes; (2) knowingly breeding, possessing, renting, loaning, donating, purchasing, selling, housing, maintaining, leasing, borrowing, transporting, moving, delivering, or receiving a great ape for the purpose of conducting such research; or (3) using federal funds to conduct such research. Defines "invasive research" as research that may cause death, bodily injury, pain, distress, fear, injury, or trauma to great apes, including drug testing or exposure to a substance that may be detrimental to the ape's health or psychological well-being. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) and other appropriate federal authorities to provide for the permanent retirement of all great apes that are owned or under the control of the federal government and that are being maintained in any facility for the purpose of breeding for, holding for, or conducting invasive research. Sets forth civil penalties for violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
