<bill session="109" type="h" number="3053" updated="2013-07-19T19:31:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Eastern Santa Clara River Basin Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To remediate groundwater contamination caused by perchlorates in the city of Santa Clarita, California.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400267"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2005--Introduced.
Eastern Santa Clara River Basin Protection Act - Requires the Secretary of the Army to participate in studies and other investigative activities and in the construction, planning, and design of projects determined by the Secretary to offer a long-term solution to groundwater perchlorate contamination in the Eastern Santa Clara River Basin in Santa Clarita, California. Requires investigative activities and projects to include sites that are sources of perchlorate and located in Santa Clarita. Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1992 to authorize the Secretary to provide environmental infrastructure and construction assistance for such projects. Directs the Secretary to allow credit for in-kind services provided by a non-Federal sponsor before initiation of a project.</summary>
</bill>
