<bill session="112" type="h" number="6517" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STEM Network Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Education to make grants to State-based STEM networks to expand STEM education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400185"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2012-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
STEM Network Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to award matching grants to state-based STEM networks or similar organizations to increase elementary and secondary school students' achievement in the STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics) disciplines, particularly in rural and low-income schools. Includes among grant uses: testing, sharing, and scaling up STEM education research, promising practices, and exemplary programs; identifying state STEM education weaknesses and prioritizing strategies to address them; implementing rigorous common STEM education content standards; developing and implementing innovative STEM assessments; promoting and developing pre- and in-service STEM teacher training; developing STEM career pathways and workforce education and training programs that reflect 21st century workforce needs; and facilitating the implementation of extended STEM learning times on school sites. Requires grantees to conduct periodic independent evaluations of their effectiveness in accomplishing those activities. Prohibits the Secretary from: (1) endorsing or approving any STEM curriculum designed for use in an elementary school, secondary school, or institution of higher education; or (2) requiring a state, local educational agency, or school to adopt a specific STEM program or instructional materials.</summary>
</bill>
