<bill session="112" type="h" number="1221" updated="2013-07-20T01:20:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Equity in Government Compensation Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Equity in Government Compensation Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To suspend the current compensation packages for the senior executives of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac and establish compensation for such positions in accordance with rates of pay for senior employees in the Executive Branch of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412481" joined="2011-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2011-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2011-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2011-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2011-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412475" joined="2011-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2011-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2011-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412402" joined="2011-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-31">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises Prior to Referral.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 6 .</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 52 - 4.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-01-17T19:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 112-366, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-17T19:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Oversight and Government discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-01-17T19:45:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="247">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 247.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/17/2012--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Equity in Government Compensation Act of 2011 - Requires the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency to: (1) suspend the compensation packages approved for 2011 for the executive officers of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) (government-sponsored enterprises or GSEs); and (2) establish, in lieu of such packages, a compensation system for such officers in accordance with the schedules of compensation and benefits established and adjusted pursuant to the compensation schedule comparability requirements of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989. Expresses the sense of Congress that each executive officer of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac performing services for an enterprise on the date of enactment of this Act whose compensation package is suspended should return to the Secretary of the Treasury (clawback) any compensation earned in 2010 and 2011 that was in excess of the maximum annual rate of basic pay authorized for a position in level I of the Executive Schedule. Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer any such amounts returned to the Secretary to a specified account in the Treasury for receiving gifts and proceeds from their sale or redemption, and dedicated to reducing the public debt. Subjects Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac executive officers to the executive compensation requirements of the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008. Prohibits the compensation of any executive officer of Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac whose compensation package is suspended under this Act from exceeding the compensation of the highest compensated employee of the Federal Housing Finance Agency. Establishes requirements for determining compensation rates for GSE employees according to the General Schedule for federal civil service employees. Declares that Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac employees shall not be considered federal employees.</summary>
</bill>
