<bill session="112" type="h" number="755" updated="2013-07-20T01:16:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Investing in Our Future Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose an excise tax on currency transactions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2011-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2011-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2011-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2011-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E262-263"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2011--Introduced.
Investing in Our Future Act of 2011- Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on currency transactions exceeding $10,000 equal to 0.005% of the value of the currency acquired in the transaction (currency transaction tax). Establishes in the Treasury: (1) the Child Care Assistance Trust Fund, which shall be funded with 10% of the revenues from the currency transactions tax and which shall be used to provide increased allocations to states for child care assistance; (2) the Multilateral Global Health Trust Fund, which shall be funded with 25% of the revenues from such tax and from which the Secretary of State shall make grants to assist developing countries in addressing HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria, maternal mortality, family planning, neglected diseases, and other health issues; and (3) the Global Climate Change Adaptation and Mitigation Trust Fund, which shall be funded with 25% of the revenues from such tax and which shall be used for contributions to the Green Climate Fund, and the Adaptation Fund, established pursuant to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change. Requires remaining tax revenues to be used for federal budget deficit reduction or reduction of the federal debt.</summary>
</bill>
