<bill session="111" type="s" number="593" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ban Poisonous Additives Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ban the use of bisphenol A in food containers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3086-3087"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3087-3088" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1523"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2009--Introduced.
Ban Poisonous Additives Act of 2009 - Treats any food container that is composed, in whole or in part, of bisphenol A or that can release bisphenol A into food as a container that is composed of a poisonous or deleterious substance for purposes of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act. Bans the use of such containers. Allows the Secretary of Health and Human Services to grant a waiver of such ban for one year (renewable for an additional year) under specified circumstances. Requires any product for which the Secretary grants a waiver to display a prominent warning on its label of the potential health effects associated with bisphenol A. Directs the Commissioner of Food and Drugs to periodically review substances listed in federal regulations and generally recognized as safe. Requires any such substances that are shown by new scientific evidence to cause reproductive or developmental toxicity in humans or animals to be banned or otherwise restricted. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require (currently, permits) a manufacturer or supplier of a food contact substance to notify the Secretary of the identity, intended use, and safety of any such substance and of determinations as to the health effects of such substance.</summary>
</bill>
