<bill session="109" type="s" number="2824" updated="2013-07-19T20:38:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">COMPETE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Competitive and Open Markets that Protect and Enhance the Treatment of Entrepreneurs Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reduce the burdens of the implementation of section 404 of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300004" joined="2006-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2006-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2006-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300015" joined="2006-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2006-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2006-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2006-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2006-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5405"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Corporate accountability"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Corporate management"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2006--Introduced.
Competitive and Open Markets that Protect and Enhance the Treatment of Entrepreneurs Act, or the COMPETE Act - Amends the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 regarding the management assessment of internal controls in the annual report of each issuer of registered securities to require certain rules of the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to permit a small public company to elect voluntarily not to provide in its annual report an assessment of (or a related public accounting firm attestation concerning) the effectiveness of its internal control structure and financial reporting procedures, if it meets specified size criteria. Includes among such criteria: (1) total market capitalization of less than $700 million; (2) total product revenue of less than $125 million; and (3) fewer than 1500 record beneficial holders. Directs the SEC and the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board (Board) to: (1) alter the standard for review from a remote likelihood standard for noting weaknesses to a 5% de minimus material weakness criterion (based on 5% of net profits); (2) establish specific guidelines for measuring certain terms; and (3) modify independence rules to allow prudent interaction between registered public accounting firms performing such assessments and internal consultants. Directs the SEC and the Board to: (1) jointly study and report to Congress on the principles-based Turnbull Guidance under the securities laws of the United Kingdom; and (2) compare and contrast such principles to the implementation of Sarbanes-Oxley requirements.</summary>
</bill>
