<bill session="112" type="s" number="3074" updated="2013-07-20T02:43:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Password Protection Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit employers from compelling or coercing any person to authorize access to a protected computer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2012-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="5684"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2012--Introduced.
Password Protection Act of 2012 - Amends the federal criminal code to subject to a fine any employer who knowingly and intentionally: (1) compels or coerces any person to provide the employer with a password or similar information to access a protected computer not owned by such employer; or (2) discharges, disciplines, discriminates, or threatens to take such actions, against any person who fails to authorize access to such computer, has filed a complaint or instituted a proceeding regarding such action, or testified or is about to testify in any such proceeding. Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of a court of competent jurisdiction to grant equitable relief in a civil action, if the court believes that the information sought to be obtained is relevant to protecting the intellectual property, a trade secret, or confidential business information of the party seeking relief. Exempts an employer's actions from such prohibition if: (1) the employer discharges or disciplines an individual for good cause; (2) a state enacts a law that specifically waives such prohibition with respect to a particular class of state or agency employees and the employer's action relates to an employee in such class; or (3) an executive agency, military department, or other executive branch entity specifically waives the prohibition with respect to a particular class of employees who may have access to classified information.</summary>
</bill>
