<bill session="111" type="h" number="6204" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Charter School Good Governance and Transparency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require States receiving funds under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish policies with respect to the auditing of charter schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412379"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2010--Introduced.
Charter School Good Governance and Transparency Act - Requires states to provide each charter school in the state that receives funds under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 with a list of licensed, independent auditors that perform governmental audits. Requires states to develop and implement policies requiring such charter schools to: (1) maintain their financial records in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, and applicable state and federal requirements; (2) be audited annually by a licensed, independent auditor, with the findings made public and filed with their authorized public chartering agency and state; and (3) address all audit findings and report to their authorized public chartering agency on actions taken to do so. Directs states to: (1) require such chartering agencies to report significant audit findings and the measures schools take to address them; and (2) submit overall summary analyses of the annual audits to the Secretary of Education.</summary>
</bill>
