<bill session="109" type="s" number="746" updated="2013-07-19T20:19:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Inland Empire Regional Water Recycling Initiative</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Inland Empire regional recycling project and in the Cucamonga Valley Water District recycling project.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3420-3421"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3421" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="802"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3638"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2005--Introduced.
Inland Empire Regional Water Recycling Initiative - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior: (1) in cooperation with the Inland Empire Utilities Agency, to participate in the design, planning, and construction of the Inland Empire regional water recycling project; and (2) in cooperation with the Cucamonga Valley Water District, to participate in the design, planning, and construction of the Cucamonga Valley Water District satellite recycling plants in Rancho Cucamonga, California, to reclaim and recycle approximately two million gallons per day of domestic wastewater. Limits the Federal share of the cost of each project to 25 percent.</summary>
</bill>
