<bill session="112" type="h" number="1056" updated="2013-07-20T01:19:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patent Continuing Disclosure Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 35, United States Code, with respect to false marking.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2011-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2011-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412473" joined="2011-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2011-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intellectual Property, Competition and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU12" subcommittee="Intellectual Property, Competition and the Internet" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2011--Introduced.
Patent Continuing Disclosure Act - Amends federal patent law to prohibit fining for false marking (counterfeiting or imitating patent marks to deceive the public into believing articles are patented) any person who makes, uses, offers for sale, or sells within or imports into the United States, an expired patent item affixed with the word "patent" (along with the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office [USPTO] patent number granted to that person) if, after the expiration of the patent: (1) there is no change in the manufacturing or production process, or (2) the word "expired" is placed before the word "patent" (or the patent number) when a change in the manufacturing or production process occurs. Defines the term "change in the manufacturing or production process" as an intentional expansion, enhancement, improvement, or repair, that suspends, for a period of at least 24 hours, the normal operating procedures through which the item is assembled, made, crafted, manufactured, built, or fabricated from individual components or raw materials, or both.</summary>
</bill>
