<bill session="111" type="s" number="470" updated="2013-07-20T00:27:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Combating Organized Retail Crime Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to combat organized crime involving the illegal acquisition of retail goods for the purpose of selling those illegally obtained goods through physical and online retail marketplaces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2010-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2475-2476"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2476-2479" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2009--Introduced.
Combating Organized Retail Crime Act of 2009- Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) expand the definitions of the crimes of transporting and selling or receiving stolen goods to include thefts having an aggregate value of $5,000 or more during any 12-month period; (2) modify the crime of fraud involving access devices to include the Universal Product Code label or similar product code label as an access device; and (3) set forth provisions to prevent sales of illegally obtained goods in a physical (e.g., flea market, open air market) or online retail marketplace and to grant enforcement powers to states to obtain injunctive and other relief against persons engaged in organized retail crime. Requires the Attorney General to establish a suspected illegal sales activity form and a suspicious activity report form for the reporting of suspected sales of illegally-obtained items in a physical or online retail marketplace. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and, if appropriate, amend federal sentencing guidelines for persons convicted of offenses involving organized retail crime.</summary>
</bill>
