<bill session="112" type="s" number="2148" updated="2013-07-20T02:35:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lead Exposure Reduction Amendments Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Toxic Substance Control Act relating to lead-based paint renovation and remodeling activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2012-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2012-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2012-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2012-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5911"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2012--Introduced.
Lead Exposure Reduction Amendments Act of 2012 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA) to exclude from the definition of "abatement" any renovation, remodeling, landscaping, or other activity: (1) the primary purpose of which is to repair, restore, or remodel a structure or dwelling; and (2) that incidentally results in a reduction or elimination of lead-based paint hazards. Removes from the definition of "lead-based paint" lead levels that may be established by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) for paint or surface coating that are not otherwise specified in such definition. Requires the Administrator to: (1) conduct a lead-based paint certification study prior to proposing any new regulation applicable to target housing or public or commercial buildings constructed before 1978; and (2) complete and publish such study no later than a year prior to proposing any new regulation applicable to such structure or dwelling. Exempts from such regulations emergency renovations that result from a sudden, unexpected event that presents a risk to the public health or safety or threatens to cause significant damage to equipment or property if not attended to immediately. Prohibits such regulation from requiring post-abatement clearance testing. Requires the Administrator, in promulgating regulations relating to renovation or remodeling activities in target housing in which the owner resides, to include a provision that permits the owner to authorize the renovation or remodeling contractor to forego compliance with such regulation if: (1) no pregnant woman or child under the age of six resides in such housing; and (2) the owner certifies that the renovation or remodeling project is to be carried out at the target housing of the owner, that no such woman or child resides in such housing, and that such contractor will be exempt from employing the work practices required by such regulation. Exempts contractors from liability resulting from any misrepresentation of the owner of the target housing. Requires the Administrator to: (1) establish a process by which the Administrator shall identify and approve a commercially available lead-based paint test kit that is inexpensive, does not require special training, and enables users to determine the presence of lead at the job site; and (2) suspend implementation of such regulation relating to renovation and remodeling until the Administrator identifies and approves one or more test kits that meet such criteria.</summary>
</bill>
