<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1310" updated="2013-07-19T21:01:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Government of Iran's lack of protection for internationally recognized human rights creates poor conditions for religious freedom in the Islamic Republic of Iran.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2008--Introduced.
Calls for the release of all religious prisoners in Iran and for U.S. officials to speak out publicly about the deteriorating conditions for freedom of thought, conscience, and religion or belief in Iran. Calls on the United Nations Human Rights Council to monitor and demand compliance with the recommendations of the representatives of those special mechanisms that have already visited Iran. Supports: (1) the continued designation of Iran as a "country of particular concern" under the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998; (2) funding to promote democracy and human rights in Iran; (3) the commission of an independent review of Voice of America Persian and Radio Farda; and (4) the establishment of a diplomatic envoy to Iran. Calls on the government of Iran to: (1) release all prisoners held because of their religious or political beliefs; and (2) respect the human rights of all its citizens.</summary>
</bill>
