<bill session="109" type="h" number="2109" updated="2013-07-19T19:22:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out certain authorities under an agreement with Canada respecting the importation of municipal solid waste, to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize States to restrict receipt of foreign municipal solid waste, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2005-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2005-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2005-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2005-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2005-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2005-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2005-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2005-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="593"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="346"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit any person from importing, transporting, or exporting municipal solid waste for final disposal or for incineration in violation of the Agreement Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of Canada Concerning the Transboundary Movement of Hazardous Waste or any regulation implementing such agreement. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) perform the functions of the Designated Authority of the United States with respect to such importation and exportation under the agreement; and (2) implement and enforce the notice and consent provisions of the agreement as well as its other provisions. Sets forth factors to consider in determining whether to consent to the importation of municipal solid waste. Requires that the views of States be given substantial weight. Authorizes the Administrator to issue orders assessing civil penalties, requiring compliance, or both, or to commence civil actions in U.S. district court to address violations of this Act. Limits civil penalties assessed pursuant to an administrative order to $25,000 per day of noncompliance. Authorizes persons subject to administrative orders to request a public hearing. Authorizes States to enact laws imposing limitations (including prohibitions) on the receipt and disposal of foreign municipal solid waste. States that no such action shall be considered to impose an undue burden on interstate or foreign commerce.</summary>
</bill>
