<bill session="111" type="h" number="6079" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Workforce Housing Opportunity Simplification Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate affordable workforce homeownership in, and develop the full-time resident communities of, resort areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412308"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Federal Housing Finance Agency"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/9/2010--Introduced.
Workforce Housing Opportunity Simplification Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act to authorize the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act to authorize the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), to purchase, service, sell, lend on the security of, and otherwise deal in affordable workforce housing mortgages for one-family residences: (1) that shall be used as the mortgagor's residence at least 8 of any 12 months and 240 days of any 365 days; (2) located within, or are part of, a multifamily housing development meeting certain requirements; and (3) located in a resort county. Exempts such mortgages from any requirements and guidelines of such government sponsored entities (also known as GSEs) that are inconsistent with such authority and with the GSEs' duty under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to serve the market for affordable workforce housing mortgages. Limits the application of this Act to such mortgages in Colorado resort counties (Eagle County, Grand County, and Summit County). Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to require the GSEs to develop loan products and flexible underwriting guidelines to facilitate a secondary market for affordable workforce housing mortgages under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
