<bill session="112" type="h" number="2574" updated="2013-07-20T01:32:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Jobs Now Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to create a pilot program to award grants to units of general local government and community-based organizations to create jobs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2011--Introduced.
Jobs Now Act of 2011 - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to direct the Secretary of Labor to carry out a two-year pilot program to award competitive grants to general local government units or community-based organizations to retain, employ, or train employees who provide them a public service. Prescribes program requirements, including that: (1) each unit or organization grantee give priority to the retention, employment, and training of veterans, individuals with disabilities, individuals who receive unemployment benefits, or dislocated workers; and (2) the Secretary give priority to the award of grants to units and organizations with high unemployment, foreclosure, and poverty rates.</summary>
</bill>
