<bill session="111" type="h" number="6498" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Children Across State Lines Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to determine the extent to which reports of suspected or known instances of child abuse or neglect involving a potential combination of jurisdictions, such as intrastate, interstate, Federal-State, and State-Tribal, are screened out solely on the basis of the cross-jurisdictional complications, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/7/2010--Introduced.
Protecting Children Across State Lines Act - Amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to authorize the continuing interdisciplinary program of research of the Secretary of Heatlh and Human Services (HHS) to focus on the extent to which reports of suspected or known instances of child abuse or neglect involving a potential combination of jurisdictions (intrastate, interstate, federal-state, and state-tribal) are being screened out solely on the basis of cross-jurisdictional complications. Authorizes the Secretary of HHS to award grants to public or private organizations to develop best practices for the handling of reports of suspected or known child abuse or neglect related fatalities involving a potential combination of jurisdictions. Requires each state receiving a grant for child abuse and neglect prevention and treatment programs to include in its annual report the number of children reported during the year as abused or neglected who were screened out because of cross-jurisdictional complications. Authorizes the Secretary of HHS to make grants to assist states in developing, establishing, and operating programs designed to improve the handling of reports of suspected or known instances of child abuse or neglect, including reports involving a potential combination of jurisdictions, in a manner that ensures appropriate action is taken to protect children. Requires the state multidisciplinary task force on children's justice to review comprehensively every three years the handling of reports of suspected or known instances of child abuse or neglect involving a potential combination of jurisdictions, including efforts to coordinate and ensure appropriate action is taken.</summary>
</bill>
