<bill session="112" type="h" number="3693" updated="2013-07-20T01:42:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cents and Sensibility Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 31, United States Code, to save the American taxpayers money by immediately altering the metallic composition of the 1-cent coin, to require a prompt review and report, with recommendations, for cost-saving changes in the metallic content of other circulating United States coins, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412461"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2011-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2011-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic Monetary Policy and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3694"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2011--Introduced.
Cents and Sensibility Act - Revises the discretionary authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe the weight and the composition of the alloy of the one-cent coin. Requires that the one-cent coin be: (1) produced primarily of steel, and (2) treated to impart a copper color to its appearance so that the appearance is similar to one-cent coins produced of a copper-zinc alloy. Instructs the Secretary, in minting 1-cent coins, to use only steel produced in the United States unless: (1) the Secretary determines doing so would be inconsistent with the public interest, or (2) steel is not produced in the United States in sufficient and reasonably available quantities. Directs the Secretary to submit to certain congressional committees the initial report concerning production costs and technologies required by the Coin Modernization, Oversight, and Continuity Act of 2010.</summary>
</bill>
