<bill session="111" type="h" number="5976" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Focusing Resources, Economic Investment, and Guidance to Help Transportation Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the efficiency, operation, and security of the national transportation system to move freight by leveraging investments and promoting partnerships that advance interstate and foreign commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412186"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2010-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2010-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3629"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2010--Introduced.
Focusing Resources, Economic Investment, and Guidance to Help Transportation Act of 2010 - Declares U.S. policy with respect to freight transportation. Establishes within the Office of the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) an Office of Freight Planning and Development. Directs the Secretary to develop a long-term National Freight Freight Transportation Strategic Plan to guide planning and investments in the national transportation system to move freight. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop new or improve existing tools to support an outcome-oriented, performance-based approach to evaluate proposed freight-related and other transportation projects; (2) facilitate the collection of transportation-related data to support a broad range of evaluation methods and techniques to assist in making transportation investment decisions; and (3) consider improvements to the Commodity Flow Survey that reduce identified freight data gaps and deficiencies and help evaluate forecasts of transportation demand. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a competitive grant program for capital investment projects that improve the efficiency of the national transportation system to move freight; and (2) give priority to projects with the highest system performance improvement relative to their benefit-cost analysis. Limits the federal share of project net capital costs at 80%. Requires a grant recipient to submit to the Secretary: (1) a project management plan and an annual financial plan for a project with a total cost of $500 million or more; and (2) an annual financial plan for a project with a total cost of $100 million or more. Repeals specified prohibitions against the transfer of amounts from the Highway Trust Fund to the Port Infrastructure Development Fund.</summary>
</bill>
