<bill session="110" type="h" number="4051" updated="2013-07-19T21:39:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Housing Assistance Authorization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize appropriations for assistance for the National Urban League, the Raza Development Fund, the Housing Partnership Network, and the National Community Renaissance Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-11-08">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1923"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Blacks"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Community facilities"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Moderate income housing"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/2007--Introduced.
Housing Assistance Authorization Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to make a grant to the National Urban League to provide technical and financial assistance to local non-profit organizations to undertake community development and affordable housing projects and programs serving low- and moderate-income households, particularly through organizations located in neighborhoods with substantial populations of African American income-disadvantaged households. Authorizes the Secretary also to make a grant to the Raza Development Fund to provide technical and financial assistance to local nonprofit organizations to undertake similar projects and programs serving low- and moderate-income households, particularly through organizations in neighborhoods with substantial populations of income-disadvantaged households of Hispanic origin. Authorizes the Secretary to make a grant to the Housing Partnership Network to create, sustain, and improve access to affordable housing and community facilities benefiting very low-, low-, and moderate-income households and communities. Authorizes the Secretary to make a grant to the National Community Renaissance Program to undertake affordable housing projects benefitting very low-, low-, and moderate-income households.</summary>
</bill>
