<bill session="112" type="h" number="326" updated="2013-07-20T01:13:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mobile Home Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 to provide for rental assistance payments to assist certain owners of manufactured homes who rent the lots on which their homes are located.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2011-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E100"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/2011--Introduced.
Mobile Home Protection Act - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 (section 8 voucher program) to require a public housing agency (PHA) to contract to make section 8 rental assistance payments directly to a low-income family (rather than to the owner of the real property on which the family's manufactured [mobile] home is located) that owns a manufactured home, rents the real property on which it is located, and is a family to whom assistance under such Act has been made available, if: (1) the owner of the real property refuses to enter into a contract to receive assistance payments, (2) the family was residing in the manufactured home on the real property at the time such assistance was initially made available on the family's behalf, (3) the family provides assurances to the agency that amounts from the assistance payments are used for rental of the real property, and (4) such rental otherwise complies with the Act's requirements for assistance.</summary>
</bill>
