<bill session="110" type="s" number="3557" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">America Saving for Personal Investment, Retirement, and Education Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ASPIRE Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to encourage savings, promote financial literacy, and expand opportunities for young adults by establishing KIDS Accounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3740"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial planning"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Personal budgets"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Introduced.
America Saving for Personal Investment, Retirement, and Education Act of 2008 or the ASPIRE Act of 2008 - Establishes a KIDS Account Fund in the Treasury. Establishes within the Fund a Kids Investment and Development Savings Account (KIDS Account). Makes eligible to contribute to such account, and to receive a matching federal contribution, any U.S. citizen born after December 31, 2007, and under 18 years of age, whose modified adjusted gross income is below the applicable national median adjusted gross income amount. Creates the KIDS Account Fund Board to establish a default investment program under which, in a manner similar to a lifecycle investment program, sums in each KIDS Account are allocated to investment funds in the KIDS Account Fund based on the amount of time before the account holder attains the age of 18. States that, for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code, each KIDS Account shall be treated in the same manner as a Roth IRA. Applies Roth IRA requirements separately to KIDS accounts. Provides for: (1) distributions for higher education expenses; and (2) privately managed KIDS accounts. Subjects the Board to the same composition requirements, duties, and responsibilities as the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board. Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Financial Literacy and Education Commission, to develop programs to promote the financial literacy of account holders of KIDS Accounts.</summary>
</bill>
