<bill session="112" type="s" number="3425" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Offshoring Notification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act to provide a notice requirement regarding offshoring.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2012--Introduced.
Offshoring Notification Act - Amends the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act to extend its coverage not only to each of the 50 states and the District of Columbia but also to the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau, and each U.S. territory or possession. Revises the requirement that an employer give 60-day written notice to employees, state dislocated worker units, and local governments before ordering a plant closing or mass layoff. Requires such notice to include information stating whether: (1) the employer plans to continue producing goods or providing services that affected employees have been producing or providing, and (2) the production or provision will be performed for the employer by employees or contractors outside the United States (offshoring).</summary>
</bill>
