<bill session="110" type="h" number="485" updated="2013-07-19T21:08:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Tracts Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Tracts Act to facilitate the exchange of small tracts of land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/2007--Introduced.
Small Tracts Reform Act - Amends the Small Tracts Act to provide for the sale, exchange, or interchange of National Forest System (NFS) lands, the sale or exchange of which is either not practicable or not expedient under any other authority of the Secretary of Agriculture and which are parcels or parts of parcels of 100 acres or less which are interspersed with or adjacent to lands which have been transferred out of Federal ownership and which are determined by the Secretary, because of location or size, not to be subject to efficient administration.</summary>
</bill>
