<bill session="110" type="h" number="1775" updated="2013-07-19T21:19:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freedom of Information Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 552 of title 5, United States Code (popularly known as the Freedom of Information Act) to require the disclosure of certain information related to Federal contractors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400065"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Information Policy, Census, and National Archives.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO23" subcommittee="Information Policy, Census, and National Archives" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2007--Introduced.
Freedom of Information Improvement Act - Amends the Freedom of Information Act concerning requests involving access to records relating to federal contracts. Provides that information submitted to the federal government to obtain, amend, or clarify a contract shall not be considered to be trade secrets or commercial or financial information that is privileged or confidential, unless the information is proprietary information. Requires an agency to release requested information (unless shown to be exempt): (1) relating to whether a contractor performed the work required; (2) indicating the use of substandard materials or work practices; (3) relating to information that is discovered as part of a government investigation of a contract or that is revealed because of the existence of credible evidence raising doubts concerning the contractor's performance because of investigations for past poor performance or because the contractor has been the subject of credible and consistent press reports pertaining to performance of government contracts; or (4) if disclosure of the information will contribute to public understanding and knowledge.Requires any information released pursuant to this Act to relate solely to the federal contract involved and not to unrelated aspects of the company concerned.</summary>
</bill>
