<bill session="112" type="h" number="2971" updated="2013-07-20T01:35:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lincoln Legacy Infrastructure Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles 23, 45, and 49, United States Code, to encourage the use of private-public partnerships in transportation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412422"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1300"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2011--Introduced.
Lincoln Legacy Infrastructure Development Act - Prohibits the Secretary from imposing a federal surcharge on a state that has allowed the placement of blind vending facilities in rest and recreation areas, and in safety rest areas, located on Interstate System (IS) rights-of-way. Revises state high occupancy vehicle (HOV) facility requirements to increase from a minimum of two to a minimum of three the number of occupants per vehicle for use of an HOV facility in cases of congestion meeting certain criteria. Amends the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to remove limits on the number of state or local governments or public authorities with which the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements to establish value pricing pilot programs (in effect, allowing extension of the programs to all such authorities). Amends the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century (TEA-21) to increase from 3 to 10 the number of IS highways, bridges, or tunnels where a state may collect tolls for the reconstruction and rehabilitation of IS highway corridors. Amends the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU) to eliminate restrictions on: (1) the number of projects under the express lanes demonstration program (currently 15), and (2) the number of IS facilities on which the Secretary may collect IS construction tolls (currently 3). Eliminates the nonsubordination of secured loans and lines of credit used to finance surface transportation project costs to the claims of any holder of project obligations in the event of the obligor's bankruptcy, insolvency, or liquidation. (Thus allows subordination of secured loans and lines of credit to such claims.) Makes eligible for railroad rehabilitation and improvement direct loans and loan guarantees: (1) projects and activities that benefit high-speed rail, and (2) development phase activities. Directs the Administrator of the Federal Transit Administration (FTA) to establish a six-year public-private partnership experimental program to encourage recipients of certain federal assistance to carry out tests and experimentation in the public transportation project development process designed to: (1) attract private investment in such projects (including high occupancy/toll [HOT] lane facilities); and (2) increase project management flexibility and innovation, improve efficiency, allow for timely project implementation, and create new revenue streams. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to remove the cap on the aggregate allowable amount of tax-exempt bonds to finance qualified highway or surface freight transfer facilities. Revises a specified formula in order to reduce annual adjustments to pay schedules for federal employees for FY2013-FY2021.</summary>
</bill>
