<bill session="111" type="hc" number="184" updated="2013-07-20T00:14:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress that the bankruptcy proceedings of Lehman Brothers Holding Inc. and Lehman Brothers Europe Inc. be resolved in an equitable and expeditious process between the United States and United Kingdom, and that the interests of American investors be given due consideration and be treated with urgency throughout.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400271"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2009--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) Lehman Brothers Holding Inc. and Lehman Brothers Europe Inc. bankruptcy administrators in the United States and United Kingdom should establish an international framework for coordinating bankruptcy proceedings among the business holdings and operations in each country; (2) the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) should dedicate sufficient resources to ensure an expedited resolution serving the interest of American investors in an equitable manner; and (3) there should be increased cooperation among the various Lehman Brothers entities as well as the respective U.S. and United Kingdom regulatory agencies to insure the swift return of customer assets held in Lehman Brothers Europe Inc.'s prime brokerage unit.</summary>
</bill>
