<bill session="112" type="s" number="1018" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Defense Sexual Trauma Response Oversight and Good Governance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Defense STRONG Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, and the Ike Skelton National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011 to provide for implementation of additional recommendations of the Defense Task Force on Sexual Assault in the Military Services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2011-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2011-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2012-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1529"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/2011--Introduced.
Defense Sexual Trauma Response Oversight and Good Governance Act (Defense STRONG Act) - Amends the Ike Skelton National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011 to require the Director of the Sexual Assault Prevention and Response Office to be appointed from general or flag officers or Department of Defense (DOD) employees in a comparable Senior Executive Service position. Requires the assignment within each military brigade or equivalent unit level of at least one full-time Sexual Assault Response Coordinator and one full-time Sexual Assault Victim Advocate, allowing the Secretary of the military department concerned to assign additional coordinators and/or advocates based on the demographics or needs of the unit. Allows only members of the Armed Forces (members) or DOD civilian personnel to be assigned as coordinators or advocates as of October 1, 2013. Directs the Secretary of Defense to establish a professional training and certification program for such coordinators and advocates. Entitles any member, or dependent of a member, who is the victim of a sexual assault to legal assistance provided by a military legal assistance counsel and coordinator and advocate services, regardless of whether the member elects unrestricted or restricted (confidential) reporting of the assault. Makes privileged any communications between a member or dependent and a coordinator, advocate, or person staffing a helpline. Directs the Secretary to establish a system for tracking and permanently maintaining any medical, investigative, and other records prepared or obtained by DOD in connection with a sexual assault involving a member or dependent. Requires the transfer from the Secretary to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) of certain medical information in anticipation of a member's discharge, release, retirement, medical treatment, or claim for disability. Provides for the expedited consideration of, and priority for, an application by victims of sexual assault for a permanent change of station or unit transfer based on humanitarian conditions. Requires each military department Secretary to develop curricula to provide sexual assault prevention and response training and education for members and civilian employees of that department. Directs the Secretary to: (1) provide for the inclusion of a sexual assault prevention and response training module at each level of professional military education, and (2) require managers of specialty skills associated with first responders to integrate sexual assault response training in initial and recurring first responder training courses.</summary>
</bill>
