<bill session="113" type="s" number="1074" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend Federal recognition to the Chickahominy Indian Tribe, the Chickahominy Indian Tribe-Easter Division, the Upper Mattaponi Tribe, the Rappahannock Tribe, Inc., the Monacan Indian Nation, and the Nansemond Indian Tribe.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3858"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="2190"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2013 - Extends federal recognition to the following Indian tribes of Virginia and establishes their relationship with the federal government as described below: (1) the Chickahominy Tribe, (2) the Chickahominy Indian Tribe--Eastern Division, (3) the Upper Mattaponi Tribe, (4) the Rappahannock Tribe, Inc., (5) the Monacan Indian Nation, and (6) the Nansemond Indian Tribe. Makes the tribes and their members eligible for all services and benefits provided by the federal government to federally recognized Indian tribes. Establishes the service area of each tribe and requirements for each tribe regarding its membership roll, governing documents, and governing body. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, on request of any of the tribes, to take specified lands into trust for the benefit of that tribe, to be considered part of that tribe's reservation. Prohibits the tribes from conducting gaming activities. Prohibits this Act from affecting the hunting, fishing, trapping, gathering, or water rights of the tribes and their members. Requires Virginia to exercise jurisdiction over all criminal offenses committed, and all civil actions arising, on lands in Virginia owned by, or held in trust by the United States for, the tribes. Authorizes the Secretary to accept all or any portion of Virginia's jurisdiction over such offenses and actions on verification by the Secretary of a tribe's certification that the tribe possesses the capacity to reassume such jurisdiction. Prohibits the use of eminent domain to acquire lands in fee or in trust for an Indian tribe recognized under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
