<bill session="111" type="h" number="6181" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Infrastructure Investment Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage investments in infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2010-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1690"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2010--Introduced.
American Infrastructure Investment Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend until January 1, 2013, the period for issuing Build America Bonds and for credits allowable to issuers of such bonds. Allows funding through such bonds for capital expenditures for levees and flood control projects. Exempts private activity bonds for sewage and water supply facilities from the state volume caps applicable to such bonds. Allows Indian tribal governments to issue tax-exempt private activity bonds to provide water or sewage facilities. Extends through 2011 the exemption from alternative minimum tax (AMT) treatment of interest on certain tax-exempt bonds. Extends through 2011 the period for issuing recovery zone economic development bonds and recovery zone facility bonds. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to allocate 2010 national limitations on recovery bonds based upon state unemployment statistics. Allows a full offset against the AMT for new market tax credit amounts. Extends through 2011: (1) the tax exemption allowed for interest on bonds guaranteed by a federal home loan bank; and (2) small issuer rules for the allocation of tax-exempt interest expense by financial institutions.</summary>
</bill>
