<bill session="111" type="s" number="3957" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Graduate Medical Education Reform Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a medical education trust fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-11-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7972-7973"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7973-7974" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2010--Introduced.
Graduate Medical Education Reform Act of 2010 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish and implement procedures under which the amount of payments that a hospital would otherwise receive for indirect medical education (IME) costs for discharges occurring during an applicable period is adjusted based on the performance of the hospital on specified measures of health care work force priorities. Requires bonus payments to a hospital if at least 33% of its full-time equivalent residents were enrolled in medical residency programs in primary care during the applicable period. Directs the Secretary to establish a program of payments to eligible hospitals for direct and indirect expenses associated with operating graduate medical residency training programs. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress and the National Health Care Workforce Commission on the graduate medical education (GME) payments that hospitals receive under the Medicare program. Establishes in the Treasury the Medical Education Trust Fund. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the fees on insured and self-insured health plans to provide partial financing for the Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
