<bill session="111" type="sr" number="154" updated="2013-07-20T00:17:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-19">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution honoring the entrepreneurial spirit of small business concerns in the United States during National Small Business Week, beginning May 17, 2009.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2009-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-05-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5646-5647" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5646-5647" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5623-5624" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="sr" number="540"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2009--Passed Senate without amendment.
Honors the entrepreneurial spirit of small businesses during National Small Business Week beginning May 17, 2009. Applauds the efforts and achievements of small business owners and their employees. Recognizes the work of the Small Business Administration (SBA) and its resource partners in providing assistance to entrepreneurs and small businesses. Urges the President to ensure that: (1) applicable procurement goals for small businesses are reached by all federal agencies; (2) guaranteed loans, microloans, and venture capital are made available for startup and growing small businesses; (3) necessary federal resources are provided to management assistance programs delivered by SBA resource partners; (4) reforms to the SBA disaster loan program are implemented as quickly as possible; (5) tax policy spurs small business growth, creates jobs, and increases competitiveness; (6) the federal government reduces the regulatory compliance burden on small businesses; and (7) broader health reform efforts address specific needs of small businesses and the self-employed in providing quality and affordable health insurance coverage to their employees.</summary>
</bill>
