<bill session="112" type="h" number="5911" updated="2013-07-20T02:01:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lead Exposure Reduction Amendments Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act relating to lead-based paint renovation and remodeling activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400392"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412458" joined="2012-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2012-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412452" joined="2012-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2012-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412433" joined="2012-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412464" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2012-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2012-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412475" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2012-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2012-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2012-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2012-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2012-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="409888" joined="2012-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412217" joined="2012-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2012-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2148"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2012--Introduced.
Lead Exposure Reduction Amendments Act of 2012 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA) to exclude from the definition of "abatement" any renovation, remodeling, or other activity: (1) the primary purpose of which is to repair, restore, or remodel target housing, public buildings constructed before 1978, or commercial buildings; and (2) that incidentally results in a reduction or elimination of lead-based paint hazards. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), no later than one year prior to proposing any renovation and remodeling regulation, to study the extent to which persons engaged in such activities: (1) are exposed to lead, and (2) disturb lead and create a lead-based paint hazard. Exempts from any such regulation an emergency renovation that is carried out in response to an event that is an act of God as defined by the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA), that presents a risk to the public health or safety, or that threatens to cause significant damage to equipment or property if not attended to immediately. Prohibits such a regulation from requiring post-abatement clearance testing. Requires the Administrator to promulgate regulations to permit an owner of a residential dwelling that is target housing, who resides in such dwelling, to authorize a contractor to forego compliance with such a regulation if the owner submits a certification stating that: (1) the renovation or remodeling project is to be carried out at such dwelling, (2) no pregnant woman or child under the age of six resides or will reside in such housing, and (3) the owner acknowledges that such contractor will be exempt from the requirements of such regulation. Prohibits the Administrator from holding a contractor responsible for a misrepresentation made by the owner of such dwelling unless the contractor has actual knowledge of such a misrepresentation. Requires the Administrator to: (1) recognize a qualifying test kit for use under such Act, and (2) suspend enforcement of any regulation relating to renovation and remodeling of target housing and commercial buildings constructed after January 1, 1960, and public buildings constructed between January 1, 1960, and January 1, 1978, until a specified period after the Administrator recognizes such a test kit.</summary>
</bill>
