<bill session="113" type="h" number="1617" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Jobs to Restore the American Dream Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To create an emergency jobs program that will fund 2,242,000 positions during fiscal years 2014 and 2015.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2013-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2013-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, Agriculture, the Judiciary, Science, Space, and Technology, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/2013--Introduced.
Emergency Jobs to Restore the American Dream Act - Requires the Secretary of Education to make grants to states for the modernization, renovation, or repair of public schools, including early learning facilities and charter schools, to make them safe, healthy, high-performing, and technologically up-to-date. Allocates grant funds among states on the basis of the relative portion of school improvement funds provided to local educational agencies (LEAs) in each state under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Reserves 2% of the grant funds for assistance to outlying areas and Indian schools. Reserves 5% of the grant funds for LEAs serving geographic areas: (1) with significant economic distress, (2) recovering from a natural disaster, or (3) containing a military installation selected for closure. Requires states to reallocate such grant funds to LEAs on the basis of each LEA's share of school improvement funds received by LEAs in the state for the previous fiscal year. Allows LEAs to give priority to projects involving the abatement, removal, or interim control of asbestos, polychlorinated biphenyls, mold, mildew, lead-based hazards, or a proven carcinogen. Requires the iron and steel used in projects funded under this Act to have been produced in the United States, subject to specified exceptions. Directs LEA grantees to use their grants for public school modernization, renovation, repairs, construction, or maintenance that meet the Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED) Green Building Rating System standards, Energy Star standards, Collaborative for High Performance Schools (CHPS) criteria, Green Building Initiative environmental design and rating standards (Green Globes), or equivalent standards adopted by the entities that have jurisdiction over such LEAs. Requires the Secretary to work with grant recipients to promote appropriate opportunities for individuals enrolled in YouthBuild, Job Corps, junior or community college, or preapprenticeship programs to gain employment experience on projects funded under this Act. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) grants to institutions of higher education to provide an additional 250,000 part-time work-study jobs; (2) creation of an additional 100,000 Public Lands Corps positions; (3) the retention, rehiring, and hiring of 300,000 education jobs; (4) grants to state, local, and Indian tribal governments to hire and rehire overall an additional 40,000 career law enforcement officers; and (5) the hiring and rehiring of an additional 12,000 firefighters. Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to eligible health care and long-term care (LTC) providers to hire and retain 40,000 health care and LTC professionals. Authorizes appropriations for state and local government units to establish a Community Corps to create an additional 750,000 jobs for unemployed individuals to carry out specified activities. Amends the Head Start Act to authorize appropriations to employ an additional 100,000 full-time infant and toddler Head Start specialists.</summary>
</bill>
