<bill session="113" type="h" number="2120" updated="2013-11-02T06:36:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Valley-Wide Noise Relief Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To allow mandatory nighttime curfews at certain airports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2013-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2013--Introduced.
Valley-Wide Noise Relief Act of 2013 - Permits an airport sponsor to implement a total mandatory nighttime curfew (no aircraft operations during the 9-hour period beginning at 10 p.m.) if it: (1) had a voluntary curfew in effect for certain aircraft on November 5, 1990; and (2) was created by an intergovernmental agreement established by a state statute enacted before that date that, along with the statute, imposes noise mitigation obligations. Permits the sponsor of an airport meeting other criteria to implement a partial mandatory nighttime curfew (no operations for certain aircraft for not longer than the 9-hour period beginning at 10 p.m.) if it: (1) had a partial curfew in effect before November 5, 1990; (2) operates under the supervision of a board of airport commissioners that, on January 1, 2010, oversaw operation of three or more airports, at least two of which have airport operating certificates; and (3) on January 1, 2010, failed to comply with a cumulative noise standard established by state law. Requires an airport sponsor to provide airport users and other interested parties reasonable notice of the terms of the curfew, including the penalties for curfew violations, no later than 90 days before its implementation.</summary>
</bill>
