<bill session="113" type="sr" number="184" updated="2013-11-02T06:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-24">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing refugee women and girls on World Refugee Day.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2013-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2013-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2013-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2013-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2013-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2013-06-24" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5098" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5027-5028" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2013--Introduced.
Supports the goals of World Refugee Day. Reaffirms the Senate's commitment to the protection, well-being, and self-reliance of refugee women and girls and their families in U.S. humanitarian policy, programs, and diplomacy and recognizes the work of the United States Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to this end. Reiterates the importance of targeted programs for refugee women and girls that prevent and respond to gender-based violence, support self-reliance, and promote leadership skills. Recognizes the work of the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration of the Department of State, the Office of Refugee Resettlement of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), nongovernmental organizations, advocacy groups, and communities across the United States in resettling refugees in the United States. Celebrates the contributions that refugee women and girls make to their families and communities.</summary>
</bill>
