<bill session="112" type="h" number="4381" updated="2013-07-20T01:47:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Planning for American Energy Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Planning for American Energy Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish goals for an all-of-the-above energy production plan strategy on a 4-year basis on all onshore Federal lands managed by the Department of the Interior and the Forest Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412405"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412478" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2012-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412393" joined="2012-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 14.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-06-15T12:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-530.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-06-15T12:32:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="378">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 378.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4480"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2012--Reported to House amended.
Planning for American Energy Act of 2012 - Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) and the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to publish every four years a Quadrennial Federal Onshore Energy Production Strategy to direct federal land energy development and department resource allocation in order to promote the energy security of the United States. Instructs the Secretary to consult with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration on the projected energy demands of the United States for the next 30 years and on how energy derived from federal onshore lands can put the United States on a trajectory that meets such demand during the next 4 years, with a goal for increasing energy independence and production. Requires the Secretary to determine a domestic strategic production objective for the development of energy resources from such lands. Expresses the sense of Congress that federally recognized Indian tribes may elect to set their own production objectives as part of the Strategy. Grants the relevant Secretary all necessary authority to make determinations regarding which additional federal lands available for leasing at the time the lease sale occurs will be available to meet the production objectives established by the strategies. Directs the Secretary to also take all necessary actions to achieve such objectives unless the President determines that it is not in U.S. national security and economic interests to increase federal domestic energy production and to further decrease dependence upon foreign energy sources. Requires the Secretary, within 12 months of this Act's enactment, to complete a programmatic environmental impact statement in accordance with certain requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA). Deems such statement sufficient to be in compliance with NEPA requirements for all necessary resource management and land use plans associated with implementation of the Strategy. Requires the Secretary to submit to: (1) the President and Congress, each proposed strategy, together with comments received from the affected states, federally recognized tribes, and local governments prior to publishing it; and (2) Congress the first Strategy within 18 months of enactment.</summary>
</bill>
