<bill session="109" type="hc" number="486" updated="2013-07-19T20:06:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress that the Government of Turkmenistan should take immediate steps to improve its respect for human rights and democratic practices, in keeping with its international commitments and obligations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2006-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2006-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2006-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1875"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Assassination"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Censorship"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Embezzlement"/>
    <term name="Emigration"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Normal trade relations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Opposition (Political science)"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Prison violence"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Psychiatric hospitals"/>
    <term name="Punishment"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Turkmenistan"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2006--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the government of Turkmenistan should: (1) release from prison and psychiatric institutions all prisoners of conscience and political prisoners, including Mukhametkuli Aimuradov, Sapardurdy Khajiev, Annakurba Amanklychev, Kakabai Tedjenov, Cheper Annaniyazova, and Nasrullah ibn Ibadullah; (2) provide the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) with access to all detained persons, including Batyr Berdyev and Boris Shikhmuradov; (3) investigate the death in custody of Ogulsapar Muradova; (4) provide fair retrials of those imprisoned for the alleged 2002 assassination attempt of President Niyazov; (5) provide independent investigations into allegations of torture, ill-treatment; and deaths in custody; (6) permit the normal functioning of opposition groups, independent nongovernmental groups; (7) cease the use of collective punishment, psychiatric hospitals, and house arrest of relatives and associates of perceived dissidents; (8) allow press and related freedoms; (9) end the diversion of state funds into President Niyazov's personal offshore accounts; (10) make educational reforms; (11) continue to discuss human rights and democratization in Turkmenistan and; and (12) support increased Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) activities in Turkmenistan. Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should consider: (1) appropriate responses if the government of Turkmenistan continues to ban peaceful independent political party participation in the upcoming December elections; (2) designating Turkmenistan a "country of particular concern;" (3) withholding Turkmenistan's waiver under the Jackson-Vanik amendment until the right to freedom of movement is ensured; (4) encouraging companies which transport Turkmen gas to account for revenues and make public the identities of all their shareholders and beneficiaries; (5) raising with the European Union (EU), as well as transit and purchasing countries, the importance of not entering into trade agreements with Turkmenistan until the government demonstrates a commitment to implementing basic norms of fiscal transparency; (6) issuing a report on the personal assets and wealth of President Niyazov; and (7) working with other U.N. member states to introduce a resolution denouncing human rights violations in Turkmenistan.</summary>
</bill>
