<bill session="112" type="s" number="618" updated="2013-07-20T02:21:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Egyptian-American Enterprise Fund Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Tunisian-American Enterprise Fund Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Egyptian-American Enterprise Fund Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Tunisian-American Enterprise Fund Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote the strengthening of the private sector in Egypt and Tunisia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-05-17">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 112-25.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-06-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="79">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 79.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2237"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tunisia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2011--Reported to Senate amended.
Title I: Egyptian-American Enterprise Fund - Egyptian-American Enterprise Fund Act - Authorizes the President to establish or designate a private, nonprofit organization (the Egyptian-American Enterprise Fund) to promote: (1) the Egyptian private sector and joint U.S.-Egyptain ventures, (2) good corporate governance and transparency in Egypt, and (3) security through job creation and the creation of an Egyptian middle class. Title II: Tunisian-American Enterprise Fund - Tunisian-American Enterprise Fund Act - Authorizes the President to establish or designate a private, nonprofit organization (the Tunisian-American Enterprise Fund) to promote: (1) the Tunisian private sector and U.S.-Tunisian joint ventures, (2) good corporate governance and transparency in Tunisia, and (3) security through job creation and the creation of a Tunisian middle class. Authorizes the President to make grants to carry out a Fund's purposes provided that the Fund agrees to: (1) end its reinvestment cycle not later than December 31, 2021, unless the Secretary of State determines that the Fund should be extended; (2) ensure that grant funds are not provided to or through any individual, private or government entity, or educational institution that advocates, or engages or has engaged in money laundering or terrorist activity; or (3) return any remaining funds to the the U.S. Treasury to be used to reduce U.S. debt. Sets forth reporting requirements. States that the Funds' Boards of Directors should adopt the best practices and procedures used by Enterprise Funds, including those for which funding has been made available pursuant to the Support for East European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989.</summary>
</bill>
