<bill session="109" type="s" number="3488" updated="2013-07-19T20:43:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tax-Free Healthcare Savings, Access, and Portability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue code of 1986 to expand the permissible use of health savings accounts to include health insurance payments, to increase the dollar limitation for contributions to health savings accounts, to allow the rollover of unused funds from health reimbursement arrangements to health savings accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2006-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2006-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2006-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2006-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance portability"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2006--Introduced.
Tax-Free Healthcare Savings, Access, and Portability Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow premiums for high deductible health insurance coverage to be paid from health savings accounts; (2) increase the contribution limits for such accounts; (3) permit rollovers to health savings accounts from health reimbursement arrangements; (4) exempt employers from health savings account contribution requirements in the case of certain acutely or chronically ill employees; (5) allow a new tax deduction for premiums paid for high deductible health insurance coverage; (6) allow a tax credit for employment taxes paid with respect to premiums for high deductible health plans and contributions to health savings accounts; and (7) provide tax incentives for health saving account insurance portability.</summary>
</bill>
