<bill session="113" type="h" number="651" updated="2013-11-02T06:24:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Refugee Resettlement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify provisions of law relating to refugee resettlement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2013-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration And Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2013--Introduced.
Strengthening Refugee Resettlement Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to work with the heads of other relevant federal agencies to conduct a review of refugee processing with the goal of streamlining processing, consistent with maintaining security. Directs the Secretary of State (Secretary) to establish overseas refugee English language and work orientation training programs prior to the departure for the United States of refugees who have been approved for U.S. admission. Permits: (1) refugees (and their spouses and children) to be admitted to the United States as lawful permanent residents, and (2) asylum seekers (and their spouses and children) to be granted lawful permanent residency. Directs the Secretary when setting the amount of reception and placement grants to: (1) adjust the grant amount to account for anticipated initial refugee resettlement needs, and (2) ensure that funding is provided to national resettlement agencies at the beginning of the fiscal year. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the President should appoint a White House Coordinator on Refugee Protection. Requires the Director of the Office of Refugee Resettlement (Director) to make grants to national resettlement agencies to operate a case management system to assist individuals access eligible services, benefits, and assistance provided by the Office, federal, state, or local agencies, and private or nonprofit organizations. Requires the Office, subject to available appropriations, to provide refugees with a minimum of 12 months' assistance and social services for employment, health, and living expenses. Authorizes the Director to award grants to community-based organizations, nonprofit organizations, and resettlement agencies for programs to assist newcomers integrate into U.S. civic life. Expands eligibility for, and participation in, the refugee matching grant program (federal-private refugee assistance). Establishes a Domestic Emergency Refugee Resettlement Fund to meet unanticipated refugee resettlement needs. Makes SSI (supplemental security income) benefits available to qualified aliens, U-visa aliens (victim of criminal activity), or certain T-visa aliens (victims of trafficking in persons) who were ineligible for such benefits because of their failure to acquire citizenship within seven years. Makes a child who has been granted special immigrant status as a victim of criminal activity (U-visa) eligible for specified refugee benefits.</summary>
</bill>
