<bill session="111" type="h" number="4507" updated="2013-07-19T23:53:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cyber Security Domestic Preparedness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish the Cyber Security Domestic Preparedness Consortium, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400339"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2010-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM08" subcommittee="Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM12" subcommittee="Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2010--Introduced.
Cyber Security Domestic Preparedness Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish the Cyber Security Domestic Preparedness Consortium to: (1) provide training to state and local first responders and officials specifically for preparing and responding to cyber security attacks; (2) develop and update a curriculum and training model; (3) provide technical assistance services to build and sustain capabilities in support of cyber security preparedness and response; and (4) conduct cyber security training and simulation exercises to defend against and respond to cyber attacks. Authorizes the Secretary to establish a Cyber Security Training Center to provide training courses and other resources for state and local first responders and officials to improve preparedness and response capabilities.</summary>
</bill>
