<bill session="111" type="s" number="1767" updated="2013-07-20T00:39:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Blue Ridge Parkway and Town of Blowing Rock Land Exchange Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize a land exchange to acquire land for the Blue Ridge Parkway from the Town of Blowing Rock, North Carolina, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2009-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-282.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1121"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2009--Introduced.
Blue Ridge Parkway and Town of Blowing Rock Land Exchange Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to exchange approximately 20 acres of land within the boundary of the Blue Ridge Parkway, identified as Blowing Rock Reservoir, for approximately 192 acres of land owned by the town of Blowing Rock, North Carolina. Permits the equalization of the values of the lands proposed for exchange to be achieved by an adjustment to their acreage if they are found to be not equal in value. Requires the lands acquired by the Secretary through the exchange to be administered as part of the Parkway. Grants the Secretary, if the town wants to dispose of the reservoir property, the right of first refusal to acquire that property for the Parkway.</summary>
</bill>
