<bill session="111" type="h" number="5700" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Service Member Second Amendment Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect the rights under the Second Amendment to the Constitution of the United States of members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense by prohibiting the Department of Defense from requiring the registration of privately owned firearms, ammunition, or other weapons not stored in facilities owned or operated by the Department of Defense, and by prohibiting the Department of Defense from infringing on the right of individuals to lawfully acquire, possess, own, carry, or otherwise use privately owned firearms, ammunition, or other weapons on property not owned or operated by the Department of Defense.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400284"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3388"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/2010--Introduced.
Service Member Second Amendment Protection Act of 2010 - Prohibits the Secretary of Defense (DOD) from prohibiting, issuing any requirement relating to, or collecting or recording any information relating to the otherwise lawful acquisition, possession, ownership, carrying, or other use of a privately-owned firearm, privately-owned ammunition, or another privately-owned weapon by a member of the Armed Forces or a DOD civilian employee on property that is not owned or operated by DOD. Nullifies any existing DOD regulation promulgated prior to enactment of this Act that restricts weapon ownership or use in violation of this Act. Requires the destruction of any record containing information about weapon ownership or use that was collected prior to enactment of this Act. Provides that nothing in this Act limits the authority of the Secretary to: (1) regulate the possession, carrying, or other use of a firearm, ammunition, or other weapon by a member of the Armed Forces or by a DOD civilian employee while engaged in official duties or while wearing the uniform of an Armed Force; or (2) create or maintain records relating to an investigation, prosecution, or adjudication of any alleged violation of law.</summary>
</bill>
