<bill session="110" type="s" number="646" updated="2013-07-19T22:25:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Nursing Promotion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to increase the nursing workforce.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2000-2002"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2088" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Emigration"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Physical therapy"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2007--Introduced.
Rural Nursing Promotion Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a Nurse Distance Education Pilot Program through which grants may be awarded for activities to increase accessibility to nursing education in order to: (1) provide assistance to individuals in rural areas who want to study nursing to enable such individuals to receive appropriate nursing education; (2) promote the study of nursing at all educational levels; (3) establish additional slots for nursing students at existing nursing education programs; and (4) establish new nursing education programs at institutions of higher education.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) report to Congress on the source of newly licensed nurses and physical therapists in each state; (2) contract with the National Academy of Sciences Institute of Medicine to determine the necessary level of federal investment under the Public Health Service Act to eliminate the domestic nursing and physical therapist shortage; and (3) collaborate with other agencies in working with the five countries from which the most nurses and physical therapists arrived to address health worker shortages caused by emigration.Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to exempt aliens seeking U.S. entry to perform labor in shortage occupations from worldwide and per-country numerical limitations through September 30, 2017. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide for a process to review and make a determination upon a petition filed for immigrant status for such an alien within 30 days.</summary>
</bill>
