<bill session="109" type="s" number="2002" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">BSE and Other Prior Disease Prevention and Public Health Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide protection against bovine spongiform encephalopathy and other prion diseases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2005-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12767-12768"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12768-12770" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural estimating and reporting"/>
    <term name="Agricultural industries"/>
    <term name="Agricultural wastes"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Blood"/>
    <term name="Bovine spongiform encephalopathy"/>
    <term name="Cattle"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Deer"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elk"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fur trade"/>
    <term name="Goats"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat inspection"/>
    <term name="Meat packing industry"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Proteins"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sheep"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/14/2005--Introduced.
BSE and Other Prion Disease Prevention and Public Health Protection Act - Prohibits the importation of a covered article that: (1) if containing animal-derived material, does not state in English that the covered article contains animal-derived material and the name of the derivative animal, and if a ruminant, identifies the country of origin and states whether specified risk material from the ruminant is or may be part of the covered article; (2) if not containing animal-derived material, does not state in English that the covered article does not contain animal-derived material; and (3) contains animal-derived material from a ruminant that was in any country at a time at which there was a transmission risk of bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE). Prohibits the introduction into interstate or foreign commerce of a covered article that contains: (1) specified risk material from a ruminant, or any material from a ruminant that was in any foreign country when there was a BSE transmission risk; or (2) any material from a ruminant exhibiting signs of a neurological disease. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) develop an enforcement plan for the regulatory ban of certain animal proteins in ruminant feed; (2) promulgate regulations prohibiting same-farm admixing of ruminant and nonruminant feed; (3) in conjunction with the National Prion Disease Pathology Research Center at Case Western Reserve University, expand survey efforts for prion diseases in humans; and (4) monitor animal feed and provide for the registration of certain animal feed businesses. Directs the Secretary to accelerate the establishment of a ruminant identification program capable of tracing, within 48 hours, the movements of disease-exposed animals from birth to slaughter. Directs the Secretaries to: (1) jointly establish a prion disease task force; and (2) develop appropriate compliance standards. Defines: (1) covered article; (2) prion disease; and (3) specified risk material.</summary>
</bill>
