<bill session="113" type="h" number="143" updated="2013-11-02T06:20:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lead By Example Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide that matching contributions to the Thrift Savings Fund for Members of Congress be made contingent on Congress completing action on a concurrent resolution on the budget, for the fiscal year involved, which reduces the deficit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412483"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/3/2013--Introduced.
Lead By Example Act - Prohibits matching contributions to the Thrift Savings Fund for Members of Congress: (1) for any pay period beginning before the date on which Congress completes action on a budget resolution for the fiscal year in which the first day of such pay period occurs, and (2) unless the deficit for such fiscal year (as set forth in the budget resolution) is less than the deficit for the preceding fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
