<bill session="109" type="h" number="471" updated="2013-07-19T19:08:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the frequency of disclosure of information by political organizations and to improve the linkage between databases for public disclosure of election-related information maintained by the Department of the Treasury and the Federal Election Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400233"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise disclosure requirements for tax-exempt political organizations. Requires such an organization to make monthly reports in any election year in which it accepts contributions or makes expenditures of $25,000 or more. Requires quarterly reports for organizations with less than $25,000 in contributions or expenditures, but requires a change to monthly reporting upon receipt of contributions in excess of $25,000 or the making of expenditures greater than $25,000. Requires: (1) pre-election and post-election reports; and (2) semiannual reports in years in which a regularly scheduled election is not held. Requires: (1) the Secretary of the Treasury to take actions to increase disclosure to the public of tax-exempt political organization reporting; and (2) the Secretary and the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to take actions to improve the linkage between the databases for public disclosure of election related information maintained by the Department of the Treasury and the FEC.</summary>
</bill>
