<bill session="109" type="h" number="426" updated="2013-07-19T19:08:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-27T19:26:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-06-27T19:26:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Remote Sensing Applications Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Remote Sensing Applications Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage the development and integrated use by the public and private sectors of remote sensing and other geospatial information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="2005-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E94"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27T19:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 109-157.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-06-27T19:26:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="95">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 95.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban growth"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2005--Reported to House amended.
Remote Sensing Applications Act of 2005 - (Sec. 4) Directs the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to establish a program of grants for pilot projects to explore the integrated use of sources of remote sensing and other geospatial information to address State, local, regional, and tribal agency needs. Requires the Administrator, in awarding grants, to give preference to specified types of projects. Requires the Administrator to seek opportunities to assist: (1) in the development of commercial applications potentially available from the remote sensing industry; and (2) State, local, regional, and tribal agencies in applying remote sensing and geospatial information technologies for growth management. Limits the provision of assistance for a project to three years. Requires each grant recipient to: (1) report project results to the Administrator; and (2) conduct at least one workshop for potential users to disseminate the lessons learned from the project. (Sec. 5) Requires the Administrator to establish an advisory committee to monitor the program. Instructs the advisory committee to consult with the Federal Geographic Data Committee and other industry representatives and organizations. Requires the Administrator to transmit to Congress an independent evaluation of program effectiveness. (Sec. 6) Directs the Administrator to ensure that project results are retrievable through an Internet-accessible database. (Sec. 7) Requires the Administrator to establish an educational outreach program to increase awareness at institutions of higher education and State, local, regional, and tribal agencies of the potential applications of remote sensing and geospatial information. (Sec. 8) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
