<bill session="110" type="s" number="744" updated="2013-07-19T22:26:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAVE LIVES Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Spectrum Availability for Emergency-Response and Law-Enforcement to Improve Vital Emergency Services Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide greater public safety by making more spectrum available to public safety, to establish the Public Safety Interoperable Communications Working Group to provide standards for public safety spectrum needs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2512-2514"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2007--Introduced.
Spectrum Availability for Emergency-Response and Law-Enforcement to Improve Vital Emergency Services Act or the SAVE LIVES Act - Establishes the Public Safety Interoperable Communications Working Group to provide continuing advice to the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) and the Department of Homeland Security regarding public safety interoperable communications. Declares that the 24 MHz band of spectrum allocated to public safety services should be used by state, local, and regional public safety organizations for interoperable voice and data communications. Requires the FCC to complete a specified Notice of Proposed Rulemaking regarding the 700MHz Band and issue rules allowing certain channels within the current 24 MHz band of public safety spectrum to accommodate data communications. Requires the FCC to issue a notice of proposed rulemaking regarding the allocation for auction of the 30MHz band of recovered analog spectrum and establish specifications for a national public safety broadband network. Establishes the Public Safety Broadband Trust Corporation and requires, if no bidder is successful, granting it a license for the use of such spectrum. Specifies Corporation duties, including facilitating development of such network. Authorizes the FCC to enter into an agreement with the Corporation to guarantee loans to the Corporation. Pledges the full faith and credit of the United States for principal and interest.</summary>
</bill>
