<bill session="112" type="s" number="3517" updated="2013-07-20T02:47:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Panama-Pacific International Exposition and Panama Canal Commemorative Coins Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in commemoration of the centennial of the Panama-Pacific International Exposition and the Panama Canal.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="6331"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Panama Canal"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
Panama-Pacific International Exposition and Panama Canal Commemorative Coins Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to mint and issue, in commemoration of the centennial of the Panama-Pacific International Exposition and the Panama Canal: (1) $5 octagonal gold coins, (2) $5 round gold coins, (3) $1 silver coins, and (4) half-dollar clad coins. Requires the design of such coins to be a close likeness of the two gold and one half-dollar coins issued by the San Francisco Mint at the opening of the Pan-Pacific Exposition and the medal awarded to every U.S. citizen who worked for a continuous two-year period on the construction of the Panama Canal. Restricts the issuance of such coins to the one-year period beginning on January 1, 2015. Prescribes the sale price of the coins and coin surcharges. Requires such surcharges to be distributed to: (1) the San Francisco Museum and Historical Society for the design and construction of appropriate exhibitions in the San Francisco Museum and Historical Society; and (2) the National Park Foundation to be used for programs, construction, or preservation work at President Theodore Roosevelt's home in Oyster Bay, New York.</summary>
</bill>
