<bill session="109" type="h" number="841" updated="2013-07-19T19:11:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-03T14:39:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-03-03T14:39:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Special Elections/Appointments Provisions bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Continuity in Representation Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Continuity in Representation Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Continuity in Representation Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require States to hold special elections to fill vacancies in the House of Representatives not later than 45 days after the vacancy is announced by the Speaker of the House of Representatives in extraordinary circumstances, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To require States to hold special elections to fill vacancies in the House of Representatives not later than 49 days after the vacancy is announced by the Speaker of the House of Representatives in extraordinary circumstances.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2005-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2005-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2005-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="2005-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2005-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2005-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17T13:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Ney asked unanimous consent that the Committee on House Administration have until midnight on Feb. 24 to file a report on H.R. 841. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-24T18:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on 109-8, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-24">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than Feb. 24, 2005.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-24T18:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-02-24T18:20:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="3">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 3.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-03-01T20:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 125 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 841 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T11:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 125 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T11:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 125.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H953-970" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H959" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T11:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 841 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T11:16:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 125 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T11:16:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steven C. LaTourette to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T11:16:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 60 minutes of general debate on H.R. 841.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T12:02:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 125, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ney amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T12:12:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 125, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Millender-McDonald amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T12:35:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Millender-McDonald amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Millender-McDonald demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment were postponed until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T12:37:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 125, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T12:45:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson-Lee (TX) demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment were postponed until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T12:46:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T13:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Baird moved to strike the enacting clause.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T13:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to strike the enacting clause.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T13:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to strike the enacting clause withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T13:29:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 841.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T13:30:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T13:30:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T13:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Conyers moved to recommit with instructions to House Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H967-969" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T13:31:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Conyers motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment which adds a new paragraph with provisions for minimum required voting systems and poll workers in polling places used in special elections.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T13:43:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 196 - 223 (Roll no. 51).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>On passage. Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T14:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T14:10:00-05:00">
      <text>PROCEEDINGS VACATED - By unanimous consent, the proceedings by which the motion to reconsider was laid on the table were vacated and the Chair restated the question on adoption of the bill. Subsequently, Ms. Millender-McDonald demanded a recorded vote on the question of passage of the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-03-03T14:39:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="52" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 329 - 68 (Roll no. 52).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T14:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03T14:40:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-03-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="61">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 61.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="125"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Soldier voting"/>
    <term name="Special elections"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h17"/>
    <amendment number="h18"/>
    <amendment number="h19"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/3/2005--Passed House amended.
Continuity in Representation Act of 2005 - (Sec. 2) Amends Federal law concerning the election of Senators and Representatives to require States to hold special elections for the House of Representatives within 49 days after a vacancy is announced by the Speaker of the House in the extraordinary circumstance that vacancies in representation from the States exceed 100. Waives the 49-day requirement if, during the 75-day period beginning on the date of the vacancy announcement, a regularly scheduled general election or another special election for the office involved is to be held. Requires determination of the candidates who will run in the special election: (1) not later than ten days after the vacancy announcement by the political parties authorized by State law to nominate candidates; or (2) by any other method the State considers appropriate. Sets forth requirements for judicial review of any action brought for declaratory or injunctive relief to challenge such a vacancy announcement. Requires a final decision within three days of the filing of such an action. Makes a final decision non-reviewable. Requires a State, in conducting a special election under this Act, to ensure to the greatest extent practicable (including through the use of electronic means) that absentee ballots are transmitted to absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters not later than 15 days after the Speaker of the House announces that the vacancy exists. Requires a State to accept and process any otherwise valid ballot or other election material from an absent uniformed services voter or an overseas voter, as long as the ballot or other material is received by the appropriate State election official not later than 45 days after the State transmits it to the voter. Applies this Act to the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, and the U.S. Virgin Islands.</summary>
</bill>
