<bill session="112" type="hr" number="631" updated="2013-07-20T01:08:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-26T14:15:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-04-26T14:15:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3523) to provide for the sharing of certain cyber threat intelligence and cyber threat information between the intelligence community and cyber security entities, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4628) to extend student loan interest rates for undergraduate Federal Direct Stafford Loans; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-25T19:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-454, by Mr. Nugent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-25T19:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. The rule makes in order as original text for purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 112-20 and provides that it shall be considered as read. The rule waives all points of order against the amendment in the nature of a substitute. The rule makes in order only those amendments printed in the Rules Committee report. The rule further provides that it shall be in order at any time through the legislative day of April 27, 2012, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules. The rule provides further for a closed rule for consideration of H.R. 4628. The rule provides one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit. Finally, the rule provides that the Committee on Appropriations may, at any time before 6 p.m. on Wednesday, May 2, 2012 recommit. Finally, the rule provides that the Committee on Appropriations may, at any time before 6 p.m. on Wednesday, May 2, 2012 file, privileged reports to accompany measures making appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2013.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-04-25T19:46:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="127">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 127.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26T12:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2147-2156" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26T12:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 631.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26T14:06:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 179 (Roll no. 182).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2155" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-04-26T14:15:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="183" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 236 - 185 (Roll no. 183).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2147" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26T14:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="3523"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4628"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2012--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3523) to provide for the sharing of certain cyber threat intelligence and cyber threat information between the intelligence community and cyber security entities, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4628) to extend student loan interest rates for undergraduate Federal Direct Stafford Loans.</summary>
</bill>
