<bill session="111" type="h" number="2029" updated="2013-07-19T23:29:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Marine Mammal Research Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Marine Mammal Commission to establish a national research program to fund basic and applied research on marine mammals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Marine Mammal Commission"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/2009--Introduced.
National Marine Mammal Research Program Act of 2009 - Amends the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to require the Marine Mammal Commission to establish the National Marine Mammal Research Program and a National Marine Mammal Research Program Office for the Research Program. Includes in the Program's purposes: (1) undertaking research on marine mammals, the factors that affect their populations and habitats, and related mitigation; and (2) coordinating and strengthening scientific research by developing partnerships among federal agencies, academia, industry, and other members of the oceanographic and marine mammal scientific communities. Authorizes the Commission to enter into contracts, make grants, or enter other arrangements as necessary to carry out the Program. Directs the President to create a National Marine Mammal Research Coordinating Committee, including in its duties: (1) developing a national marine mammal research plan; and (2) seeking to enter into an agreement with the National Research Council to periodically evaluate the scientific content of the plan and the implementation of research conducted under the Program.</summary>
</bill>
