<bill session="111" type="h" number="3629" updated="2013-07-19T23:44:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Borderlands Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to develop and implement a mitigation plan to address the ecological impacts of border security measures and activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400339"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-22">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-22">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2009--Introduced.
Healthy Borderlands Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to develop and implement a comprehensive mitigation plan to address the ecological and environmental impacts of border security infrastructure, measures, and activities along the international land borders of the United States. Requires the plan to include measures to address and mitigate the full range of such impacts, including: (1) preserving, maintaining, and restoring wildlife migration corridors, key habitats, and the ecologically functional connectivity among key habitats sufficient to ensure that species remain viable and are able to adapt to the impacts of climate change; (2) addressing control of invasive species; (3) maintaining hydrological functionality; and (5) protection of cultural and historical resources. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out the plan on any federal, state, private, or tribal lands, provided that activities are carried out in full consultation with, and with the concurrence of, the owner or entity with principal responsibility for the management of such lands. Authorizes the Secretary to transfer funds of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to other federal agencies for: (1) expenditure under programs of such agencies that are designed to fund conservation-related activities on nonfederal lands; and (2) mitigation activities on federal lands managed by such agencies.</summary>
</bill>
