<bill session="111" type="h" number="3300" updated="2013-07-19T23:41:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Derivative Trading Accountability and Disclosure Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide increased transparency and regulatory requirements for the trading of certain derivative financial instruments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412296"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412264" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400631" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412288" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412332" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412192" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2009-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG16" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities and Risk Management" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2009--Introduced.
Derivative Trading Accountability and Disclosure Act - Establishes within the Department of the Treasury the Office of Derivatives Supervision (Office) to: (1) implement this Act and oversee the registration of derivatives traders; (2) coordinate with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) in developing comprehensive, standardized regulations for derivatives transactions; and (3) facilitate information exchange among specified agencies regarding the development of derivatives regulations. Makes it unlawful for any unregistered derivatives trader to make use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce to effect any transactions in, or to induce or attempt to induce the purchase or sale of any type of derivative. Prescribes registration requirements for derivatives traders. Grants the SEC and CFTC authority to: (1) issue separate proposed regulations imposing specified requirements governing trading in the derivative instruments over which each Commission has jurisdiction; (2) impose civil penalties; (3) issue cease and desist orders; and (4) order an accounting and disgorgement. Requires the Office to invite representatives of the SEC, the CFTC, regulators of domestic and foreign boards of trade, and other experts, to participate in a working group of international regulators to review international standards in order to evaluate international regulations regarding harmonization of substantive commodities and securities regulation for economically equivalent instruments.</summary>
</bill>
