<bill session="109" type="h" number="5678" updated="2013-07-19T19:54:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pipeline Safety and Reliability Improvement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for enhanced safety and environmental protection in pipeline transportation, to provide for enhanced reliability in the transportation of the Nation's energy products by pipeline, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2006-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-03">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Environmental Quality, Interior, Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman .</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5782"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy shortages"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excavation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Geographic information systems"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Liquefied natural gas"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2006--Introduced.
Pipeline Safety and Reliability Improvement Act of 2006 - Amends federal transportation law to revise certain one-call notification system minimum requirements to subject to certain civil and criminal penalties any person who: (1) excavates without first using the one-call notification system to establish the location of underground pipelines; (2) disregards pipeline location information or markings; or (3) fails to take reasonable steps to prevent pipeline damage during excavation. Requires state damage prevention programs to subject persons who violate program requirements to certain civil penalties and other enforcement actions. Requires a state that has an annual pipeline safety program certification, or a pipeline safety agreement, to have a qualified damage prevention program in order to qualify for a grant to improve its damage prevention program. Authorizes such grants to states that take action to remedy a pipeline safety-related condition that has been ordered to be corrected. Makes technology development grants to eligible organizations to prevent pipeline damage caused by excavation activities. Urges the streamlining of state and local government permitting procedures for pipeline repair projects (current law) and hazardous liquid pipeline construction projects. Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) participate in international forums that establish or recommend mandatory standards for transporting gas and hazardous liquids by pipeline in international commerce; and (2) provide assistance to domestic and international organizations to reduce or eliminate inconsistent requirements that inhibit the safety of pipeline transportation in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce. Authorizes the Secretary to conduct analyses of the domestic transport capacity of petroleum products by pipeline.</summary>
</bill>
