<bill session="111" type="h" number="1035" updated="2013-07-19T23:21:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-23">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Amendments Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Amendments Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Amendments Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental and Native American Public Policy Act of 1992 to honor the legacy of Stewart L. Udall, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412188" joined="2009-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2009-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412187" joined="2009-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2009-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2009-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E258"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8834-8836" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1035.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27T16:04:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Cassidy objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-28T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8935" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-07-28T18:14:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/27/2009 H8834" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-28T18:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-23">
      <text>Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-23">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9757" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2009-09-23" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9757" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-09-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07T18:14:00-04:00">
      <text>House agreed to Senate amendment with an amendment pursuant to H.Res. 806.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="806"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="806"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="432"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1818"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2546"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/23/2009--Passed Senate amended.
Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Amendments Act of 2009 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental and Native American Public Policy Act of 1992 to rename the Act as the Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Foundation Act. (Sec. 3) Adds to the Act's findings to salute Stewart L. Udall's leadership in environmental and Native American policy as a member of Congress, Secretary of the Interior, environmental lawyer, and author. (Sec. 5) Renames the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation as the Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Foundation. Requires the Executive Director of the Foundation to be paid at a senior executive rate. (Sec. 6) Directs the Foundation to award grants to the Udall Center for Studies in Public Policy, at the University of Arizona, to conduct training, research, and other activities with regard to the involvement of Native American and Alaska Native professionals in health care and public policy. Refers to recipients of scholarships, fellowships, and internships under the Act as Udall Scholars, Udall Fellows, and Udall Interns, respectively. (Currently, they are known as Morris K. Udall Scholars.) (Sec. 7) Renames the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Trust Fund, the Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Trust Fund. Allows the use of reasonable amounts of the Trust Fund for official reception and representation expenses, not to exceed $5,000 for a fiscal year. (Sec. 9) Declares that the use of the Foundation or the United States Institute for Environmental Conflict Resolution for independent and impartial assessment, mediation, or other related services in connection with a dispute or conflict related to the environment, public lands, or natural resources shall not be considered the establishment or use of an advisory committee within the meaning of the Federal Advisory Committee Act. (Sec. 10) Sets forth administrative provisions that allow the Foundation to: (1) appoint personnel without regard to federal law provisions governing appointments in the competitive service; (2) pay up to four employees, in addition to the Executive Director, at senior executive pay rates; and (3) rent office space in the District of Columbia or its environs.</summary>
</bill>
