<bill session="111" type="s" number="3575" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National All Schedules Prescription Electronic Reporting Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend and reauthorize the controlled substance monitoring program under section 399O of the Public Health Service Act and to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to share information about the use of controlled substances by veterans with State prescription monitoring programs to prevent misuse and diversion of prescription medicines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2010-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5791"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5791-5792" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5710"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2010--Introduced.
National All Schedules Prescription Electronic Reporting Reauthorization Act of 2010 - Amends the National All Schedules Prescription Electronic Reporting Act of 2005 to include as a purpose of such Act to foster the establishment of state-administered controlled substance monitoring systems in order to ensure that appropriate law enforcement, regulatory, and state professional licensing authorities have access to prescription history information for the purposes of investigating drug diversion and prescribing and dispensing practices of errant prescribers or pharmacists. Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise and update the controlled substance monitoring program, including to: (1) allow grants to be used to maintain and operate existing state controlled substance monitoring programs; (2) require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to redistribute any funds that are returned among the remaining grantees; (3) require a state that is not in compliance with the requirements for such program to submit a plan for bringing the state into compliance; and (4) require a state to provide the Secretary with aggregate data and other information to enable the Secretary to evaluate the success of the state's program and to submit a progress report to Congress. Requires a state receiving a grant to: (1) facilitate prescriber use of the state's controlled substance monitoring system; and (2) educate prescribers on the benefits of the system both to them and society. Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to disclose information about a veteran or the dependent of a veteran to a state controlled substance monitoring program to the extent necessary to prevent misuse and diversion of prescription medicines.</summary>
</bill>
