<bill session="113" type="h" number="1208" updated="2013-11-02T06:29:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Manhattan Project National Historical Park Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Manhattan Project National Historical Park Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Manhattan Project National Historical Park in Oak Ridge, Tennessee, Los Alamos, New Mexico, and Hanford, Washington, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412476" joined="2013-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2013-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-66.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-17T14:46:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="42">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 42.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2013--Reported to House without amendment.
Manhattan Project National Historical Park Act - (Sec. 5) Establishes the Manhattan Project National Historical Park as a unit of the National Park System, which may be composed of specified facilities, lands, or interests in one or more eligible areas or parts of such areas in Oak Ridge, Tennessee; Los Alamos, New Mexico; and Hanford, Washington. Requires inclusion of the B Reactor National Historic Landmark in Hanford. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) and the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to enter into an agreement to govern their respective roles in administering the facilities, lands, or interests in land under the DOE's jurisdiction to be included in the Park. (Sec. 7) Requires the Secretary to consult with interested state, county, and local officials, and members of the public before executing any such agreement and in developing the general management plan. Adds to the Park lands, interests in land, or facilities within the eligible areas which are acquired by the Secretary or are included in an amendment to the agreement. (Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary to develop a general management plan for the Park in consultation and collaboration with the Oak Ridge, Los Alamos, and Richland DOE site offices. Authorizes the Secretary to provide interpretive tours of historically significant Manhattan Project sites and resources that are located outside the boundary of the Park. Prohibits the acquisition by condemnation of any land or interest in land under, or for the purposes of, this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into agreements with federal agencies to provide public access to, and management, interpretation, and historic preservation of, historically significant Manhattan Project resources under their control; and (2) accept donations from, and enter into cooperative agreements with, state, local, and tribal governments, organizations, or individuals to further the purpose of such an interagency agreement or to provide visitor services and administrative facilities within proximity to the Park. Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance for the management, interpretation, and historic preservation of historically significant Manhattan Project resources not included in the Park. (Sec. 9) Prohibits anything in this Act, the establishment of the Park, or the management plan from being construed as creating buffer zones outside of the Park. Prohibits anything in this Act from constituting a cause of action respecting activities outside or adjacent to the established boundary of the Park.</summary>
</bill>
