<bill session="113" type="s" number="170" updated="2013-11-02T06:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Recreational Fishing and Hunting Heritage and Opportunities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to recognize the heritage of recreational fishing, hunting, and recreational shooting on Federal public land and ensure continued opportunities for those activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2013-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2013-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2013-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2013-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S367"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1825"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3197"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1335"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/29/2013--Introduced.
Recreational Fishing and Hunting Heritage and Opportunities Act - Requires a federal public land management official, in cooperation with the respective state and fish and wildlife agency, to exercise the authority of the official under law, including regarding land use planning, to facilitate the use of, and access to, federal public land for hunting, recreational fishing, and recreational shooting, except as described in this Act. Requires the heads of federal public land management agencies to exercise their discretion in a manner that supports and facilitates hunting, recreational fishing, and recreational shooting opportunities, to the extent authorized under applicable law. Requires that Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and Forest Service land, excluding land on the Outer Continental Shelf, be open to hunting, recreational fishing, or recreational shooting unless the managing agency acts to close lands to such activity. Permits closures or restrictions on such land for purposes including resource conservation, public safety, energy or mineral production, energy generation or transmission infrastructure, water supply facilities, national security, or compliance with other law. Allows agencies to: (1) lease or permit use of federal public land for recreational shooting ranges, and (2) designate specific land for recreational shooting activities. Excepts from such use or designation land including a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System, land designated as a wilderness study area or administratively classified as wilderness eligible or suitable, and primitive or semiprimitive areas. Requires annual reports on closures of federal public lands to hunting, recreational fishing, or recreational shooting. Sets forth requirements for specified closures or significant restrictions involving 1280 or more contiguous acres of federal public land or water to hunting or recreational fishing or related activities. Instructs federal public land agencies to consult with the advisory councils specified in Executive Orders 12962 (relating to recreational fisheries) and 13443 (relating to the facilitation of hunting heritage and wildlife conservation) in carrying out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
