<bill session="109" type="h" number="423" updated="2013-07-19T19:08:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeland Infrastructure Power Security and Assurance Incentives Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Energy to establish an Advanced Power System Technology Incentives Program to fund the development and deployment of new advanced technologies such as advanced fuel cells, turbines, or hybrid power systems or power storage systems to generate or store electric energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400400"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2005-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Energy storage"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="High technology"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2005--Introduced.
Homeland Infrastructure Power Security and Assurance Incentives Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Secretary of Energy to establish an Advanced Power System Technology Incentive Program of incentive payments to eligible owners or operators to: (1) support deployment of new advanced power system technologies such as fuel cells, turbines, hybrid, and storage system power technologies; and (2) improve and protect certain critical governmental, industrial, and commercial processes. Requires such funding to be used to increase power generation through enhanced operational, economic, and environmental performance.</summary>
</bill>
