<bill session="111" type="s" number="703" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Health Security Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for health care for every American and to control the cost and enhance the quality of the health care system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1200"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2009--Introduced.
American Health Security Act of 2009 - Establishes the State-Based American Health Security Program to provide every U.S. resident who is a U.S. citizen, national, or lawful resident alien with health care services. Requires each participating state to establish a state health security program. Eliminates benefits under: (1) titles XVIII (Medicare), XIX (Medicaid), and XXI (State Children's Health Insurance) (SCHIP) of the Social Security Act; (2) the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program; and (3) the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services (CHAMPUS). Requires each state health security program to prohibit the sale of health insurance in that state that duplicates benefits provided under the program. Establishes the American Health Security Standards Board to: (1) develop policies, procedures, guidelines and requirements to carry out this Act; (2) establish uniform reporting requirements; (3) provide for an American Health Security Advisory Council and an Advisory Committee on Health Professional Education; and (4) establish a national health security budget specifying the total federal and state expenditures to be made for covered health care services. Establishes the American Health Security Quality Council to: (1) review and evaluate practice guidelines, standards of quality, performance measures, and medical review criteria; and (2) develop minimum competence criteria. Establishes the Office of Primary Care and Prevention Research within the Office of the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH). Amends the Internal Revenue Code to create the American Health Security Trust Fund and appropriates to the Fund specified tax liabilities and current health program receipts.</summary>
</bill>
