<bill session="110" type="s" number="2772" updated="2013-07-19T22:45:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for the investigation of suicides committed by members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2008-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Suicide"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2008--Introduced.
Amends federal armed forces law to add provisions concerning investigations of suicides committed by members of the Armed Forces (members). Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned, in the case of a member's suicide, to establish a board, made up of commissioned officers serving on active duty, to investigate the causes contributing to the suicide, including preventive actions that could have been taken. Requires: (1) the protection of confidentiality with respect to such investigations; (2) the investigation to be completed within 30 days after the suicide; and (3) an interim and final board report to the Secretary concerned. Directs the Secretary concerned to make public the investigation results, while protecting the confidentiality of the member. Requires all reports received by the Secretary concerned to be transmitted to the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs, who shall take appropriate actions to reduce the incidence of suicide among members.</summary>
</bill>
