<bill session="109" type="h" number="3062" updated="2013-07-19T19:31:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Underground Storage Tank Compliance Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce the instances of releases from underground storage tanks by strengthening tank inspections, operator training, program enforcement, oxygenated fuel cleanup, and providing States greater Federal resources from the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400150"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400139" joined="2005-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Oxygenates"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum storage"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Reformulated gasoline"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Underground storage"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2005--Introduced.
Underground Storage Tank Compliance Act of 2005 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to distribute to states at least 80 percent of the funds authorized to be appropriated under this Act from the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund to pay the reasonable costs incurred under cooperative agreements of: (1) certain corrective actions; (2) directly related administrative expenses; or (3) enforcement of state or local requirements regulating underground storage tanks (USTs). Allows undistributed funds to be used for enforcing UST regulations. Requires the Administrator or a state with an approved program to require compliance inspections of USTs at least once every three years. Requires the study of compliance assurance programs that could serve as an alternative to the inspection programs. Directs the Administrator to publish operator training guidelines and states to develop and implement a training strategy consistent with stated requirements. Authorizes the use of funds made available for the petroleum response program to carry out corrective actions with respect to releases of fuel containing an oxygenated fuel additive that presents a threat to human health or welfare or the environment. Permits the use of trust funds for release prevention and compliance (as well as corrective actions). Requires compliance reports by any federal or state agency responsible for USTs. Authorizes a state or the Administrator to prohibit the delivery of regulated substances (motor fuels) to non-compliant tanks. Provides temporary relief for certain tanks in remote locations. Includes underground storage tank systems and release response activity (as well as underground storage tanks) that are under federal jurisdiction under the UST control and abatement requirements. Requires compliance strategy reports by any federal agency responsible for USTs which list the USTs and describe compliance actions. Requires the Administrator and Indian Tribes to correct UST releases on Indian lands.</summary>
</bill>
