<bill session="113" type="s" number="9" updated="2013-11-02T06:52:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean and Fair Elections Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen our Nation's electoral system by ensuring clean and fair elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S47-48" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/2013--Introduced.
Clean and Fair Elections Act - Expresses the sense of the Senate with respect to congressional attention to elections and voting, including concerning: structuring election administration and campaign finance systems so that the interests of the American public are the first priority; greater transparency and an end to anonymous political spending by shadow groups and special interests; disclosure of campaign contributions in a searchable, public online database, safeguarding the right to vote, including by prohibiting deceptive and misleading efforts to prevent voters from exercising the franchise; streamlining voting procedures; passage of legislation that includes expanded absentee voting, mandatory early voting periods, and voter registration reforms; ensuring that local election officials have working voting systems that are accessible, secure, and easy to use; state plans to reduce lines at polling places and provide additional flexibility in the event of a natural disaster or other emergency; and enforcement of the guarantees of the Fourteenth and Fifteenth Amendments to the Constitution and the Voting Rights Act of 1965 so that all Americans are able to vote and have their votes count without discrimination.</summary>
</bill>
