<bill session="111" type="s" number="4044" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Combating Autism Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize and strengthen the Combating Autism Act of 2006 (Public Law 109-416), to establish a National Institute of Autism Spectrum Disorders, to provide for the continuation of certain programs relating to autism, to establish programs to provide services to individuals with autism and the families of such individuals and to increase public education and awareness of autism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2010-12-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-12-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10515-10516"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/17/2010--Introduced.
Combating Autism Reauthorization Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the National Institute of Autism Spectrum Disorders for 10 years to conduct and support research, training, the dissemination of health information, and other programs with respect to autism spectrum disorders.&#160; Sets forth the duties of the Director of the Institute, which include making recommendations regarding the consolidation of programs of the National Institutes of Health (NIH). Transfers NIH activities on autism spectrum disorders to the Institute.&#160; Expands such activities to include translational research.&#160; Authorizes the Director of NIH to transfer personnel, permit use of facilities, and obtain administrative support for the Institute. Extends grants and programs for autism spectrum disorders and developmental disabilities. Extends and revises provisions related to the Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee. Requires the Comptroller General to study federal progress on autism spectrum disorders and autism services, interventions, and treatments. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish grant programs related to autism spectrum disorders, including to: (1) provide services to children, transitioning youth, and adults with autism spectrum disorders; (2) carry out multimedia campaigns; and (3) establish and maintain a national technical assistance center. Amends the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 to require the Secretary to make grants to enable protection and advocacy systems to address the needs of individuals with autism spectrum disorders.</summary>
</bill>
