<bill session="111" type="h" number="1436" updated="2013-07-19T23:24:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Government Efficiency, Effectiveness, and Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the evaluation of Government programs for efficiency, effectiveness, and accountability.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400657"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO24" subcommittee="Government Management, Organization, and Procurement" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2009--Introduced.
Government Efficiency, Effectiveness, and Accountability Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the President should establish government-wide strategic and performance plans; and (2) each federal agency head should consult with the congressional committees with jurisdiction over the agency at the beginning of each Congress regarding the agency's performance plan. Requires each agency head to: (1) conduct an assessment of each agency program at least once every five fiscal years; (2) determine how assessment information can help save taxpayers money; (3) develop a plan for merging programs with duplicative missions; (3) identify program best practices for allocating resources; and (4) determine program performance levels and ways to improve low performance. Requires assessment results and resulting agency actions to be submitted in a report to Congress at the same time the President submits the annual federal budget. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to: (1) develop a government-wide system to cross reference programs within each agency to make programs more effective and efficient; (2) provide notice of, and an opportunity for public comment on, each program to be assessed; and (3) develop a process for controlling the quality of program assessment data and certify the quality of such data. Changes: (1) the date by which the heads of each federal agency are required to submit strategic plans for program activities to September 30 of each year following a presidential election; and (2) the period of coverage for strategic plans from five to four years.</summary>
</bill>
