<bill session="112" type="s" number="237" updated="2013-07-20T02:18:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Government Accountability Office Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Government Accountability Office Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 31, United States Code, to enhance the oversight authorities of the Comptroller General, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-10-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with amendments. With written report No. 112-159.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-04-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="363">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 363.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2012--Reported to Senate amended.
Government Accountability Office Improvement Act of 2011- (Sec. 2) Authorizes the Comptroller General (GAO) to: (1) obtain federal agency records required to discharge his or her duties, including by bringing civil actions under this Act, (2) make and retain copies of agency records, and (3) administer oaths when investigating fraud or federal employee misconduct. (Sec. 4) States that no provision of the Social Security Act, the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, or the Hart-Scott-Rodino Antitrust Improvements Act of 1976 (including any information disclosed to the Assistant Attorney General of the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice (DOJ) or the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) for purposes of pre-merger review under the Clayton Act) shall be construed to limit, amend, or supersede GAO's&#160;authority to obtain any information, inspect, or copy any record under this Act. Requires GAO to prescribe policies and procedures to protect from public disclosure proprietary or trade secret information obtained pursuant to this Act. Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to: (1) alter or amend the prohibitions against the disclosure of trade secrets or other sensitive information prohibited by federal and other applicable laws; or (2) affect prohibitions applicable to GAO against unauthorized disclosure of information. (Sec. 5) Requires GAO to notify a congressional committee or Member of Congress if an agency has not provided within 30 days information requested by GAO relating to any request from such committee or Member. (Sec. 6) Requires agency statements on actions taken or planned in response to GAO recommendations to be submitted to the congressional committees with jurisdiction over the pertinent agency program or activity and to GAO.</summary>
</bill>
