<bill session="109" type="s" number="2357" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Right Time to Reinvest in America's Competitiveness and Knowledge Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Right TRACK Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">America's Better Classroom Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Employee Free Choice Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Fair Minimum Wage Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Global Worker Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">New National Defense Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Trade Adjustment Assistance Equity for Service Workers Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">United States Workers Protection Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Workers Equity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for economic security and prosperity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1648-1651"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Astronautics"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employment subsidies"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care fraud"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="High technology"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International corporations"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nanotechnology"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Plant shutdowns"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Railroad finance"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development tax credit"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space flight"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Telecommuting"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2006--Introduced.
Right Time to Reinvest in America's Competitiveness and Knowledge Act or Right TRACK Act - Amends specified federal laws to establish: (1) the Presidential Research and Development Advisory Committee to advise the President on the allocation of federal resources in education and technology development; and (2) an interagency working group to develop collaborative research in biomedical, science, engineering, and technology research. Makes permanent the extension of a research and development (R&amp;D) tax credit. Authorizes appropriations for FY2007-FY2013 to increase funding of R&amp;D activities of certain federal agencies. Allows a tax credit for the purchase of nanotechnology developer stocks. Establishes a national broadband policy for improving and expanding broadband access in the United States by 2010. Sets forth reauthorizations for Amtrak. America's Better Classroom Act of 2005 - Allows a tax credit to holders of qualified public school modernization bonds. New National Defense Education Act - Requires a biennial national assessment of student achievement and grade 12 student preparedness in reading, mathematics, and science. Authorizes prekindergarten through grade 16 student preparedness council grants to states to ensure a state's academic content and student academic achievement standards and assessments meet certain benchmarks. Makes competitive grants to institutions of higher education to improve the recruitment of teachers from students majoring in mathematics, science, engineering, technology, or a critical-need foreign language. Requires an eligible state to provide contract for educational opportunity (CEO) grants to low-income students who complete CEO requirements and enroll in a two-or four-year degree-granting institution of higher education. Provides for grants to: (1) improve mathematics, science, and engineering and technology education infrastructure in public elementary schools and secondary schools and to provide scholarships to make higher education tuition free for low-income and middle-income undergraduate and graduate students to earn degrees in science, technology, engineering, mathematics, and critical-need foreign languages; and (2) develop programs that expose public elementary and secondary school, undergraduate, and graduate students to foreign languages and cultures. Requires an employer to give 90-day notice before ordering the offshoring of jobs. Defines as foreign base company income and taxable as subpart F income any imported property income derived by a foreign corporation in a taxable year. United States Workers Protection Act of 2006 - Prohibits: (1) outsourced federal government work or a contract for the procurement of goods or services from being performed outside the United States unless certain requirements are met; and (2) the disbursement of federal funds to a state if any of the funds will be spent for goods or services performed outside the United States. Limits the application of certain trade authorities procedures implementing bilateral or regional trade agreements unless such agreements prohibit forced and compulsory labor and child labor. Imposes an additional duty on any article from a country that manipulates the rate of exchange between its currency and the U.S. dollar unless the President certifies to Congress that such country is no longer manipulating the rate to gain an unfair competitive advantage in international trade. Global Worker Fairness Act - Establishes a wage insurance program for workers displaced due to unfair trade competition. Trade Adjustment Assistance Equity for Service Workers Act of 2006 - Extends trade adjustment assistance (TAA) to workers in a service sector firm or a public agency. Authorizes the payment of amounts for training of adversely affected workers due to unfair trade competition through FY2012. Workers Equity Act - Permits TAA where an employer has shifted production of like articles to a foreign country that has been extended permanent normal trade relations by the United States. Establishes an Office of Community Trade Adjustment in the Department of Commerce to coordinate the federal response to economic dislocation. Employee Free Choice Act - Certifies a bargaining representative without directing an election if a majority of the bargaining unit employees have authorized designation of the representative and there is no other currently certified or recognized exclusive employee representative. Fair Minimum Wage Act of 2006 - Sets forth graduated increases of the federal minimum wage up to $7.25 an hour.</summary>
</bill>
