<bill session="109" type="s" number="1994" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fuel Security and Consumer Choice Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require that an increasing percentage of new automobiles be dual fueled automobiles, to revise the method for calculating corporate average fuel economy for such vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2006-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2005-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2005-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12685-12686"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="4673"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/2005--Introduced.
Fuel Security and Consumer Choice Act - Amends federal transportation law to require manufacturers of new automobiles that can operate on gasoline or diesel fuel (dual fueled automobiles) to manufacture such automobiles by increasing percentages for 10 model years and beyond. Allows manufacturers to earn credits which may be applied to any three consecutive model years after the year in which they were earned if the manufacturer exceeds the number of dual fueled automobiles required to be manufactured in a particular year. Authorizes a manufacturer to sell credits to another manufacturer to enable the purchaser to meet the percentage requirements under this Act. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to measure the fuel economy for each model of dual fueled automobile based on certain formulas.</summary>
</bill>
