<bill session="109" type="h" number="464" updated="2013-07-19T19:08:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Indian Tribal Federal Recognition Administrative Procedures Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for administrative procedures to extend Federal recognition to certain Indian groups, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400128"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2005--Introduced.
Indian Tribal Federal Recognition Administrative Procedures Act of 2005 - Establishes the Commission on Indian Recognition. Sets forth procedures for an Indian group to submit letters of intent and a petition to the Commission requesting Federal recognition as an Indian tribe (effectively transferring the Federal recognition process from the Bureau of Indian Affairs to the Commission). Specifies the requirements of a petition for recognition. Requires the Commission upon receiving a petition to: (1) send acknowledgment of receipt in writing to the petitioner; and (2) conduct a review to determine whether the petitioner is entitled to be recognized as an Indian tribe. Authorizes the petitioner to seek judicial review of a final determination with respect to a petition in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia. Makes an Indian tribe upon recognition by the Commission: (1) eligible for services and benefits from the Federal Government that are available to other federally recognized Indian tribes by virtue of their status as Indian tribes with a government-to-government relationship with the United States; and (2) have responsibilities, obligations, privileges, and immunities of those Indian tribes. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to Indian groups seeking Federal recognition as Indian tribes to enable them to conduct research to substantiate, and prepare documentation necessary for submission of, documented petitions under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
