<bill session="111" type="s" number="3509" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safer Oil and Gas Production Research and Development Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to promote the research and development of technologies and best practices for the safe development and extraction of natural gas and other petroleum resources, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2010-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5114"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5716"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3516"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3643"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3663"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2010--Introduced.
Safer Oil and Gas Production Research and Development Act of 2010 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) direct the Secretary of Energy to implement a deepwater (in lieu of ultra-deepwater) technologies research and development program, which includes addressing technology challenges for well control and accident prevention; and (2) implement research supportive of such activities through the Department of Energy (DOE). Revises the petroleum resources research and development program to: (1) replace ultra-deepwater activities with deepwater architecture, well control and accident prevention and deepwater technology, including drilling to deep formations in waters greater than 500 feet (currently, greater than 15,000 feet); and (2) replace complementary research performed by the National Energy Technology Laboratory with safety and environmental technology research and development for drilling activities aimed at well control and accident prevention performed by DOE. Directs the Secretary to ensure the safe and environmentally responsible production of natural gas and other petroleum resources of the United States. Revises requirements for focus areas for awards for research, development, and demonstration to include: (1) individual deepwater resources exploration and production technologies aimed at improving operational safety and reducing environmental impacts of exploration and production activities; (2) nontoxic materials for use in exploration and production activities; (3) accident prevention and environmental mitigation of unconventional natural gas and other petroleum resources exploration and production; and (4) safety and accident prevention technology research and development, with special attention to small producers. Directs the Secretary to arrange with the National Academy of Sciences to study: (1) whether the benefits provided through each award during calendar year 2011 have been maximized; and (2) new areas of research that could be implemented to meet program objectives. Replaces the Ultra-Deepwater Advisory Committee and the Unconventional Resources Technology Advisory Committee with a Program Advisory Committee. Revises the formula for allocation of amounts obligated from the Safe Oil and Gas Production and Accident Prevention Research Fund, with an increased allocation for safety technology research and development.</summary>
</bill>
