<bill session="112" type="h" number="6378" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Air and Health Quality Empowerment Zone Designation Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the designation of, and the award of grant with respect to, air and health quality empowerment zones.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2012-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2012--Introduced.
Air and Health Quality Empowerment Zone Designation Act of 2012 - Allows the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to designate an area as an air and health quality empowerment zone if the air pollution control district or other local governmental entity (area entity) authorized to regulate air quality for the area nominates the area for such designation, including by submitting a strategic plan designed to address air quality challenges, achieve attainment of air quality standards, and improve the health of the population in the area. Requires a designated area to meet the following criteria: (1) it has been designated as being in extreme nonattainment of the national ambient air quality standard for ozone and in nonattainment of the national ambient air quality standard for PM2.5 (particulate matter diameter); (2) it had nitrogen oxide emissions from farm equipment and emissions of volatile organic compounds from farming in excess of specified limits; (3) it meets or exceeds the national average per capita incidence of asthma; (4) it experiences unemployment rates higher than the national average; and (5) the area entity will provide matching contributions of federal funds toward the activities to be carried out under the strategic plan, which may be in cash or in-kind, fairly evaluated, including plant, equipment, or services. Makes the effective period of area designation the shorter of 10 years or the period ending with revocation by the Administrator. Authorizes grants to an area entity on behalf of each air and health quality empowerment zone for the purpose of carrying out the strategic plan submitted under this Act. Requires a report to Congress on the impact of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
