<bill session="111" type="s" number="1316" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Indian Reservation Bank Branch Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to modify requirements relating to the location of bank branches on Indian reservations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2009-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2009-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6889"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2009--Introduced.
Indian Reservation Bank Branch Act of 2009 - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act and the Revised Statutes of the United States to set forth conditions under which Indian tribes may permit branching of banks on Indian reservations. Permits approval of a state bank application to establish and operate a de novo branch within the boundaries of one or more Indian reservations (regardless of whether the Indian reservations are located within the state bank's home state), if the host reservation enacts a law meeting specified requirements. Exempts such a state bank from certain requirements and conditions governing an application for an interstate merger transaction. Prohibits specified state nonmember banks that establish or operate a branch on Indian reservations, except in certain circumstances, from establishing additional branches outside of such reservations in any state in which the Indian reservation is located. Amends the Revised Statutes of the United States to authorize the Comptroller of the Currency to approve an application of a national bank to establish and operate a de novo branch within the boundaries of an Indian reservation, subject to the same requirements, conditions, and prohibitions of this Act with regard to state banks.</summary>
</bill>
