<bill session="112" type="s" number="3326" updated="2013-07-20T02:45:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the African Growth and Opportunity Act to extend the third-country fabric program and to add South Sudan to the list of countries eligible for designation under that Act, to make technical corrections to the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States relating to the textile and apparel rules of origin for the Dominican Republic-Central America-United States Free Trade Agreement, to approve the renewal of import restrictions contained in the Burmese Freedom and Democracy Act of 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2012-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2012-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2012-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2012-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-07-18">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Reported by Senator Baucus without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-07-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="459">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 459.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-653.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5904-5907, S5920-5921, S5934" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2012-08-02" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5920-5921" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>By Senator Baucus from Committee on Finance filed written report. Report No. 112-225. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="5986"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Costa Rica"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dominican Republic"/>
    <term name="El Salvador"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Guatemala"/>
    <term name="Honduras"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="South Sudan"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2771"/>
    <amendment number="s2772"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Passed Senate without amendment.
(Sec. 1) Amends the African Growth and Opportunity Act to extend through FY2015 the third-country fabric rule granting duty-free treatment of apparel articles wholly assembled, or knit-to-shape and wholly assembled, or both, in one or more lesser developed beneficiary sub-Saharan African countries, regardless of the country of origin of the fabric or the yarn used to make such articles. Revises the term "sub-Saharan African country" to include the Republic of South Sudan (South Sudan) under such Act. (Sec. 2) Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to modify textile and apparel rules of origin for the Dominican Republic-Central America-United States Free Trade Agreement (CAFTA-DR). (Sec. 3) Amends the Burmese Freedom and Democracy Act of 2003 to renew, for three years, the President's authority to ban the import of Burmese products. Approves the renewal of certain import restrictions contained in the Act. Deems this resolution a renewal resolution which shall take effect upon its enactment or July 26, 2012, whichever occurs first. (Sec. 4) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require estimated tax payments which are otherwise due in the third quarter of 2017 for corporations with assets of at least $1 billion to be 100.25% of such amount. Requires the next required installment to be appropriately reduced to reflect the amount of this increase. (Sec. 5) Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to extend certain customs users fees for the processing of merchandise entered into the United States from August 2, 2021, to October 22, 2021, and other specified customs users fees from December 8, 2020, to October 29, 2021.</summary>
</bill>
