<bill session="111" type="sr" number="118" updated="2013-07-20T00:17:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution to provide Internet access to certain Congressional Research Service publications.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2009-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4900" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3762"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional Research Service (CRS)"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2009--Introduced.
Directs the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate, in consultation with the the Director of the Congressional Research Service (CRS), to make publicly available through a centralized electronic system the following CRS-produced information (plus an index of such information that is available through the CRS website): (1) Issue Briefs; (2) CRS Reports that are available to Members of Congress through the CRS website; and (3) Authorization of Appropriations and Appropriations Products. Exempts from such requirements: (1) any information determined to be confidential by the CRS Director or the head of a department or agency that provided the information to CRS; and (2) documents, other than those described in clauses (1) through (3), that are the product of a congressional research request.Allows the Sergeant at Arms, in consultation with the CRS Director, to revise the information made publicly available by removing information concerning CRS employees, removing material that may infringe copyright protection, and making necessary changes to ensure accuracy and currency. Requires access to the information made available pursuant to this resolution through Senate committee and Member websites. Directs the Sergeant-at-Arms to ensure that such websites provide the same capability to find the cited CRS information as the CRS website. Makes the Sergeant at Arms responsible for maintaining and updating the information and for establishing a database within six months after adoption of this resolution.</summary>
</bill>
