<bill session="111" type="h" number="3753" updated="2013-07-19T23:45:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PRIDE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Providing Resources to Improve Dual Language Education Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish dual-language education programs in low-income communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2009-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2010-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/2009--Introduced.
Providing Resources to Improve Dual Language Education Act of 2009 or the PRIDE Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award up to five grants to partnerships of local educational agencies (LEAs), early childhood education programs, and technical assistance providers for the implementation of dual language demonstration programs designed to enhance and assess the biliteracy, bilingualism, and multicultural skills of low-income minority and limited English proficient students from preschool through grade five. Directs the Secretary to: (1) arrange for an entity that has dual language program experience to provide technical assistance to LEA grantees and evaluate the programs funded by this Act; and (2) disseminate information on model practices implemented under such programs that are appropriate for use by early childhood education providers to improve the school readiness of limited English proficient students.</summary>
</bill>
