<bill session="109" type="sr" number="202" updated="2013-07-19T20:08:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-19">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution urging the Government of Sudan and the Sudan People's Liberation Movement/Army to fully implement the Comprehensive Peace Agreement of January 9, 2005.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300045"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2005-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-07-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8499-8500" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8499-8500" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8490-8491" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2005--Passed Senate without amendment.
Commends the people of Sudan on the signing of the January 2005 Comprehensive Peace Agreement, and urges the government of National Unity of Sudan to fully implement the Agreement. Requests that the U.S. government closely monitor the Agreement's implementation and events on the ground in Sudan, including in Darfur. Urges the U.S. government to: (1) maintain sanctions on the government of Sudan until the Agreement's implementation; and (2) renew efforts to implement additional sanctions through the U.N. Security Council until peace in Darfur is achieved and those responsible for genocide and other crimes are brought to justice. Urges the government of National Unity of Sudan to use the Agreement as the basis for peaceful resolution of the conflicts in Darfur and other areas of Sudan. Supports: (1) expansion of the African Union's mission in Darfur, encouraging its continued support from the United States, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), and other countries and international organizations; (2) the U.N. mission in the Sudan and its expansion to protect civilians and aid workers throughout Sudan; (3) U.S. humanitarian and reconstruction assistance to the southern Sudan and Darfur; and (4) international efforts to facilitate the safe return of refugees and internationally displaced persons in Sudan. Calls upon the governments of all countries in the Sudan region and around the world to support and monitor the Agreement's full implementation.</summary>
</bill>
