<bill session="109" type="h" number="3419" updated="2013-07-19T19:34:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Northern Nevada Sustainable Development in Mining Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to dispose of certain public lands that are subject to mining operations in Pershing County, Nevada, to support sustainable development opportunities for the community in which the mining operations occur through privatization of the lands allowing for productive post-mining land use that provides for economic development opportunities and local government revenues, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2005--Introduced.
Northern Nevada Sustainable Development in Mining Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to Couer Rochester, Inc., in return for a payment of $500 per acre, specified federal lands in Pershing County, Nevada, subject to Coeur Rochester Inc.'s mining claims maintained under the general mining laws. Prohibits any conveyance of land under this Act from being subject to review, consultation, or approval under any other federal law. Provides for the disposition of the proceeds of conveyances of land under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
