<bill session="112" type="h" number="3530" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freddie Mac Debt Reduction Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the exercise of clean-up call options under securities issued by the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation and to prohibit any new mortgage-backed securities issued by such enterprises to contain provisions for a clean-up call option.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2011-11-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/30/2011--Introduced.
Freddie Mac Debt Reduction Act of 2011 - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 with respect to the exercise of options on mortgage-backed securities by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) or, during the term of any conservatorship or receivership of Freddie Mac, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA). Directs Freddie Mac (or FHFA as its conservator or receiver) to exercise any option on a mortgage-backed security with a clean-up call option Freddie Mac has issued if the residual holder of the security is willing to share at least 50% of any excess proceeds from the exercise of the option with FHFA as conservator or receiver, which would thereby reduce the liability of taxpayers. (A clean-up call option allows a transferor of assets, in this case mortgage assets, to buy them back after the outstanding asset values have been reduced substantially.) Defines mortgage-backed security with a clean-up call option as any mortgage-backed security under which there is an option or right to redeem all remaining classes of the security whenever the aggregate remaining principal of the mortgage would be less than the optional redemption or clean-up call percentage. Directs the Director to prohibit Freddie Mac and the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) from issuing any mortgage-backed security with a clean-up call option. Directs the Director to ensure that any excess proceeds received as a result of the exercise of any clean-up call options be used only to reduce the budget deficit of the federal government.</summary>
</bill>
