<bill session="109" type="h" number="2595" updated="2013-07-19T19:27:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Land Transfer Compensation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Administrator of General Services and the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal property to the District of Columbia to increase the District's taxable property base as compensation for a structural fiscal imbalance caused by Federal mandates.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1082"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-31">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2005--Introduced.
Fair Land Transfer Compensation Act - Requires the Administrator of General Services and the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the District of Columbia, without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to U.S. Reservation 13 and Poplar Point, Anacostia Park, respectively. Requires the Administrator and the Secretary each to: (1) conduct an appraisal of the property (including improvements if appropriate), based on fair market value; and (2) report to Congress on the results, including an estimate of all financial benefits to be generated on an annual basis to the District, and an assessment of the impact the conveyance will have in reducing the structural financial imbalance of the District. Exempts the United States from any liability or responsibility pursuant to such transfer for any additional remedial action: (1) with respect to hazardous substances not existing on the property as of the date of conveyance, unless the presence of such hazardous substances on the property was caused by the United States; or (2) caused, required, or arising out of actions of the District of Columbia or any of the District's agents, contractors, or assigns.</summary>
</bill>
