<bill session="111" type="s" number="574" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Plain Writing Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Plain Writing Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance citizen access to Government information and services by establishing that Government documents issued to the public must be written clearly, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2009-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2009-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2009-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2009-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-03-23" withdrawn="2009-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3032"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3032-3033" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-12-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment. With written report No. 111-102.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-12-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="222">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 222.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="946"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/9/2009--Reported to Senate amended.
Plain Writing Act of 2009 - Requires each executive agency to use plain writing in every document (other than a regulation) issued to the public, including documents and other text released in electronic form. Requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to issue guidance on implementing such requirements to agencies as a circular. Authorizes agencies, pending issuance of such guidance, to follow the writing guidelines developed by the Plain Language Action and Information Network or their own guidance as long as it is consistent with such guidelines. Requires each agency head to report to specified congressional committees on how the agency intends to: (1) communicate the requirements of this Act to employees; (2) train employees in plain writing; (3) meet the plain writing requirement; (4) ensure ongoing compliance with this Act; and (5) designate a senior official to be responsible for implementing this Act. Requires: (1) agency heads to report on compliance to OMB; and (2) OMB to report on the progress of agencies to such committees. Declares that: (1) there shall be no judicial review of compliance with this Act; and (2) no provision of this Act shall be construed to create any enforceable right or benefit.</summary>
</bill>
