<bill session="111" type="h" number="3430" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">DSH Collaborative Care Network Pilot Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a Medicare DSH pilot program under which participants shall establish collaborative care networks to reduce the use of emergency departments, inpatient and other expensive resources of hospitals and other providers and provide more comprehensive and coordinated care to low-income individuals, including those without health insurance coverage, and to establish a Collaborative Care Network Center.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400355"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2009-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2009-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2009-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2009--Introduced.
DSH Collaborative Care Network Pilot Program Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to carry out a Medicare disproportionate share hospital (DSH) pilot program under which participating DSHs shall receive additional Medicare funds to establish model projects to: (1) reduce the unnecessary use of items and services furnished in hospital emergency departments; (2) manage chronic conditions to reduce their severity, negative health outcomes, and expense; (3) provide more comprehensive and coordinated care to low-income vulnerable individuals and individuals without health insurance coverage or with inadequate coverage; (4) increase preventive services, including screening and counseling, to those who would otherwise not receive them; (5) ensure the availability of community-wide safety net services; and (6) accomplish other specified goals. Makes funds available under the Pilot Program for a participating DSH to create and support collaborative care networks that would: (1) assist low-income individuals without adequate health care coverage access and use health services, as well as enroll in applicable public or private health insurance programs; and (2) improve health care by providing case management, application assistance, and appropriate referrals. Directs the Secretary to create within HHS a Collaborative Care Network Center.</summary>
</bill>
