<bill session="109" type="h" number="2489" updated="2013-07-19T19:26:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving Government Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Inspector General Act of 1978 to enhance the independence of the Inspectors General, to create a Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2005-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2005-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Professional education"/>
    <term name="Removal of officials"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Term limits"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2005--Introduced.
Improving Government Accountability Act - Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to allow an Inspector General (IG) to be removed from office prior to the expiration of his or her term only on the grounds of either: (1) permanent incapacity; (2) inefficiency; (3) neglect of duty; (4) malfeasance; or (5) conviction of a felony or conduct involving moral turpitude. Establishes the term of office of each IG as seven years and permits reappointment. Makes similar amendments respecting the appointment of IGs of certain designated Federal entities. Authorizes an IG to annually transmit an appropriation estimate and request to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and to the appropriate congressional committees, in addition to the head of the establishment concerned. Requires the President to include in each annual budget specified IG appropriation information. Establishes within the Executive Branch the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency to increase the professionalism and effectiveness of personnel in IG offices. Establishes an Integrity Committee for the Council to review and refer for investigation allegations that are made against IGs and certain staff of the IG Offices. Considers each Office of IG to be a separate Federal agency. Empowers IGs of certain designated Federal entities with the same law enforcement authority provided to other IGs. Provides for the application of semiannual reporting requirements concerning the activities of offices of the IG with respect to inspection and evaluation reports.</summary>
</bill>
