<bill session="112" type="sc" number="31" updated="2013-07-20T02:16:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-01T18:05:00-04:00">PASSED:CONCURRENTRES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-11-01T18:05:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A concurrent resolution directing the Secretary of the Senate to make a correction in the enrollment of S. 1280.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2011-10-13" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6562" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6562" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6516" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-10-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-18T11:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-18T11:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-01T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Ros-Lehtinen asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-01T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7185" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:CONCURRENTRES" datetime="2011-11-01T18:05:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7185" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-11-01T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1280"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Peace Corps"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/2011--Passed House without amendment.
Directs the Secretary of the Senate to make corrections to the enrollment of S. 1280 (Kate Puzey Peace Corps Volunteer Protection Act of 2011) to: (1) amend the Peace Corps Act to terminate on October 1, 2018, provisions providing for the establishment of the Office of Victim Advocacy and the Sexual Assault Advisory Council; (2) terminate by that date the requirements that the President annually conduct a confidential survey of volunteers regarding Peace Corps programs and staff effectiveness and volunteer safety and annually submit information on sexual assault and other crimes against volunteers; (3) terminate by that date the requirement that the Peace Corps Inspector General submit a biennial report on reports received from volunteers relating to misconduct, mismanagement, or policy violations by Peace Corps staff, breaches of confidentiality of volunteers, and actions taken to assure the safety of volunteers who provide such reports; (4) change the interval for Inspector General reports on the effectiveness and implementation of the sexual assault risk-reduction and response training and the sexual assault policy; (5) direct the President, rather than the Peace Corps Director, to perform a review at least every three years to evaluate the allocation and delivery of resources across the countries the Peace Corps serves and, at the request of the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Senate or House Foreign Relations Committee, to brief such committees on each such review; and (6) repeal provisions terminating such Act seven years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
