<bill session="112" type="h" number="1577" updated="2013-07-20T01:23:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize advance appropriations for military personnel, reserve personnel, and National Guard personnel accounts of the Department of Defense, generally title I of the annual Department of Defense appropriations Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412483"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2011--Introduced.
Requires that, for each fiscal year beginning with FY2012, discretionary new budget authority provided in an appropriations Act for the military personnel accounts of the Department of Defense (DOD) shall: (1) be made available for that fiscal year; and (2) include, for each account, advance discretionary new budget authority that first becomes available for the first fiscal year after the budget year. Directs the Secretary of Defense to: (1) include in annual budget documents detailed estimates of the funds necessary for the military personnel accounts for the fiscal year following the fiscal year for which the budget is submitted, and (2) report annually to Congress on the sufficiency of DOD resources for the next fiscal year for the provision of military pay and allowances for regular and reserve military personnel.</summary>
</bill>
