<bill session="113" type="h" number="2220" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Support More Assets, Resources, and Technology on the Border Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for operational control of the international border of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412478" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412508" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2013-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, Rules, Energy and Commerce, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2013--Introduced.
Support More Assets, Resources, and Technology on the Border Act of 2013 or the SMART Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) take actions to achieve and maintain operational control of the U.S.-Mexico border (defined as a condition in which there is at least a 90% probability that all illegal border crossers are apprehended and narcotics and other contraband are seized); and (2) report to the Comptroller General (GAO) on such actions, achievement, and maintenance. Directs the Comptroller General, within 90 days after such report is submitted, to: (1) consult with state and local officials along such border regarding such operational control; and (2) report on such operational control to specified congressional committees. Requires the House of Representatives and the Senate to vote on a joint resolution on the question of whether such report should be disapproved within 90 days of receiving it or such joint resolution shall be deemed passed. Requires the Comptroller General to submit an annual report on such operational control. Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to: (1) deploy up to an additional 10,000 members of the National Guard along the U.S.-Mexico border as requested by border states; and (2) provide funds to the governor of a state who submits a state border control activities plan, which is approved by the Secretary, that specifies how personnel of the National Guard of such state are to be used in border control activities. Authorizes National Guard personnel to be ordered to carry out border control activities. Authorizes: (1) the DHS Secretary to deploy smart border technologies if necessary to achieve and maintain such operational control; and (2) the Defense Secretary to transfer specified eligible equipment returned from DOD operations to federal, state, and local agencies, with preference to agencies that will use such equipment primarily to strengthen border security. Requires the DHS Secretary: (1) if such a joint resolution of disapproval on operational control passes, to appoint an additional 1,500 Border Patrol agents; (2) make grants to sheriffs' departments along the border in Texas, Arizona, New Mexico, and California to hire additional deputies; and (3) establish the biometric entry and exit data system required under the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004. Authorizes the DHS Secretary to make competitive grants for public-private partnerships that finance equipment and infrastructure to improve the public safety of residents of U.S. rural areas near the border by enhancing access to mobile communications for such persons. Directs the the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to ensure that an individual who is apprehended unlawfully crossing, or attempting to unlawfully cross, the border into the United States is counted only once for purposes of counting border apprehensions.</summary>
</bill>
