<bill session="109" type="h" number="6048" updated="2013-07-19T19:57:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Outpatient Therapy Value-Based Purchasing Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide incentives to Medicare participating suppliers and providers of services that are outpatient physical therapy services (including outpatient speech-language pathology services) and occupational therapy services to report quality and efficiency measures and to provide for a value-based purchasing program for payments for such services under the Medicare Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400434"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-07">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Occupational therapy"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Physical therapy"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2006--Introduced.
Medicare Outpatient Therapy Value-Based Purchasing Act of 2006 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to authorize providers of outpatient physical therapy services and of occupational therapy services to submit to a national therapy outcomes database information on quality and efficiency (Q &amp; E) measures. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish procedures for disclosure of such information to the public. Directs the Secretary to establish a value-based purchasing program for such services under which service providers will receive higher payments for high quality care, reduced payments for low quality care, or no payments if they have not submitted Q &amp; E information. Revises requirements for the treatment of such services under the Medicare therapy cap, especially during the period before implementation of the value-based purchasing program. Requires physical or occupational therapists who furnish Medicare therapy services as an incident to physicians' services meet the licensing requirements of the Secretary. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary shall develop a system under which each covered provider of covered outpatient therapy services participating in the Medicare program has a unique supplier identification number in order to enable the Secretary to monitor the quality and efficiency of such services.</summary>
</bill>
