<bill session="112" type="h" number="3829" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">CARE for Kids Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Childcare Accountability and Responsibility Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require a criminal background check for employees of child care providers, family child care providers, and adults who reside in the private residences of family child care providers in States that receive funds from the Child Care and Development Block Grant Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400661"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2012-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2012-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2012-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2012-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2012--Introduced.
Childcare Accountability and Responsibility Act of 2012 or the CARE for Kids Act of 2012 - Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to require a national criminal background check for an individual who is a child care staff member, a family child care provider, or an adult who resides in the home of a family child care provider in any state that receives funds from the Child Care and Development Block Grant Program. Requires that such background check include: (1) a search of the national Sex Offender Registry, the National Crime Information Center, state criminal registries, and state-based abuse and neglect registries and databases; and (2) a Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) fingerprint check. Makes a child care provider ineligible for Program funds if the criminal background check reveals an adult felony conviction of any such individual for: (1) child abuse or neglect; (2) spousal abuse; (3) a crime against children (including child pornography); (4) a violent crime; or (5) distribution, possession with intent to distribute, or importation of a controlled substance committed within the previous five years. Allows: (1) a child care provider or an individual subject to a background check to appeal the results to the appropriate designated state agency, and (2) a state to collect a fee from providers for such background checks to defray costs.</summary>
</bill>
