<bill session="109" type="h" number="6297" updated="2013-07-19T20:00:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freedom to Bank Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To sunset Federal laws and regulations which treat the American people like children by denying them the opportunity to make their own decision regarding control of their bank accounts and what type of information they wish to receive from their banks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1918"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Introduced.
Freedom to Bank Act - Terminates any provision of federal law (other than the Internal Revenue Code) that subjects a consumer to a penalty for withdrawing or transferring funds from any transaction account or any savings or time deposit. Declares that no creditor, depository institution, or credit union shall be required to provide periodic statements of account to a customer unless the customer has notified it of an election to receive such statements. Requires such entities to establish a procedure for notifying customers of their right to elect to receive statements of account and the method for implementing such election.</summary>
</bill>
