<bill session="111" type="s" number="1269" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Food Safety Rapid Response Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for enhanced foodborne illness surveillance and food safety capacity, to establish regional food safety centers of excellence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2010-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2009--Introduced.
Food Safety Rapid Response Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to strengthen and expand foodborne illness surveillance systems to: (1) inform and evaluate efforts to prevent foodborne illness; and (2) enhance the identification and investigation of, and response to, foodborne illness outbreaks. Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to: (1) enhance foodborne illness surveillance systems to improve the collection, analysis, reporting, and usefulness of data on foodborne illnesses; and (2) improve capacity for foodborne illness surveillance in states. Requires the Secretary to establish five regional Food Safety Centers of Excellence to serve as regional resources for state and local public health professionals in investigating and responding to foodborne illnesses.</summary>
</bill>
