<bill session="111" type="h" number="6266" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sex Offender Notification of International Travel Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act to require sex offenders to notify appropriate government officials before traveling internationally, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400356"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Sex Offender Notification of International Travel Act - Amends the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act to require sex offenders required to register under such Act to notify their residential jurisdictions of their intent to travel from the United States to another country, regardless of the duration of the travel. Requires the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), to develop an international travel notification form to obtain information about sex offenders traveling outside the United States, including each such offender's name, address, social security number, email addresses, citizenship, passport or passport card number, and travel itinerary and the purpose of the trip. Establishes: (1) a Cyber Crimes Center (CCC) in the United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement Office of DHS to address criminal acts crossing U.S. borders through cyberspace; and (2) the Child Exploitation Investigations Center within the CCC to coordinate all agency child exploitation initiatives relating to child exploitation, child trafficking, and forced child labor. Authorizes the CCC to create and advance public awareness campaigns to further its mission. Directs the Attorney General, in consultation with the DHS Secretary, to conduct research and development activities for the prevention and investigation of child exploitation crimes. Amends the federal criminal code to extend the authority to issue administrative subpoenas in federal offenses involving the sexual exploitation or abuse of children to the DHS Secretary and the Postmaster General.</summary>
</bill>
