<bill session="113" type="s" number="655" updated="2013-11-02T06:57:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Urban Jobs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to authorize the Secretary of Labor to provide grants for Urban Jobs Programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412586" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2013-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="1340"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2013--Introduced.
Urban Jobs Act of 2013 - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to authorize the Secretary of Labor to make competitive grants to national or regional private nonprofit community-based organizations to carry out Urban Jobs Programs to provide job training, education, and support services and activities for eligible urban youth to provide them with a pathway to employment, or education leading to employment. Defines "eligible youth" as individuals ages 18 to 24 who: (1) are not enrolled in secondary or post-secondary school, or (2) are or have been subject to the criminal justice process. Directs the Secretary to establish a National Jobs Council Advisory Committee. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) community-based affiliates should establish local jobs council advisory committees to aid in establishing local community support for local implementation of the program; and (2) at least one-third of the members of the committee should be employers in high-impact, high-growth industries in the locality.</summary>
</bill>
