<bill session="112" type="sr" number="516" updated="2013-07-20T02:15:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on the restitution of or compensation for property seized during the Nazi and Communist eras.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4775-4776" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-09-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="527">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 527.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="766"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2012--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Recognizes the unmet needs of many Holocaust survivors and the urgency of addressing those needs. Expresses appreciation for the efforts of the European countries that have implemented legislation for the restitution of, or compensation for, private, communal, and religious property confiscated during the Nazi or Communist eras and welcomes the efforts of the governments of many post-Communist countries to address the status of such property. Urges each government that has not already done so to implement legislation to effect the in rem return of, or the payment of, compensation for such confiscated property. Calls on each government to establish restitution and compensation schemes in a simple, transparent, and timely manner to provide a real benefit to those who suffered from the unjust confiscation of their property. Calls on the Secretary of State to issue an updated report on property restitution in Central and Eastern Europe.</summary>
</bill>
