<bill session="111" type="h" number="4424" updated="2013-07-19T23:52:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhancing Renewable Energy Investment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase the energy credit for equipment used to generate electricity by geothermal power, to extend the grants for specified energy property, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412232"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/12/2010--Introduced.
Enhancing Renewable Energy Investment Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a 30% energy tax credit through 2016 for equipment used to produce electricity by geothermal power; and (2) require the inclusion in gross income for income tax purposes of employee compensation deferred under a nonqualified deferred compensation plan of certain foreign entities when there is no substantial risk of forfeiture of the rights to such compensation. Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Tax Act of 2009 to allow an extension of the grant period for specified energy property in lieu of applicable tax credits.</summary>
</bill>
