<bill session="111" type="h" number="5002" updated="2013-07-19T23:57:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">No Sanctuary for Illegals Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To end the cycle of illegal immigration in the United States and withdraw Federal funds from States and political subdivisions of States that interfere with the enforcement of Federal immigration law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-13">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-13">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1868"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5796"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2010--Introduced.
No Sanctuary for Illegals Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) increase border patrol recruitment incentives by offering a ($40,000 maximum) repayment of higher education loans; and (2) develop border patrol retention incentives through the establishment of a retention program. Authorizes the Secretary to deploy newly developed technologies to secure U.S. international land and maritime borders. Directs the Secretary to: (1) prioritize border fence construction; and (2) report to Congress regarding such construction's progress. Requires that if an alien who is unlawfully present in the United States is arrested for any offense by a state or local law enforcement agency the head of such agency shall immediately notify United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) of the arrest and the alien's identity. Requires that such an arrested alien be detained by ICE and presented before an immigration judge for expedited U.S. removal without release from detention and without further hearing or review. Provides for criminal penalties and expedited removal for such a removed alien who subsequently returns unlawfully to the United States. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) to make inadmissible an alien who has been unlawfully present in the United States for any period of time and who enters or seeks to enter the United States unlawfully. (Current law requires the period of unlawful presence to be more than one year.) Amends INA to consider a person born in the United States "subject to the jurisdiction" of the United States for citizenship at birth purposes if the person is born in the United States of parents, one of whom is: (1) a U.S. citizen or national; (2) a lawful permanent resident alien whose residence is in the United States; or (3) an alien performing active service in the U.S. Armed Forces. Prohibits a federal government officer or employee from providing federal funds to any state or political subdivision that is determined to be interfering with efforts to enforce federal immigration laws. Terminates such prohibition when the state or political subdivision enters into an agreement with the Secretary to cease such interference.</summary>
</bill>
