<bill session="111" type="s" number="3271" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vehicle Event History Information Capturing Leads to Engineering Safety Improvements Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">VEHICLE Safety Improvements Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend section 30166 of title 49, United States Code, to require the installation of event data recorders in all motor vehicles manufactured for sale in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2761"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5169"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5345"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2010--Introduced.
Vehicle Event History Information Capturing Leads to Engineering Safety Improvements Act of 2010 or VEHICLE Safety Improvements Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to promulgate regulations to require: (1) each new light-, medium-, and heavy-duty motor vehicle manufactured for sale or lease in the United States to be equipped with an event data recorder (EDR) meeting certain requirements; and (2) any data stored in the EDR of such vehicles to be accessible and retrievable by a commercially available universal data reader. Requires the owner's manual of new motor vehicles to indicate clearly the presence of EDRs. Prohibits the retrieval of information recorded or transmitted by an EDR by any person other than the owner of the motor vehicle in which such device is installed, unless: (1) a court authorizes it, the owner consents, or the information is retrieved by a government motor vehicle safety agency; and (2) neither the personally identifiable information of the vehicle owner or driver nor the vehicle identification number (VIN) is disclosed in the retrieval of information.</summary>
</bill>
