<bill session="112" type="hr" number="540" updated="2013-07-20T01:07:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-08T14:07:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-02-08T14:07:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3521) to amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to provide for a legislative line-item veto to expedite consideration of rescissions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412416"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-02-07T16:54:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-389, by Mr. Woodall.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-07T16:54:00-05:00">
      <text>The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill and amendment in the nature of a substitute. The resolution makes in order as original text for purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee print 112-12. The resolution provides that it shall be in order at any time through the legislative day of February 9, 2012, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules, as though under clause 1(c) of rule XV, relating to a measure addressing securities trading based on nonpublic information.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-02-07T16:54:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="111">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 111.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-02-08T12:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H593-602" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-08T12:40:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 540.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-08T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 240 - 184 (Roll no. 43).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H601" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-02-08T14:07:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="44" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 238 - 175 (Roll no. 44).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H593" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-02-08T14:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="3521"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/7/2012--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3521) to amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to provide for a legislative line-item veto to expedite consideration of rescissions.</summary>
</bill>
