<bill session="110" type="h" number="7287" updated="2013-07-19T22:07:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">21st Century Wellness Trust Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a Wellness Trust.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2008-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3674"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Health services administration"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2008--Introduced.
21st Century Wellness Trust Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the Wellness Trust within the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to be headed by the Trust Fund Board. Requires the Trustees to submit to Congress and make publicly available reports on: (1) a system for certification and recertification of prevention health workers to complement the health system; (2) payment methodologies and options for paying certified prevention health workers for clinical preventive care; and (3) the amount of money spent on prevention by public health, public and private health insurers, and applicable self-insured health plans during the most recent year for which such data is available.Requires the Trustees to: (1) establish a plan for delivering and financing prevention priorities and implement pilot programs; and (2) issue a ranked list of designated prevention priorities based on the potential of an activity to improve health and the activity's cost effectiveness.Directs the Trustees to establish, support, and sustain the infrastructure for an effective wellness system that includes: (1) an information clearinghouse on prevention priorities; (2) an electronic prevention record or registry; and (3) training for prevention health workers.Establishes in the Treasury a Wellness Trust Fund. Sets forth funding sources.Requires the Trust to enter into contracts to reimburse certified prevention health workers for the prevention services designated by the Trustees as prevention priorities. Directs the Trustees to: (1) develop targets for and determine payment methodologies for prevention priorities.</summary>
</bill>
