<bill session="113" type="s" number="1135" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FRAC Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fracturing Responsibility and Awareness of Chemicals Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to repeal a certain exemption for hydraulic fracturing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1921"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="332"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2013--Introduced.
Fracturing Responsibility and Awareness of Chemicals Act or FRAC Act - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to repeal the exemption from restrictions on underground injection of fluids or propping agents granted to hydraulic fracturing operations relating to oil and natural gas production activities under such Act. Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to allow the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to prescribe regulations that authorize a state, one year after such regulations are promulgated, to seek primary enforcement responsibility for hydraulic fracturing operations for oil and natural gas without seeking to assume primary enforcement responsibility for other types of underground injection control wells, including underground injection control wells that inject brine or other fluids that are brought to the surface in connection with oil and natural gas production or any underground injection for the secondary or tertiary recovery of oil or natural gas. Requires: (1) state underground injection programs to direct a person conducting hydraulic fracturing operations to disclose to the state (or the Administrator if the Administrator has primary enforcement responsibility in such state) the chemicals and proppants intended for use in underground injections before the commencement of such operations and the chemicals actually used after the end of such operations; and (2) a state or the Administrator to ensure the accuracy and completeness of the disclosed information and make it available to the public. Requires the applicable person using hydraulic fracturing, when a medical emergency exists and the proprietary chemical formula of a chemical used in such hydraulic fracturing is necessary for medical diagnosis, treatment, or emergency response to disclose such formula or the specific chemical identity of a trade secret chemical to the state, the Administrator, a first responder, or healthcare practitioner upon request, regardless of the existence of a written statement of need or a confidentiality agreement. Authorizes such person to require the execution of such statement and agreement as soon as practicable. Authorizes first responders or healthcare practitioners to share any information disclosed with other persons if the information is medically necessary, but prohibits such personnel from making such information publicly available.</summary>
</bill>
