<bill session="110" type="h" number="7187" updated="2013-07-19T22:06:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Labeling Education and Nutrition Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">LEAN Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to nutrition labeling of food offered for sale in food service establishments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2008-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="2008-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2008-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2008-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2008-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2008-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2008-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2135"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3575"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Diet"/>
    <term name="Food service"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Restaurants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2008--Introduced.
Labeling Education and Nutrition Act of 2008 or the LEAN Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to authorize a food service establishment to provide nutrition information for a food item by: (1) providing calories and nutrient information required for food intended for human consumption; (2) disclosing such information in written form; and (3) making such disclosure available upon request prior to purchase.Requires the labeling of a standard food item served or offered for sale in a food service establishment that is part of a chain that operates 20 or more establishments under the same trade name to disclose, in a clear and conspicuous manner, prior to the point of purchase: (1) the number of calories on a menu board, on a sign meeting certain requirements, in the menu, or as part of or supplement to the menu; (2) specified nutrient information, in writing and upon request; (3) a statement directing the consumer to the availability of additional nutrient information; and (4) a statement providing suggested daily caloric intake, on a menu or menu board that does not list calories.Declares a person to have knowingly or willfully violated the requirements of this Act if the person: (1) purposefully fails to make a disclosure required by this Act; or (2) makes a disclosure with the intent to deceive.Provides that a reasonable basis determination of nutrition information shall be required only once per standard food item if certain requirements are met.Preempts state laws not identical to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
