<bill session="110" type="s" number="1148" updated="2013-07-19T22:30:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission and the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-158.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-07-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-09-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-179.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-09-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="377">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 377.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1520"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="1520"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1520"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Interstate commissions"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2007--Reported to Senate amended.
Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission Act of 2007 - (Sec. 4) Establishes: (1) the Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission to plan, develop, and execute programs and activities to commemorate the 400th anniversary of the voyage of Samuel de Champlain (the first European to discover and explore Lake Champlain); and (2) the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission to plan, develop, and execute programs and activities to commemorate the 400th anniversary of the voyage of Henry Hudson (the first European to sail up the Hudson River) and the 200th anniversary of the voyage of Robert Fulton (the first person to use steam navigation on a commercial basis). (Sec. 6) Sets forth requirements regarding Commission meetings, including a requirement for such meetings at least twice annually or at the call of the Chairperson or majority of Commission members.(Sec. 7) Sets forth Commission powers. Prohibits the Commissions from purchasing real estate. Authorizes the Commissions to make grants not to exceed $20,000 to: (1) communities, nonprofit organizations, and state commemorative commissions to develop programs to assist in the Champlain and Hudson-Fulton commemorations; and (2) research and scholarly organizations to research, publish, or distribute information relating to the early history of the voyages of Samuel de Champlain, Henry Hudson, and Robert Fulton. Directs the Champlain Commission to coordinate and consult with the Lake Champlain Basin Program to provide grants and technical assistance for the development of activities commemorating the voyage of Samuel de Champlain. (Sec. 8) Authorizes the Commissions to accept the services of, and provide reimbursement for, personnel detailed from New York or Vermont and the Lake Champlain Basin Program.(Sec. 9) Requires the Commissions to report to the Secretary by September 30, 2010, regarding their activities, funds received and expended, and their findings and recommendations. (Sec. 10) Terminates the Commissions on December 31, 2010. (Sec. 11) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
