<bill session="110" type="h" number="5724" updated="2013-07-19T21:53:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States-Colombia Trade Promotion Agreement Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To implement the United States-Colombia Trade Promotion Agreement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2008-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1092 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5724. The resolution relates to the consideration of H.R. 5724, to implement the United States-Columbia Trade Promotion Agreement. The resolution provides that section 151(e)(1) and section 151(f)(1) of the Trade Act of 1974 shall not apply in the case of H.R. 5724.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-10T13:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1092 passed House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="1092"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hr" number="1252"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="2830"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Textile industry"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/2008--Introduced.
United States-Colombia Trade Promotion Agreement Implementation Act - Approves the United States-Colombia Trade Promotion Agreement (the Agreement) entered into with the government of Colombia. Provides for the Agreement's entry into force upon certain conditions being met on or after January 1, 2009.Authorizes the President to proclaim actions, and other appropriate officers of the U.S. government to issue regulations, necessary to ensure appropriate implementation of any provision of this Act that takes effect on the date the Agreement enters into force.Provides for: (1) administration of dispute settlement proceedings; (2) arbitration of certain claims against the United States; and (3) specified tariff modifications. Prescribes requirements for: (1) enforcement of textile and apparel rules of origin; (2) actions for relief from imports benefiting from the Agreement; and (3) certain textile and apparel safeguard measures.Amends the Trade Agreements Act of 1979 to make eligible for U.S. government procurement products or services of a foreign country or instrumentality that is a party to the Agreement.Provides for the following offsets: (1) amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to extend the authority for the collection of customs user fees for a specified period; and (2) amends the Tax Increase Prevention and Reconciliation Act of 2005 to increase by one percentage point the current increased percentage of any required installment of corporate estimated tax otherwise due in July, August, or September 2012, and by two percentage points the amount of any required installment of corporate estimated tax otherwise due in July, August, or September 2013.</summary>
</bill>
