<bill session="112" type="s" number="3289" updated="2013-07-20T02:45:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Children's Mental Health Accessibility Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to expand the Medicaid home and community-based services waiver to include young individuals who are in need of services that would otherwise be required to be provided through a psychiatric residential treatment facility, and to change references in Federal law to mental retardation to references to an intellectual disability.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2012-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2012-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4153"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/13/2012--Introduced.
Children's Mental Health Accessibility Act of 2012 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to: (1) expand the Medicaid home and community-based services waiver to include youth in need of services provided in a psychiatric residential treatment facility; (2) limit, under the waiver, the total number of Medicaid inpatient bed days at psychiatric residential treatment facilities during each fiscal year to the total number for the previous fiscal year as increased by the estimated percentage increase (if any) in the population of individuals under 21 residing in the state over the preceding 12-month period; and (3) change references to mental retardation to references to an intellectual disability.</summary>
</bill>
