<bill session="112" type="s" number="2233" updated="2013-07-20T02:35:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Jobs Originated through Launching Travel Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">JOLT Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to stimulate international tourism to the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2012-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2012-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2012-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2012-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2012-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2012-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2012-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2012-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Immigration, Refugees and Border Security . Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSJU04" subcommittee="Immigration, Refugees and Border Security" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3341"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3855"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5741"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2046"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3199"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Brazil"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2012--Introduced.
Jobs Originated through Launching Travel Act or the JOLT Act - Authorizes the Secretary of State to modify or enter into agreements with certain countries on a nonreciprocal basis to allow for longer visa validity periods. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to transfer authority to establish and collect the premium fee for employment-based petitions and applications from the Attorney General (DOJ) to the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS). Directs the Secretary of State to: (1) offer for a fee premium visitor visa processing (absent security concerns, within three business days of visa request); (2) decrease nonimmigrant visa application and issuance fees in selected countries when there is a low demand from such countries for visitor visas; and (3) conduct interviews and review applications within 15 days after an applicant's appointment request, and within one year after enactment of this Act, within 10 days after such request. States that the premium fee shall be sufficient to cover costs for: (1) processing such visas in China, India, and Brazil; and (2) creating mobile units to process applications and conduct interviews in large cities that do not have a U.S. embassy or consulate. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to admit into the United States a qualifying Canadian citizen over 50 years old and spouse and children, for a period of at least 240 days, if the person owns a U.S. residence or has rented a U.S. accommodation for the duration of such stay. Revises the visa waiver program to: (1) authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to designate any country as a program country; (2) adjust visa refusal rate criteria, including addition of a 3% maximum overstay rate; and (3) revise probationary and termination provisions. Amends the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to include in the Global Entry Trusted Traveler Network individuals who meet security requirements and are employed and sponsored by an international organization which maintains a strong working relationship with the United States. Prohibits enrollment in the Network of a person who is a citizen of a state sponsor of terror as defined in the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010.</summary>
</bill>
