<bill session="112" type="s" number="1802" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out programs and activities that connect Americans, especially children, youth, and families, with the outdoors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2011-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2012-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2012-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7131"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7131-7133" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="3353"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/2011--Introduced.
Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to issue one cooperative agreement per state to eligible entities to implement and update a five-year Healthy Kids Outdoors State Strategy for encouraging Americans, especially children, youth, and families, to be physically active outdoors. Requires each Strategy to provide for subgrants to local partners for the implementation of the strategy through one or more of the program activities relating to outdoor recreation as described in this Act. Requires eligible entities to provide a 25% match of the funding that they receive under this Act through in-kind contributions or cash. Directs the President to issue a national strategy for encouraging Americans to be physically active outdoors. Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to carry out a study of national significance on the health impacts of the strategies under this Act. Requires the Secretary to provide technical assistance to grantees and to disseminate best practices that emerge from the state strategies funded by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
