<bill session="109" type="s" number="1808" updated="2013-07-19T20:29:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Beneficiary Assistance Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to improve the qualified medicare beneficiary (QMB) and specified low-income medicare beneficiary (SLMB) programs within the medicaid program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2005-10-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10802-10803"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10803-10805" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="3980"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Computer matching"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Estates (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Welfare recipients"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/2005--Introduced.
Medicare Beneficiary Assistance Improvement Act - Renames the benefit programs for lower income Medicare beneficiaries under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA), commonly referred to as the "qualified Medicare beneficiary (QMB) program" and the "special low-income Medicare beneficiary (SLMB) program," as the Medicare Savings Programs. Amends SSA title XIX with respect to Medicare Savings Programs to: (1) increase the SLMB eligibility income level from 120% to 135% of the poverty line; (2) deem to be qualified Medicare beneficiaries in certain states individuals already receiving benefits under SSA title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI); (3) permit individual self-certification of income and use of a simplified QMB or SLMB application form; (4) provide for automatic reenrollment; (5) direct the Commissioner of Social Security to provide for QMB and SLMB outreach through local offices of the Social Security Administration; (6) eliminate the assets test; (7) prohibit estate recovery under QMB and SLMB; and (8) provide for three months retroactive eligibility with respect to Medicare cost-sharing for QMBs. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary), the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Administrator of Social Security to arrange for a demonstration project to identify Medicare beneficiaries who are likely, based on Internal Revenue Service (IRS) data, to qualify for benefits under the QMB or SLMB programs, or to be entitled to a premium or cost-sharing subsidy for low-income individuals under the Medicare prescription drug program. Requires the Secretary to enter into a demonstration project to provide states with funds to use such information to do ex parte determinations or utilize other methods for identifying and enrolling potentially eligible individuals. Requires the Commissioner of Social Security to send a notice and application for Medicaid benefits to individuals identified as likely to be eligible for QMB or SLMB benefits, or entitled to a premium and cost-sharing subsidy for low-income individuals under the Medicare prescription drug program, when notifying them of their eligibility for Medicare benefits.</summary>
</bill>
