<bill session="112" type="h" number="2272" updated="2013-07-20T01:29:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">LEARN Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Literacy Education for All, Results for the Nation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a comprehensive literacy program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2012-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2011-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2011--Introduced.
Literacy Education for All, Results for the Nation Act or LEARN Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to states for comprehensive planning to improve the literacy of children from birth through grade 12. Directs the Secretary to award grants to states to implement their comprehensive literacy plans for such children through: (1) competitive subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) or early learning programs for specified activities that support early language and literacy development in children from birth through kindergarten entry; (2) competitive subgrants to LEAs that have the highest numbers or percentages of disadvantaged students and students reading or writing below grade level for specified activities to improve the literacy of students in kindergarten through grade 12, including the provision of family literacy services; and (3) additional state activities that include providing technical assistance to subgrantees, coordinating literacy programs and resources throughout the state, disseminating information on promising literacy programs, and enhancing the credentials of literacy instructors. Allots implementation grants to states on the basis of each state's share of disadvantaged students. Requires the Secretary to: (1) perform a five-year national evaluation of the implementation and effect of the literacy initiatives supported by this Act, and (2) provide technical assistance and information on literacy instruction to educational entities. Authorizes the Secretary to withhold this Act's funding from states and subgrantees, and states to withhold funding from subgrantees, whose initiatives are not making significant progress in improving student literacy.</summary>
</bill>
