<bill session="111" type="s" number="874" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">El Rio Grande Del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Rio Grande del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish El Rio Grande Del Norte National Conservation Area in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2009-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4674-4675"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4675-4676" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-65.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-135.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="285">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 285.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5334"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Rio Grande Del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act - Establishes Rio Grande Del Norte National Conservation Area in New Mexico, consisting of approximately 235,980 acres of public land in Taos and Rio Arriba Counties for the purposes of conserving, protecting, and enhancing for the cultural, archaeological, natural, ecological, geological, historical, wildlife, educational, recreational, and scenic resources of such Conservation Area. Sets forth requirements for the management of the Conservation Area regarding the use of motorized vehicles and new roads, grazing, collection of pine nuts and firewood for noncommercial use, and utility right-of-way upgrades. Requires the Secretary to ensure the protection of religious and cultural sites and to provide occasional access to them by tribal members for traditional cultural and customary uses. Requires the Secretary to develop a management plan for the Conservation Area. Makes any acquired land within the boundary of the Conservation Area part of such Area. Bars the changing of the management status of any area within the boundary of the Conservation Area that is: (1) designated as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System; or (2) managed as an area of critical environmental concern. Designates the Cerro Del Yuta Wilderness and Rio San Antonio Wilderness as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Makes any acquired land or interests within the boundary of the wilderness areas part of the area in which the land is located. Sets forth requirements for the management of the wilderness areas regarding livestock grazing, protective perimeters and buffer zones, and activities and uses conducted outside the wilderness areas. Releases the public land within the San Antonio Wilderness Study Area not designated as wilderness from further study for designation as wilderness. Requires the Conservation Area and the wilderness areas designated by this Act to be administered as components of the National Landscape Conservation System. Specifies this Act's effect on fish and wildlife located on public land in New Mexico. Withdraws federal land within the Conservation Area and the Wilderness designated by this Act, including any acquired land and interests, from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. Prohibits anything in this Act from enlarging, diminishing, or otherwise modifying any treaty rights. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
