<bill session="109" type="s" number="3656" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HIV Prevention Youth Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide additional assistance to combat HIV/AIDS among young people, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2006-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2006-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2006-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2006-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2006-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7517-7518"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7518-7519" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Condoms"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Sex education"/>
    <term name="Sexual abstinence"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2006--Introduced.
HIV Prevention for Youth Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that sexually active young people who live in a country where HIV infection is spreading through the general population, rather than being confined to specific populations should be: (1) considered at high risk of contracting HIV infection; and (2) provided with the knowledge, skill-building programs, and tools to protect themselves from HIV infection. Amends the United States Leadership Against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria Act of 2003 to define "abstinence-until-marriage programs" as programs that place the highest priority on encouraging unmarried individuals to abstain from sexual activity, which if practiced 100% correctly and consistently is the only certain way to protect against exposure to HIV and other sexually transmitted infections. (Such programs include information on the health benefits of delayed sexual debut in reducing HIV transmission and may be used to support approaches that promote skill-building strategies for practicing abstinence.) Reserves at least 33% of the Act's appropriations for FY2006-FY2008 for prevention of the sexual transmission of HIV (currently, for HIV/AIDS prevention). Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to include within the activities for which HIV/AIDS assistance is available preventive intervention education for sexually active young people who live in a country experiencing a generalized HIV epidemic. Defines " generalized epidemic" as a country where: (1) HIV infection is spreading through the general population, rather than being confined to specific populations, such as sex workers and their clients, injecting drug users, and men who have sex with men; and (2) the HIV infection rate among people between the ages of 15 and 49 exceeds 1%.</summary>
</bill>
