<bill session="110" type="h" number="6094" updated="2013-07-19T21:57:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">World War II War Crimes Accountability Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To hold the surviving Nazi war criminals accountable for the war crimes, genocide, and crimes against humanity they committed during World War II, by encouraging foreign governments to more efficiently prosecute and extradite wanted criminals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-20">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-20">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3007"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Nazism"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2008--Introduced.
World War II War Crimes Accountability Act of 2008 - Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States should encourage extradition and prosecution of the remaining Nazi war criminals; (2) the Simon Wiesenthal Center should be commended for its historic work in bringing to light the atrocities of the Holocaust and in advancing justice for Nazi war criminals through Operation: Last Chance; and (3) the Office of Special Investigation of the Department of Justice is advancing U.S. foreign policy by bringing wanted World War II criminals to justice and should be commended for its actions. Directs the Attorney General, in evaluating the effect on U.S. law enforcement and security interests for purposes of a country's eligibility for visa waiver program designation, to consider the extent to which such country is: (1) cooperating in extraditing or prosecuting Nazi war criminals; and (2) admitting into its territory aliens ordered removed from the United States because of participation in Nazi persecution, genocide, torture, or extrajudicial killing. Authorizes the President, after congressional notification, to not terminate a country's designation based upon such evaluation if in the national interest.</summary>
</bill>
