<bill session="113" type="h" number="2218" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-25T11:41:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-25T11:41:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coal Residuals Reuse and Management Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Coal Residuals Reuse and Management Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Coal Residuals Reuse and Management Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act to encourage recovery and beneficial use of coal combustion residuals and establish requirements for the proper management and disposal of coal combustion residuals that are protective of human health and the environment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412487"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412541" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412427" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412508" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400657" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412549" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412463" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412280" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412462" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412392" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412538" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412402" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412428" joined="2013-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 31 - 16.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10T18:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-148.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-10T18:23:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="107">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 107.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 315 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2218 and H.R. 1582.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T09:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 315.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5055-5072" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T09:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2218 and H.R. 1582.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T09:17:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 315 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T09:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Rob Bishop to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T09:18:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2218.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T10:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 315, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly Part A Amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T10:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 315, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waxman Part A Amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Waxman Part A Amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Waxman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T10:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 315, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tonko Part A Amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T10:36:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tonko Part A Amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Tonko demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T10:37:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoptopn of amendments which were debated earlier and on which further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T11:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2218.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T11:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5070" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T11:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5061-5065" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T11:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. McCollum moved to recommit with instructions to Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5070" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5070" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T11:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proeeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCollum motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion to seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to require that the implementing agency of any coal ash permit granted under the bill ensure that all wet disposal structures meet criteria for design, construction, operation, and maintenance sufficient to prevent contamination of groundwater and sources of drinking water, including the Great Lakes pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T11:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5071" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T11:31:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 192 - 225, 1 Present (Roll no. 417).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5071" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="418" datetime="2013-07-25T11:41:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 265 - 155 (Roll no. 418).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25T11:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="153">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 153.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="315"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="315"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h414"/>
    <amendment number="h415"/>
    <amendment number="h416"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/25/2013--Passed House amended.
Coal Residuals Reuse and Management Act of 2013 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act (SWDA) to authorize states to adopt and implement coal combustion residuals (CCRs) permit programs. Requires each state governor to notify the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) within 6 months about whether such state will implement a program. Requires states that decide to implement a program to: (1) submit to the Administrator, within 36 months, a certification that the program meets the specifications of this Act; and (2) maintain either an approved municipal solid waste program or other system of prior approval and conditions under such Act for the control of hazardous disposal or an authorized state hazardous waste program. Requires the certification to include an emergency action plan for state response to a leak or spill at a structure that receives CCRs. Authorizes the state to update the certification as needed to reflect changes to the CCRs permit program. Establishes minimum requirements for CCRs permit programs. Requires the revised criteria established by this Act to apply to owners or operators of structures, including surface impoundments, that receive CCRs. Directs the agency responsible for implementing such a program to require that an independent registered professional engineer certify that: (1) the design of each structure that receives CCRs is in accordance with recognized and generally accepted good engineering practices for containment of the maximum volume of CCRs and liquids which can be impounded therein, and (2) the construction and maintenance of the structure will ensure structural stability. Directs such agencies to require the owner or operator of a structure that receives CCRs and that is classified by the state as posing a high hazard potential pursuant to the guidelines published by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), entitled "Federal Guidelines for Dam Safety: Hazard Potential Classification System for Dams," to prepare and maintain an emergency action plan that identifies responsible persons and actions to be taken in the event of a dam safety emergency. Directs such agencies to require the inspection of such surface impoundment structures at least annually by an independent registered professional engineer to assure that the design, operation, and maintenance of the surface impoundment is in accordance with recognized and generally accepted good engineering practices for containment of the maximum volume of CCRs and liquids that can be impounded, so as to ensure dam stability. Directs such agencies to require: (1) the owner or operator of the structure that has had an inspection or evaluation that revealed a potentially hazardous condition to immediately take action to mitigate such condition and notify appropriate state and local first responders, (2) structures that are surface impoundments that receive CCRs to be periodically evaluated for appearances of structural weakness, (3) action to correct structural deficiencies according to a schedule determined by the agency, and (4) closing of a structure if such deficiencies are not corrected according to the schedule. Directs such agencies to require structures to be constructed with a base located a minimum of two feet above the upper limit of the water table, unless it is demonstrated that: (1) the hydrogeologic characteristics of the structure and surrounding land would preclude such a requirement, and (2) the function and integrity of the liner system will not be adversely impacted by contact with the water table. Directs such agencies to require that owners or operators of structures address wind dispersal of dust by requiring cover or by wetting CCRs with water to a moisture content that prevents wind dispersal, facilitates compaction, and does not result in free liquids. Authorizes owners or operators of structures to propose alternative methods to address wind dispersal of dust that will provide comparable or more effective control of dust. Directs such agencies to require that owners and operators apply for and obtain a permit incorporating the requirements of the CCRs permit program. Authorizes such agencies to: (1) obtain information for compliance purposes; (2) require monitoring and testing to ensure compliance; (3) inspect structures and review records relevant to the design, operation, and maintenance of structures; and (4) implement and enforce such program. Sets forth revised criteria for such programs with respect to: (1) design, groundwater monitoring, corrective action, and closure and post-closure for structures; (2) location restrictions for structures in floodplains, wetlands, fault areas, seismic impact zones, and unstable areas; (3) air quality; (4) financial assurance; (5) surface water; (6) record keeping; (7) run-on and run-off control systems for landfills and other land-based units other than surface impoundments that receive CCRs; and (8) run-off control systems for surface impoundments that receive CCRs. Requires states to notify owners and operators of such structures of the obligation to apply for and obtain a permit and the groundwater record keeping requirements no later than: (1) 12 months after a state submits a certification of a program under this Act, (2) 30 months after a state notifies the Administrator that it does not intend to develop such program, or (3) 36 months after the enactment of such program that is being implemented by the Administrator. Directs such agencies to require such owners or operators to comply with such criteria and groundwater record keeping requirements no later than: (1) 12 months after a state submits its certification, (2) 42 months after the Administrator receives notice that a state will not operate its own permit program, or (3) 48 months after the enactment of such program that is being implemented by the Administrator. Requires such agencies to issue a final permit incorporating the requirements of such program or final denial for an application no later than: (1) 48 months after the state submits its certification, (2) 78 months after the Administrator receives notice from a state that it does not intend to operate its own permit program, or (3) 84 months after the enactment of such program that is being implemented by the Administrator. Requires agency collaboration with a structure's owner or operator to identify a deadline by which a permit application must be submitted. Authorizes owners and operators to continue to operate under existing authority: (1) until such deadlines are in effect, and (2) after such deadlines are in effect and before such agency has issued a final permit incorporating the requirements of such program if a structure meets such criteria and has not been directed to close. Sets forth: (1) closure requirements for surface impoundments if they do not have specified liner systems and do not meet specified design criteria for municipal solid waste landfills, (2) deadlines for compliance with the groundwater protection standard for structures subject to corrective action; and (3) requirements for extending deadlines. Requires the time period and method for a structure's closure to be set forth in a closure plan that establishes a deadline for completion and that takes into account the structure's site-specific characteristics. Directs the closure plan for a surface impoundment to require the removal of liquid and the stabilization of remaining waste as necessary to support the final cover. Requires the Administrator to: (1) provide a state with notice of, and an opportunity to remedy, deficiencies; and (2) consider certain criteria in determining if a state program is deficient. Requires the Administrator to implement such a program for a state only if: (1) the governor of the state notifies the Administrator that the state will not implement a program; (2) the state is notified of, but fails to remedy, program deficiencies; or (3) the state notifies the Administrator that it will no longer implement such a program. Authorizes a state to obtain review of a determination by the Administrator that the state has failed to remedy such deficiencies as if such determination was a final regulation. Prohibits the Administrator from having concurrent enforcement authority when a state is implementing a CCRs permit program, unless assistance is provided at the request of the head of a lead state agency that is implementing the program. Prohibits the Administrator from applying such programs to the utilization, placement, and storage of CCRs at surface mining and reclamation operations. Prohibits this Act from being construed as affecting the authority of the Administrator under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) with respect to CCRs. (Sec. 3) Prohibits this Act from being construed to: (1) alter the EPA regulatory determination, entitled "Notice of Regulatory Determination on Wastes from the Combustion of Fossil Fuels," that the fossil fuel combustion wastes addressed do not warrant regulation under SWDA; (2) affect the authority of a state to request, or the Administrator to provide, technical assistance under SWDA; or (3) affect the obligations of the owner or operator of a structure (as defined by SWDA) under the Federal Power Act concerning electric reliability.</summary>
</bill>
