<bill session="110" type="s" number="666" updated="2013-07-19T22:26:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oil Industry Tax Break Repeal Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to terminate certain incentives for oil and gas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Depletion allowances"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy transportation"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Geophysical prediction"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2007--Introduced.
Oil Industry Tax Break Repeal Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase the amortization period for the geological and geophysical expenditures of certain large integrated oil companies (defined as having an average daily worldwide crude oil production level of at least 500,000 barrels and more than $1 billion in gross receipts) from five to seven years; (2) limit the oil depletion allowance; (3) terminate accelerated depreciation of natural gas distribution lines and Alaska natural gas pipelines, expensing of equipment used in refining of liquid fuels, the tax deduction for intangible drilling and development costs, and the tax credits for enhanced oil recovery and for producing oil and gas from marginal wells; (4) classify natural gas gathering lines as 15-year property for depreciation purposes; and (5) deny large integrated oil companies the tax deduction for income attributable to the domestic production of oil, natural gas, or related products.Requires large integrated oil companies to revalue their LIFO inventories of crude oil, natural gas, or other petroleum products according to a specified formula. Denies such oil companies a foreign tax credit for payments to certain foreign countries from which they receive a specified economic benefit as a dual capacity taxpayer. Establishes in the Treasury the Energy Trust Fund and directs the transfer to such Fund of revenues resulting from the repeal of oil industry tax benefits by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
