<bill session="110" type="s" number="3065" updated="2013-07-19T22:48:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area and Dominguez Canyon Wilderness Area Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area and Dominguez Canyon Wilderness Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area and the Dominguez Canyon Wilderness Area.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400619"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-603.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="997">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 997.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="6162"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Stream conservation"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended.
Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area and Dominguez Canyon Wilderness Area Act - Establishes the Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area in Colorado to conserve and protect the unique and nationally important values of certain public land and the water resources of area streams that are necessary to support aquatic, riparian, and terrestrial species and communities. Requires management of the Conservation Area as a component of the National Landscape Conservation System. Specifies the uses of the Conservation Area, including allowing the use of motorized vehicles in the Area. Designates certain lands in Mesa, Montrose, and Delta Counties in Colorado as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System, to be known as the Dominguez Canyon Wilderness Area. Sets forth provisions for the management of the Conservation Area and the Wilderness, including with regard to: (1) grazing leases and permits and the grazing of livestock; (2) the control of fire, insects, diseases, and nonnative invasive plants and noxious weeds; and (3) water rights. Withdraws all federal land within the Conservation Area and the Wilderness and all land and interests in land acquired by the United States within such area and wilderness from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire non-federal land within the boundaries of the Conservation Area or the Wilderness only through exchange, donation, or purchase from a willing seller. Provides for the continuation of adequate access by private landowners to inholdings in the Conservation Area. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) develop a comprehensive management plan for the long-term protection and management of the Conservation Area; and (2) establish the Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area Advisory Council to advise the Secretary on the preparation and implementation of the management plan. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
