<bill session="110" type="h" number="655" updated="2013-07-19T21:09:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pathway to Preservation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for more accurate valuation of multifamily housing properties, and loans for such properties, that are sold at a discount by the Department of Housing and Urban Development to facilitate acquisition of such properties that maintains the properties as affordable housing.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Cooperative housing"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2007--Introduced.
Pathway to Preservation Act of 2007 - Amends the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 to redefine "loan market value," which currently means the value of a multifamily (rental or cooperative housing project) loan, without taking into account any affordability requirements. Repeals the condition that affordability requirements not be taken into account. Defines "loan market value" as the value of a multifamily (rental or cooperative housing project) loan using industry standard appraisal practices, including consideration of the cost of repairs needed for the property subject to the loan to comply with minimum safety and building standards and the cost of maintaining the affordability restrictions applicable under the original loan or grant for the property. Redefines "property market value," which currently means the value of a multifamily (rental or cooperative housing project) real property for its current use, without taking into account any affordability requirements. Repeals the condition that affordability requirements not be taken into account. Defines "property market value" as the value of a multifamily (rental or cooperative housing project) real property for its current use, as determined using industry standard appraisal practices, including consideration of the cost of repairs needed for the property subject to the loan to comply with minimum safety and building standards and the cost of maintaining the affordability restrictions applicable under the original loan or grant for the property.</summary>
</bill>
