<bill session="109" type="h" number="5727" updated="2013-07-19T19:55:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Meat and Poultry Products Traceability and Safety Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act and the Poultry Products Inspection Act to improve the safety of meat and poultry products by enhancing the ability of the Secretary of Agriculture to retrieve the history, use, and location of a meat or poultry product through a recordkeeping and audit system or registered identification, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400101"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2006-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock and Horticulture .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Livestock and Horticulture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3601"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3601"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural estimating and reporting"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cattle"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Goats"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat inspection"/>
    <term name="Meat packing industry"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Produce trade"/>
    <term name="Sheep"/>
    <term name="Swine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2006--Introduced.
Meat and Poultry Products Traceability and Safety Act of 2006 - Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act and the Poultry Products Inspection Act to direct that cattle, sheep, swine, goats, horses, mules and other equines, and poultry presented for slaughter for human consumption, and the carcasses or parts of carcasses and the meat and food products of those animals shipped in interstate commerce be identified in a manner that enables the Secretary of Agriculture to trace: (1) each animal to any location at which the animal was held at any time before slaughter; and (2) each carcass or part of a carcass and food product forward from slaughter through processing and distribution to the ultimate consumer. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) prohibit or restrict entry to a slaughtering establishment of an animal not so identified; and (2) require that each person, firm, or corporation required to identify livestock maintain accurate records. Directs the Secretary to establish a traceability system for all stages of production, processing, and distribution of meat and meat food products and poultry and poultry food products.</summary>
</bill>
