<bill session="112" type="s" number="3691" updated="2013-07-20T02:48:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening The Resiliency of Our Nation on the Ground Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STRONG Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to minimize the economic and social costs resulting from losses of life, property, well-being, business activity, and economic growth associated with extreme weather events by ensuring that the United States is more resilient to the impacts of extreme weather events in the short- and long-term, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2012-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-12-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8204"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2012--Introduced.
Strengthening The Resiliency of Our Nation on the Ground Act or the STRONG Act - Requires the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to establish and chair an interagency working group with cabinet-level representation from all relevant federal agencies in order to: (1) provide a strategic vision of extreme weather resilience; (2) conduct a gap and overlap analysis of federal agencies' current and planned activities related to achieving short- and long-term resilience to extreme weather and its impacts on the United States, such as flooding and drought; and (3) develop a National Extreme Weather Resilience Plan. Requires the Plan to include the establishment of an online, publicly available information clearinghouse to be used by federal agencies and other stakeholders to inform resilience-enhancing efforts and to build off and complement existing federal efforts. Provides for a coordinating entity to establish and maintain such clearinghouse. Requires such coordinating entity to coordinate the implementation of the Plan and to track its progress. Requires the submission of specified reports.</summary>
</bill>
