<bill session="109" type="s" number="1374" updated="2013-07-19T20:25:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for a border preparedness pilot program on Indian land.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2005-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2005-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7989"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7989-7990" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-07-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="159">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 159.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Office of Domestic Preparedness, to establish a border preparedness pilot program of direct grants to up to six eligible tribal governments on Indian land located on or near the border of the United States with Canada or Mexico. Requires recipients to use grant funds to: (1) facilitate coordination with federal, state, and local governments of the tribe's response to a security threat to an international border of the United States; (2) enhance the tribe's capability as a first responder to an illegal crossing by an immigrant over such a border; (3) provide training and technical assistance in the use of effective surveillance technologies and integrated communication systems and equipment; and (4) provide technical advice and assistance to plan and implement strategies to detect and prevent any illegal entry into tribal land, and the transportation of any illegal substance within or near its boundaries.</summary>
</bill>
