<bill session="111" type="h" number="3416" updated="2013-07-19T23:42:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disaster Assistance Voting Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend to individuals evacuated from their residences as a result of a major disaster the right to use the absentee balloting and registration procedures available to military and overseas voters under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, to direct the Election Assistance Commission to make grants to States to respond to election administration needs which result from a major disaster, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2009-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2009--Introduced.
Disaster Assistance Voting Act of 2009 - Applies certain protections for absent military and overseas voters to individuals evacuated (eligible evacuees) as a result of a major disaster. Requires any eligible evacuee to be treated in the same manner as an absentee uniformed services voter and overseas voter for purposes of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act. Deems such an individual to be entitled to vote by absentee ballot for purposes of the National Voter Reigistration Act of 1993 and the Help America Vote Act of 2002. Directs the Election Assistance Commission to make grants to eligible states to: (1) restore and replace supplies, materials, and equipment used in the state election administration which were damaged as a result of a major natural disaster; and (2) conduct outreach and education for voters displaced for the same reason. Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require delay for at least three (currently, two) consecutive federal general elections before removal of eligible evacuees from the official list of voters by reason of their not voting or appearing to vote in several consecutive such elections. Requires each motor vehicle authority and each voter registration agency in a state to take necessary steps to notify individuals to whom their services are provided of the protections afforded by this Act and of the requirements for obtaining them, including submission of an affidavit stating that the individual intends to return to the place of residence where the individual is otherwise qualified to vote. Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to direct the President to send a similar notice to each individual and household receiving assistance under that Act.</summary>
</bill>
