<bill session="113" type="h" number="2550" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Minority Small Business Enhancement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to enhance services to small business concerns that are disadvantaged, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400350"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Minority Small Business Enhancement Act of 2013 - Amends the Small Business Act to consider an individual with a net worth of less than $1.5 million as eligible for participation in a Small Business Administration (SBA) program providing grants to small businesses owned and controlled by economically disadvantaged individuals. Allows a small business to receive SBA developmental assistance under the program for the entire period of an SBA-guaranteed loan. Redefines the term "bundled contract" to mean a contract or order entered into to meet procurement requirements that are consolidated in a bundling of contract requirements, without regard to its designation by the procuring agency or whether a study of the effects of the solicitation on civilian or military personnel has been made, subject to exceptions. Expands the definition of "bundling of contract requirements." Makes the revised and expanded definitions inapplicable to contracts for construction services under $65 million or under $5 million for all other types of contracts. Increases from: (1) 23% to 25% the government-wide small business procurement contract goal, and (2) 5% to 10% the government-wide procurement goal for small disadvantaged businesses and women-owned businesses. Limits the number of categories for which a small business may qualify under such goals. Requires a report from the Comptroller General to Congress on disparities in the awarding of federal contracts to small businesses owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, small businesses, and other businesses.</summary>
</bill>
