<bill session="112" type="h" number="3685" updated="2013-07-20T01:42:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Herger-Feinstein Quincy Library Group Forest Recovery Act to extend and expand the scope of the pilot forest management project required by that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2011-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2011-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 16.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-06-15T11:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-524, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-15T11:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-06-15T11:27:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="372">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 372.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2578"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2012--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Amends the Herger-Feinstein Quincy Library Group Forest Recovery Act (the Act) to extend the term of the pilot forest management project for the Plumas, Lassen, and Tahoe National Forests in California. Requires that when the Regional Forester for Region 5 initiates the process of amending or revising such plans for the pilot project area (the federal lands within the Plumas and Lassen National Forests and the Sierraville Ranger District of Tahoe National Forest designated as available for group selection) the process include the preparation of at least one alternative that incorporates the pilot project and area designations, the resource management activities, and other aspects of the Quincy Library Group Community Stability Proposal. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to expand the pilot project area to include all of the National Forest System lands in California or Nevada that lie within the Sierra Nevada and Cascade Province, Lake Tahoe Basin Management Unit, and Humboldt-Toiyabe and Inyo National Forests. Deems those areas that are designated as deferred under the Act, but located in Tehama County, south and west of Lassen Peak, as being designated as available for group selection.</summary>
</bill>
