<bill session="111" type="h" number="4757" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Insurance Rate Authority Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of a Health Insurance Rate Authority to establish limits on premium rating, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2010-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2010-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3078"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2010--Introduced.
Health Insurance Rate Authority Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a uniform process for the review of potentially unreasonable increases in rates for health insurance coverage, including premiums. Directs the Secretary to establish a Health Insurance Rate Authority to advise and make recommendations to the Secretary. Sets forth corrective actions for unreasonable increases in rates. Requires the Secretary to ensure that the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or other appropriate body will provide to the Secretary and the Authority a report on: (1) state authority to review rates and take corrective action; (2) rating requests received by a state and actions taken; (3) justifications by insurance issuers for rate requests; and (4) a recommended definition of unreasonable rate increase. Requires the Secretary to determine for which states: (1) the state insurance commissioner will review rate increases and take corrective action; and (2) the Secretary will undertake such actions based on the Secretary's determination that such states lack sufficient authority and capability. Directs the Secretary to develop a uniform data collection system for new and increased rate information. Requires the Authority to produce annually a single, aggregate report on insurance market behavior. Directs states, as a condition of receiving a grant under this Act, to provide the Secretary with information about trends in rate increases in health insurance coverage in premium rating areas in the state. Requires the Secretary to carry out a program to award grants to states to carry out this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to enforce this Act if a state does not substantially enforce its provisions. Establishes civil penalties for violations.</summary>
</bill>
