<bill session="110" type="h" number="482" updated="2013-07-19T21:08:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-07T14:39:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-02-07T14:39:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American River Pump Station Project Transfer Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">American River Pump Station Project Transfer Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">American River Pump Station Project Transfer Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to transfer ownership of the American River Pump Station Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-06T13:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Napolitano moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-06T13:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1227-1228" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-06T13:19:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 482.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-06T13:25:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07T14:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1303" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-02-07T14:39:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="80" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 425 - 0 (Roll no. 80).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 2/6/2007 H1227" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07T14:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-119.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-06-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="252">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 252.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
American River Pump Station Project Transfer Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to transfer ownership of the American River Pump Station Project located at Auburn, California, to the Placer County Water Agency. Makes federal costs associated with construction of the Project nonreimbursable. Authorizes the Secretary to grant title to the Agency in full satisfaction of U.S. obligations under Land Purchase Contract 14-06-859-308 to provide a water supply to that Agency. Requires the Secretary, before conveying such land and facilities, to comply with requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, the Endangered Species Act of 1973, and any other applicable law. Provides that, upon the transfer, the United States shall not be liable for damages relating to the land or facilities.</summary>
</bill>
