<bill session="110" type="h" number="6690" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sound Dollar and Economic Stimulus Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To stimulate the economy and provide for a sound United States dollar by defining a value for the dollar, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Open market operations"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2008--Introduced.
Sound Dollar and Economic Stimulus Act of 2008 - Requires the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to: (1) make the value of the U.S. dollar equal to the market value of 0.05 of a troy ounce of gold; and (2) maintain that value at this level.Directs the Board to: (1) conduct open market operations against an explicit target for the price of gold on the exchange operated by the Commodities Exchange, Inc. (COMEX) of the New York Mercantile Exchange, Inc.; and (2) not perform such operations indirectly, as in the current practice of targeting the federal funds rate.Requires the Board to use its banking and bank regulatory powers to maintain and promote stable and effective financial markets during and after the transition to a defined value for the U.S. dollar.Entitles all entities that depreciate capital assets for tax purposes to 100% expensing of all capital investment for tax purposes in the year that the investment is made.Requires the Congressional Budget Office (CBO), in addition to the scoring CBO will do of the tax changes provided in this Act, to calculate the impact on federal revenues on a present value basis.</summary>
</bill>
