<bill session="110" type="s" number="1473" updated="2013-07-19T22:33:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Madera Water Supply Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to enter into a cooperative agreement with the Madera Irrigation District for purposes of supporting the Madera Water Supply Enhancement Project.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6850-6851"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6851-6852" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-376.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="1855"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation districts"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2007--Introduced.
Madera Water Supply Enhancement Act - Finds that: (1) the Bureau of Reclamation and others have conducted numerous studies regarding the Madera Water Supply Enhancement Project, California; (2) the Project is feasible; and (3) the Bureau shall not conduct any further studies or reports related to determining its feasibility. Requires all planning, design, and construction of the Project to be undertaken in accordance with a cooperative agreement between the Secretary and the Madera Irrigation District. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into a cooperative agreement for the support of Project design and construction. Limits the federal share of Project capital costs to 25%. Considers: (1) capital, planning, design, permitting, financing, construction, and land acquisition costs incurred by the District prior to this Act's enactment to be part of the nonfederal share; and (2) in-kind services performed by the District to be part of the local share. Requires the District to receive credit toward the nonfederal share for reasonable costs incurred from participation in the planning, design, permitting, financing, and construction of the Project and for the fair market value of lands used or acquired for the Project. Prohibits the Secretary from providing funds for operation or maintenance. Makes Project operation, ownership, and maintenance the sole responsibility of the District. Directs the Secretary, before obligating funds, to work cooperatively with the District to use plans, designs, and engineering and environmental analyses that have already been prepared by the District. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this Act 10 years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
