<bill session="112" type="s" number="1838" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program on service dog training therapy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2011-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2011-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2012-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7302" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-668.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/2011--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to commence a three-year pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of using service dog training activities as components of integrated post-deployment mental health and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) rehabilitation programs at Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) medical centers to positively affect veterans with such symptoms and to produce specially trained service dogs for veterans. Requires the pilot program to be carried out at one VA medical center selected by the Secretary other than the VA health care system in Palo Alto, California. Makes veteran participation voluntary. Requires the Secretary to: (1) collect program data to determine its effectiveness, as well as the advisability of expanding the program to additional VA medical centers; and (2) report annually to Congress for the duration of the pilot program.</summary>
</bill>
