<bill session="110" type="h" number="1562" updated="2013-07-19T21:17:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-27T19:57:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-03-27T19:57:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Katrina Housing Tax Relief Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Katrina Housing Tax Relief Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Katrina Housing Tax Relief Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend and expand certain rules with respect to housing in the GO Zones.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2007-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="2007-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-03-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-03-23T15:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 110-66.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-03-23T15:05:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="37">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 37.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-03-27T19:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rangel moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-27T19:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3150-3153" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-27T19:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1562.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-03-27T19:57:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3150" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-03-27T19:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax incentives"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/2007--Passed House amended.
Katrina Housing Tax Relief Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) qualify certain buildings in the Gulf Opportunity Zone, the Rita Go Zone, and the Wilma GO Zone (GO Zones) placed in service before 2011 for the housing tax credit without regard to certain otherwise applicable restrictions if such buildings receive (or received) a state or local housing credit allocation in 2006, 2007, or 2008; (2) extend through 2010 the treatment of such Go Zones as difficult development areas for purposes of the increased housing tax credit; (3) exclude certain assistance provided under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (e.g., community development block grants), the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2006, or the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Hurricane Recovery, 2006, in determining whether Go Zone buildings eligible for the housing tax credit are federally subsidized and therefore subject to limitations on such tax credit; and (4) treat qualified GO Zone repair and reconstruction loans provided prior to January 1, 2011, as qualified rehabilitation loans for purposes of the tax exemption for exempt facility and mortgage bonds.Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to the House Ways and Means Committee and the Senate Finance Committee on state and local practices in allocating and utilizing tax incentives provided by this Act. Requires such committees to hold public hearings if the report includes findings of significant fraud, waste or abuse.Denies a pre-levy hearing to taxpayers upon whom the Secretary of the Treasury has served a disqualified employment tax levy. Defines a "disqualified employment tax levy" as any levy in connection with the collection of employment taxes if: (1) the person subject to the levy requested a hearing with respect to unpaid employment taxes arising in the most recent two-year period before the beginning of the taxable period with respect to which the levy is served; and (2) such levy is served before February 29, 2016.Amends the Tax Increase Prevention and Reconciliation Act of 2005 to increase from 106.25% to 106.45% the estimated tax rate in the third quarter of 2012 for corporations with assets of not less than $1 billion.</summary>
</bill>
