<bill session="110" type="h" number="2389" updated="2013-07-19T21:24:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Energy Efficient Businesses Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To help small businesses to develop, invest in, and purchase energy efficient buildings, fixtures, equipment, and technology.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412225"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="2007-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3221"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3221"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric appliances"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2007--Introduced.
Small Energy Efficient Businesses Act - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to: (1) authorize financial assistance through the Small Business Administration (SBA) to state and local development companies for projects that reduce energy consumption by at least 10%, reduce the use of non-renewable energy sources, or generate renewable energy sources; and (2) provide loan limits for such projects. Amends the Small Business Act to direct the SBA Administrator to make small business loans to purchase energy efficient equipment or fixtures, or to reduce the borrower's energy consumption. Authorizes a small business development center to carry out a small business sustainability initiative (support to small businesses to evaluate their energy efficiency and achieve increased efficiency). Directs the Administrator to develop and coordinate a program to provide small business education on energy efficiency. Authorizes small business investment companies to issue Energy Saving debentures. Requires the Administrator to establish a Renewable Fuel Capital Investment Program under which the Administrator may: (1) enter into participation agreements with renewable fuel capital investment companies to promote the research, development, manufacture, and marketing of renewable energy sources; and (2) guarantee debentures issued by such companies.</summary>
</bill>
