<bill session="111" type="s" number="3842" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Justice for All Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Effective Administration of Criminal Justice Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect crime victims' rights, to eliminate the substantial backlog of DNA samples collected from crime scenes and convicted offenders, to improve and expand the DNA testing capacity of Federal, State, and local crime laboratories, to increase research and development of new DNA testing technologies, to develop new training programs regarding the collection and use of DNA evidence, to provide post conviction testing of DNA evidence to exonerate the innocent, to improve the performance of counsel in State capital cases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2010-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7510-7511"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7511-7515" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2010--Introduced.
Justice for All Reauthorization Act of 2010 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) include as a victim's right the right to be informed of rights and to be provided contact information for the Office of the Victims' Rights Ombudsman of the Department of Justice (DOJ); and (2) expand eligibility for post-conviction DNA testing in criminal proceedings other than death penalty cases. Amends the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 to revise the Debbie Smith DNA Backlog Grant Program to: (1) require the development of protocols and practices for the accurate, timely, and effective collection and processing of DNA evidence and require states and local governments to adopt such protocols and practices; (2) expand the authority of the Attorney General to make grants for the collection, processing, testing, and analysis of DNA evidence; (3) allow the use of grant funds to alleviate a backlog of cases with respect to a forensic science other than DNA analysis; (4) impose penalties on states and local governments for noncompliance with Program requirements; and (5) extend funding for the Program through FY2015. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to: (1) require government entities to coordinate with regional health care providers to notify sexual assault victims of the availability of free rape exams; and (2) authorize increased appropriations for FY2011-FY2015 for the Paul Coverdell Forensic Sciences Improvement Grant Program. Amends the Justice for All Act of 2004 to: (1) authorize increased appropriations for FY2011-FY2015 for crime victims legal assistance grants; (2) authorize appropriations for FY2011-FY2015 for DNA research and development, DNA programs of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), DNA identification of missing persons and human remains, and the Kirk Bloodsworth Post-Conviction DNA Testing Grant Program; (3) authorize appropriations for FY2011-FY2015 for legal representation of indigent criminal defendants in state capital cases; (4) authorize appropriations for FY2011-FY2015 for incentive grants to states to ensure consideration of claims of actual innocence in criminal cases; and (5) require the Director of the National Institute of Justice to establish best practices for evidence retention and to assist state, local, and tribal governments in adopting and implementing such practices. Effective Administration of Criminal Justice Act of 2010 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to require grant applicants under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program to include in grant applications a comprehensive statewide plan for the improvement of the administration of the criminal justice system. Makes it unlawful for government entities or their agents to engage in a pattern or practice of conduct that deprives indigent defendants of their constitutional rights to assistance of counsel in criminal proceedings.</summary>
</bill>
