<bill session="110" type="h" number="1887" updated="2013-07-19T21:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Superfund Equity and Megasite Remediation Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the financing for Superfund for purposes of cleanup activities with respect to those Superfund sites for which removal and remedial action is estimated to cost more than $50 million, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400178"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2007-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1179"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1179"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Pollution taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2007--Introduced.
Superfund Equity and Megasite Remediation Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reinstate the Hazardous Substance Superfund financing rate and the corporate environmental income tax, except in certain calendar quarters in which the unobligated balance in the Hazardous Substance Superfund exceeds $5.7 billion. Provides for a 50% increase in the Hazardous Substance Superfund financing rate and the corporate environmental income tax between 2008 and 2013 to fund response actions at Superfund sites estimated to cost more than $50 million (megasites) or which pose high health risks.Establishes the Megasites and High Risk Sites Cleanup Account in the Hazardous Substance Superfund. Transfers to such Account revenues resulting from the temporary 50% increase in the Hazardous Substance Superfund financing rate and the corporate environmental income tax.Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to report to Congress annually on the progress of response actions funded by the Hazardous Substance Superfund.</summary>
</bill>
