<bill session="112" type="s" number="3365" updated="2013-07-20T02:45:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State Court Interpreter Grant Program Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Attorney General to award grants to State courts to develop and implement State court interpreter programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2012-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4823-4824"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4824-4825" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1258"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2012--Introduced.
State Court Interpreter Grant Program Act of 2012 - Directs the Administrator of the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice (DOJ) to make grants to state courts to develop and implement programs to assist individuals with limited English proficiency to access and understand state court proceedings in which they are a party. Authorizes the use of grant awards by state courts to: (1) develop or enhance a court interpreter program; (2) develop, institute, and administer language certification examinations; (3) recruit, train, and certify qualified court interpreters; (4) pay for salaries, transportation, and technology necessary to implement the court interpreter program; (5) provide for remote interpretation services to facilitate certified court interpretations when costs prohibit in-person interpretation; or (6) engage in other activities prescribed by the Attorney General.</summary>
</bill>
