<bill session="109" type="h" number="366" updated="2013-07-19T19:07:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-04T13:54:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-05-04T13:54:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vocational and Technical Education for the Future Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Vocational and Technical Education for the Future Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Vocational and Technical Education for the Future Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Technical Education Act of 1998 to strengthen and improve programs under that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2005-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2005-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400662" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400642" joined="2005-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2005-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400303" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2005-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="2005-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2005-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E100-101"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-03-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17T14:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 109-25.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-03-17T14:48:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="11">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 11.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-05-03T19:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 254 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 366 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and the Workforce now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T11:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 254 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 254.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2896-2917" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H2905-2912" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 366 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and the Workforce now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 254 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ray LaHood to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 366.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T12:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 254, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Castle amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T12:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 254, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Wu amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T13:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 254, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Millender-McDonald amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T13:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 366.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T13:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2915" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T13:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller, George moved to recommit with instructions to Education and Labor.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2915-2917" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2915" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T13:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the George Miller (CA) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require that the bill be reported back to the House with an amendment inserting a prohibition on the use of funds for propaganda.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T13:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2916" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T13:45:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 197 - 224 (Roll no. 153).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2916-2917" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-05-04T13:54:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="154" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 416 - 9 (Roll no. 154).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-07-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="155">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 155.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="254"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="250"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="109" type="s" number="250"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="250"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Automobile repair"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Career education"/>
    <term name="Charter schools"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Displaced homemakers"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal mandates"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Palau Islands"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Single-parent families"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h104"/>
    <amendment number="h105"/>
    <amendment number="h106"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/4/2005--Passed House amended.
Vocational and Technical Education of the Future Act - Amends the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Applied Technology Education Act of 1998 (the Act) to reauthorize and revise its programs. (Sec. 3) Revises the definition of vocational and technical education (VTE) to provide that the sequence of courses it offers: (1) may include preparation for careers requiring a baccalaureate degree (this is currently not permitted); (2) may include provision of skills or courses necessary to enroll in the required sequence; and (3) at the postsecondary level, provides for a one-year certificate, an associate degree, or industry-recognized credential. (Sec. 5) Extends through FY 2011 the authorization of appropriations for programs under the Act. Includes, as part of the funding for basic Perkins grants to States for VTE, funding for Tech-Prep education programs (currently funded separately under a title II repealed by this Act). (Sec. 6) Prohibits: (1) construing the Act to authorize Federal mandates with respect to State or local curricula or payment of any costs not paid for under the Act; (2) requiring a State to have academic and VTE content or student academic and VTE achievement standards approved or certified by the Federal government to receive assistance under the Act; and (3) precluding a State that declines to submit an application for assistance under the Act from applying for assistance under any other program administered by the Secretary of Education (the Secretary). Provides that these prohibitions shall not be construed to affect specified accountability requirements. (Sec. 7) Revises the allotment for national activities to reduce the portion of funds reserved for outlying areas. Revises hold-harmless provisions to set the FY 2005 funding level for VTE grants to States and for Tech-Prep programs as the minimum State allotment. Retains, for FY 2006, certain minimum State allotment requirements. Revises within-State allocation formulas to increase the minimum portion of funds to be distributed to secondary school programs and postsecondary VTE programs. Reduces the minimum portion for State plan administration, but retains a specified minimum monetary amount for such purpose. (Sec. 8) Sets forth separate core indicators of State performance for secondary and postsecondary VTE students. Requires academic standards for secondary students under the Act to conform with those established by States that participate in programs for disadvantaged students under title I, part A of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act (ESEA-IA), as amended by the No Child Left Behind Act of of 2001 (NCLBA). Requires eligible recipients to establish local adjusted levels of performance standards and agreements in their local plans. Requires both local and State reports to: (1) disaggregate data for each of the indicators of performance for the categories of students enumerated under ESEA-IA as amended by NCLBA; and (2) identify and quantify disparities or gaps in performance between any such category of students and the performance of all students served by the local recipient or State agency. (Sec. 9) Requires international comparisons to be in the aggregate, for purposes of national program performance information. Directs the Secretary to appoint an independent advisory council to advise on, and analyze findings and recommendations resulting from, a national program assessment. Authorizes the Secretary to award incentive grants to eligible agencies for exemplary performance in carrying out VTE programs under the Act. (Sec. 10) Increases VTE grant amounts for Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands. Directs the Secretary to make a grant to the Republic of Palau. Makes Palau ineligible for funding for outlying areas under the Act when it enters an agreement for extension of U.S. educational assistance after enactment of this Act. Extends the authorization of appropriations for grants to programs at tribally controlled VTE institutions. Prohibits the Secretary from requiring the use of a restricted indirect cost rate for such grants. Extends the authorization of appropriations for national and State-level occupational and employment information activities. (Sec. 11) Revises requirements for State administration to replace a reference to preparation for nontraditional training and employment with one to preparation for nontraditional fields. (Sec. 12) Requires State plans to describe how Tech-Prep activities will be carried out, with specified allocated funds, to prepare students for postsecondary education or employment in high-demand occupations, through a seamless program of advanced academic and technical courses that include a minimum of two years of secondary school preceding graduation and a minimum of two years of higher education or an apprenticeship program of at least two years following secondary instruction. Requires State plans to cover a six-year, rather than five-year, period. Includes charter school authorizers and organizers, parents, students, and community organizations among entities to be involved in the hearing process and State plan development. Includes institutions of higher education in State plan development, but removes a requirement for representatives of special populations. Requires State plans to include provisions for: (1) developing model sequences of courses for VTE content areas; (2) criteria to assess the extent to which local plans will promote continuous and substantial improvement in academic achievement and technical skill attainment; (3) development of a progression of courses to lead to a postsecondary one-year certificate, associate's or baccalaureate degree, or proficiency credential in conjunction with a secondary school diploma; (4) eligible recipients' mutual assistance and coordination in offering model sequences of courses; (5) linking of secondary and postsecondary VTE; and (6) comprehensive professional development of VTE and related personnel. (Sec. 13) Directs the State agency to use the local adjusted levels of performance in reviewing local evaluations to determine if a local program improvement plan is required and technical assistance is necessary. Authorizes the State agency to sanction local recipients and make alternative arrangements in specified circumstances. (Sec. 14) Revises requirements for State leadership activities to include: (1) use of technology in required mathematics and science education; (2) teacher development for teachers at secondary and postsecondary levels, with inservice and preservice training and increasing academic and industry knowledge and skills; (3) integrating academics and VTE to ensure achievement in core academic subjects; (4) incentive grants to eligible recipients for exemplary performance; (5) entrepreneurship education and training; and (6) supporting initiatives to facilitate transition of sub-baccalaureate career and technical education students into baccalaureate degree programs. (Sec. 16) Eliminates a special rule for redistribution of funds. (Sec. 17) Revises requirements for local plans for VTE programs to include: (1) comprehensive professional development of personnel; and (2) activities to prepare special populations, including single parents and displaced homemakers, for high-skill, high-wage occupations. (Sec. 18) Includes support of Tech-Prep programs among local uses of VTE funds. Sets forth local uses relating to: (1) the State-developed model sequence of courses; (2) linking of secondary and postsecondary VTE programs; (3) VTE-related mathematics and science education; (4) activities for special populations; (5) adult students changing careers or updating skills; (6) industry professionals as postsecondary faculty; (7) integration of academic education and VTE; (8) distance education; (9) entrepreneurship education and training; (10) development of new proposed model sequences of courses; (11) information on supportive services; and (12) training of automotive technicians in diesel retrofitting, hybrid, hydrogen, and alternative fuel automotive technologies. (Sec. 19) Repeals title II of the Act, Tech-Prep Education. (Sec. 20) Redesignates the current title III, General Provisions, as title II of the Act. Sets forth requirements for equitable participation of private school children in programs under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
