<bill session="112" type="h" number="6557" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">College Cost Reduction Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Higher Education Regulatory Reform Task Force, to establish procedures for the presentation and expedited consideration by Congress of the recommendations of the Higher Education Regulatory Reform Task Force, to establish requirements for college cost reduction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412239"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
College Cost Reduction Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Education to establish the Higher Education Regulatory Reform Task Force to prepare a report, that is to be submitted to Congress and made available on a publicly accessible website, on federal regulatory requirements for institutions of higher education (IHEs). Requires the report to contain: (1) a list of rules that are determined to be outmoded, duplicative, ineffective, or excessively burdensome; (2) an analysis of how the costs of such rules outweigh their benefits; (3) recommendations to consolidate, modify, simplify, or repeal such rules and a description of the justification for and impact of such recommendations; and (4) recommendations on establishing a permanent entity to review new regulatory requirements affecting IHEs. Requires the President to submit to Congress a legislative proposal for carrying out some or all of the recommendations contained in the report. Includes, as part of that proposal, a requirement that the Secretary promulgate regulations requiring IHEs to control annual tuition increases and penalizing noncompliant schools. Establishes congressional procedures to expedite consideration of the President's proposal.</summary>
</bill>
