<bill session="112" type="h" number="6611" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patient Access to Drugs in Shortage Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to promote public notification and provide incentives to reduce drug shortages, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412269"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2012-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2012-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2012-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2012-11-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-29">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/29/2012--Introduced.
Patient Access to Drugs in Shortage Act of 2012 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA), with respect to use of average sales price payment methodology for drugs and biologicals, to prescribe a formula for determining the payment amount, using the volume-weighted wholesale acquisition cost, for a multiple source or a single source sterile injectable drug product with three or fewer active manufacturers, if there is no period of exclusivity in effect or available. Incorporates such payment methodology under the hospital outpatient department prospective payment system for any such drug furnished between July 1, 2013, and January 1, 2020. Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to exempt from the rebate agreement requirement a multiple source drug furnished between July 1, 2013, and January 1, 2020, and for which payment may be made under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medicare Insurance). Amends the Public Health Service Act to exclude such multiple source drugs from the term "covered outpatient drug" subject to specified price limitations under the "340B" drug pricing program. Directs the Secretary to contract with an independent entity to study the effects of this Act on patient access to sterile products. Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to exclude certain branded prescription drugs on a specified drug shortage list from the annual fee imposed on branded prescription pharmaceutical manufacturers and importers.</summary>
</bill>
