<bill session="111" type="s" number="686" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dorothy I. Height and Whitney M. Young, Jr. Social Work Reinvestment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Social Work Reinvestment Commission to advise Congress and the Secretary of Health and Human Services on policy issues associated with the profession of social work, to authorize the Secretary to make grants to support recruitment for, and retention, research, and reinvestment in, the profession, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3686-3687"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3687-3690" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="795"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/2009--Introduced.
Dorothy I. Height and Whitney M. Young, Jr. Social Work Reinvestment Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish the Social Work Reinvestment Commission to provide independent counsel to Congress on policy issues associated with the recruitment for, and retention, research, and reinvestment in, the profession of social work. Directs the Commission to study and report to Congress on issues facing the social work profession, including: (1) fair market compensation, high social work educational debt, social work workforce trends, translating social work research to practice, and social work safety; and (2) state-level social work licensure policies and reciprocity agreements for providing services across state lines. Requires such study to assess the professional capacity of the social work workforce to serve and respond successfully to the increasing biopsychosocial needs of individuals, groups, and communities in certain areas, including aging and child welfare. Authorizes the Secretary to award: (1) workplace improvement grants to eligible entities and individuals to address workplace concerns for the social work profession, including caseloads, compensation, social work safety, supervision, and working conditions; and (2) research grants, education and training grants, and community-based programs of excellence grants. Directs the Secretary to: (1) contract with a national social work research entity to serve as a coordinating center and clearinghouse for information on activities funded under the grants; and (2) develop a multi-media outreach campaign and issue public service announcements that advertise and promote the social work profession.</summary>
</bill>
