<bill session="112" type="h" number="6477" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Taxpayer Protection Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen America's financial infrastructure, by requiring pre-funding for catastrophe losses using private insurance premium dollars to protect taxpayers from massive bailouts, and to provide dedicated funding from insurance premiums to improve catastrophe preparedness, loss prevention and mitigation, and to improve the availability and affordability of homeowners insurance coverage for catastrophic events, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412186"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2012--Introduced.
Taxpayer Protection Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish the National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection to advise the Secretary regarding the estimated loss costs associated with reinsurance protection contracts. Requires the Secretary to implement a program that utilizes premiums from eligible state or multi-state plans to pre-fund future natural catastrophe recovery by making available for purchase, only by such plans, contracts for reinsurance coverage. Requires such contracts to cover insured property losses covered under primary insurance contracts to homeowners, mobile home owners, renters, and condominium owners for specified natural perils. Prescribes requirements for the operation of state plans and the terms of reinsurance contracts. Encourages states to create and maintain catastrophe funds for themselves or with other states. Sets forth requirements for the treatment of insured losses and maximum federal liability. Establishes in the Treasury the Catastrophe Preparedness Fund, consisting of contract sales receipts and any amounts borrowed or earned, which shall be used to pay Commission administrative costs and loss payments under reinsurance contracts. Prohibits the authorization or appropriation of federal funds for the Fund or for implementing the reinsurance liquidity protection program. Establishes a post-catastrophe market stabilization program for liquidity loans to: (1) expedite payment of claims under state catastrophe insurance programs, (2) authorize the Secretary to issue loans to assist financial recovery from significant natural catastrophes, and (3) promote the availability of private capital to state catastrophe insurance programs in order to provide liquidity and capacity. Establishes the National Readiness, Preparedness and Mitigation Committee to administer a Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation Grant Program of grants to state and local governments, nonprofit organizations, and other appropriate public and private entities to develop programs and initiatives to improve disaster response, citizen preparedness and protection, and prevention and mitigation of losses from natural catastrophes.</summary>
</bill>
