<bill session="111" type="h" number="2006" updated="2013-07-19T23:29:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Elder Justice Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Social Security Act to enhance the social security of the Nation by ensuring adequate public-private infrastructure and to resolve to prevent, detect, treat, intervene in, and prosecute elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2010-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412224" joined="2010-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2009-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412234" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400442" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400092" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2009-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412188" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2009-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412289" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2009-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2009-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2009-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412233" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2009-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412313" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2009-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Energy and Commerce, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="795"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2009--Introduced.
Elder Justice Act - Amends the Social Security Act to establish an Elder Justice program under title XX (Block Grants to States for Social Services). Establishes within the Office of the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) an Elder Justice Coordinating Council (EJCC). Establishes the Advisory Board on Elder Abuse, Neglect, and Exploitation. Directs the Secretary to make grants to eligible entities to establish stationary and mobile forensic centers, to develop forensic expertise regarding, and provide services relating to, elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation. Directs the Secretary to provide incentives for individuals to train for, seek, and maintain employment providing direct care in a long-term care (LTC) facility. Directs the Secretary to make grants to LTC facilities to: (1) offer continuing training and varying levels of certification to employees who provide direct care to LTC facility residents; and (2) provide bonuses or other benefits to employees who achieve certification. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to assist LTC facilities in offsetting the costs for standardized clinical health care informatics systems designed to improve patient safety and reduce adverse events and health care complications resulting from medication errors. Directs the Secretary to ensure that HHS: (1) provides funding to state and local adult protective services services offices that investigate reports of elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation; and (2) collects and disseminates related data in coordination with the Department of Justice. Establishes a program of annual adult protective services grants to states. Directs the Secretary to make grants to eligible entities to: (1) improve the capacity of state LTC ombudsman programs to respond to and resolve abuse and neglect complaints; and (2) conduct pilot programs with state or local LTC ombudsman offices. Directs the Secretary to establish programs to provide and improve ombudsman training for national organizations and state LTC ombudsman programs. Amends part A of SSA title XI to require each individual owner, operator, employee, manager, agent, or contractor of an LTC facility receiving certain federal support to report to the Secretary and local law enforcement entities any reasonable suspicion of crimes occurring in such facility. Requires the owner or operator of such an LTC facility to notify the Secretary and the appropriate state regulatory agency of a facility's impending closure, as well as a plan for the transfer and adequate relocation of facility residents. Directs the Secretary to study and report to the EJCC and appropriate congressional committees on establishing a national nurse aide registry. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) study, analyze, and report to Congress, the Secretary, and the states on state laws and practices relating to elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation; and (2) develop objectives, priorities, policies, and a long-term plan for elder justice programs and activities. Requires the Comptroller General to review and report to Congress on existing federal programs and initiatives in the federal criminal justice system relevant to elder justice. Authorizes the Attorney General to award victim advocacy grants to eligible entities to study the special needs of victims of elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation. Directs the Attorney General to award grants to provide: (1) training, technical assistance, policy development, multidisciplinary coordination, and other types of support to local and state prosecutors and courts, as well as employees of state Attorneys General and Medicaid Fraud Control Units handling elder justice-related matters; and (3) similar types of support to police, sheriffs, detectives, public safety officers, corrections personnel, and other front line law enforcement responders who handle elder justice matters to fund specially designated elder justice positions or units designed to support front line law enforcement in elder justice matters. Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to reauthorize the missing Alzheimer's Disease patient alert program. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a long-term care facility worker employment tax credit.</summary>
</bill>
