<bill session="113" type="h" number="1422" updated="2013-11-02T06:31:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1978 to provide for Scientific Advisory Board member qualifications, public participation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412581"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412549" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400626" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 16.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-07-22T16:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 113-165.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-22T16:42:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="119">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 119.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2013--Reported to House amended.
EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2013 - Amends the Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1978 to revise the process of selecting members of the Science Advisory Board, guidelines for participation in Board advisory activities, and terms of office. (The Board provides scientific advice to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency [EPA].) Prohibits federally registered lobbyists from being appointed to the Board. Revises the procedures for providing advice and comments to the Administrator by: (1) including risk or hazard assessments in the regulatory proposals and documents made available to the Board, and (2) requiring advice and comments to be included in the record regarding any such proposal and published in the Federal Register. Revises the operation of Board member committees and investigative panels to: (1) require that they operate in accordance with the membership, participation, and policy requirements (including new requirements for public participation in advisory activities of the Board) contained in this Act; (2) deny them authority to make decisions on behalf of the Board; and (3) prohibit direct reporting to EPA. Adds guidelines for the conduct of Board advisory activities, including concerning: (1) avoidance of making policy determinations or recommendations, (2) communication of uncertainties, (3) dissenting members' views, and (4) periodic reviews to ensure that such activities address the most important scientific issues affecting EPA. Prohibits this Act from being construed as supplanting the requirements of the Federal Advisory Committee Act or the Ethics in Government Act of 1978.</summary>
</bill>
