<bill session="110" type="s" number="2489" updated="2013-07-19T22:42:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oglala Sioux Tribe Angostura Irrigation Project Modernization and Development Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Oglala Sioux Tribe Angostura Irrigation Project Modernization and Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance and provide to the Oglala Sioux Tribe and Angostura Irrigation Project certain benefits of the Pick-Sloan Missouri River basin program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2007-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-06-19">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Dorgan without amendment. With written report No. 110-506.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1090">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1090.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="883"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Oglala Sioux Tribe Angostura Irrigation Project Modernization and Development Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) carry out the modernization and improvement of facilities at the Angostura Irrigation Unit of the Pick-Sloan Missouri River basin program; and (2) provide for the delivery of water saved through such modernization and improvement for fish and wildlife purposes and environmental restoration on the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation (South Dakota). Authorizes appropriations.Establishes in the Treasury the Oglala Sioux Tribal Development Trust Fund. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) deposit $92.5 million into such Trust Fund by the first day of the 11th fiscal year after the enactment of this Act; and (2) make payments to the Oglala Sioux Tribe of the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation as requested by the Tribe pursuant to tribal resolution. Requires the Tribal Council to prepare a plan for the use of such payments for economic and infrastructure development and for educational, health, recreational, and social welfare objectives of the Tribe or members of the Tribe. Provides for the review and updating of such plan and the auditing of the activities of the Tribe in carrying out the plan. Prohibits payments to any member of the Tribe on a per capita basis. States that no payment made to the Tribe under this Act shall result in the reduction or denial of any service or program to which the Tribe or any member of the Tribe is otherwise entitled under federal law. Authorizes appropriations to pay the administrative expenses of the Trust Fund. Declares that nothing in this Act affects: (1) any right or claim of the Tribe under the Treaty of Fort Laramie of September 17, 1851, or April 29, 1868; or (2) reserved water rights of the Tribe.</summary>
</bill>
