<bill session="109" type="h" number="2862" updated="2013-07-19T19:29:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-22">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-11-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2006, Commerce, Justice, Science, State</title>
    <title type="popular">Commerce Department FY2006 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Justice Department FY2006 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Science FY2006 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">State Department FY2006 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Science, State, Justice, Commerce, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of State and Related Agency Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Science Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Science, State, Justice, Commerce, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Department of Justice Appropriations, Act 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Department of State and Related Agency Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Science Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Departments of Commerce and Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Science Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Departments of Commerce and Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Combat Meth Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Helping to House the Victims of Hurricane Katrina Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Science Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Science, State, Justice, Commerce, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Department of State and Related Agency Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Science Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for Science, the Departments of State, Justice, and Commerce, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2006, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An Act making appropriations for the Departments of Commerce and Justice, Science, and related agencies, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2006, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400435"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-10T11:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 109-118, by Mr. Wolf.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-06-10T12:00:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="66">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 66.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-06-13T19:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 314 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2862 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T11:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 314 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T11:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 314.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4415-4472" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR  H4437, H4449, H4455, H4457-4458, H4459-4460, H4461, H4463, CR 6/15/2005 H4494-4495" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T11:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2862 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T11:31:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 314 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T11:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Doc Hastings to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T11:33:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2862.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Obey amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Obey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Obey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Obey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Terry amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Terry amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Terry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Boswell amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T13:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Issa amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T13:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Davis (IL) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T13:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Velazquez amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T14:27:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Velazquez amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Velazquez demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Reichert amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Reichert amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Reichert demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T14:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Baird amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T15:05:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Baird amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Baird demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stearns amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Stearns amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Stearns demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Dreier amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>EXTENSION OF DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with an additional 8 minutes of debate on the Dreier amendment to be equally divided and controlled.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T15:52:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Dreier amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Mollohan demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T17:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T17:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Wolf moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T17:26:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T17:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2862 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14T17:27:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Wolf asked unanimous consent that, during further proceedings of H.R. 2862 in the Committee of the Whole and pursuant to H. Res. 314, the list of eligible amendments be limited to a list submitted to the desk. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T10:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4494-4553" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4498-4500" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4503-4504" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4504-4505, H4507-4508" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4509-4511" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4512-4514" label="text of Title VI as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4515" label="text of Title VII as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T10:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T10:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wolf amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T10:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Weiner amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Weiner amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Weiner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Weiner amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T11:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mica amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T11:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Inslee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T11:20:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Inslee amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Inslee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Inslee amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T11:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hayworth amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T11:50:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hayworth amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hayworth demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Hayworth amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T11:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Reyes amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moore (WI) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T12:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Porter raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Porter stated that section 607 of the bill sought to change existing law and constituted legislation in an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T12:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McDermott amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T12:51:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Flake demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Paul amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T12:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Hinchey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T13:38:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hinchey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hinchey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schiff amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T13:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Otter amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T13:52:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Chocola amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T15:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jones (OH) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jones (OH) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Jones (OH) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Hostettler amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T15:25:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hostettler amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hostettler demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T15:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Sanders amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T16:30:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sanders amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sanders demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the King (IA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T16:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Nadler amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T16:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stearns amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T17:10:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T17:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Wolf moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T17:53:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15T17:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2862 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T11:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4580-4606" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T11:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Paul amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T11:58:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Paul amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Paul demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Paul amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hefley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T12:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hefley amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hefley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Hefley amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T12:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Markey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T12:19:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Markey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Markey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Markey amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T12:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tancredo amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T12:31:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tancredo amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Tancredo demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Tancredo amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T12:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Cleaver amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T12:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tancredo amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tancredo amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Tancredo demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Tancredo amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T12:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T13:16:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson-Lee (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T13:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moran (VA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T13:28:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Moran (VA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Moran (VA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Maloney amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T14:04:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Maloney amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Maloney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T14:04:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of specified amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T15:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2862.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4605" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the remaining amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4605-4606" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4605" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-06-16T16:01:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="268" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 418 - 7 (Roll no. 268).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T16:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, Science and Related Agencies. Approved for full committee consideration without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported by Senator Shelby with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 109-88.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-06-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="137">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 137.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9745-9770, S9776-9802" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9745-9768" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>The committee substitute agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-09">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9865, S9867, S9872-9874, S9887-9888" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-12">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9898-9908" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-13">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9947-9949, S9953-9955, S9962-9980" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10002-10016, S10018-10028, S10031-10032" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10058, S10059-10066, S10070-10080" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2005-09-15" how="roll" result="pass" roll="235" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Yea-Nay Vote. 91 - 4. Record Vote Number: 235.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendments, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Shelby; Gregg; Stevens; Domenici; McConnell; Hutchison; Brownback; Bond; Cochran; Mikulski; Inouye; Leahy; Kohl; Murray; Harkin; Dorgan; Byrd.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02T16:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Wolf asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02T16:03:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02T16:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02T16:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Schwartz (PA) moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9492-9496" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9492" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02T16:04:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Schwartz (PA) motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 2862. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the managers on the part of the House to insist on the House level for the Small Business Administration's Business Loan Program Account and recede to the Senate on Section 525 of the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02T16:32:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9496" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02T16:32:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02T16:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02T16:33:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED APPOINTMENT OF CONFEREES - The Chair announced that the appointment of the managers on the part of the House would be postponed until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02T19:41:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Wolf, Taylor (NC), Kirk, Weldon (FL), Goode, LaHood, Culberson, Alexander, Lewis (CA), Mollohan, Serrano, Cramer, Kennedy (RI), Fattah, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-04">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-07T18:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 109-272 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9713-9811" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-08T18:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 538 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2862.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09T12:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 538 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09T12:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Wolf brought up conference report H. Rept. 109-272 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 538.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10065-10074" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09T12:58:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 2862.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09T14:03:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10074" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09T14:04:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 2862, the Chair announced that pursuant to the rule, the Yeas and Nays were ordered. The Chair postponed further proceedings on the adoption of the conference report until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09T14:53:00-05:00">
      <text>The House proceeded to consider the conference report H.Rept. 109-272 as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10082-10083" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09T15:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="2005-11-09T15:02:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="581" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 397 - 19 (Roll no. 581).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-15">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12812-12824" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-11-16" how="roll" result="pass" roll="329" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 94 - 5. Record Vote Number: 329.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12921-12923" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-11-22">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-11-22" type="public" number="109-108">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-108.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP16" subcommittee="Commerce, Justice, and Science and Related Agencies" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="314"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="538"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Arabs"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Arson"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Astronautics"/>
    <term name="Astronomy"/>
    <term name="Atmosphere"/>
    <term name="Attorneys general"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting Board of Governors"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Capital cities"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Clergy"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commission on Civil Rights"/>
    <term name="Community policing"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against the elderly"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Criminology"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="DNA"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dogs"/>
    <term name="Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug courts"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equal Employment Opportunity Commission"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal Prison Industries, Inc."/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Fishery agreements"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International employees"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="Iron and steel industry"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Legal Services Corporation"/>
    <term name="Legal aid"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Marijuana"/>
    <term name="Marine Mammal Commission"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine mammals"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Morocco"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oceanography"/>
    <term name="Office of Science and Technology Policy"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police communication systems"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Prison violence"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Severance pay"/>
    <term name="Shellfish"/>
    <term name="Singapore"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space exploration"/>
    <term name="Space shuttles"/>
    <term name="Space stations"/>
    <term name="Stalking"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Steel"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication systems"/>
    <term name="Telecommuting"/>
    <term name="Telemarketing"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Tobacco exports"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Turtles"/>
    <term name="U.S. Institute of Peace"/>
    <term name="Undercover operations"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h248"/>
    <amendment number="h249"/>
    <amendment number="h250"/>
    <amendment number="h251"/>
    <amendment number="h252"/>
    <amendment number="h253"/>
    <amendment number="h254"/>
    <amendment number="h255"/>
    <amendment number="h256"/>
    <amendment number="h257"/>
    <amendment number="h258"/>
    <amendment number="h259"/>
    <amendment number="h260"/>
    <amendment number="h261"/>
    <amendment number="h262"/>
    <amendment number="h263"/>
    <amendment number="h264"/>
    <amendment number="h265"/>
    <amendment number="h266"/>
    <amendment number="h267"/>
    <amendment number="h268"/>
    <amendment number="h269"/>
    <amendment number="h270"/>
    <amendment number="h271"/>
    <amendment number="h272"/>
    <amendment number="h273"/>
    <amendment number="h274"/>
    <amendment number="h275"/>
    <amendment number="h276"/>
    <amendment number="h277"/>
    <amendment number="h278"/>
    <amendment number="h279"/>
    <amendment number="h280"/>
    <amendment number="h281"/>
    <amendment number="h282"/>
    <amendment number="h283"/>
    <amendment number="h284"/>
    <amendment number="h285"/>
    <amendment number="h286"/>
    <amendment number="h287"/>
    <amendment number="h288"/>
    <amendment number="h289"/>
    <amendment number="h290"/>
    <amendment number="h291"/>
    <amendment number="h292"/>
    <amendment number="h293"/>
    <amendment number="s1648"/>
    <amendment number="s1649"/>
    <amendment number="s1650"/>
    <amendment number="s1651"/>
    <amendment number="s1652"/>
    <amendment number="s1653"/>
    <amendment number="s1654"/>
    <amendment number="s1655"/>
    <amendment number="s1656"/>
    <amendment number="s1657"/>
    <amendment number="s1658"/>
    <amendment number="s1659"/>
    <amendment number="s1660"/>
    <amendment number="s1661"/>
    <amendment number="s1662"/>
    <amendment number="s1663"/>
    <amendment number="s1664"/>
    <amendment number="s1665"/>
    <amendment number="s1666"/>
    <amendment number="s1667"/>
    <amendment number="s1668"/>
    <amendment number="s1669"/>
    <amendment number="s1670"/>
    <amendment number="s1671"/>
    <amendment number="s1672"/>
    <amendment number="s1673"/>
    <amendment number="s1674"/>
    <amendment number="s1675"/>
    <amendment number="s1676"/>
    <amendment number="s1677"/>
    <amendment number="s1678"/>
    <amendment number="s1679"/>
    <amendment number="s1680"/>
    <amendment number="s1681"/>
    <amendment number="s1682"/>
    <amendment number="s1683"/>
    <amendment number="s1684"/>
    <amendment number="s1685"/>
    <amendment number="s1686"/>
    <amendment number="s1687"/>
    <amendment number="s1688"/>
    <amendment number="s1689"/>
    <amendment number="s1690"/>
    <amendment number="s1691"/>
    <amendment number="s1692"/>
    <amendment number="s1693"/>
    <amendment number="s1694"/>
    <amendment number="s1695"/>
    <amendment number="s1696"/>
    <amendment number="s1697"/>
    <amendment number="s1698"/>
    <amendment number="s1699"/>
    <amendment number="s1700"/>
    <amendment number="s1701"/>
    <amendment number="s1702"/>
    <amendment number="s1703"/>
    <amendment number="s1704"/>
    <amendment number="s1705"/>
    <amendment number="s1706"/>
    <amendment number="s1707"/>
    <amendment number="s1708"/>
    <amendment number="s1709"/>
    <amendment number="s1710"/>
    <amendment number="s1711"/>
    <amendment number="s1712"/>
    <amendment number="s1713"/>
    <amendment number="s1714"/>
    <amendment number="s1715"/>
    <amendment number="s1716"/>
    <amendment number="s1717"/>
    <amendment number="s1718"/>
    <amendment number="s1719"/>
    <amendment number="s1720"/>
    <amendment number="s1721"/>
    <amendment number="s1724"/>
    <amendment number="s1725"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/22/2005--Public Law.
Science, State, Justice, Commerce, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006 - Makes appropriations for FY2006 for science-related programs, the Departments of State, Justice, and Commerce, and related agencies. Title I: Department of Justice - Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2006 - Makes appropriations for the Department of Justice for FY2006 for: (1) general administration, including for Department information sharing technology, conversion to narrowband communications, administration of pardon and clemency petitions and immigration-related activities, the Federal Detention Trustee, and the Department of Justice Office of Inspector General; (2) the U.S. Parole Commission; (3) legal activities, including reimbursement from the Vaccine Injury Compensation Trust Fund for processing cases under the National Childhood Vaccine Injury Act of 1986, for antitrust enforcement, the Offices of the U.S. Attorneys,the U.S. Trustee Program, and the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission; (4) the U.S. Marshals Service (including for courthouse security equipment, and construction in space controlled, occupied, or utilized by the U.S. Marshals Service in U.S. courthouses and federal buildings), fees and expenses of witnesses, the Community Relations Service, and for certain uses of the Assets Forfeiture Fund; (5) interagency crime and drug enforcement; (6) the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); (7) the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA); (8) the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATFE); (9) the federal prison system, including for the construction of new buildings and facilities and for the Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated (subject to certain limitations on administrative expenses); (10) the Office on Violence Against Women for violence against women prevention and prosecution programs; and (11) Office of Justice Programs, including state and local law enforcement assistance, the Weed and Seed Program Fund, community-oriented policing services (including a transfer of funds), juvenile justice programs, and public safety officers benefits. Specifies certain uses and limits on, or prohibitions against, the use of funds appropriated by this Act. (Sec. 102) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated by this title to: (1) pay for an abortion, except where the life of the mother would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term, or in the case of rape; or (2) require any person to perform or facilitate an abortion. (Sec. 104) Declares that nothing in the prohibition against the use of funds for abortions shall remove the obligation of the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to provide escort services necessary for a female inmate to receive an abortion outside of a federal facility. (Sec. 105) Prohibits more than 5% of any appropriation made available for the current fiscal year for the Department of Justice in this Act from being transferred between such appropriations, but no such appropriation, except as otherwise specifically provided, shall be increased by more than 10% by any such transfers. Prohibits the transfer of any of the funds appropriated to "Buildings and Facilities, Federal Prison System" in this or any other Act to "Salaries and Expenses, Federal Prison System", or any other Department of Justice account, unless the President certifies that such a transfer is necessary to U.S. national security interests. Bars such authority from being delegated and subjects that authority to section 605 of this Act. (Sec. 106) Authorizes the Attorney General to extend through FY2007 the Personnel Management Demonstration Project for certain positions of the ATFE Bureau without limitation on the number of employees or the positions covered. (Sec. 107) Extends certain authorities for FBI and DEA undercover investigative operations to the ATFE Bureau in the conduct of undercover investigative operations and makes such authorities applicable with respect to any such operation initiated by the ATFE Bureau that is necessary for the detection and prosecution of crimes against the United States. (Sec. 108) Prohibits the use of funds made available to the Department of Justice in this Act for the purpose of transporting an individual who is a prisoner pursuant to conviction for crime under state or federal law and is classified as a maximum or high security prisoner, other than to a prison or other facility certified by the Federal Bureau of Prisons as appropriately secure for housing such a prisoner. (Sec. 109) Prohibits funds appropriated by this Act from being used by federal prisons to purchase cable television services, to rent or purchase videocassettes, videocassette recorders, or other audiovisual or electronic equipment used primarily for recreational purposes. Excludes from such prohibition the renting, maintaining, or purchasing of audiovisual or electronic equipment for inmate training, religious, or educational programs. (Sec. 110) Directs the Attorney General, within the funds provided under "Justice Information Sharing Technology", to establish an investment review board, which the Deputy Attorney General shall head. Requires the Department of Justice to submit: (1) a plan outlining the governance structure and membership of the board; and (2) to the House and Senate Appropriations Committees, the project criteria that will initiate the board's oversight, including a listing of all projects to be reviewed during FY2006. (Sec. 111) Repeals the prohibition limiting the selection of individuals for the FBI-DEA Senior Executive Service to career civil service employees. (Sec. 112) Directs the Attorney General, within funds provided for the DEA, to establish a Methamphetamine Task Force within the DEA, which shall be responsible for improving and targeting the federal government's policies respecting the production and trafficking of methamphetamine. (Sec. 113) Amends the Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003 to: (1) provide that nothing in the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 or any other provision of law shall prevent the Bureau of Justice Statistics of the Department of Justice, in carrying out the annual statistical review and analysis of the incidence and effects of prison rape required by that Act, from reporting to the designated public officials such information regarding child abuse or child neglect with respect to which the statutes or regulations of a state require prompt reporting; and (2) extend, by one year, the deadline for the National Prison Rape Elimination Commission to submit a report on its study on the impacts of prison rape in the United States. (Sec. 114) Requires the Attorney General to waive the matching requirement for the purchase of bulletproof vests under the Bulletproof Vest Partnership Grant Act of 1998 for any law enforcement agency that purchased defective Zylon-based body armor with federal funds pursuant to such Act between October 1, 1998, and September 30, 2005, and seeks to replace such body armor, provided that the law enforcement agency can present documentation to prove the purchase of Zylon-based body armor with funds provided to it under such Act. Title II: Department of Commerce and Related Agencies - Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006 - Makes appropriations for FY2006 for: (1) the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative; (2) the International Trade Commission; (3) the International Trade Administration (ITA); (4) the Bureau of Industry and Security; (5) the Economic Development Administration; (6) the Minority Business Development Agency; (7) economic and statistical analysis programs; (8) the Bureau of the Census; (9) the National Telecommunications and Information Administration; (10) public telecommunications facilities planning and construction grants; (11) the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office; (12) the Under Secretary for Technology/Office of Technology Policy; (13) the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), including amounts for the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership of NIST, the Advanced Technology Program of NIST, and construction of new research facilities; (14) the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), including transfers of funds and an amount for procurement, acquisition, and construction of capital assets; (15) restoration of Pacific salmon populations; (16) the Coastal Zone Management Fund; (17) the fisheries finance program account; (18) departmental management; (19) the U.S. Travel and Tourism Promotion Program; and (20) the Department of Commerce Office of Inspector General. Declares that, with regard to the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative and the ITA, negotiations shall be conducted within the World Trade Organization (WTO) to recognize the right of members to distribute monies collected from antidumping and countervailing duties. Instructs that the negotiations be conducted within the WTO consistent with the negotiating objectives contained in the Trade Act of 2002. Exempts the ITA from the requirements of Circular A-25 (or any successor administrative regulation or policy) issued by the Office of Management and Budget. Specifies certain uses and limits on, or prohibitions against, the use of funds appropriated by this Act. (Sec. 203) Prohibits more than 5% of any appropriation made available for the current fiscal year for the Department of Commerce in this Act from being transferred between such appropriations, but no such appropriation, except as otherwise specifically provided, shall be increased by more than 10% by any such transfers. Provides that, for NOAA, this section shall provide for transfers among appropriations made only to NOAA. Prohibits such appropriations from being transferred and reprogrammed to other Department of Commerce bureaus and appropriation accounts. (Sec. 205) States that, funds made available for salaries and expenses to administer the Emergency Steel Loan Guarantee Program under Public Law 108-199 (Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2004) shall remain available until expended. Amends the Emergency Steel Loan Guarantee Act of 1999 to extend the Emergency Loan Guarantee Board's authority from December 31, 2005, until December 31, 2007. (Sec. 206) Prohibits the use of any funds under this Act to register, issue, transfer, or enforce any trademark of the phrase "Last Best Place." (Sec. 207) Provides, from the amounts made available elsewhere in this title to the "National Institute of Standards and Technology, Construction of Research Facilities", specified amounts for: (1) a cooperative agreement with the Medical University of South Carolina; (2) the National Formulation Science Laboratory at the University of Southern Mississippi; (3) the University of Mississippi Research Park; (4) the Alabama State University Science and Education Building; (5) Tuscaloosa, Alabama, revitalization; (6) the Biomedical Research Center at the University of Alabama at Birmingham; (7) the Institute for Security Technology Studies; (8) Thayer School of Engineering; (9) WVHTCF Research Facility; and (10) the University of Alabama for the design and construction of the Science and Engineering Center. (Sec. 208) Provides, from the amount made available from the fund entitled "Promote and Develop Fishery Products and Research Pertaining to American Fisheries", specified amounts to be provided to: (1) the Alaska Fisheries Marketing Board; and (2) the Southern Shrimp Alliance for its "Wild American Shrimp Marketing Program." (Sec. 209) Transfers, from amounts made available under the heading "Procurement, Acquisition, and Construction, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration," a specified amount to NASA for the planning, design, and construction of Building 3203, for the planning and design of Buildings 3205 and 3216, and for certain infrastructure improvements. Title III: Science - Science Appropriations Act, 2006 - Makes appropriations for FY2006 for: (1) the Office of Science and Technology Policy; (2) the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), including a transfer of funds and for science, aeronautics, and exploration , exploration capabilities (including a transfer of funds), and the NASA Office of Inspector General; and (3) the National Science Foundation (NSF), including for research and related activities, major research equipment and facilities, education and human resources, the Office of the National Science Board, and the NSF Office of Inspector General. Requires the Secretary of Commerce, annually, to include in the budget justification materials that such Secretary submits to Congress in support of the Department of Commerce budget, an estimate for each NOAA procurement, acquisition, and construction program having a total multiyear program cost of more than $5 million and an estimate of the budgetary requirements for each such program for each of the five subsequent fiscal years. Specifies certain uses and limits on, or prohibitions against, the use of funds appropriated by this Act. Title IV: Department of State and Related Agency - Department of State and Related Agency Appropriations Act, 2006 - Makes appropriations for the Department of State for FY2006 for: (1) administration of foreign affairs, diplomatic and consular programs (including a transfer of funds); (2) the Capital Investment Fund; (3) the expenses relating to the modernization of the information technology systems and networks of the Department of State; (4) the Office of Inspector General; (5) educational and cultural exchange programs; (6) representation allowances; (7) protection of foreign missions and officials; (8) U.S. embassy security, construction, and maintenance; (9) emergencies in the diplomatic and consular service (including a transfer of funds); (10) the repatriation loans program account (including a transfer of funds); (11) the American Institute in Taiwan; (12) the Foreign Service Retirement and Disability Fund; (13) international organizations, peacekeeping, and commissions; (14) the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico; (15) plan preparation and construction of authorized projects; (16) the International Joint Commission and the International Boundary Commission, United States and Canada; (17) international fisheries commissions; (18) the Asia Foundation; (19) the Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue Trust Fund; (20) the Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Incorporated; (21) the Israeli Arab Scholarship Program; (22) the Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange Between East and West in the State of Hawaii; (23) the National Endowment for Democracy; and (24) the Broadcasting Board of Governors. Specifies certain uses and limits on or prohibitions against the use of funds appropriated by this Act. (Sec. 403) Bars the use of funds under in this Act by the Department of State or the Broadcasting Board of Governors to provide assistance to the Palestinian Broadcasting Corporation. (Sec. 404) Directs the Senior Policy Operating Group on Trafficking in Persons to coordinate policies related to international trafficking in persons, including traffickers and victims of severe forms of trafficking. (Sec. 405) Requires the Secretary of State, for purposes of registration of birth, certification of nationality, or issuance of a passport of a U.S. citizen born in the City of Jerusalem, upon request of the citizen, to record the place of birth as Israel. (Sec. 406) Provides, from the funds appropriated by this Act under the heading "Diplomatic and Consular Programs" specified amounts for: (1) an endowment for the Center for Asian Democracy; (2) a grant to the Center for the Study of the Presidency for a public diplomacy initiative; (3) a grant to Operation Smile for a public diplomacy program; and (4) a grant to MiraMed for programs to combat human trafficking. (Sec. 407) Makes funds appropriated under this title for the Broadcasting Board of Governors and the Department of State available for obligation and expenditure notwithstanding certain sections of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956, the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1994 and 1995, and the National Security Act of 1947. (Sec. 408) Makes funds provided in this title for Educational and Cultural Exchange Programs, National Endowment for Democracy, International Broadcasting Operations, and Broadcasting Capital Improvements available in the amounts contained in the respective tables included in the report accompanying this Act. (Sec. 409) Provides from the funds appropriated or otherwise made available in this title, not more than $1.0355 billion to be available for payment to the United Nations (UN) for assessed and other expenses of international peacekeeping activities. (Sec. 410) Amends the Foreign Affairs Reform and Restructuring Act of 1998 to extend the United States Advisory Commission on Public Diplomacy to October 1, 2006. (Sec. 411) Prohibits any of the funds appropriated under this title from being made available to pay any contribution of the United States to the U.N. if the U.N. implements or imposes any taxation on any U.S. persons. (Sec. 412) Expresses the sense of Congress that the amount of any loan for the renovation of the U.N. headquarters building located in New York, New York, should not exceed $600 million. Requires the Secretary of State, if any loan exceeds such amount, to notify Congress of the current cost of the renovation and cost containment measures. (Sec. 413) Prohibits the use of any of the funds by this title for any U.N. undertaking when it is made known to the federal official having authority to obligate or expend such funds that: (1) the U.N. undertaking is a peacekeeping mission; (2) such undertaking will involve U.S. armed forces under the command or operational control of a foreign national; and (3) the President's military advisors have not submitted to the President a recommendation that such involvement is in U.S. national security interests and the President has not submitted to Congress such a recommendation. (Sec. 414) Prohibits the expenditure of any of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available under this title for any purpose for which appropriations are prohibited by the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 for: (1) opening, operating, or expanding any U.S. diplomatic or consular post in the Socialist Republic of Vietnam that was not operating on July 11, 1995 or increasing the number of personnel assigned in that country; and (2) the issuance of visas to any individuals named or implicated in certain killings or murders in Haiti. (Sec. 416) Prohibits a project to construct a U.S. diplomatic facility from including office space or other accommodations for an employee of a federal agency or department if the Secretary of State determines that such department or agency has not provided to the Department of State the full amount of advanced funding for its share of the costs for such facility. Excludes the Marine Corps from such prohibition. (Sec. 417) Bars ceilings and earmarks contained in this title from being applicable to funds or authorities appropriated or otherwise made available by any subsequent Act unless such Act specifically so directs. Provides that earmarks or minimum funding requirements contained in any other Act shall not be applicable to funds appropriated by this title. Title V: Related Agencies - Makes appropriations for FY2006 for the : (1) Antitrust Modernization Commission; (2) Commission for the Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad; (3) Commission on Civil Rights; (4) Commission on International Religious Freedom; (5) Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe; (6) Congressional-Executive Commission on the People's Republic of China; (7) Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC); (8) Federal Communications Commission (FCC); (9) Federal Trade Commission (FTC); (10) Legal Services Corporation, including for basic field programs and required independent audits; (11) Marine Mammal Commission; (12) National Veterans Business Development Corporation; (13) Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC); (14) Small Business Administration (SBA), including the Office of Inspector General; (15) Surety Bond Guarantees Revolving Fund, the Business Loans Program Account, and the Disaster Loans Program Account; (16) State Justice Institute; (17) United States-China Economic and Security Review Commission; (18) United States Institute of Peace; and (19) United States Senate-China Interparliamentary Group. Authorizes the SBA to award grants under the Women's Business Center Sustainability Pilot Program. Requires that, of amounts provided for Women's Business Centers, not less than 41% shall be available to continue such Centers in sustainability status. Title VI: General Provisions - Specifies certain uses and limits on, or prohibitions against, the use of funds appropriated by this Act. (Sec. 601) Prohibits the use of any part of any appropriation contained in this Act for publicity or propaganda purposes not authorized by Congress. (Sec. 602) Prohibits any part of any appropriation contained in this Act from remaining available for obligation or expenditure beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly so provided herein. (Sec. 605) Prohibits the reprogramming of funds as specified, including any reprogramming that either creates a new program or eliminates an existing program, unless the Appropriations Committees of the House and Senate are notified 15 days in advance. (Sec. 606) Prohibits, hereafter, the use of any of the funds made available in this Act to implement, administer, or enforce any guidelines of the EEOC covering harassment based on religion, when it is made known to the federal entity or official to which such funds are made available that such guidelines do not differ in any respect from the proposed guidelines published by the EEOC on October 1, 1993. (Sec. 607) Provides that, if it has been finally determined by a court of federal agency that any person intentionally affixed a label bearing a "Made in America" inscription, or any inscription with the same meaning, to any product sold in or shipped to the United States that is not made in the United States, such person shall be ineligible to receive any contract or subcontract made with funds made available in this Act, pursuant to prescribed debarment, suspension, and ineligibility procedures. (Sec. 608) Requires the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, Broadcasting Board of Governors, NSF, NASA, FCC, SEC, and SBA to provide the House and Senate Appropriations Committees with a quarterly accounting of the cumulative balances of any unobligated funds that were received by such agency during any previous fiscal year. (Sec. 609) Requires any costs incurred by a department or agency funded under this Act resulting from personnel actions taken in response to funding reductions included in this Act to be absorbed within the total budgetary resources available to such department or agency. (Sec. 610) Prohibits the use of funds in this Act to promote the sale or export of tobacco or tobacco products or to seek the reduction or removal by any foreign country of restrictions on the marketing of tobacco or tobacco products (except for the reduction or removal of restrictions which are not applied equally to all tobacco or tobacco products of the same type). (Sec. 612) Bars amounts deposited or available in the Crime Victims Fund in any fiscal year in excess of $625 million from being available for obligation until the following fiscal year. (Sec. 613) Earmarks specified additional SBA funds for certain entities. (Sec. 614) Prohibits any of the funds made available to the Department of Justice in this Act from being used to discriminate against or denigrate the religious or moral beliefs of students who participate in programs for which financial assistance is provided from those funds, or of the parents or legal guardians of such students. (Sec. 615) Requires all disaster loans issued in Alaska or North Dakota to be administered by the SBA and to not be sold during FY2006. (Sec. 617) Requires the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the SEC, and the SBA to certify that telecommuting opportunities have increased over levels certified to the House and Senate Appropriations Committees for FY 2005, to make quarterly reports on the status of telecommuting programs, and to maintain a Telework Coordinator. (Sec. 618) Declares that the Secretary of Commerce, with the consent of the President, shall represent the U.S. Government in negotiating and monitoring international agreements regarding fisheries, marine mammals, or sea turtles. Makes such Secretary responsible for the development and interdepartmental coordination of U.S. policies with respect to such negotiations and agreements. (Sec. 619) Requires NASA and the NSF to certify that telecommuting opportunities are available to 100 percent of their eligible workforce, to make quarterly reports on the status of telecommuting programs, and to designate a Telework Coordinator. (Sec. 620) Provides that, any funds provided in this Act used to implement E-Government initiatives shall be subject to the procedures set forth in sec. 605 of this Act. (Sec. 621) Requires the ATFE Bureau to include certain disclaimers in data releases on the limitations of data in firearms tracing studies with respect to firearms-related crime. (Sec. 622) Prohibits any of the funds appropriated by this Act from being used by the FCC to modify, amend, or change its rules or regulations for universal service support payments to implement the February 27, 2004, recommendations of the Federal-State Joint Board on Universal Service regarding single connection or primary line restrictions on such payments. (Sec. 623) Prohibits the use of any of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available under this Act to issue patents on claims directed to or encompassing a human organism. (Sec. 624) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for the support or justification of the use of torture by any official or contract employee of the United States. (Sec. 625) Earmarks (out of amounts made available in this Act for the Departments of State, Justice, and Commerce, the U.S. Trade Representative, the Broadcasting Board of Governors, NASA, and the NSF) funds to implement the Capital Security Cost Sharing Program. (Sec. 626) Prohibits funds made available to NASA in this Act from being used for voluntary separation incentive payments unless the Administrator of NASA has first certified to Congress that such payments would not result in the loss of skills related to the safety of the Space Shuttle or the International Space Station or to the conduct of independent safety oversight in NASA. (Sec. 627) Authorizes the NASA Administrator to sell NASA-owned property on the Camp Parks Military Reservation, Alameda County, California, and to credit the net proceeds of such sales as offsetting collections to its Exploration, science, and aeronautics account. Requires such funds to be used to replace the facilities at Camp Parks that are still required, and/or to improve other NASA-owned facilities. (Sec. 628) Directs the President, through his designee the NASA Administrator and in consultation with other Federal agencies, to develop a national aeronautics policy to guide NASA aeronautics programs through 2020, which includes a description of the priority areas of research for aeronautics through FY2011. Instructs the NASA Administrator, in developing the policy, to consider specified questions which shall be discussed in the policy statement. Permits the NASA Administrator to enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to help develop the policy. Requires such Administrator to submit the new national aeronautics policy to specified congressional committees and to make available to Congress any study done by a non-governmental entity that was used in the development of the national aeronautics policy. (Sec. 629) Prohibits any funds made available under this Act or any other Act from being spent to pay administrative expenses or to compensate a U.S. officer or employee in connection with requiring an export license for the export to Canada of components, parts, accessories, or attachments for certain firearms with a total value not exceeding $500 wholesale in any transaction, provided that specified conditions are met by the exporting party. Requires the District Director of Customs and postmasters to permit the export without a license of any such unclassified articles to Canada for end use in Canada or return to the United States, or temporary import of Canadian-origin items from Canada for end use in the United States or return to Canada for a Canadian citizen. Allows the President to require export licenses on a temporary basis under this section if, the Government of Canada has inadequate import controls for the articles specified in this section, such that a significant diversion of such articles has and continues to take place for use in international terrorism or in the escalation of a conflict in another nation. (Sec. 630) Bars any department, agency, or U.S. instrumentality receiving appropriated funds under this Act or any other Act from obligating or spending such funds to pay administrative expenses or the compensation of any U.S. officer or employee to deny any application for a permit to import U.S. origin "curios or relics" firearms, parts, or ammunition. (Sec. 631) Prohibits the use of any of the funds under this Act to include in any bilateral or multilateral trade agreement specified text of the United States-Singapore Free Trade Agreement, the United States-Australia Free Trade Agreement, or the United States-Morocco Free Trade Agreement. (Sec. 632) Requires that, of the funds appropriated to the FTC, at least than $1 million shall be used by the FTC to conduct an immediate investigation into nationwide gasoline prices in the aftermath of Hurricane Katrina. (Sec. 633) Amends the Universal Service Antideficiency Temporary Suspension Act to extend the prohibition on applying certain provisions relating to limitations on expending and obligating appropriations amounts and the apportionment of appropriations to the collection or receipt of federal universal service contributions and the expenditure or obligation of amounts attributable to such contributions for universal service support programs. (Sec. 634) Prohibits the use of any of the funds made available in this Act to send or otherwise pay for the attendance of more than 50 employees of agencies or departments of the U.S. government who are stationed in the United States, at any single international conference occurring outside the United States, unless the Secretary of State determines that such attendance is in the national interest. (Sec. 635) Directs the United States-China Economic and Security Review Commission to investigate and report exclusively on each of the following areas: (1) the role of the People's Republic of China (China) in the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction and other weapons, including actions the United States might take to encourage China to cease such practices; (2) the qualitative and quantitative nature of the transfer of U.S. production activities to China; (3) the effect of China's economy on world energy supplies and the role the United States can play in influencing China's energy policy; (4) the extent of access to and use of U.S. capital markets by China; (5) the economic and security relationship among the United States, Taipei, and China, China's national budget, and the fiscal strength of China in relation to internal instability in China and the likelihood of externalization of problems arising from such internal instability; (6) science and technology programs, the degree of non-compliance by China with agreements between the United States and China on prison labor imports and intellectual property rights, and U.S. enforcement policies respecting such agreements; (7) China's compliance with its accession agreement to the WTO; and (8) the implications of restrictions on speech and access to information in China for its relations with the United States in the areas of economic and security policy. (Sec. 636) Amends the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005 to permit the unexpended balances (currently, the unobligated balance) appropriated by title V of the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002 for necessary expenses of the United States-Canada Alaska Rail Commission to be transferred as a direct lump-sum payment to the University of Alaska. (Sec. 637) Prohibits the use of any of the funds made available in this Act to pay expenses for any U.S. delegation to any specialized agency, body, or UN commission if such commission is chaired or presided over by a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined, for purposes of the exercise of certain foreign policy controls on the export of goods or technology to countries that have repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism, has provided support for such acts. (Sec. 638) Rescinds, as provided in this section, 0.28% of the budget authority provided for in FY2006 for any discretionary account in this Act. Title VII: Rescissions - Rescinds certain unobligated balances available to the Department of Justice for: (1) General Administration (Working Capital Fund); (2) legal activities (Assets Forfeiture Fund) (3) the FBI (Salaries and Expenses); and (4) the Office of Justice Programs (Community Oriented Policing Services). Rescinds certain unobligated balances available to the Department of Commerce for NOAA. Rescinds certain unobligated balances available to related agencies for the: (1) FCC (Salaries and Expenses); (2) FTC (Salaries and Expenses); (3) Marine Mammal Commission (Salaries and Expenses); and (4) SBA (Salaries and Expenses and Business Loans Program Account).</summary>
</bill>
