<bill session="112" type="h" number="159" updated="2013-07-20T01:11:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TBI Treatment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program under which the Secretaries make payments for certain treatments of traumatic brain injury and post-traumatic stress disorder.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
TBI Treatment Act - Directs the Secretaries of Defense (DOD) and Veterans Affairs (Secretaries) to carry out a five-year pilot program under which each Secretary establishes a process for providing payments to facilities for treatments of traumatic brain injury (TBI) or post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) received by members of the Armed Forces and veterans in facilities other than military treatment facilities or Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) medical facilities. Subjects such payments to specified conditions, including approved treatment or study protocols. Requires the VA Secretary to notify each veteran with a service-connected injury or disability of the opportunity to receive such treatment or study protocol. Requires the Secretaries to jointly: (1) develop and maintain a database containing data from each patient case involving the use of such treatments; and (2) report annually to Congress on the implementation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
