<bill session="113" type="h" number="161" updated="2013-11-02T06:20:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bringing Economic Advancement and Coastal Health Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Water Resources Development Act of 1976 to direct the Secretary of the Army to evaluate the feasibility of continuing Federal participation in a beach nourishment project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400266"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Seashores and lakeshores"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2013--Introduced.
Bringing Economic Advancement and Coastal Health Act - Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1976 to: (1) authorize the Chief of Engineers to provide periodic authorized beach nourishment for a water resources development project for such additional period as he or she determines necessary, but not beyond the 50th year that begins after the date of initiation of construction (current law) or after the date of the last estimated periodic nourishment as contemplated in the Chief's Report, whichever is later; and (2) require the Chief of Engineers, before the end of such 50-year period, to evaluate the feasibility of continuing federal participation in the beach nourishment project.</summary>
</bill>
