<bill session="109" type="s" number="1640" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Price Gouging bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protection From Price Gouging Against Disaster Victims Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit price gouging relating to certain goods and services in areas affected by major disasters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9845-9846" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1744"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer goods"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/2005--Introduced.
Protection From Price Gouging Against Disaster Victims Act of 2005 - Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to direct the Federal Trade Commission to: (1) consult with certain senior law enforcement officials following declaration of a major disaster by the President in order to determine whether unconscionably excessive prices for any consumer good or service are being charged in the affected area; (2) establish a toll-free hotline to receive consumer reports of price gouging in the affected area; and (3) establish a program to develop and distribute public informational materials in English and Spanish to assist residents of the affected area in detecting and avoiding price gouging. Prohibits unconscionably excessive prices for any consumer good or service in an affected area during the 180-day period after the date on which a major disaster is declared by the President. Subjects violations of this Act to specified civil and criminal penalties. Authorizes victims and state Attorneys General to bring a civil action against violators of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
