<bill session="111" type="s" number="3529" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">AMERICA Works Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Manufacturing Efficiency and Retraining Investment Collaboration Achievement Works Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require that certain Federal job training and career education programs give priority to programs that provide an industry-recognized and nationally portable credential.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412324"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5441-5442"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4072"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2010--Introduced.
American Manufacturing Efficiency and Retraining Investment Collaboration Achievement Works Act or AMERICA Works Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998, with respect to statewide and local adult and youth workforce investment employment and training programs, to require a one-stop delivery system, in selecting and approving training services, or programs of training services, to give priority consideration to state- and local board-approved services and programs that lead to an industry-recognized and nationally portable credential that is in high demand in the local area served and listed in the skill credential registry created under this Act. Amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to require the same priority consideration in the state and local plans for career and technical education programs as well as in tech prep programs. Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to direct the Secretary of Commerce to give priority consideration to Trade Adjustment Assistance (TAA) training programs that lead to a industry-recognized and nationally portable credential listed in the skill credential registry that is in high demand in the local area served by the corresponding one-stop delivery system. Requires the Secretary of Labor to: (1) create a registry of skill credentials; and (2) list them in the registry if they are required by federal or state law for an occupation, or are from the Manufacturing Institute-Endorsed Manufacturing Skills Certification System. Authorizes the Secretary to list a credential in the registry if it is an industry-recognized and nationally portable credential consistent with established industry competency models, including the one for the American College Test National Career Readiness Certification.</summary>
</bill>
