<bill session="111" type="sc" number="60" updated="2013-07-20T00:23:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">An original concurrent resolution setting forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2011, revising the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal year 2010, and setting forth the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2012 through 2015.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300026"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-26">
      <text>Committee on the Budget. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Conrad. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-04-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="358">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 358.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2654-2663" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax reform and tax simplification"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2010--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Sets forth the congressional budget for the federal government for FY2011, including the appropriate budgetary levels for FY2010 and FY2012-FY2015. Title I: Recommended Levels and Amounts - (Sec. 101) Lists recommended budgetary levels and amounts for FY2010-FY2015 with respect to: (1) federal revenues; (2) new budget authority; (3) budget outlays; (4) deficits; (5) public debt; and (6) debt held by the public. (Sec. 102) Lists the appropriate levels of new budget authority, outlays, and administrative expenses for Social Security, U.S. Postal Service discretionary administrative expenses, and specified major functional categories for FY2010-FY2015. Title II: Reserve Funds - (Sec. 201) Provides for certain deficit-neutral and/or deficit-reduction reserve funds for legislation for: (1) promotion of employment and job growth; (2) stabilization and improvement of the regulation of the financial and housing sector; (3) tax relief and reform; (4) investments in clean energy and preservation of the environment; (5) assistance to working families and children; (6) investments in America's infrastructure; (7) America's veterans, and returning and wounded servicemembers; (8) higher education; (9) health care; (10) investments in counties and schools; (11) the federal judiciary; (12) recommendations of the National Commission on Fiscal Responsibility and Reform; (13) improper payments; (14) terminated programs; (15) small business tax relief; (16) greater accountability for the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (ARRA) funding and for health care reform; (17) reduction of tax increases on low-and middle-income Americans and protection of retirees; (18) promotion of corporate tax fairness; (19) taxpayer access to Internal Revenue Service (IRS) appeals; (20) increased difficulty for corporations to influence elections; (21) repeal of deductions from mineral revenue payments to states; and (22) increased transparency regarding foreign holders of U.S. debt and risk assessment related to the federal debt. Title III: Budget Process - Subtitle A: Budget Enforcement - (Sec. 301) Makes it out of order to consider in the Senate any legislation that would cause the discretionary spending limits in this section to be exceeded. Permits waiver or suspension of such prohibition, or successful appeals from rulings of the Chair, only by an affirmative vote of three-fifths (60) of the Senate. Sets discretionary spending limits for FY2010-FY2013. Provides for adjustments to discretionary spending limits, budgetary aggregates, and allocations for: (1) continuing disability reviews and Supplemental Security Income (SSI) redeterminations for the Social Security Administration (SSA); (2) IRS tax enforcement; (3) health care fraud and abuse control; (4) unemployment insurance improper payments reviews; and (5) support for ongoing overseas deployments and other activities. (Sec. 302) Makes it out of order to consider in the Senate any legislation that would require advanced appropriations other than for: (1) any FY2012-FY2013 programs, projects, activities, or accounts identified in the joint explanatory statement of managers accompanying this resolution, but only in an aggregate of up to $28.852 billion in new budget authority in each year; (2) the Corporation for Public Broadcasting; and (3) the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for the Medical Services, Medical Support and Compliance, and Medical Facilities accounts of the Veterans Health Administration. Permits waiver or suspension of such prohibition, or successful appeals from rulings of the Chair, only by an affirmative vote of three-fifths (60) of the Senate. (Sec. 303) Requires the Senate to treat as an emergency requirement the amounts of new budget authority, outlays, and receipts in all fiscal years resulting from a provision of direct spending or receipts legislation or appropriations for discretionary accounts that Congress designates as an emergency requirement. Declares that such new budget authority, outlays, and receipts resulting from any emergency requirement shall not count for purposes of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (CBA), pay-as-you-go, long and short-term deficits, and the discretionary spending limit requirements of this resolution. Makes it out of order to consider in the Senate any legislation that would provide an emergency designation, for the purpose of the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 or this resolution, unless each designation is accompanied by an "Affirmation of Emergency Designation" document filed with the Clerk of the Senate and signed by 16 Senators. Subjects any emergency requirement designation in the Senate to a point-of-order. Permits waiver or suspension of such requirements, or successful appeals from rulings of the Chair, only by an affirmative vote of three-fifths (60) of the Senate. (Sec. 304) Allows the Chairman of the Senate Budget Committee to adjust the estimate of budgetary effects of legislation to exclude amounts of qualifying budgetary effects if the legislation: (1) amends or supersedes the system for updating physician payments under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act; (2) amends the Estate and Gift Tax under the Internal Revenue Code; (3) extends the Alternative Minimum Tax (AMT) relief for individuals under the Code; or (4) extends middle-class tax cuts under the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 (EGTRRA) or the Jobs and Growth Tax Relief and Reconciliation Act of 2003 (JGTRRA). Permits the Chairman to make adjustments only for points of order in specified resolutions relating to: (1) pay-as-you-go; and (2) long- and short-term deficits. (Sec. 305) Extends through FY2020 certain CBA mechanisms for enforcement of budgetary points of order in the Senate. (Sec. 306) Makes it out of order to consider in the Senate reconciliation legislation that produces an increase in outlays if the effect of all the provisions in the jurisdiction of any committee is to create or result in gross new direct spending that exceeds 20% of the total savings instructions to the committee. Permits waiver or suspension of such prohibition, or successful appeals from rulings of the Chair, only by an affirmative vote of three-fifths (60) of the Senate. Subtitle B: Other Provisions - (Sec. 311) Requires Senate committees to review programs and tax expenditures in their jurisdiction, and provide recommendations to the Senate Budget Committee to improve governmental performance and to reduce waste, fraud, abuse, or program duplication in their views and estimates reports. (Sec. 312) Requires the joint explanatory statement accompanying the conference report on any budget resolution in the Senate to include in its committee allocations to the Committees on Appropriations amounts for the discretionary administrative expenses of the SSA and of the Postal Service. (Sec. 315) Makes it out of order to consider a budget resolution in the Senate unless it: (1) contains a specified "Truth in Debt Disclosure" section; and (2) includes a table that contains, for each of the previous 12 fiscal years, specified information based on the budget resolution for each such fiscal year. Declares that, if any portion of the Social Security surplus is projected to be spent and/or the gross federal debt in the 5th year of the budget window is greater than the debt projected in the current year, then the report, print, or statement of managers accompanying the budget resolution shall contain a section that: (1) details the circumstances making it in the national interest to allow federal debt to increase rather than taking steps to reduce it; and (2) provides a justification for allowing the surpluses in the Social Security Trust Fund to be spent on other federal functions even as the baby boom generation retires, program costs are projected to rise dramatically, the debt owed to Social Security is about to come due, and the Trust Fund is projected to go insolvent. (Sec. 316) Declares that the levels assumed in this budget resolution allow the gross federal debt to rise: (1) by $4.71 trillion from FY2010 to FY2015; and (2) by $15,250 on every U.S. citizen from FY2010 to FY2015. (Sec. 317) States that such levels cut: (1) spending as a percent of gross domestic product (GDP) by 11%; (2) the deficit as a percent of GDP by 70%; and (3) taxes by $780 billion. Title IV: Reconciliation - (Sec. 401) Instructs the Senate Committee on Finance to report reconciliation bills or resolutions by certain dates to: (1) reduce the deficit by $2 billion for FY2010-FY2015; and (2) increase the statutory debt limit by no more than $50 billion.</summary>
</bill>
