<bill session="110" type="h" number="3535" updated="2013-07-19T21:34:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homebuyer's Protection Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to require escrow accounts for the payment of property taxes and insurance for all subprime loans, and to expand the coverage of the appraisal requirements under the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412220"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2007-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Mortgage banks"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Property insurance"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2007--Introduced.
Homebuyer's Protection Act of 2007 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to require a creditor to establish, in an insured depository institution, an escrow or impound account for payment of taxes and hazard insurance at the time of the consummation of a subprime mortgage transaction. Requires such account to remain in existence for as long as the subprime mortgage is outstanding. Requires creditors, before consummating a consumer credit transaction involving an impound, trust, or escrow account, to provide the following written disclosures: (1) that an escrow or impound account will be established; (2) the amount required to fund such account; (3) the amount in the initial year of estimated taxes and hazard insurance premiums; and (4) the estimated monthly amount payable for taxes and hazard insurance. Amends the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 to extend its appraisal requirements to all real estate related financial transactions, not only those that are federally related.</summary>
</bill>
