<bill session="111" type="h" number="5859" updated="2013-07-20T00:05:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To award a Congressional Gold Medal to the World War II members of the Civil Air Patrol.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2010-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3237"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2010--Introduced.
Directs the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives to arrange for the award of a single Congressional Gold Medal to honor collectively the World War II members of the Civil Air Patrol (CAP) in recognition of their military service and exemplary record during World War II. Requires the Medal's display at the Smithsonian Institution. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Medal should be made available for display elsewhere, particularly at locations associated with the CAP. Permits the Secretary of the Treasury to strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal, at a price sufficient to cover the costs of the medals.</summary>
</bill>
