<bill session="112" type="h" number="6393" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Health Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to consider the best interest of the veteran when determining whether the veteran should receive certain contracted health care, to amend the Wounded Warrior Act to improve access to certain medical care for former members of the Armed Forces with severe injuries or illnesses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412502"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2012-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2012--Introduced.
Veterans Health Access Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, when it is determined that Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) facilities are not capable of furnishing economic hospital care or medical services because of geographical inaccessibility or the care or services required, to determine whether or not to furnish such care or services to a veteran in a non-VA facility. Requires such determination to be made within 30 days following the request for such care or services. Amends the Wounded Warrior Act to authorize the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to allow any former member of the Armed Forces with a severe injury or illness to receive necessary medical and dental care in a non-VA facility when such care is determined by the member's physician to be in their best interest. Extends such authority through 2016.</summary>
</bill>
