<bill session="113" type="h" number="2890" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Incentives for Business and Individual Investment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend certain tax incentives for investment in the District of Columbia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1173-1174"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3272"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2013--Introduced.
District of Columbia Incentives for Business and Individual Investment Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to tax incentives for investment in the District of Columbia, to: (1) reauthorize provisions for designating a District of Columbia Enterprise Zone and extend the deadline for such designation until December 31, 2015; (2) reauthorize the issuance authority for District of Columbia tax-exempt economic development bonds and extend until December 31, 2015, the deadline for issuing such bonds; (3) extend through 2014 the period for acquiring DC Zone assets (i.e., DC Zone business stock, partnership interests, and business property) eligible for an exemption from capital gains tax and through 2020 the period during which gain from the sale of such assets shall qualify for such exemption; and (4) extend through December 31, 2014, the deadline for purchasing a residence in the District of Columbia to qualify for the first-time District of Columbia homebuyers tax credit.</summary>
</bill>
