<bill session="109" type="h" number="6287" updated="2013-07-19T20:00:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Heritage Areas Partnership Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish criteria for and to create a National Heritage Areas System in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="2006-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="760"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="243"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Social life and customs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Introduced.
National Heritage Areas Partnership Act - Establishes a National Heritage Areas System through which the Secretary of the Interior shall provide technical and financial assistance to local coordinating entities to support the establishment, development, and continuity of National Heritage Areas. Directs the Secretary to assess and report on the feasibility of designating proposed Areas and on the future of Areas already designated. Specifies feasibility criteria, including that an Area has an assemblage of natural, historic, or cultural resources that tell a nationally important story. States that designation of an Area shall be: (1) by Act of Congress; and (2) contingent on the prior completion of a feasibility study and an affirmative determination by the Secretary that the area meets such criteria. Sets forth requirements for Area management plans. Instructs local coordinating entities to submit plans to the Secretary for approval. Specifies approval criteria, including that resource protection and interpretation strategies would adequately protect, enhance, and interpret the natural, historic, scenic, and cultural resources of the Area. Requires local coordinating entities to submit annual reports on performance goals, accomplishments, finances, and expenditures. Sets forth such entities' authority for using federal funds. Authorizes appropriations for such Areas. Terminates the Secretary's authority to provide financial assistance (to be matched by such entities) 15 years after enactment of the law designating an Area.</summary>
</bill>
