<bill session="111" type="h" number="4575" updated="2013-07-19T23:53:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Open College Textbook Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize grants for the creation, update, or adaption of open textbooks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400437"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-02">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-02">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1714"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Books and print media"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2010--Introduced.
Open College Textbook Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive one-year grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs), professors from IHEs, and producers of open textbooks to create or update open textbooks, or adapt textbooks into open formats, for postsecondary coursework. (Open textbooks are defined as college textbooks or course materials in electronic format that are licensed under an open license, which is an irrevocable intellectual property license that grants the public the right to access, customize, and distribute copyrighted material.) Requires such textbooks to be posted on an easily accessible and interoperable website and made available to the public free of charge. Directs the Secretary to develop a peer review and evaluation process to ensure that these textbooks are of the highest quality, accurate in content, and meet or exceed market quality and accessibility standards. Requires all elementary, secondary, and postsecondary educational materials created through federal grants to be licensed under an open license, posted on an easily accessible and interoperable website, and made available to the public free of charge. Expresses the sense of Congress that IHEs should encourage professors to consider open textbooks within the generally accepted principles of academic freedom which give faculty the right and responsibility to select pedagogically appropriate coursework.</summary>
</bill>
