<bill session="112" type="s" number="3294" updated="2013-07-20T02:45:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAVE Elders Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Abuse, Violence, and Exploitation of Elders Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to dedicate funds from the Crime Victims Fund to victims of elder abuse, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412384"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3490"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/2012--Introduced.
Stop Abuse, Violence, and Exploitation of Elders Act of 2012 or the SAVE Elders Act of 2012 - Amends the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 to designate specified funds from the Crime Victims Fund for grants for compensation and assistance to victims of elder abuse. Defines "elder abuse" under that Act: (1) to mean the abuse, exploitation, or neglect of an individual who is age 65 or older and lawfully present in the United States; and (2) with respect to a state that receives a grant, to include any other conduct that is defined as such under the laws of the state. Requires the Director of the Office of Victims of Crime to use such funds to make grants to states to support: (1) eligible crime victim assistance programs that provide assistance to victims of elder abuse; and (2) programs that improve the investigation, handling, and prosecution of cases of elder abuse. Apportions specified percentages of grant amounts among the states, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, the U.S. Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands and requires the amounts remaining after such apportionment to be distributed among the states based on: (1) the population of individuals age 65 or older in a state relative to the population of such individuals in all states, (2) the population of individuals age 65 or older in a state in relation to the population of the state, and (3) the overall rate of crime in a state. Requires the Attorney General: (1) acting through the Inspector General of the Department of Justice (DOJ), to periodically review all DOJ grants to ensure the purposes of the grants are achieved in the most efficient manner possible; (2) to submit an assessment of each DOJ grant program to determine the extent of overlap and duplication; and (3) to direct any DOJ office that carries out a grant program to coordinate with other offices to review anticipated grant awards.</summary>
</bill>
