<bill session="109" type="s" number="3614" updated="2013-07-19T20:44:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Unprivileged Combatant Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide comprehensive procedures for the adjudication of cases involving unprivileged combatants.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6796-6797, S6801"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6797-6801" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Courts-martial and courts of inquiry"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Trials"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2006--Introduced.
Unprivileged Combatant Act of 2006 - Authorizes the President to establish military commissions (commissions) for the trial of unprivileged combatants. Defines an "unprivileged combatant" as an individual who: (1) has been designated as an enemy combatant by a Combatant Status Review Tribunal; or (2) a field tribunal determines is not entitled to the protections of the Geneva Convention, and has assisted in, attempted, or conspired in taking up arms against the United States. Establishes exclusive commission jurisdiction to hear any matter involving an unprivileged combatant who has been detained by the Department of Defense (DOD) for not less than 180 consecutive days at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba. Allows a commission to hear any criminal prosecution involving international terrorism and violations of the law of war. Gives the U.S. Court of Military Appeals exclusive jurisdiction of appeals in such matters, with final review by the U.S. Supreme Court via writ of certiorari. Prescribes commission requirements, including at least 12 members, three military officers, and one military judge. Requires: (1) the Secretary of Defense to develop a complete listing of all persons being detained by DOD at Guantanamo Bay that the government wishes to continue to detain as an unprivileged combatant; and (2) the list to be updated every 60 days. Directs DOD, within 30 days after a suspected unprivileged combatant has been detained, to conduct a field tribunal to determine whether the detainee is an unprivileged combatant and whether the detainee is entitled to the rights afforded under the Geneva Convention. Requires a detainee to be released and repatriated to the appropriate country unless a classification tribunal board finds that: (1) the detainee is a threat to U.S. national security; or (2) there are reasonable grounds to believe that, if released, the detainee would take up arms against the United States. Requires rehearings for each detainee at least every 180 days. Provides classification tribunal procedures, procedures for criminal prosecution, and trial procedures for unprivileged combatants.</summary>
</bill>
