<bill session="113" type="h" number="2999" updated="2013-11-02T06:44:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ABC Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accurate Background Check Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 28, United States Code, to provide for procedures ensuring accuracy in employment-related exchanges of records and information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
Accurate Background Check Act of 2013 or the ABC Act of 2013 - Amends the federal judicial code to&#160;require the Attorney General (DOJ) to provide procedures to ensure the accuracy and completeness of certain criminal records and information exchanged for employment background checks. Directs the Attorney General, if a record or information is inaccurate or incomplete, to correct, delete, or amend such information within 10 days after a request is made and prior to releasing the record to the requesting entity. Requires the Attorney General, in such an instance, to also research state and local recordkeeping systems, maintain a disposition document database to be searched along with other federal databases, and notify reporting jurisdictions of any updated information. Considers a record or information to be incomplete if it indicates that an arrest was made and does not include the disposition of such arrest. Requires the Attorney General, prior to such an employment background check exchange, to obtain the signed consent of the subject of such information, provide the applicant an opportunity to challenge the record, notify the requesting entity of any such challenge, and complete an investigation of such challenge within 30 days. Extends the procedures established pursuant to this Act to apply to authorized&#160;exchanges for: (1) national security background investigations for employment in federal service, (2) government-wide security standards for forms of identification issued to federal employees and contractors, and (3) government background checks for the issuance of transportation security cards to access the secure areas of shipping vessels and facilities.</summary>
</bill>
