<bill session="112" type="h" number="3821" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">After School for America's Children Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize 21st century community learning centers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2012-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2012-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2012-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2012-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2012-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2012-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2012-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2012-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2012-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1370"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2012--Introduced.
After School for America's Children Act of 2012 - Amends the 21st Century Community Learning Centers program under part B of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA). (21st Century Community Learning Centers provide students with before and afterschool programs to improve their academic performance.) Requires the Centers to provide: (1) students with activities that are targeted to their academic needs and aligned with the instruction they receive during the school day, and (2) students' families with opportunities for active and meaningful engagement in their children's education. Includes Indian tribes or organizations among the local public or private entities that are eligible for grants from states to establish the Centers. Requires states to use at least 93% (currently 95%) of their allotment from the Secretary of Education to provide grants to those entities. Allows states to use up to 5% (currently, 3%) of their allotment for certain state activities. Requires states to use a rigorous peer review process in reviewing grant applications. Allows states to renew a grant under part B based on the grantee's performance during the original grant period. Prohibits the Secretary or states from giving funding priority to applicants that propose to use the funds to extend the regular school day. Includes among the activities grants may fund: (1) core academic subject education activities, including those that allow students to recover or attain credits; (2) literacy education programs; (3) programs that support a healthy, active lifestyle; (4) services for the disabled; (5) programs that support global education and competence; (6) social and emotional learning programming; and (7) programs that build science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) skills and support innovative STEM teaching methods. Reauthorizes the 21st Century Community Learning Centers program through FY2017.</summary>
</bill>
