<bill session="111" type="h" number="3179" updated="2013-07-19T23:40:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-15T15:38:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-09-15T15:38:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SIG TARP Small Business Awareness Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">SIG TARP Small Business Awareness Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 to require the Special Inspector General for the Troubled Asset Relief Program to include the effect of the Troubled Asset Relief Program on small businesses in the oversight, audits, and reports provided by the Special Inspector General, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2009-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-15T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Moore (KS) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-15T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9527-9529" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-15T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3179.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-09-15T15:38:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9528" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-09-15T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2009--Passed House amended.
SIG TARP Small Business Awareness Act of 2009 - Amends the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA) to direct the Special Inspector General (SIG) for the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) to examine how smaller financial institutions are being affected by: (1) expenditures under TARP (especially the adequacy of financial assistance); (2) the considerations and determinations of the Secretary of the Treasury (Secretary) and the regulators of such smaller financial institutions regarding capital adequacy and troubled assets; and (3) the effects that TARP financial assistance has had upon small businesses, including by type and by region. Instructs the SIG to include, in quarterly reports to Congress, information on actions by the Secretary and any financial institutions receiving TARP assistance to include and utilize minorities and women, and minority- and women-owned businesses, in any solicitation or contract. Requires such reports to include information on: (1) the levels of inclusion and utilization of women, minorities, and women- and minority-owned businesses; (2) the type of such contracts or solicitations, their dollar amounts, and the total number of them; and (5) any other activities to increase the participation of women, minorities, and women- and minority-owned businesses, including recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
