<bill session="109" type="s" number="1433" updated="2013-07-19T20:26:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ready To Educate All Children Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a grant program to enable institutions of higher education to improve schools of education to better prepare teachers to educate all children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8562-8564"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="College teachers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2005--Introduced.
Ready to Educate All Children Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive matching grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) to establish partnerships with high poverty local educational agencies or high poverty schools (local partners) to establish or enhance a clinically-based elementary or secondary school teacher training program. Requires grant priority to be given to an IHE, which is in partnership with a nonprofit organization that is a teacher union or group representing teachers in a school, and that proposes to establish a track for hiring teachers in urban or rural high need schools participating in the partnership prior to July 1 of an academic year. Requires an IHE receiving such a grant to: (1) establish a partnership with a local partner to establish or enhance such a program; (2) facilitate a partnership among the IHE's departments to ensure that future teachers are prepared to teach; and (3) implement a project-based assessment. Requires such IHE also to use grant funds for at least three activities listed.Makes a student who participates in a program funded under this Act eligible for student assistance under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 during the student's fifth year of study for a teaching degree (if such clinically-based program is a teaching-degree study requirement).</summary>
</bill>
