<bill session="111" type="s" number="3450" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require publicly traded coal companies to include certain safety records in their reports to the Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="2010-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4550-4551"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/2010--Introduced.
Requires a publicly traded coal or other mine company that is required to file a periodic securities report with the Securities Exchange Commission (SEC) to include in the report: (1) the total number of violations of mandatory health or safety standards that could significantly contribute to the cause and effect of a coal or other mine safety or health hazard for which the operator of the coal or other mine received a citation or order to comply from the Mine Safety and Health Administration; (2) a list of such coal or other mines that have received written notice of a pattern of such violations from the Administration; and (3) any pending legal action before the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission involving such coal or other mine. Requires publicly traded coal or other mine companies to file a current report with the SEC on Form 8-K disclosing any receipt of: (1) an imminent danger order to shutdown issued by the Secretary of Labor; and (2) any written notice of a pattern of violations from the Administration.</summary>
</bill>
