<bill session="113" type="h" number="2017" updated="2013-11-02T06:36:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to improve the operations of the Election Assistance Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2013-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/2013--Introduced.
EAC Improvements Act of 2013 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to: (1) reauthorize the Election Assistance Commission (EAC), and (2) require states to participate in post-general election surveys. Requires the EAC to: (1) conduct and publish a survey of each polling place used in an election to determine the percentage of them in compliance with standards under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990; (2) establish an escrow account for making payments to accredited laboratories for the costs of the testing carried out in connection with the certification, decertification, and recertification of voting system hardware and software; (3) establish a schedule of fees for such testing; and (4) maintain and publish an updated list of all accredited laboratories. Directs the EAC to analyze various factors that affect the costs to state and local governments of administering elections for federal office. Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to study the administrative operations of the EAC, including various methods for increasing their efficiency and cost-effectiveness.</summary>
</bill>
