<bill session="112" type="h" number="6640" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize a land exchange involving the acquisition of private land adjacent to the Cibola National Wildlife Refuge in Arizona for inclusion in the refuge in exchange for certain Bureau of Land Management lands in Riverside County, California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2012-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2012--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to River Bottom Farms of La Paz County, Arizona, specified Bureau of Land Management (BLM) land in Riverside County, California, in exchange for two specified parcels of non-federal land in the county from River Bottoms Farms that are contiguous to the Cibola National Wildlife Refuge. Subjects the conveyed federal land to valid existing rights, including easements, rights-of-way, utility lines, and any other valid encumbrances on the such land as of the date of conveyance. Requires the values of the federal and non-federal lands to be exchanged to be equal, or equalized, by a cash payment to the Secretary or River Bottom Farms, as appropriate. Requires the acquired non-federal land to become a part of the Cibola Wildlife Refuge.</summary>
</bill>
