<bill session="112" type="h" number="342" updated="2013-07-20T01:13:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles XIX and XVIII of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010, with respect to payment of disproportionate share hospitals (DSH) under the Medicare and Medicaid programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400204"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-19">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-19">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/2011--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to report to Congress on the Medicare DSH (disproportionate share hospital) payment system, taking into account the impact of the health care reforms under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA), as amended by the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 (HCERA), in reducing the number of uninsured individuals. Requires the Secretary to make specified adjustments to the Medicare DSH payment system, including an additional payment to hospitals based on the amount of uncompensated care they have provided, if there is a significant decrease in the national rate of uninsurance as a result of corrected PPACA. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA), as amended by PPACA and HCERA, to eliminate certain current requirements for adjustments to Medicare DSH payments. Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid), as amended by PPACA and HCERA, to postpone specified Medicaid DSH reductions scheduled for FY2014-FY2020 until FY2018-FY2024.</summary>
</bill>
