<bill session="112" type="h" number="2439" updated="2013-07-20T01:31:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Removing GSEs Charters During Receivership Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 to authorize the Federal Housing Finance Agency, as receiver of Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac, to revoke the charters of such enterprises or any limited-life regulated entity established under such receivership.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412461"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2011-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-12">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/2011--Introduced.
Removing GSEs Charters During Receivership Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 to authorize the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA), as a receiver of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) (government-sponsored enterprises or GSEs), to revoke the charters of such enterprises. Requires the FHFA to revoke the particular GSE's charter not later than the winbding up or termination of the limited-life regulated entity established with respect to such GSE Repeals the current prohibition against revocation, annulment, or termination of a GSE's charter by the receiver.</summary>
</bill>
