<bill session="109" type="h" number="4090" updated="2013-07-19T19:40:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Whatever It Takes to Rebuild Act, Part II</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to modify the terms of the community disaster loan program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2005-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400635" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2005-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2139-2140"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/2005--Introduced.
Whatever It Takes to Rebuild Act, Part II - Repeals the Community Disaster Loan Act of 2005. Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to make community disaster loans to any state government which may suffer a substantial loss of tax and other revenue as a result of a major disaster, and has demonstrated a need for financial assistance in order to perform its governmental functions. Removes the $5 million cap set for community disaster loans. Provides that in the case of a community disaster loan made to a state or local government which suffers a substantial loss of tax and other revenues as a result of a major disaster the President determines to be an incident of national significance: (1) the amount of the loan shall not be subject to the current limitation of 25% of the annual operating budget of that state or local government for the fiscal year in which the major disaster occurs; and (2) the President shall not require the payment of any interest or principal on a loans.</summary>
</bill>
