<bill session="112" type="h" number="3657" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Emergency Re-establishment of Obligations (NERO) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify the authority of the Chairman of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to act on behalf of the Commission during emergencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400400"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2011-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2011-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2011--Introduced.
Nuclear Emergency Re-establishment of Obligations (NERO) Act - Prohibits the Chairman of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) from exercising emergency authority to make decisions or take actions otherwise reserved for the full Commission unless the Chairman has declared an emergency based upon: (1) an imminent safety threat to a facility or materials licensed or regulated by the NRC, or (2) a determination by senior officials of designated agencies that a security incident exists that poses an imminent threat to a facility or materials licensed or regulated by the NRC. Prescribes additional procedures if the Chairman does declare such emergency exists. Subjects to approval by the full Commission all appointments by the NRC Chairman of NRC officers. Prescribes time limits for NRC review of requested briefs. Directs the NRC to revise its procedures to ensure that any allegation of wrongdoing on the part of the NRC Chairman is referred to the Inspector General of the NRC. Instructs the NRC Chairman to authorize all domestic and international travel requested by NRC members for official business unless a notice of disapproval is submitted to the full Commission specifying the basis for the disapproval. Prohibits adoption of any budget or budget revision unless each NRC member has been given an opportunity to: (1) participate in the development of such budget or revision after being provided access to all relevant information, and (2) vote on the approval of such budget or revision.</summary>
</bill>
