<bill session="110" type="s" number="2404" updated="2013-07-19T22:41:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Advanced Laboratory Diagnostics Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve payments under the Medicare clinical laboratory fee schedule.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1321"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="DNA"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Molecular biology"/>
    <term name="Proteins"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2007--Introduced.
Medicare Advanced Laboratory Diagnostics Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) establish a demonstration project to evaluate new approaches to coding and payment under the Medicare program (title XVIII of the Social Security Act (SSA)) for clinical diagnostic laboratory tests; and (2) appoint a standing panel to determine tests to be included in the project and make recommendations derived from project results to the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Amends SSA title XVIII with respect to: (1) correction of erroneous determinations and other changes in fee schedule and national limitation amounts for clinical diagnostic laboratory tests; (2) issuance of regulations on gap-filling methodology in determining the Medicare fee schedule for such tests; (3) increased transparency of the process for determining fee schedule amounts for new tests; and (4) mandatory advance notice of clinical diagnostic laboratory test amounts being considered for adjustment under inherent reasonableness authority.</summary>
</bill>
