<bill session="110" type="s" number="1927" updated="2013-07-19T22:37:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-05">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protect America Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Protect America Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Protect America Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Protect America Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to provide additional procedures for authorizing certain acquisitions of foreign intelligence information and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2007-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-08-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="324">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 324.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10861-10872" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2007-08-03" how="roll" result="pass" roll="309" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 60 - 28. Record Vote Number: 309.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10871-10872" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-04T11:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-04T11:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-04T20:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated pursuant to a previous order.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9952-9966" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-04T20:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered pursuant to a previous order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-04T20:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on S. 1927.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-04T21:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9965" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2007-08-04T22:19:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="836" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 183 (Roll no. 836).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9953-9954" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-08-04T22:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2007-08-04">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2007-08-05">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2007-08-05">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2007-08-05" type="public" number="110-55">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 110-55.</text>
    </enacted>
    <action datetime="2007-09-25">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3356"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2011"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2649"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/5/2007--Public Law.
Protect America Act of 2007 - Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) to state that nothing under its definition of "electronic surveillance" shall be construed to encompass surveillance directed at a person reasonably believed to be located outside the United States. Allows the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) and the Attorney General (AG), for periods up to one year, to authorize the acquisition of foreign intelligence information concerning persons outside the United States if the DNI and AG determine that: (1) there are reasonable procedures in place for determining that such acquisition concerns persons outside the United States, and such procedures will be subject to review by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court (Court); (2) the acquisition does not constitute electronic surveillance; (3) the acquisition involves obtaining foreign intelligence information from or with the assistance of a communication service provider or other person who has access to communications; (4) a significant purpose of the acquisition is to obtain foreign intelligence information; and (5) the minimization procedures (procedures to ensure the smallest level of privacy intrusion while obtaining such information) to be used meet the definition of minimization procedures under FISA. Requires such determination to be certified and submitted to the Court. Requires the AG to report to: (1) the Court the procedures by which the government determines that such acquisitions do not constitute electronic surveillance; and (2) the congressional intelligence and judiciary committees semiannually concerning acquisitions made during the previous six-month period. Terminates this Act 180 days after its enactment. Makes authorizations for the acquisition of information made by this Act, and directives issued pursuant to such authorizations, effective until their expiration.</summary>
</bill>
