<bill session="112" type="s" number="1260" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">College LIFE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">College Literacy in Finance and Economics Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require financial literacy and economic education counseling for student borrowers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4032-4033" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4040"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2535"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2011--Introduced.
College Literacy in Finance and Economics Act of 2011 or College LIFE Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education (IHEs) to provide student borrowers under the Federal Family Education Loan, Direct Loan, and Perkins Loan programs with financial literacy counseling within 45 days of their first receipt of such a loan and prior to the completion of their studies or when they leave school. Requires student borrowers to receive at least four hours of counseling on each occasion. Makes such counseling requirements inapplicable to borrowers of consolidation loans. Requires financial literacy counseling to include information on the Financial Education Core Competencies as determined by the Financial Literacy and Education Commission. Directs the Secretary of Education to develop a curriculum that IHEs may use to fulfill this Act's requirements.</summary>
</bill>
