<bill session="109" type="hc" number="326" updated="2013-07-19T20:04:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-22">PASSED:CONCURRENTRES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the sine die adjournment of the first session of the One Hundred Ninth Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400322"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-19T06:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12285-12286" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-12-19T06:23:00-05:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12285-12286" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-19T06:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:CONCURRENTRES" datetime="2005-12-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14421" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S14421" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/22/2005--Passed Senate without amendment.
Provides for an adjournment sine die of: (1) the House of Representatives on any legislative day from December 18-December 24, 2005, or from December 26-December 31, 2005 (or until another time of reassembly under this concurrent resolution); and (2) the Senate on any day from December 19-December 24, 2005, or from December 26-December 31, 2005 (or until another time of reassembly). Provides that when: (1) the House adjourns on any legislative day of the second session of the 109th Congress from January 3-January 28, 2006, it stand adjourned until January 31, 2006 (or until another time of reassembly under this concurrent resolution, whichever occurs first); (2) the Senate recesses or adjourns on any day of the second session of the 109th Congress from January 3-January 16, 2006, it stand recessed or adjourned until January 18, 2006, or until such day and time as may be specified by its Majority Leader or his designee (or until another time of reassembly, whichever occurs first); and (3) the Senate recesses or adjourns on any day from January 20-January 28, 2006, it stand recessed or adjourned until January 31, 2006, or until such day and time as may be specified by its Majority Leader or his designee (or until another time of reassembly, whichever occurs first). Authorizes the Speaker of the House and the Majority Leader of the Senate, or their respective designees, acting jointly after consultation with the Minority Leaders of the House and of the Senate, to notify the Members of the House and the Senate, respectively, to reassemble at such place and time as they may designate whenever, in their opinion, the public interest shall warrant it.</summary>
</bill>
