<bill session="109" type="h" number="3054" updated="2013-07-19T19:31:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 to require appropriations to cover the estimated subsidy costs of monetary resources provided by the United States Government to the International Monetary Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400359"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 to declare that, beginning with FY 2007, no appropriation may be made for an increase in the quota of the United States in the International Monetary Fund (IMF) unless it includes new budget authority sufficient to cover the estimated costs to the United States of providing direct loans, loan guarantees, other financing mechanisms (and their modifications) made by or through the IMF to IMF borrowing nations at interest rates below the cost to the Government after appropriate adjustments for maturity and credit risk. Requires the expenditures in the President's budget to reflect the costs to the Government of providing credit to IMF borrowing nations at such interest rates.</summary>
</bill>
