<bill session="109" type="h" number="75" updated="2013-07-19T19:04:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Government Accountability and Streamlining Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Comptroller General to prepare statements for bills and resolutions reported by committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate on whether any new entities, programs, or functions authorized by the bills or resolutions are redundant with existing Federal entities, programs, or functions and could be more efficiently performed by an existing Federal entity, program, or function, and to require such statements to accompany reports on legislation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400019" joined="2005-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2005--Introduced.
Government Accountability and Streamlining Act of 2005 - Requires the Comptroller General, to the extent practicable, to prepare for, and to accompany, each public bill and joint resolution reported by a congressional subcommittee or committee a determination of whether: (1) the measure authorizes new Federal entities, programs, or functions; (2) an existing entity or program carries out functions similar to those authorized by the measure; and (3) the existing entity or program may more effectively and efficiently perform the functions and carry out the measure's purposes than the proposed entity or program.</summary>
</bill>
