<bill session="113" type="h" number="2542" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regulatory Flexibility Improvements Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 6 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Regulatory Flexibility Act), to ensure complete analysis of potential impacts on small entities of rules, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412563" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412486" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412429" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2013-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412596" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412405" joined="2013-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 15 - 9.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Regulatory Flexibility Improvements Act of 2013 - Amends the Regulatory Flexibility Act of 1980 (RFA) to revise the definition of "rule" under such Act to exclude a rule of particular (and not general) applicability relating to rates, wages, and other financial indicators and to define "economic impact" with respect to a proposed or final rule as any direct economic effect on small entities from such rule and any indirect economic effect on small entities that is reasonably foreseeable and that results from such rule. Includes tribal organizations within the definition of "small governmental jurisdictions" for purposes of such Act. Requires initial and final regulatory flexibility analyses to: (1) describe alternatives to a proposed rule that minimize any adverse significant economic impact or maximize the beneficial significant economic impact on small entities, and (2) include revisions or amendments to a land management plan developed by the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior under specified Acts. Requires each federal agency to include in its regulatory flexibility agenda a description of the sector of the North American Industrial Classification System that is affected by a proposed agency rule which is likely to have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities. Expands elements of initial and final regulatory flexibility analyses under RFA to include estimates and descriptions of the cumulative economic impact of a proposed rule on a small entity. Repeals provisions allowing a waiver or delay of the completion of an initial regulatory flexibility analysis. Requires the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to issue rules governing federal agency compliance with RFA requirements. Authorizes the Chief Counsel to modify or amend such rules, to intervene in agency adjudication relating to such rules, and to inform an agency of the impact of its rulemaking on small entities. Revises requirements for agency notification of the SBA Chief Counsel for Advocacy prior to the publication of any proposed rule. Requires agencies to provide the Chief Counsel with: (1) all materials prepared or utilized in making the proposed rule, and (2) information on the potential adverse and beneficial economic impacts of the proposed rule on small entities. Requires each agency to publish in the Federal Register a plan for the periodic review of existing and new rules that have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities to determine whether such rules should be continued, changed, or rescinded. Provides for judicial review of an agency final rule for compliance with RFA requirements after the publication of such rule. Grants federal courts of appeal jurisdiction to review all final rules issued in accordance with RFA. Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the SBA Chief Counsel for Advocacy, in addition to the SBA Administrator, to specify detailed definitions or standards by which a business may be determined to be a small business (size standard) for purposes of such Act or the Small Business Investment Act of 1958. Amends the Small Business Regulatory Enforcement Fairness Act of 1996 to require federal agencies, in preparing small entity compliance guides, to solicit input from affected small entities or associations of small entities.</summary>
</bill>
