<bill session="113" type="h" number="1720" updated="2013-11-02T06:33:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local School Foods Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To conduct a pilot program in support of efforts to increase the amount of purchases of local fresh fruits and vegetables for schools and service institutions by giving certain States the option of receiving a grant from the Secretary of Agriculture for that purpose instead of obtaining commodities under Department of Agriculture programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412239"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412477" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412453" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2013-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Horticulture, Research, Biotechnology, and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG14" subcommittee="Horticulture, Research, Biotechnology, and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1947"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3102"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="679"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2013--Introduced.
Local School Foods Act of 2013 - Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to conduct a pilot program under which the Secretary will give up to five participating states the option of receiving a grant in an amount equal to the value of the USDA-provided commodities that the participating state would otherwise receive for each of FY2014-FY2018. States that a grant shall be used to purchase fresh fruits and vegetables for distribution to schools and service institutions that participate in the food service programs under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966.</summary>
</bill>
