<bill session="112" type="s" number="2023" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a safety performance rating system for motorcoach services and operations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2011--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to prescribe regulations requiring each motor carrier owning or leasing at least one motorcoach transporting passengers subject to DOT jurisdiction to display prominently in each motorcoach an understandable letter grade rating system allowing motorcoach passengers to compare the safety performance of motorcoach operators. Requires that such regulations also require motor carriers and any person selling motorcoach tickets to display the rating system in all announcements, advertisements, and points of sale for such motorcoach services and operations. Defines "motorcoach" as the term "over-the-road bus" is defined under the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century, except that "motorcoach": (1) includes a motor vehicle used to transport passengers that has a gross vehicle weight of at least 10,001 pounds, and (2) excludes a bus used in public transportation that is provided by a state or local government or a school bus.</summary>
</bill>
