<bill session="111" type="s" number="734" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Veterans Health Care Access and Quality Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the capacity of the Department of Veterans Affairs to recruit and retain physicians in Health Professional Shortage Areas and to improve the provision of health care to veterans in rural areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2009-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3988-3989"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3989-3991" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2009--Introduced.
Rural Veterans Health Care Access and Quality Act of 2009 - Removes the $44,000-per-individual limit on authorized payments by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) health professionals education debt reduction program. Requires notice to potential employees of their eligibility and selection for participation in such program. Includes VA facilities in the list of medical facilities eligible for the assignment of participants under the National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program. Requires the Director of the VA's Office of Rural Health to develop an Office five-year strategic plan. Authorizes the use of volunteer counselors as part of the Vet Center program. Directs the Secretary to carry out a program of teleconsultation for the provision of remote mental health and traumatic brain injury assessments in VA facilities not otherwise able to provide such assessments without contracting out or reimbursing other providers for such services. Requires the Secretary, for each Veterans Integrated Services Network, to negotiate with each party that has contracts to provide services at more than one community-based outpatient clinic in that Network to consolidate such contracts. Directs the Secretary to designate a rural outreach coordinator at each such clinic at which not less than 50% of the veterans enrolled reside in a highly rural area. Provides for peer review of health care services and patient records within the Network. Authorizes reimbursement for veterans' beneficiaries for air travel when it is the only practical way to reach a VA health care facility. Directs the Secretary to carry out a pilot program on incentives for physicians who assume responsibilities of primary care and mental health services to veterans at community hospitals in health professional shortage areas.</summary>
</bill>
