<bill session="111" type="s" number="3780" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Recovery Through Building Renovation Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a building efficiency retrofit loan credit support program, a State building revolving fund grant program, and a commercial and large building grant program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2010-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7091"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7091-7093" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2010--Introduced.
Recovery Through Building Renovation Act of 2010 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to authorize the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to provide credit support for debt or repayment obligations incurred in connection with financing the installation of efficiency or renewable energy measures (efficiency obligations) in commercial, industrial, municipal, university, school, and hospital facilities. Directs the Secretary to establish guidelines for such credit support, including: (1) standards for assessing, and threshold levels for, the expected energy savings; (2) examples of financing mechanisms that qualify as efficiency obligations; (3) eligibility criteria; and (4) lien priority requirements. Requires the Secretary to prioritize: (1) the maximization of energy savings with the available credit support funding; (2) the establishment of a clear application and approval process; and (3) the distribution of projects receiving credit support across states or geographical regions. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish an initial minimum energy savings requirement for eligible projects that results in the greatest amount of energy savings on a per project basis; and (2) annually adjust that requirement and any other credit support terms deemed necessary taking into account market conditions and available funding. Limits credit support to 90% of the principal amount of the efficiency obligation or $10 million for any single project. Authorizes the Secretary to charge reasonable fees for such credit support. Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) the MUSH Building Efficiency Program to provide grants to state revolving funds to finance energy efficiency retrofit projects for buildings that are owned or controlled by a municipality, a state or public university, a school or school district, or a publicly owned hospital; and (2) a program that provides grants to state or tribal governments to support property assessed clean energy bonds and other tax assessment-based financing mechanisms to support building retrofit projects expected to produce significant energy efficiency gains.</summary>
</bill>
