<bill session="112" type="h" number="4068" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Under Secretary for Science and Technology in the Department of Homeland Security to contract with an independent laboratory to study the health effects of backscatter x-ray machines used at airline checkpoints operated by the Transportation Security Administration and provide improved notice to airline passengers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400341"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412424" joined="2012-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Transportation Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="2044"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2012--Introduced.
Directs the Under Secretary for Science and Technology in the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to arrange for an independent study of the effects on human health caused by the use of backscatter x-ray machines at airline checkpoints operated by the Transportation Security Administration (TSA). Directs the TSA Administrator to ensure that large, readable signs or equivalent electronic displays are placed at the front of airline passenger check points where backscatter advanced imaging technology machines are used for screening to inform airline passengers that they may request undergoing alternative screening procedures.</summary>
</bill>
