<bill session="110" type="s" number="3000" updated="2013-07-19T22:47:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Native American Veterans Access Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to include Federally recognized tribal organizations in certain grant programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs for the several States and territories, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-05-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3979"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3979" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2008--Introduced.
Native American Veterans Access Act of 2008 - Provides for treatment of a health facility of a tribal organization as a state home for purposes of grant payments to such homes for veterans' domiciliary care, nursing home care, and hospital care. Exempts a health facility of a tribal organization from the prohibition against the Secretary of Veterans Affairs treating a new facility as a state home after September 30, 2009.Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to assist tribal organizations in constructing or acquiring facilities for furnishing domiciliary or nursing home care to veterans and in expanding, remodeling, or altering existing buildings for furnishing domiciliary care, nursing home care, adult day health care, or hospital care to veterans in homes.Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to include tribal organizations in veterans employment and training programs and grants.</summary>
</bill>
