<bill session="111" type="h" number="1491" updated="2013-07-19T23:25:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securing Equity for the Economic Development of Low Income Areas Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to reauthorize and expand the New Markets Venture Capital Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400661"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2009-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="2009-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Tax.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSM19" subcommittee="Finance and Tax" name="House Small Business"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2009--Introduced.
Securing Equity for the Economic Development of Low Income Areas Act of 2009 - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), in selecting companies to participate in the New Markets Venture Capital Program (Program), to select at least one company from each geographic region of the SBA. Requires (current law authorizes) the Administrator to make grants to such companies to be used for loans to new-market small businesses, and to guarantee debentures issued by such companies. Establishes the Office of New Markets Venture Capital, headed by a Director, to administer the Program. Revises the definition of "low income geographic area" for Program eligibility purposes. Requires a study by the SBA's Chief Counsel for Advocacy on the availability of equity capital in low-income urban and rural areas. Authorizes operational assistance grants to conditionally approved companies.</summary>
</bill>
