<bill session="109" type="s" number="3926" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Empower America: Securing America's Energy Future Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Arctic Coastal Plain Domestic Energy Security Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Coal-to-Liquid Fuel Promotion Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Corporate Average Fuel Economy Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Deep Ocean Energy Resources Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Gas Petroleum Refiner Improvement and Community Empowerment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Gas PRICE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Gasoline Consumer Anti-price-gouging Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">National Geo Fund Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Rigs to Reefs Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the energy, economic, and national security of America, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300085"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9904-9906"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Career education"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Geophysical prediction"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining engineering"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Ocean energy resources"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Submarine oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Telecommuting"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2006--Introduced.
Empower America: Securing America's Energy Future Act of 2006 - Coal-to-Liquid Fuel Promotion Act of 2006 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to make eligible for Department of Energy (DOE) loan guarantees any large-scale coal-to-liquid facilities that use domestic coal resources to produce at least 10,000 barrels a day of liquid transportation fuel. Directs the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) to establish a coal-to-liquid facilities loan program. Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer funds to the Secretary for a clean coal power initiative. Gas Petroleum Refiner Improvement and Community Empowerment Act, or the Gas PRICE Act - Obligates the Secretary of Commerce and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to take specified steps to streamline the petroleum refinery permitting process. Deep Ocean Energy Resources Act of 2006 - Sets forth actions under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) with respect to oil and natural gas production from leased tracts within the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS), especially the sharing of OCS receipts with neighboring states. Rigs to Reefs Act of 2006 - Revises OCSLA to direct the Secretary of the Interior to issue regulations for authorizing use of a decommissioned offshore oil and gas platform or other facility for an artificial reef, scientific research, or any other authorized use. Federal Energy Natural Resources Enhancement Fund Act of 2006 - Institutes a Federal Energy Natural Resources Enhancement Fund. Energy and Mineral Schools Reinvestment Act - Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to provide funds to historic and existing state-chartered recognized petroleum or mining schools and related institutions. National GEO Fund Act of 2006 - Creates a National Geo Fund for grants to support geothermal and geopressure oil and gas energy production, as well as a new program for fuel production from strategic unconventional resources and oil and gas resources using CO2 enhanced recovery. Arctic Coastal Plain Domestic Energy Security Act of 2006 - Keeps specified areas in the Coastal Plain of Alaska, including the Sadlerochit Spring Area, separate from oil and natural gas leasing activity for purposes of environmental, wildlife, and cultural management. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to establish a competitive and environmentally sound oil and gas leasing program on the Coastal Plain. Specifies lease terms and related requirements. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 and Biomass Research and Development Act of 2000 to fund biomass and other renewable energy resource research and development. Directs the Secretary of Energy to conduct an electric drive transportation technology research, development, demonstration, and commercial application program. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow an income tax credit for qualified teleworking expenses; and (2) exclude employer-provided computer equipment from gross income as a fringe benefit. Corporate Average Fuel Economy Reform Act of 2006 - Amends federal transportation law to require the Secretary of Transportation to revise average fuel economy standards for passenger automobiles. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to provide funding for the Advanced Building Efficiency Testbed and energy efficient public building programs, and the energy efficiency public information initiative. Gasoline Consumer Anti-Price-Gouging Protection Act - Prohibits suppliers from selling gasoline or petroleum distillates at unjustifiably increased prices in areas where the President or the Federal Trade Commission has proclaimed an emergency owing to an abnormal market disruption. Prescribes civil and criminal penalties. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend the excise tax credit for coal-to-liquids, the alternative motor vehicle credit, biodiesel income and excise tax credits, the investment tax credit with respect to solar energy property and qualified fuel cell property, the credit for production of natural gas, and the credit for residential energy efficient property. Extends specified tax incentives to encourage cellulosic ethanol production and the renewable electricity production credit. Amends the Clean Air Act to revise the authority of the EPA Administrator to make boutique fuel reductions.</summary>
</bill>
