<bill session="113" type="s" number="1037" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fourth Amendment Preservation and Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure adequate protection of the rights under the Fourth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412492"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Fourth Amendment Preservation and Protection Act of 2013 - Prohibits the federal government or a state or local government from obtaining or seeking to obtain information relating to an individual or group of individuals held by a third party in a system of records, except as authorized by this Act. Deems information obtained otherwise to be inadmissible in a criminal prosecution in a court of law. Permits the government to obtain, and a court to admit, information relating to an individual held by a third party in a system of records if: (1) the individual whose name or identification information the government is using to access the information provides express and informed consent to the search; or (2) the government obtains a warrant, upon probable cause, supported by oath or affirmation, and particularly describing the place to be searched and the persons or things to be seized.</summary>
</bill>
