<bill session="111" type="s" number="848" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Helicopter Medical Services Patient Safety, Protection, and Coordination Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to recognize and clarify the authority of the States to regulate intrastate helicopter medical services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2009-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="978"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="978"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/2009--Introduced.
Helicopter Medical Services Patient Safety, Protection, and Coordination Act - Authorizes states to regulate helicopter medical services with respect to: (1) the medical qualifications and training of helicopter medical personnel; and (2) the obligation of providers of helicopter medical services to comply with a state's health planning, patient safety, and medical service requirements. Prohibits states from imposing requirements on pilots. Authorizes states to regulate the following aspects of helicopter medical services to the extent such regulations are harmonized with applicable federal operating requirements: (1) establishment of criteria for determination of the appropriate medical institution to receive a transported patient; (2) specification of service requirements with respect to geographic areas within a state or during specified hours and days; (3) coordination of flight requests for emergency helicopter medical services; (4) compliance with medical services accreditation requirements, except where they infringe upon relevant federal operating requirements; and (5) provision of emergency helicopter medical services to all persons where needed. Authorizes a state to regulate certain aspects of helicopter medical services to the extent that such regulations are consistent with, and do not infringe upon, applicable federal operating requirements. Specifies among the aspects of helicopter medical services which states may regulate: (1) the necessary medical equipment and supplies to be carried on board or affixed to the helicopter; (2) the physical attributes of the helicopter necessary for the provision of quality medical care and for the protection of helicopter, ground medical, and emergency response personnel; and (3) specified communication capabilities among helicopter medical personnel and emergency medical services and public safety personnel, and between the flight crew and helicopter medical personnel. Requires a provider of helicopter medical services that is licensed in more than one state where state helicopter medical services regulations are inconsistent to comply with the most stringent regulation. Requires a state, if necessary, to establish regulations or negotiate mutual aid agreements with adjacent states, or providers of helicopter medical services in such states, to ensure access to such services across state borders.</summary>
</bill>
