<bill session="111" type="s" number="3718" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAVINGS Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Securing America's Veterans Insurance Needs and Goals Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure that beneficiaries of Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance receive financial counseling and disclosure information regarding life insurance payments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6890"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5993"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Securing America's Veterans Insurance Needs and Goals Act of 2010 or SAVINGS Act of 2010 - Requires a life insurance company, in order to provide life insurance for veterans under the Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance program, to: (1) provide financial counseling to the beneficiary or other person entitled to payment upon the establishment of a valid claim; and (2) include full disclosure with respect to such payment, including advantages and disadvantages of maintaining such payment with the company versus a financial institution. Prohibits a company from charging fees to a payee for maintaining such payment with the company. Requires the insured to be given the option of specifying the manner of disbursement of insurance proceeds. Requires: (1) the Director of the VA's Office of Survivor Assistance to attend each meeting of the Advisory Council on Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance; and (2) the Secretary to ensure that such Office has the necessary personnel to provide information on the receipt of such counseling.</summary>
</bill>
