<bill session="111" type="s" number="3922" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Furthering International Nuclear Safety Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to underscore the importance of international nuclear safety cooperation for operating power reactors, encouraging the efforts of the Convention on Nuclear Safety, supporting progress in improving nuclear safety, and enhancing the public availability of nuclear safety information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7812-7813"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7813" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Furthering International Nuclear Safety Act of 2010 - Directs The President to instruct the U.S. delegate to the Convention on Nuclear Safety to use U.S. influence to encourage: (1) parties to more systematically assess progress in improving nuclear safety and increase the number and public dissemination of related reports and other information; (2) the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) to further its support of the Convention; and (3) all countries that have or are considering the establishment of a civilian nuclear power program to formally join the Convention. Directs the Secretary of State to develop and submit to Congress the U.S. government's strategic plan for international nuclear safety cooperation for operating power reactors.</summary>
</bill>
