<bill session="110" type="h" number="6682" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Alaska Timber Management Areas for Education Land Selection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To allow the State of Alaska to fulfill a portion of its remaining Statehood land entitlement by selecting certain lands from within the Tongass National Forest and for those lands to be managed and operated by the Department of Natural Resources of the State as State Timber Management Areas and for other purposes under the laws of the State, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2008--Introduced.
Alaska Timber Management Areas for Education Land Selection Act - Requires, if the state of Alaska elects to select and acquire from within the Tongass National Forest specified lands in order to fulfill a portion of Alaska's remaining statehood entitlement to certain public lands within the National Forest System, conveying to the state the selected lands. Requires the election to be in the form of a bill approved by the state legislature and signed by the governor that contains specified requirements, including that: (1) up to 50% of the annual harvest of timber in state timber management areas be offered as 10-year contracts and that timber sales meet the needs of all existing wood processing operations on the Tongass National Forest; and (2) specified state receipts be deposited into an account for state kindergarten and grade school education. Sets forth provisions governing the exchange-transition period and the post-transition period, including requiring that, in the post-transition period, conveyed portions of the Tongass National Forest shall be administered and managed primarily for timber production as state timber management areas.</summary>
</bill>
