<bill session="110" type="s" number="1208" updated="2013-07-19T22:30:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security Account Number Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide additional security and privacy protection for social security account numbers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300037"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5093"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5093-5095" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3271"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2007--Introduced.
Social Security Account Number Protection Act - Prohibits any financial or related institution covered by this Act (covered entity), unless for a specific use for which no other identifier reasonably can be employed, from soliciting a Social Security number from an individual except: (1) for use in an identification, verification, accuracy, or identity proofing process; (2) for any purpose permitted under the Fair Credit Reporting Act or the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act; or (3) to comply with the requirements of federal, state, or local law. Specifies further exceptions to this prohibition. Prohibits a covered entity from displaying an individual's Social Security account number (or any derivative) on any card or tag commonly provided to employees (or to their family members), faculty, staff, or students for purposes of identification. Prohibits a state from displaying an individual's Social Security account number on his or her driver's license. Prohibits prisoner access to Social Security numbers. Prohibits the sale, provision, or display of Social Security numbers to the general public, or its acquisition or use to identify or locate a person with intent to injure or harm that person, or to use the person's identity for an illegal purpose. Specifies exceptions to this prohibition. Allows the sale, provision, or display of an individual's Social Security account number to the general public to the extent consistent with the individual's voluntary and affirmative written consent, but only if: (1) the terms of the consent and the right to refuse are presented to the individual in a clear, conspicuous, and understandable manner; (2) the individual is placed under no obligation to provide such consent; and (3) the terms and conditions of the consent authorize the individual to limit the sale, provision, or display to purposes directly associated with the transaction with respect to which the consent is sought. Authorizes the Federal Trade Commission, state attorneys general, and certain other federal regulatory agencies to enforce this Act..</summary>
</bill>
