<bill session="112" type="s" number="848" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Information Enhancement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the development of reports based on Medicare data, data that is publicly available, or private data that is provided by a requesting entity in order to improve the quality and efficiency of health care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2011--Introduced.
The Consumer Information Enhancement Act of 2011- Amends title XVIII (Medicare) to provide for the development of reports, based on Medicare data, data that is publicly available, or private data provided by a requesting entity in order to: (1) improve the quality and efficiency of health care; (2) enhance the education and awareness of consumers for evaluating heatlh care services; and (3) provide the public with reports on national, regional, and provider- and suppplier-specific performance, which may be in a provider- or supplier-identifiable format. Requires specified reporting procedures to provide for secure disclosure of Medicare data to Consumer Information Organizations meeting certain requirements under contract with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS). Directs the Secretary of HHS to permit researchers that meet criteria used to ensure the appropriateness of the release of Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services data for research purposes to: (1) have access to all Medicare data; and (2) report on the performance of service providers and suppliers.</summary>
</bill>
