<bill session="111" type="h" number="3683" updated="2013-07-19T23:45:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Teacher Incentive Fund Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish the Teacher Incentive Fund Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400626"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412387" joined="2010-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2009-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/2009--Introduced.
Teacher Incentive Fund Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to create a Teacher Incentive Fund program of competitive grants to assist states, local educational agencies (LEAs), and nonprofit organizations to develop, implement, or improve, appraisal and performance-based compensation systems to reward teachers and principals who raise student academic achievement and close the achievement gap, especially in the highest-need schools. Increases required nonfederal contributions to the program, on a graduated basis, from an amount equal 10% of the grant amount received in the first year to 70% of the grant amount received in the grant's fifth and final year. Allows the Secretary of Education to waive such matching requirement for high-need LEAs.</summary>
</bill>
