<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1206" updated="2013-07-19T21:00:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that any comprehensive plan to reform our national energy policy must promote the expanded use of renewable and alternative energy sources; increase our domestic refining capacity; promote conservation and increased energy efficiency; expand research and development, including domestic exploration; and, enhance consumer education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412256"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy demand"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy security"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2008--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that, in order to meet our nation's growing long-term energy demands and maintain our economic viability in the world marketplace, any comprehensive and economically viable energy bill must address: (1) expanded use of renewable and alternative energy sources; (2) increased domestic refining capacity; (3) promotion and incentivization of increased conservation and energy efficiency; (4) expansion and promotion of additional research and development through methods such as public-private partnerships; and (5) enhanced consumer awareness and education regarding methods to increase energy efficiency and available alternative fuel sources.</summary>
</bill>
