<bill session="111" type="h" number="2218" updated="2013-07-19T23:31:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Parental Consent Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the use of Federal funds for any universal or mandatory mental health screening program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2009-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1036"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2009--Introduced.
Parental Consent Act of 2009 - Prohibits federal funds from being used to establish or implement any universal or mandatory mental health, psychiatric, or socioemotional screening program. Prohibits federal education funds from being used to pay any local educational agency or other instrument of government that uses the refusal of a parent or legal guardian to provide consent to mental health screening as the basis of a charge of child abuse, child neglect, medical neglect, or education neglect until the agency or instrument demonstrates that it is no longer using such refusal as a basis of such charge. Defines a screening program under this Act as any mental health screening program in which a set of individuals is automatically screened without regard to whether there was a prior indication of a need for mental health treatment, including: (1) any program of state incentive grants to implement recommendations in the July 2003 report of the New Freedom Commission on Mental Health, the State Early Childhood Comprehensive System, grants for TeenScreen, and the Foundations for Learning Grants; and (2) any student mental health screening program that allows mental health screening of individuals under 18 years of age without the express, written, voluntary, informed consent of the parent or legal guardian of the individual involved.</summary>
</bill>
