<bill session="113" type="h" number="2265" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">More Energy More Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to issue an oil and gas leasing program under section 18 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act for the 5-year period 2016 through 2020, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2013-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2013--Introduced.
More Energy More Jobs Act - Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to issue a new oil and gas leasing program under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) for a five-year period in lieu of the existing Five-Year OCS Oil and Gas Leasing Program. Terminates the existing Five-Year OCS Oil and Gas Leasing Program for 2012-2017. Prescribes requirements for development of proposed new leasing programs. Requires the Secretary to: (1) allow the governor of a coastal state to nominate for leasing any OCS areas adjacent to state waters, (2) include each nominated area in the draft leasing program, and (3) consider the leasing of such areas as an alternative federal action. Requires the Secretary to include each state-nominated area in the final program unless the impacts of oil and gas development in a particular area cannot be effectively mitigated and the development is not in the national economic interest.</summary>
</bill>
