<bill session="110" type="h" number="6425" updated="2013-07-19T22:00:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeland Security Relief Corps Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to maintain a Response and Recovery Corps to perform functions related to the collective response to acts of terrorism, natural disasters, and other emergencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400402"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1379-1380"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM12" subcommittee="Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2008--Introduced.
Homeland Security Relief Corps Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to maintain within the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) a Response and Recovery Corps to perform functions related to the collective response to acts of terrorism, natural disasters, and other emergencies. Requires the Corps to consist of individuals who do not ordinarily have the duties of a full-time DHS officer or employee. Directs the Secretary to ensure that: (1) each Corps member receives core training in functions relating to emergency response or post-incident recovery and rebuilding efforts, or both; and (2) at least 30% of Corps members assigned to carry out a project reside, or resided prior to an act of terrorism, natural disaster, or other emergency, in the region in which the project is conducted. Requires the Secretary to: (1) identify response and recovery projects that warrant support from the Corps; (2) direct and oversee Corps activities; (3) govern the selection of Corps members; and (4) formulate and administer a system of uniform periodic reports on the number of individuals employed by, and the number of individuals and households receiving relief from, the Corps. Authorizes the Secretary to appoint a Corps member into federal service for the purpose of participation in Corps activities without regard to provisions governing appointments in the competitive service. Directs the Secretary to develop a plan for directing the Corps to assist in recovery and rebuilding efforts for the Gulf Coast region in the wake of Hurricane Katrina.</summary>
</bill>
