<bill session="111" type="s" number="3710" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Broadband Program Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve broadband coverage and service throughout the United States, especially in rural and tribal areas, and spectrum coverage for public safety broadband communication services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Broadband Program Reauthorization Act of 2010 - Amends provisions of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 concerning access to broadband telecommunications services in rural areas to authorize appropriations to cover the costs of grants, loans, and loan guarantees for broadband infrastructure in any area of the United States. Gives priority in making such grants, loans, and loan guarantees to projects that provide service to the highest proportion of rural residents that do not have access to broadband service and to project applications that will expand broadband opportunities in rural and tribal areas. Permits, under the Broadband Technology Opportunities Program, entities that have received waiver authority from the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to use the 763-768/793-798 MHz (700 MHz) public safety broadband spectrum to apply for funding. Authorizes appropriations for such Program. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) repeal the expensing and 60-month amortization of intangible drilling costs; (2) repeal percentage depletion for oil and gas properties; and (3) deny the deduction for income attributable to the domestic production of oil, natural gas, or its primary products.</summary>
</bill>
