<bill session="109" type="s" number="1935" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Fund for Ireland Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2006 and 2007 for United States contributions to the International Fund for Ireland, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300085"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Ireland"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Northern Ireland"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Police-community relations"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/27/2005--Introduced.
International Fund for Ireland Enhancement Act of 2005 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) U.S. assistance for the International Fund for Ireland has contributed greatly to the economic development of Northern Ireland and that both objectives of the Anglo-Irish Agreement Support Act of 1986, economic development and reconciliation, remain critical to achieving peace in the region, especially in the economically-depressed areas; and (2) the Fund is encouraged to support programs that enhance relations between communities and enhance relations between the police and the communities they serve, promote human rights training for police, and enhance peaceful mediation in neighborhoods of continued conflict. Amends the Anglo-Irish Agreement Support Act of 1986 to encourage the Fund to support programs that: (1) enhance relations between communities, and between the police and the communities they serve; (2) promote human rights training for police; (3) enhance peaceful mediation in neighborhoods of continued conflict; (4) promote training programs to enhance the new district partnership police boards recommended by the Patten Commission; and (5) assist in the transition of former British military installations and prisons into sites for peaceful, community-supported activities, such as housing, retail, and commercial development. Authorizes FY2006-FY2007 appropriations for U.S. contributions to the Fund. Expresses the sense of Congress that at least 35% of such amount for each such fiscal year should be used to carry out programs to improve local community relations and relations between the police and the people they serve.</summary>
</bill>
