<bill session="112" type="s" number="1244" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAVE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Save Our Industries Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for preferential duty treatment to certain apparel articles of the Philippines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2012-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2012-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2012-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4025-4026"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4026-4028" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2387"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="105"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2011--Introduced.
Save Our Industries Act of 2011 or SAVE Act - Grants duty-free treatment, subject to specified conditions, to certain apparel wholly assembled in the United States or the Philippines, or both, and components of such apparel consisting entirely of: (1) fabric cut in the United States or the Philippines, or both, from fabric wholly formed in the United States from yarns wholly formed in the United States; (2) components knit-to-shape in the United States from yarns wholly formed in the United States; or (3) any combination of such fabric or components. Prescribes single transformation duty-free rules for specified apparel articles, regardless of the source of the fabric, fabric components, components knit-to-shape, or yarns from which the articles are made, if they: (1) are cut and wholly assembled, or knit-to-shape, in the Philippines from any combination of such components; and (2) are imported directly into the United States from the Philippines. Prescribes requirements for review and enforcement of the program. Prescribes penalties for exporters and importers who engage in the transshipment of apparel that has been afforded preferential treatment under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
