<bill session="113" type="s" number="1239" updated="2013-11-02T07:02:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Scleroderma Research and Awareness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand the research and awareness activities of the National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention with respect to scleroderma, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Immunology"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Musculoskeletal and skin diseases"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Scleroderma Research and Awareness Act - Requires the Director of the National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases to expand, intensify, and coordinate the Institute's activities with respect to scleroderma, with particular emphasis on: (1) research focused on the etiology of scleroderma and the development of new treatment options, (2) clinical research to evaluate new treatment options, (3) basic research on the relationship between scleroderma and secondary conditions, (4) establishment of scleroderma patient registries, and (5) support for training of new clinicians and investigators with expertise in scleroderma. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to carry out an educational campaign to increase public awareness of scleroderma.</summary>
</bill>
