<bill session="112" type="h" number="6128" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Help Separated Families Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to ensure that immigration status alone does not disqualify a parent, legal guardian, or relative from being a placement for a foster child, to prohibit a State, county, or other political subdivision of a State from filing for termination of parental rights in foster care cases in which an otherwise fit and willing parent or legal guardian has been deported or is involved in (including detention pursuant to) an immigration proceeding, unless certain conditions have been met, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400347"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2012-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2012-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2012-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2012-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2012-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2012-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1249"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2012--Introduced.
Help Separated Families Act of 2012 - Amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to: (1) require state child protection standards to ensure that the immigration status alone of a parent, legal guardian, or relative shall not disqualify the parent, legal guardian, or relative from being a placement for a child; and (2) require the state procedures for criminal records checks to require the state to accept foreign identification documents as sufficient identification for purposes of initiating a criminal records check or a fingerprint-based check. Expresses the sense of Congress that the child welfare agency of a state, or of any county or other political subdivision of a state, should grant a waiver of any requirement which would prevent the placement of a child with a relative of the child, on the basis of a minor legal infraction, if the relative would otherwise be considered eligible for such a placement. Requires the state plan for foster care and adoption assistance to notify relatives seeking placement of a child that their immigration status will not be questioned, except to the extent necessary in determining eligibility for relevant services or programs. Prohibits a state or local government agency from filing for termination of parental rights in foster care cases based on the removal of the parent from the United States or the parent's involvement in an immigration proceeding, unless: (1) the state (or local agency) has made reasonable efforts to notify of the intention to file such a petition any parent of the child who has been removed from the United States, and any adult relative of the child, including through the diplomatic or consular offices of the country to which the parent was removed, and to reunify the child with any such parent or relative; or (2) the parent is unfit or unwilling to be a parent of the child.</summary>
</bill>
