<bill session="113" type="h" number="2874" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that the United States promotes women's meaningful inclusion and participation in mediation and negotiation processes undertaken in order to prevent, mitigate, and resolve violent conflict and implements the United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2013-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2013-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2013-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2013-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2013-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2013--Introduced.
Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) implementation of the United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security (NAP) is paramount in improving the lives of women around the world and increasing global stability and prosperity, (2) Congress is committed to advancing NAP principles, and (3) the President should ensure NAP's implementation and coordinate with the international community to reaffirm global commitments to implementation of United Nations Security Council Resolution 1325. States that it is U.S. policy to implement NAP. Directs the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to: (1) integrate gender goals into diplomatic and development efforts, and into agency guidance and contracting; (2) include gender in strategic and budget planning processes; and (3) review existing U.S. policies and programs on women and girls in foreign countries from a gender perspective. Directs the heads of federal departments and agencies to ensure that NAP's tenets are incorporated into all programs related to: (1) conflict prevention, (2) humanitarian and disaster response, (3) conflict mediation, (4) peacekeeping, (5) post-conflict reconstruction, (6) institution building, and (7) democracy promotion. Urges the Secretary to promote the inclusion of women in coordination and consultation with international partners. Directs the Secretary, the Administrator, the Secretary of Defense and representatives of other federal agencies to implement NAP and ensure relevant personnel training. Directs the Secretary to facilitate the efforts of partner governments to improve women's participation in peace and security processes, conflict prevention, peace-building, transitional processes, and decision making institutions in conflict-affected environments. Directs the Secretary and the Administrator to establish guidelines for overseas U.S. personnel to consult with specified stakeholders regarding U.S. efforts to: (1) prevent, mitigate, or resolve violent conflict; and (2) enhance the success of mediation and negotiation processes by ensuring women's meaningful participation.</summary>
</bill>
