<bill session="113" type="s" number="618" updated="2013-11-02T06:57:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pacific Islands Parks Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to conduct certain special resource studies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412507"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2028" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2013--Introduced.
Pacific Islands Parks Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct special resource studies of the following sites: (1) the Ka`u Coast on the island of Hawaii; (2) the northern coast of Maui, Hawaii; (3) the southeastern coast of Kauai, Hawaii; (4) historic sites on the Midway Atoll; and (5) upon request of the governor of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the island of Rota in the Commonwealth. Requires the Secretary, in conducting each such study, to: (1) evaluate the national significance of the site and the area surrounding it, (2) determine the feasibility of designating such site as a unit of the National Park System, and (3) consider other alternatives for the preservation and interpretation of the site. Requires the Secretary to update the study authorized under the National Park Service Studies Act of 1999 relating to World War II sites in the Republic of Palau. Instructs the Secretary to: (1) determine whether conditions have changed to justify designating such sites as a System unit, and (2) consider other alternatives for the preservation and interpretation of those sites.</summary>
</bill>
