<bill session="111" type="s" number="2884" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Special Agent Samuel Hicks Families of Fallen Heroes Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for the transportation of the dependents, remains, and effects of certain Federal employees who die while performing official duties or as a result of the performance of official duties.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2009-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2009-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2711"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2009--Introduced.
Special Agent Samuel Hicks Families of Fallen Heroes Act - Authorizes the head of the concerned agency to pay the moving, transportation, and relocation expenses attributable to a change of residence within the United States of the immediate family of covered employees, including any federal law enforcement officer, Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) employee, or customs and border protection officer, who dies in the performance of official duties, as well as expenses of preparing and transporting the remains of the deceased to the place where the family will reside following the employee's death (or another appropriate place for interment).</summary>
</bill>
