<bill session="113" type="s" number="15" updated="2013-11-02T06:52:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regulations From the Executive in Need of Scrutiny Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REINS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, to provide that major rules of the executive branch shall have no force or effect unless a joint resolution of approval is enacted into law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412492"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412573" joined="2013-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412556" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2013-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2013-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2013-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="367"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/2013--Introduced.
Regulations From the Executive in Need of Scrutiny Act of 2013 or the REINS Act - States that the purpose of this Act is to increase accountability for and transparency in the federal regulatory process. Revises provisions relating to congressional review of agency rulemaking to require a federal agency promulgating a rule to include in its report to Congress and to the Comptroller General (GAO) a classification of the rule as a major or nonmajor rule. Requires a joint resolution of approval of major rules to be enacted before such rules may take effect. Provides that if a joint resolution of approval is not enacted by the end of 70 session days or legislative days, as applicable, after the agency proposing the rule submits its report on such rule to Congress, the major rule shall be deemed not to be approved and shall not take effect. Permits a major rule to take effect for one 90-calendar day period without such approval if the President determines it is necessary because of an imminent threat to health or safety or other emergency, for the enforcement of criminal laws, for national security, or to implement an international trade agreement. Sets forth the congressional approval procedure for major rules and the congressional disapproval procedure for nonmajor rules. Requires the introduction of a joint resolution addressing a report classifying a rule as a major rule within three legislative days in the House of Representative and three session days in the Senate. Prohibits any amendments to such a joint resolution at any stage of the legislative process. Provides for expedited consideration of a joint resolution of approval and requires a vote on such resolution in the Senate within 15 session days after it is reported by the committee to which it was referred, or after such committee has been discharged from further consideration of the resolution. Allows a court to review whether an agency has completed the necessary requirements under this Act for a rule to take effect. Limits the effect of a joint resolution of approval of a major rule. Prohibits an agency from allowing a major rule to take effect without the congressional review procedures set forth in this Act. Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to provide that any congressional approval procedure set forth in this Act affecting budget authority, outlays, or receipts shall be assumed to be effective unless it is not approved in accordance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
