<bill session="111" type="h" number="3236" updated="2013-07-19T23:41:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Complete the Fence Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to complete at least 700 miles of reinforced fencing along the Southwest border by December 31, 2010, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400016"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2009--Introduced.
Complete the Fence Act - Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to: (1) provide that fencing that does not effectively restrain pedestrian traffic may not be used to meet the requirement that the Secretary of Homeland Security construct reinforced fencing along not less than 700 miles of the southwest U.S. border; (2) require the Secretary to complete construction of such fencing and installation of related equipment by December 31, 2010; and (3) prohibit any amounts appropriated for such fencing from being withheld because of the Secretary's failure to comply fully with consultation requirements regarding its impact on nearby communities and residents.Requires the Secretary to report to Congress by December 31, 2009, on progress made in completing such fencing and on plans for completing it by the deadline.</summary>
</bill>
