<bill session="111" type="s" number="3745" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Infrastructure Improvement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to require the Secretary of Agriculture in the case of low-income States to use 95 percent of the national average nonmetropolitan median income for purposes of determining the eligibility of communities in the States for certain rural development funding.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300068"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6898-6899"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6899" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Rural Infrastructure Improvement Act of 2010 - Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to provide that if the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) applies a median income requirement to communities for determining community facilities programs and water, waste disposal, and wastewater program eligibility in a state where the state nonmetropolitan median income is at least 90% of the national average nonmetropolitan median income, the Secretary shall use an amount equal to 95% of the national average nonmetropolitan median income in applying the median income requirement for any community in such state. Terminates such authority on September 30, 2012.</summary>
</bill>
