<bill session="109" type="hr" number="331" updated="2013-07-19T18:57:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-21T14:29:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-06-21T14:29:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2475) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2006 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400328"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-20T19:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 109-141, by Mr. Putnam.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-20T19:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Intelligence now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-06-20T19:56:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="53">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 53.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T12:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4829-4840" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T12:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 331.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T14:29:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 201 (Roll no. 288).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4838-4840" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-06-21T14:29:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4829" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="109" type="h" number="2475"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2005--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2475) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2006 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System.</summary>
</bill>
