<bill session="113" type="h" number="3216" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that members of the Armed Forces and Federal law enforcement officers continue to receive their pay and allowances despite a shutdown of the Federal Government or in the event that the debt of the United States Government reaches the statutory limit.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400221"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2013-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2013--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, during any funding gap during FY2014 when interim or full-year appropriations for the following activities have not been enacted, from amounts in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to transfer to the head of the appropriate executive agency such amounts as are necessary to continue payment of: (1) pay and allowances for members of the Armed Forces, including reserve components, on active duty; and (2) payment of salaries and benefits for sworn federal law enforcement officers. Requires such payments to be given priority over all other federally incurred obligations in the event that the public debt reaches the statutory limit.</summary>
</bill>
