<bill session="112" type="s" number="750" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Elections Now Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reform the financing of Senate elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2012-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2011-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2202-2208" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2262-2263"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-12">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights and Human Rights. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSRA" subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights and Human Rights" name="Senate Rules and Administration"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1404"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission (FEC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2011--Introduced.
Fair Elections Now Act - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) with respect to: (1) eligibility and qualifying contribution requirements and benefits of fair elections financing of Senate election campaigns, (2) establishment of a Fair Elections Fund, (3) eligibility for Fund allocations, (4) contribution and expenditure requirements, (5) a public debate requirement, (6) certification of whether or not a federal election candidate is a participating candidate, (7) benefits for participating candidates, (8) 500% matching payments to candidates for certain small dollar contributions, (9) political advertising vouchers, (10) establishment of a Fair Elections Oversight Board, (11) civil penalties for violation of contribution and expenditure requirements, (12) prohibition of joint fundraising committees with any political committee other than a candidate's authorized committee, and (13) an exception to a specified limitation on coordinated expenditures by political party committees with participating candidates for any expenditure from a qualified political party-participating candidate coordinated expenditure fund. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to: (1) prohibit the preemption of the use of a broadcasting station by a legally qualified Senate candidate who has purchased and paid for such use, (2) revise Federal Communications Commission (FCC) authority to revoke licenses for broadcasting stations who fail to provide access to Senate candidates, and (3) revise the formula for determining reduced broadcast rates for participating candidates in certain circumstances. Directs the FCC to initiate a rulemaking proceeding to establish a standardized form to be used by broadcasting stations to record and report the purchase of advertising time by or on behalf of a candidate for nomination for election, or for election, to federal elective office. Amends FECA to: (1) empower the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to petition the U.S. Supreme Court for a writ of certiorari to appeal a civil action; (2) require all designations, statements, and reports required to be filed under FECA to be filed directly with the FEC, and in computer-accessible electronic form; and (3) reduce from 48 to 24 hours after their receipt the deadline for the FEC to make designations, statements, reports, or notifications available to the public in the FEC office and on the Internet.</summary>
</bill>
