<bill session="110" type="h" number="6305" updated="2013-07-19T21:58:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify the authorities for the use of certain National Park Service properties within Golden Gate National Parks and San Francisco Maritime National Historic Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400314"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1275"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military parks"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2008--Introduced.
Makes technical and conforming amendments to public lands provisions relating to the Golden Gate National Recreation Area and the San Francisco Maritime National Historical Park. Renames the Golden Gate National Recreation Area as the Golden Gate National Parks. Designates the Golden Gate National Parks as a national park to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior.Amends the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 to make technical amendments to provisions concerning the Presidio of San Francisco and to eliminate the requirement for reversion of lands held by the Presidio Trust to the General Services Administration (GSA).Establishes the Fort Scott, Presidio of San Francisco Advisory Task Force to advise the Presidio Board of Directors on the preservation and reuse of Fort Scott.</summary>
</bill>
