<bill session="109" type="h" number="481" updated="2013-07-19T19:08:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-08-02">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Trust Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Trust Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Trust Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Trust Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Trust Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To further the purposes of the Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2000.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2005-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T18:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-107.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-06-08T18:48:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="59">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 59.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Fortuno moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5200-5202" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 481.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-06-27T15:31:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5200" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9052" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-07-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-08-02">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-08-02" type="public" number="109-45">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-45.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="57"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2005--Public Law.
Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Trust Act of 2005 - Authorizes the United States to take into trust specified real property formerly known as Dawson Ranch, including rights to all minerals and excluding improvements, in Kiowa County, Colorado, owned by the Cheyenne and Arapaho Indian Tribes of Oklahoma. Directs the Tribes to convey title to the Dawson Ranch to the United States. Declares that all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Ranch except any facilities constructed pursuant to this Act, are to be held in trust by the United States for the Tribes. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire by donation the improvements in fee. Permits the Secretary to construct a facility on the Ranch only after consulting with, soliciting advice from, and obtaining the agreement of, the Tribe, the Northern Cheyenne Tribe, and the Northern Arapaho Tribe. States that: (1) facilities constructed with federal funds or funds donated to the United States shall be owned in fee by the United States; and (2) for purposes of the construction, maintenance, or demolition of improvements or facilities, federal funds shall be expended only on improvements or facilities that are owned in fee by the United States. Requires the Ranch to be administered in perpetuity by the Secretary as part of the Site only for historical, traditional, cultural, and other uses in accordance with the Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2000. Requires that, for purposes of administration, the Secretary shall have access to the Ranch, improvements, and facilities as necessary for the management of the Site in accordance with the Act. Instructs the Secretary to take such action as is necessary to ensure that the Ranch is used only in accordance with all such requirements for the administration of the Ranch. Amends the Act to allow the Secretary to acquire land and interests in land within the boundaries of the Site which are owned by the state of Colorado (including a political subdivision of that state) only by donation or exchange (currently, only by donation).</summary>
</bill>
