<bill session="112" type="hr" number="430" updated="2013-07-20T01:06:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-13T14:06:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-10-13T14:06:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 358) to amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to modify special rules relating to coverage of abortion services under such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400643"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-12T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-243, by Ms. Foxx.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-12T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Energy and Commerce now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-10-12T13:41:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="80">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 80.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Ms. Foxx called up the resolution, H.Res. 430, and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER AGAINST CONSIDERATION - Ms. Moore stated that the provisions of H.Res. 430 violate section 426(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 by imposing an unfunded mandate and made a point of order against consideration of the resolution. Subsequently, the Chair noted that the required threshold of identifying the specific language in question had been met, and the House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the question of consideration. At the conclusion of debate on the question of consideration, the Chair will put the question to wit: Will the House now consider the resolution?</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13T12:22:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate on the Moore point of order, the Chair put the question on consideration of the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to consider the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6869-6881" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 430.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13T13:43:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6880-6881" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-10-13T14:06:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="786" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 248 - 173 (Roll no. 786).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6869" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13T14:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="358"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/2011--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 358) to amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to modify special rules relating to coverage of abortion services under such Act.</summary>
</bill>
