<bill session="110" type="s" number="1982" updated="2013-07-19T22:37:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Employee Ownership Bank Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the establishment of the United States Employee Ownership Bank, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-08-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10821"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cooperative societies"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee ownership"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Industrial relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2007--Introduced.
United States Employee Ownership Bank Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish the United States Employee Ownership Bank to foster increased employee ownership and greater employee participation in company decisionmaking throughout the United States. Requires the Bank to make: (1) loans (subordinated to the interests of all other creditors) and loan guarantees to employees to purchase a business through an employee stock ownership plan or eligible worker-owned cooperative; and (2) grants to states and nonprofit and cooperative organizations with experience in developing employee-owned businesses and worker-owned cooperatives to provide education, outreach, and technical assistance to such employee business efforts. Requires the Bank to insure such loans or loan guarantees against nonrepayment of the outstanding loan balance.</summary>
</bill>
