<bill session="111" type="s" number="1708" updated="2013-07-20T00:39:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Student Attendance Success Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a grant program to prevent truancy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2009-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-09-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9812-9817" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9812-9817" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2009--Introduced.
Student Attendance Success Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to states and, through them, competitive, renewable, three-year grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) for programmatic initiatives aimed at improving academic achievement by keeping students in school. Requires subgrant applicants to demonstrate that their schools have a history of significant truancy in grades five through nine. Requires subgrantees to use their subgrant, to the extent practicable, to partner with a community-based organization to create such programmatic initiatives. Directs the Secretary to award a grant to an nonprofit organization to establish and operate a National Resource Center on Positive Youth Development and School Success to serve as a font of information, training, and research aimed at thwarting students' risky behavior and enhancing their academic performance. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to define truancy, for purposes of this Act and the requirement that states collect truancy data under the Safe and Drug-Free Schools program, as the unexcused absence: (1) for three consecutive school days of a child required to attend elementary school; and (2) for three or more class periods on each of three consecutive school days of a child required to attend middle or secondary school.</summary>
</bill>
