<bill session="111" type="h" number="6095" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to preserve integrated care for durable medical equipment under the competitive bidding program for qualified hospital-related DME entities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2010-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/10/2010--Introduced.
Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to exempt qualified hospital-related durable medical equipment (DME) entities from programs for competitive acquisition of items and services. Defines a qualified hospital-related DME entity as a DME supplier that: (1) owns and controls, is owned and controlled by, or is under common ownership and control with one or more hospitals or one or more hospitals and a university; and (2) meets the applicable quality and financial standards. Declares that in the case of certain DME and medical supplies furnished by a qualified hospital-related DME entity in a competitive acquisition area for which a contract is in effect: (1) the competitive acquisition programs shall not apply; and (2) payment shall be made to the entity without regard to whether it submitted a bid or was awarded such a contract, and in the amount payable for such equipment and supplies under the contract for the area and period involved. Limits the application of this Act to items and services furnished by a qualified hospital-related DME entity that: (1) has provided satisfactory assurances that a substantial majority of its patients who are enrolled under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) are patients of a hospital that owns and controls, or is owned and controlled by, the entity or any provider of services affiliated with the hospital; and (2) was either furnishing items and services of such type on or before April 1, 2010, or owns and controls, is owned and controlled by, or is under common ownership and control with, a hospital (or one or more hospitals and a university) that was furnishing such items or services of such type on or before such date.</summary>
</bill>
