<bill session="113" type="h" number="882" updated="2013-11-02T06:26:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-15T19:08:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-04-15T19:08:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the awarding of a contract or grant in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold unless the prospective contractor or grantee certifies in writing to the agency awarding the contract or grant that the contractor or grantee has no seriously delinquent tax debts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2013-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-03-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T13:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 113-35.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-12T13:03:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="21">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 21.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Issa moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2001-2004" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 882.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15T17:45:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15T19:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2011-2012" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="104" datetime="2013-04-15T19:08:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays (2/3 required): 407 - 0 (Roll No. 104).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2001-2002" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2013--Passed House amended.
Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2013 - (Sec. 2) States that it is the policy of the U.S. government that no government contracts or grants should be awarded to individuals or business entities with seriously delinquent federal tax debts. (Sec. 3) Requires the head of any executive agency that issues an invitation for bids or a request for proposals for a contract in an amount greater than the simplified acquisition threshold (i.e., $150,000) to require each person submitting a bid or proposal to: (1) certify that such person does not have a seriously delinquent tax debt, and (2) authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to disclose information limited to describing whether such person has a seriously delinquent tax debt. Requires the head of any executive agency: (1) in evaluating any offer received in response to an agency solicitation for bids or proposals for a contract, to consider a certification that the offeror has a seriously delinquent tax debt to be definitive proof that the offeror is not a responsible source to do business with the federal government; and (2) to initiate a suspension or debarment proceeding against an offeror or a grant applicant after receiving an offer for a contract or grant application that contains a certification that such person has a seriously delinquent tax debt, or after receiving information from the Secretary that a submitted certification is false. Allows a waiver of such debarment requirement if an agency head certifies in writing urgent and compelling circumstances significantly affecting the interests of the United States. (Sec. 4) Requires the head of any executive agency that offers a grant in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold amount to require each grant applicant to: (1) certify that the applicant does not have a seriously delinquent tax debt, and (2) authorize the Secretary to disclose information limited to describing whether such a applicant has a seriously delinquent tax debt. Requires the agency head, in evaluating a grant application, to consider a certification that the grant applicant has a seriously delinquent tax debt to be definitive proof that the applicant is high-risk, requiring enhanced oversight. Requires the revision of the Federal Acquisition Regulation to incorporate requirements set forth in this Act relating to responsibility determinations and debarment for offerors or grant applicants. (Sec. 5) Defines "seriously delinquent tax debt" as an outstanding federal tax debt for which a notice of lien has been filed in public records. Exempts from such definition: (1) tax debts that are being paid in a timely manner under an approved installment agreement, and (2) debts for which a collection due process hearing has been requested or is pending. (Sec. 6) Makes this Act applicable to contracts and grants awarded on or after 270 days after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
