<bill session="109" type="s" number="847" updated="2013-07-19T20:20:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to lower the burden of gasoline prices on the economy of the United States and circumvent the efforts of OPEC to reap windfall oil profits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2005-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-04-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-04-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="81">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 81.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="OPEC countries"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/19/2005--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should: (1) directly confront and challenge the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) to increase oil production immediately; and (2) direct the Federal Trade Commission and Attorney General to exercise vigorous oversight over the oil markets to protect the people of the United States from price gouging and unfair practices at the gasoline pump. Declares that from the date of enactment of this Act until 30 days afterward: (1) deliveries of oil to the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) shall be suspended; and (2) one million barrels of oil per day shall be released from the SPR. Provides for the release of one million barrels of oil per day from the SPR for an additional 30 days if it is necessary to: (1) lower the burden of gasoline prices on the domestic economy; and (2) circumvent OPEC efforts to reap windfall crude oil profits.</summary>
</bill>
