<bill session="111" type="s" number="3130" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Congressional Health Benefits Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide that, if comprehensive health care reform legislation provides Americans access to quality, affordable health care is not enacted by June 30, 2010, then Members of Congress may not participate or be enrolled in a Federal employees health benefits plan under chapter 89 of title 5, United States Code.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2010--Introduced.
Stop Congressional Health Benefits Act - Prohibits a Member of Congress from participating in or being enrolled in any Federal Employees Health Benefits (FEHB) plan between July 1, 2010, through the date on which the Comptroller General reports to the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), the Secretary of the Senate, and the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives that health care reform legislation has been enacted. Makes this prohibition inapplicable if the Comptroller General determines by June 30, 2010, that such legislation has been enacted. Requires OPM to provide for a period of open enrollment for Members of Congress beginning on the earliest administratively feasible pay period following the date on which the Comptroller General reports such determination.</summary>
</bill>
