<bill session="112" type="s" number="1805" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from rejecting or otherwise determining to be inadequate a State implementation plan in any case in which the State submitting the plan has not been given a reasonable time to develop and submit the plan in accordance with a certain provision of the Clean Air Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412320"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7135-7136"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/2011--Introduced.
Prohibits the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) from rejecting a state implementation plan (SIP) or determining it to be inadequate, or from requiring compliance with a federal implementation plan for national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards, in any case in which the Administrator has not provided the state submitting the SIP at least two years after the date of promulgation of any final rule establishing an applicable standard intended to reduce the interstate transport of fine particulate matter and ozone to develop and submit an SIP. Prohibits the Administrator from rejecting a SIP during such two-year development period if, as a result of such a rejection, the state would be required to comply with such rule by not later than a year after the date of submission of the SIP. Requires the Administrator to provide in a timely manner to a requesting state any reasonable technical support, clarification, guidance, or data (including integrated planning models and other modeling) regarding the content of any final rule or regulation material to an SIP. Prohibits: (1) the proposed rule entitled "Federal Implementation Plans To Reduce Interstate Transport of Fine Particulate Matter and Ozone" from being or becoming effective until at least 18 months after this Act's enactment, or (2) requiring compliance with any standard or requirement under such rule or further regulatory action triggered by such rule until the final rule becomes effective. Requires the Administrator to continue to implement the final rule commonly known as the "Clean Air Interstate Rule'" and the rule establishing federal implementation plans for that rule as promulgated and modified by the Administrator until final action with respect to any federal regulatory mandate becomes effective in accordance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
