<bill session="111" type="h" number="3009" updated="2013-07-19T23:39:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American-Made Energy Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote alternative and renewable fuels and domestic energy production, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400345"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2009-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412262" joined="2009-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400635" joined="2009-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2009--Introduced.
American-Made Energy Act of 2009 - Establishes in the Treasury the American-Made Energy Trust Fund for alternative and renewable energy incentives and projects (e.g., wind, solar, biomass, and geothermal resources, waste to energy, hydropower, nuclear power, and coal to liquid technology). Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish, implement, and administer a competitive oil and gas leasing program on the Coastal Plain of Alaska. Repeals the prohibition against production or leasing of oil and gas resources from the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge (ANWR). Declares that the oil and gas leasing programs and activities in the Coastal Plain authorized by this Act are deemed in compliance with the purposes for which ANWR was established. Authorizes the Secretary to designate up to a total of 45,000 acres of the Coastal Plain as a special area, after consultation with the state of Alaska, the city of Kaktovik, and the North Slope Borough. Permits directional drilling in such special areas. Prescribes guidelines for implementation of lease sales. Sets forth: (1) a "no significant adverse effect" standard to govern Coastal Plain activities; (2) guidelines for expedited judicial review; and (3) a plan for federal and state distribution of revenues. Directs the Secretary to issue rights-of-way and easements across the Coastal Plain for the transportation of oil and gas. Provides for financial assistance for local government impact aid and community service assistance. Establishes in the Treasury the Coastal Plain Local Government Impact Aid Assistance Fund. Terminates all existing federal laws prohibiting expenditures to conduct oil and natural gas leasing and preleasing activities in the Outer Continental Shelf.</summary>
</bill>
