<bill session="109" type="s" number="375" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Flu Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for an influenza vaccine awareness campaign, ensure a sufficient influenza vaccine supply, and prepare for an influenza pandemic or epidemic, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage vaccine production capacity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300006"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2005-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2005-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2005-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1415"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="628"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="813"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Epidemics"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Influenza"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2005--Introduced.
Flu Protection Act of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to conduct, annually, a public influenza awareness campaign and education and outreach efforts preceding the flu season. Requires the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to urge early and full preordering of the influenza vaccine by Medicare providers. Requires the Director to: (1) work with the Administrator to publish influenza immunization rates among Medicare recipients; (2) support the development of State adult immunization programs that emphasize improving influenza vaccine delivery to high-risk populations and the general population; and (3) work with appropriate agencies to assess the efficacy of the influenza vaccine. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish a vaccine manufacturing facilities investment tax credit (20 percent of qualifying property per year) for property placed in service by December 31, 2009. Requires the Secretary to: (1) enter into contracts with manufacturers to produce additional necessary doses of the influenza vaccine; and (2) encourage States to develop a contingency plan for maximizing influenza immunization for high-risk populations in the event of a delay or shortage of the vaccine. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Vaccine Program, to establish a protocol to prevent, prepare for, and respond to an influenza pandemic or epidemic.</summary>
</bill>
