<bill session="109" type="h" number="130" updated="2013-07-19T19:05:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the General Education Provisions Act to clarify the definition of a student regarding family educational and privacy rights.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400214"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2005-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Education Reform" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Home schooling"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Students' rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2005--Introduced.
Amends the General Education Provisions Act (GEPA) to extend to families of home-schooled children certain educational and privacy rights currently available to families of public school students. Revises the definition of student for purposes of coverage regarding such family educational and privacy rights (under GEPA provisions which are also known as the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974).Includes under such coverage any person educated at a home school (whether or not State law treats a home school as a home school or a private school), if an educational agency or institution maintains education records or personally identifiable information on such person (whether or not the home-schooled person is in attendance at the agency or institution). (Current law excludes all those who are not in attendance at the agency or institution.)</summary>
</bill>
