<bill session="111" type="h" number="4220" updated="2013-07-19T23:50:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Promoting Jobs for Veterans Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs relating to small business concerns and employment assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412196" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2009-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="2010-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2904"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Tax.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSM19" subcommittee="Finance and Tax" name="House Small Business"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2009--Introduced.
Promoting Jobs for Veterans Act of 2009 - Reinstates the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) small business loan program, under which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs provides financial assistance to veterans' small businesses. Qualifies for such assistance any veteran business owner with a disability rated at 10% (under current law, 30%) or more. Removes VA authority to provide such assistance through direct loans, while maintaining authority for loan guaranties. Increases from $200,000 to $500,000 the maximum guaranty amount. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) contract-out to provide such loans; and (2) subsidize the interest rates paid under such loans. Provides a loan guarantee preference for National Guard and reserve members activated in support of the Global War on Terrorism. Requires (current law authorizes) a VA contracting officer to award contracts to small businesses owned and controlled by veterans using other than competitive procedures for contracts above the simplified acquisition threshold in order to meet VA small business procurement contracting goals. Allows the Secretary to evaluate a contract bid submitted by a small business owned and controlled by veterans on the same basis as the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) evaluates a bid submitted by a socially and economically disadvantaged small business. Amends the Small Business Act to extend the period of eligibility for certain small business assistance in the case of small businesses owned by individuals who are called or ordered to active duty for more than 30 days. Increases the amount of the monthly subsistence allowance payable to veterans participating in VA vocational rehabilitation programs. Directs the Secretary to award up to 2,000 internships annually to veterans who have completed a vocational rehabilitation program. Requires the Secretary to pay to a veteran who is unemployed for at least four months, 59 years old or younger, and ineligible for other VA education or training assistance a training assistance allowance for each month the veteran is enrolled in a program of apprenticeship or other on-job training. Authorizes the Secretary to pay a $500 monthly assistance allowance to a rural veteran teacher. Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to authorize appropriations for veterans' workforce investment programs. Directs the Secretary to include on the main VA Internet website a hyperlink with a drop-down menu entitled "Veterans Employment," which shall link to appropriate Internet employment websites.</summary>
</bill>
