<bill session="110" type="s" number="3554" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Affordable Coverage for Small Employers Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide employees of small employers with access to quality, affordable health insurance coverage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9417-9419"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Regionalism"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Introduced.
Affordable Coverage for Small Employers Act of 2008 - Establishes the National Health Coverage Policy Board as an independent agency to oversee a program to provide health insurance coverage to small employers and their employees.Directs the Policy Board to: (1) determine a comprehensive, quality, and affordable standard benefit package similar to that provided under specified large federal employees health benefits (FEHB) plans; (2) apportion the United States into regions with no less than two states each; (3) establish a Regional Health Coverage Exchange for each region to serve as a central purchasing site for health coverage, to provide information about plans, to facilitate enrollment, and to ensure health plan compliance with requirements; and (4) establish the Regional Health Coverage Exchange Board.Requires the Regional Board to develop common rating guidelines relating to the health insurance market for small employers. Directs each state to enact laws necessary to regulate its small group insurance market in accordance with such guidelines. Authorizes states to permit sole proprietors and individuals to purchase coverage through the Exchange.Sets forth requirements for a health insurance issuer to offer health care coverage through an Exchange.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a refundable tax credit for taxpayer premiums for qualified health insurance purchased through an Exchange; (2) allow a refundable tax credit for small employer contributions toward the cost of such employee health insurance; and (3) provide for advance payment of such tax credits.</summary>
</bill>
