<bill session="111" type="s" number="2871" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make technical corrections to the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2010-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-20">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller without amendment. With written report No. 111-297.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="574">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 574.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2870"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/10/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act to consider nonfederal service individuals serving as Commissioners on the Commission for the Conservation and Management of Highly Migratory Fish Stocks in the Western and Central Pacific Ocean or advisory committee members to be federal employees only for purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability. (Under current law such individuals are considered federal employees for injury compensation, ethics requirements, and criminal or civil statutes governing federal employees.) Amends the Pacific Whiting Act of 2006 to: (1) reduce to two the number of individuals appointed by the Secretary of Commerce to serve as scientific experts on the joint technical committee; and (2) consider nonfederal service individuals serving on the the joint management committee, the scientific review group, the joint technical committee, or the advisory panel to be federal employees only for purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability. (Under current law such individuals are considered federal employees for injury compensation, ethics requirements, and criminal or civil statutes governing federal employees.)</summary>
</bill>
