<bill session="111" type="s" number="2995" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Air Act Amendments of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to establish a national uniform multiple air pollutant regulatory program for the electric generating sector.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2010-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2010-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2010-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-04">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works Subcommittee on Clean Air and Nuclear Safety. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEV10" subcommittee="Clean Air and Nuclear Safety" name="Senate Environment and Public Works"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2010--Introduced.
Clean Air Act Amendments of 2010 - Amends the Clean Air Act (CAA) to require the Administrator of the Environment Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a sulfur dioxide allowance trading program to reduce sulfur dioxide emissions for fossil fuel-fired combustion devices in the contiguous states and the District of Columbia. Directs the Administrator to issue allowances authorizing specified annual tonnage amounts of emissions of sulfur dioxide from such devices for 2012-2014, 2015-2017, 2018-2020, and 2021 and thereafter. Provides for the distribution of such allowances. Requires the Administrator to establish two nitrogen oxide allowance trading programs (for specified Zone One and Zone Two states) to reduce nitrogen oxide emissions for fossil fuel-fired electric generating facilities that served as generators with nameplate capacities greater than 25 megawatts on or after January 1, 1985, and that produce electricity for sale in the contiguous states and the District of Columbia. Directs the Administrator to issue allowances authorizing specified annual tonnage amounts of nitrogen oxide emissions from such facilities in Zone One and Zone Two states for 2012-2014, 2015-2019, and 2020 and thereafter. Provides for the distribution of such allowances. Requires the Clean Air Interstate Rule and related federal implementation plans promulgated and modified by the Administrator to remain in force and effect with respect to all provisions relating to nitrogen oxides and sulfur dioxide emitted through 2011. Sets forth exceptions to the rule. Requires the Administrator to: (1) regulate coal- and oil-fired electric utility steam generating units under the CAA's regulations for sources of hazardous air pollutants; and (2) ensure that emission standards for the coal-fired electric utility steam generating units achieve at least a 90% reduction in mercury emissions when applied to the listed category as a whole. Requires electric utility steam generating units to meet maximum achievable control technology emission limitations by January 1, 2015, if the Administrator fails to promulgate nationally applicable emission limitations for such units by January 1, 2012. Requires the Administrator to promulgate regulations requiring certification of continuous emission monitoring systems to measure the quantity of mercury emitted by electric coal utility steam generating units.</summary>
</bill>
