<bill session="111" type="s" number="3326" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Job Creation and Affordable Housing Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide grants to States for low-income housing projects in lieu of low-income housing credits, and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a 5-year carryback of the low-income housing credit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2010-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2010-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4687"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2010--Introduced.
Job Creation and Affordable Housing Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to make a grant to each state equal to such state's low-income bond-subsidized housing election amount. Defines "low-income bond-subsidized housing election amount" as an amount a state may elect which does not exceed 85% of the state's bond-subsidized credit amount for low-income buildings. Requires states to use grants to make subawards to finance the construction or acquisition and rehabilitation of qualified low-income buildings. Requires the return of grant funds not used to make such subawards before January 1, 2012. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) deny a low-income housing tax credit for bond-subsidized buildings that received a subaward under this Act; (2) allow a five-year carryback of unused low-income housing tax credit amounts and a carryback for new low-income housing investments in 2010 and 2011; and (3) allow a full offset of low-income housing tax credits against regular income tax liability.</summary>
</bill>
