<bill session="109" type="hr" number="663" updated="2013-07-19T19:00:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit former Members and former officers of the House who are registered lobbyists from admission to the Hall of the House, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400383"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-31">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="646"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="648"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Capitol (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional office buildings"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional privileges and immunities"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2006--Introduced.
Amends rule IV (The Hall of the House) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to deny entitlement to the privilege of admission to the Hall of the House and adjacent rooms to any former Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner, a former Parliamentarian of the House, or a former elected officer of the House or former minority employee nominated as an elected officer of the House, if such individual is a registered lobbyist. Prohibits the House from making available to a former Member who is a registered lobbyist (except to the extent such services are made available to registered lobbyists who are not former Members) any services which are available exclusively to Members, officers, and employees of the House and former Members, including access to House office building facilities operated exclusively for Members and former Members.</summary>
</bill>
