<bill session="111" type="h" number="2888" updated="2013-07-19T23:37:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Devil's Staircase Wilderness Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Devil's Staircase Wilderness Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the designation of the Devil's Staircase Wilderness Area in the State of Oregon, to designate segments of Wasson and Franklin Creeks in the State of Oregon as wild or recreation rivers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2009-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-28">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-10-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 25 - 17.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16T15:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-337.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-11-16T15:10:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="195">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 195.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1272"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1272"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/2009--Reported to House amended.
Devil's Staircase Wilderness Act of 2009 - Designates certain federal land in Oregon as the Devil's Staircase Wilderness and as a wilderness area for inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System. Requires the Devil's Staircase Wilderness Area to be administered by the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior, subject to valid existing rights. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to decommission any National Forest System road within the wilderness boundaries and to convert Forest Service Road 4100 to a trail for primitive recreational use. Deems land acquired by the United States within the boundary of the Wilderness Area as part of the Devil's Staircase Wilderness. Specifies this Act's effect on fish and wildlife, buffer zones, and tribal rights. Withdraws the federal land designated as a wilderness area by this Act from all forms of: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials. Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate Franklin and Wasson Creeks in Oregon as wild rivers and as components of the Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</summary>
</bill>
