<bill session="109" type="s" number="1261" updated="2013-07-19T20:24:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Higher Education Simplification and Deregulation Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to simplify access to financial aid and access to information on college costs, to provide for more learning and less reporting, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300002"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6748-6751"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2005--Introduced.
Higher Education Simplification and Deregulation Act of 2005 - Amends Higher Education Act of 1965 to revise requirements relating to: (1) student access to financial aid; and (2) regulating student aid programs of institutions of higher education (IHEs). Provides for: (1) simplifying the Free Application for Federal Student Aid in an EZ FAFSA form, as well as electronic applications, and reapplications; (2) a system of early financial aid information; (3) revised processes for students with special circumstances; (4) eligibility verification; (5) year-round Pell Grants; (6) flexible loan limits for year-round study; (7) an annual listing of IHEs that are best buys in specified categories; (8) eliminating requirements to demonstrate financial need for certain types of graduate education assistance; (9) electronic voter registration; (10) review of regulatory and reporting requirements for student financial aid programs; (11) developing different environmental, health, and safety standards for research and teaching laboratories and facilities at IHES than for industrial facilities; (12) accelerated negotiated rulemaking; (13) compliance and master calendars; (14) exempting nonprofit IHEs from certain default management plan and eligibility and certification procedures; (15) renewing provisions relating to loan disbursement; and (16) IHE foreign gift or contract disclosure reports to be made available to the public rather than filed with the Secretary of Education.</summary>
</bill>
