<bill session="111" type="h" number="2922" updated="2013-07-19T23:38:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Assistance Downpayment Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a downpayment requirement for Rural Housing Service direct and guaranteed single-family home loan programs, to repeal the downpayment assistance initiative under subtitle E of title II of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act, and to prohibit use of amounts provided under certain other programs for downpayment assistance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2009--Introduced.
Federal Assistance Downpayment Reform Act of 2009 - Amends the Housing Act of 1949 to prohibit the Secretary of Agriculture from making loans for housing and buildings on adequate farms to any borrower or providing any guarantee, under the Doug Bereuter section 502 single family housing loan guarantee program, for any loan to any borrower, unless the borrower has paid, in cash or its equivalent, on account of the property to be acquired or refinanced, at least 3.5% of the property's appraised value or such larger amount as the Secretary may determine. (Thus requires downpayments for rural housing service direct and guaranteed single-family home loan programs). Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to repeal the downpayment assistance initiative that assists low-income families in achieving homeownership. Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to prohibit the use of grants under the Community Development Block Grant (CDBG) program for downpayment assistance on behalf of any family or person for the acquisition of a residence. Amends the Housing and Economic Recovery Act of 2008 to impose the same prohibition on amounts made available under the Neighborhood Stabilization program.</summary>
</bill>
