<bill session="113" type="h" number="2804" updated="2013-11-02T06:42:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ALERT Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">All Economic Regulations are Transparent Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs to publish information about rules on the Internet, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412553"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412531" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412596" joined="2013-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2013--Introduced.
All Economic Regulations are Transparent Act of 2013 or ALERT Act of 2013 - Requires the head of each federal agency to submit a monthly report to the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for each rule which such agency expects to propose or finalize during the upcoming year. Sets forth the required content of such report, including: (1) a summary of the nature of the rule, (2) the objectives of and legal basis for the issuance of the rule, (3) the stage of the rule making as of the date of submission, (4) whether the rule is subject to periodic review as a rule with a significant economic impact, (5) an approximate schedule for completing action on the rule, and (6) an estimate of its cost. Requires the Administrator to post reports on the Internet. Requires the Administrator to publish annually in the Federal Register: (1) information that the Administrator receives from each agency under this Act; (2) the number of rules and a list of each such rule that was proposed by each agency and each rule that was finalized by each agency; (3) the number of agency actions that repealed a rule, reduced the scope of a rule, reduced the cost of a rule, or accelerated the expiration date of a rule; (4) the total cost of all rules proposed or finalized; and (5) the number of rules for which an estimate of the cost of the rule was not available. Requires the Administrator to post on the Internet on an annual basis: (1) the analysis of the costs or benefits of each proposed or final rule issued by an agency for the preceding year; (2) the docket number and regulation identifier number for each such rule; (3) the number of rules reviewed by OMB for the preceding year; and (4) the number of rules for which a review by the head of an agency was completed, the number of rules submitted to the Comptroller General (GAO), and the number of rules for which a resolution of disapproval was introduced in Congress. Prohibits a rule from taking effect until the information required by this Act is posted on the Internet for not less than six months, unless the agency proposing the rule seeks an exemption under FOIA or the President determines by executive order that such rule is necessary because of an imminent threat to health or safety or other emergency, for the enforcement of criminal laws, for national security, or to implement an international trade agreement.</summary>
</bill>
