<bill session="110" type="s" number="1040" updated="2013-07-19T22:29:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tax Simplification Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to repeal the current Internal Revenue Code and replace it with a flat tax, thereby guaranteeing economic growth and greater fairness for all Americans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300089"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2007-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Flat-rate tax"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Retirement income"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax expenditures"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax simplification"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2007--Introduced.
Tax Simplification Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to replace the marginal income tax rates with a single rate of 19 percent (17 percent after December 31, 2009) on individual taxable income. Redefines "taxable income" to mean the amount by which wages, retirement distributions, and unemployment compensation exceed the standard deduction. Increases the basic standard deduction and includes an additional standard deduction for dependents. Includes in taxable income the taxable income of each dependent child under the age of 14. Replaces the current tax on corporations with a tax on every person engaged in a business activity equal to 19 percent (17 percent after December 31, 2009) of the business taxable income of such person. Makes the person engaged in the business activity liable for the tax, whether or not such person is an individual, a partnership, or a corporation. Imposes a tax of 19 percent (17 percent after December 31, 2009) on the value of excludable compensation provided during the year by an employer for the benefit of employees. Makes the employer liable for the tax. Repeals pension plan rules relating to : (1) non-discrimination; (2) contribution limits; and (3) restrictions on distributions. Revises rules relating to transfers of excess pension assets. Repeals: (1) the alternative minimum tax; (2) all income tax credits; (3) estate, gift, and generation-skipping transfer taxes; and (4) income tax provisions, except certain provisions relating to retirement distributions and tax-exempt organizations. Declares it not in order in the House of Representatives or the Senate, unless waived or suspended by a three-fifths vote, to consider any legislation that increases or adds an income tax rate, reduces the standard deduction, or provides any exclusion, deduction, credit, or other benefit that reduces federal revenues.</summary>
</bill>
