<bill session="111" type="h" number="6362" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Schools Against Violence in Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAVE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to improve school safety.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Safe Schools Against Violence in Education Act or the SAVE Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require states to allow a student who is attending a public school that does not have a safe climate for academic achievement, or who becomes a victim of a violent criminal offense while on school grounds, at a school event, or on a school bus to transfer to a safe public school within the school district. (Currently, the school must be persistently dangerous and the offense must occur on school grounds.) Requires states to: (1) permit schools to provide counseling and educational services to violent offenders in alternative settings; (2) require schools that know a violent offender is returning to school to notify the victim's parents that the offender is returning; and (3) provide school students, families, and staff with an annual report containing certain school crime statistics. Requires a state's determination that a school is unsafe to: (1) be based on those school crime statistics and certain other school data that the state is to collect; (2) be relayed to local educational agencies (LEAs) so that LEAs can relay such information to parents in a timely manner; and (3) result in ameliorative efforts by unsafe schools. Directs the Secretary of Education to: (1) make school crime statistics publicly available; and (2) publish a handbook to assist states and LEAs in meeting this Act's school crime, offense, and incident disclosure requirements. Amends the Safe and Drug-Free Schools and Communities program to augment the information LEAs must provide to states concerning students with guns to include incidents that do not involve a student's expulsion and school-related off-campus incidents, including those involving non-students. Includes bullying and cyberbullying prevention, and emergency preparedness in the federal activities required under the program. Directs the Secretary to fund schoolwide climate surveys of students, parents, and school personnel for use in creating collaborative plans for school improvement. Gives funding priority to unsafe schools.</summary>
</bill>
