<bill session="109" type="h" number="4396" updated="2013-07-19T19:43:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Vaccine Authority Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the National Vaccine Authority within the Department of Health and Human Services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2005-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2005--Introduced.
National Vaccine Authority Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) the National Vaccine Authority, under the direction of the Assistant Secretary for Vaccines. Requires the Assistant Secretary to: (1) ensure that the Authority serves as the central clearinghouse for HHS with respect to federal and private contracts for the purchase or distribution of vaccines; (2) monitor the supply and distribution of vaccines under such contracts; (3) enter into contracts to increase production of vaccines when necessary; (4) oversee the identification of vaccine strains; (5) establish, periodically review, and revise timetables by which the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) is required to identify the strains necessary to produce vaccines; (6) identify any delays in the production of vaccines; (7) ensure that such delays are accounted for as they occur; (8) oversee and monitor the distribution of vaccines; (9) develop, periodically review, and revise a vaccine emergency response and contingency plan; and (10) establish a commission to determine the current state of juvenile vaccines.</summary>
</bill>
