<bill session="111" type="s" number="295" updated="2013-07-20T00:25:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Quality and Payment Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve the quality and efficiency of the Medicare program through measurement of readmission rates and resource use and to develop a pilot program to provide episodic payments to organized groups of multispecialty and multilevel providers of services and suppliers for hospitalization episodes associated with select, high cost diagnoses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S723-724"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S724-726" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/2009--Introduced.
Medicare Quality and Payment Reform Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) review annually high volume readmission rates and resource use; (2) establish benchmarks for measuring them; and (3) make payment adjustments for subsection (d) hospitals that fail to meet such benchmarks. (Generally, a subsection (d) hospital is an acute care hospital, particularly one that receives payments under Medicare's inpatient prospective payment system (IPPS) when providing covered inpatient services to eligible beneficiaries.) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a pilot program to provide episodic payments to hospitals and other organizing entities for items and services associated with hospitalization episodes of Medicare beneficiaries with respect to one or more conditions that have a high volume, high readmission rate, or high rate of post-acute care under the Medicare program.</summary>
</bill>
