<bill session="112" type="s" number="1782" updated="2013-07-20T02:31:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Real Education for Healthy Youth Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the reduction in unintended pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections, including HIV, and the promotion of healthy relationships, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2012-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="3324"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/2/2011--Introduced.
Real Education for Healthy Youth Act of 2011 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award competitive grants to enable eligible entities to carry out programs that provide adolescents with comprehensive sex education to: (1) replicate evidence-based sex education programs, (2) substantially incorporate elements of evidence-based sex education programs, or (3) create a demonstration project based on generally accepted characteristics of effective sex education programs. Sets forth provisions regarding evaluation of such programs. Requires the Secretary to establish a common set of performance measures to assess the implementation and impact of grant programs funded under this Act. Requires the Secretary to award competitive grants to: (1) enable institutions of higher education to provide young people with comprehensive sex education with an emphasis on reducing HIV, other sexually transmitted infections, and unintended pregnancy; and (2) eligible entities to train targeted faculty and staff in order to increase effective teaching of comprehensive sex education for elementary and secondary school students. Prohibits programs funded under this Act from discriminating on the basis of actual or perceived sex, race, color, ethnicity, national origin, disability, sexual orientation, gender identity, or religion. Prohibits federal funds provided under this Act from being used for health education programs that: (1) deliberately withhold life-saving information about HIV; (2) are medically inaccurate or have been scientifically shown to be ineffective; (3) promote gender stereotypes; (4) are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of sexually active youth or lesbian, gay, bisexual, or transgender youth; or (5) are inconsistent with the ethical imperatives of medicine and public health. Amends the Public Health Service Act to repeal a provision that prohibits the use of funds appropriated for the prevention of AIDS to provide education or information designed to promote or encourage, directly, homosexual or heterosexual activity or intravenous substance abuse. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to repeal a provision that prohibits the use of funds authorized under such Act to operate a program of contraceptive distribution in schools.</summary>
</bill>
