<bill session="109" type="h" number="4128" updated="2013-07-19T19:40:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-03T18:06:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-11-03T18:06:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Eminent Domain bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect private property rights.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400004" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400037" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400038" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400045" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400633" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400096" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400658" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400167" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400202" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400214" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400644" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400287" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400305" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400322" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400626" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400336" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400353" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400620" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412010" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="409888" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400632" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400392" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400434" joined="2005-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2005-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-10-27">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 3.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-10-31T17:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 109-262.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-10-31T17:12:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="143">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 143.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02T20:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 527 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4128 with 1 hour and 30 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T12:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 527 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T14:00:00-05:00">
      <text>PERMISSION TO FILE REPORT - Mr. Sensenbrenner asked unanimous consent that the Committee on the Judiciary be permitted to file a supplemental report on H.R. 4128 prior to the comopletion of its consideration. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T14:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Judiciary, H. Rept. 109-262, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 527.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9569-9605" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4128 with 1 hour and 30 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 527 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John Kline to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T14:01:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour and 30 minutes of general debate on H.R. 4128.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T15:38:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 527, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sensenbrenner amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T15:42:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 527, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nadler amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T15:51:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nadler amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sensenbrenner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Nadler amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T15:52:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 527, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sodrel amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T15:55:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 527, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moran (VA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T16:05:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Moran (VA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sensenbrenner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Moran (VA) amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T16:05:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 527, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Turner amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T16:17:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Turner amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Turner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Turner amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T16:17:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 527, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gary Miller amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T16:29:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 527, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gingrey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T16:35:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 527, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cuellar amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T16:36:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 527, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T16:41:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 527, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Watt amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T16:53:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Watt amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Watt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Watt amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T16:54:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T17:48:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4128.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T17:48:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9604" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T17:48:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9589-9590" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-11-03T18:06:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="568" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 376 - 38 (Roll no. 568).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03T18:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="527"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="527"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3135"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3873"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3873"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h607"/>
    <amendment number="h608"/>
    <amendment number="h609"/>
    <amendment number="h610"/>
    <amendment number="h611"/>
    <amendment number="h612"/>
    <amendment number="h613"/>
    <amendment number="h614"/>
    <amendment number="h615"/>
    <amendment number="h616"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/3/2005--Passed House amended.
Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2005 - (Sec. 2) Prohibits any state or political subdivision from exercising its power of eminent domain for economic development if that state or political subdivision receives federal economic development funds during the fiscal year. (Defines "economic development" as taking private property and conveying or leasing it to a private entity for commercial enterprise carried on for profit or to increase tax revenue, the tax base, employment, or general economic health.) Makes a state or political subdivision that violates such prohibition ineligible for any such funds for two fiscal years. Provides that such a state or political subdivision is not ineligible for such funds if it returns all real property that was improperly taken and replaces or repairs any property that was destroyed or damaged. (Sec. 3) Prohibits the federal government from exercising its power of eminent domain for economic development. (Sec. 4) Establishes a private cause of action for any private property owner who suffers injury as a result of a violation of this Act. Provides that a state is not immune from any such action in a federal or state court. Places the burden on the defendant to show by clear and convincing evidence that the taking is not for economic development. Sets the statute of limitations for such an action at seven years. Allows the prevailing plaintiff's attorney to obtain reasonable attorney's fees and expert fees. (Sec. 5) Requires the Attorney General to: (1) compile a list of the federal laws under which federal economic development funds are distributed; (2) provide to each state and publish on a Department of Justice website the text of this Act, a description of the rights of property owners under this Act, and the compiled list of relevant federal laws; and (3) publish such text and description in the Federal Register. (Sec. 6) Requires the Attorney General to submit an annual report to the House and Senate Judiciary Committees identifying states or political subdivisions that have used eminent domain in violation of this Act, that have lost federal economic developments funds as a result, and/or that returned property to cure a violation. (Sec. 7) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the use of eminent domain for economic development is a threat to agricultural and other property in rural America; and (2) it is the policy of the United States to promote the private ownership of property and to protect the legal rights of private property owners. (Sec. 13) Prohibits a state or political subdivision from exercising its power of eminent domain over property of a religious or other nonprofit organization because of the organization's nonprofit or tax-exempt status or any related quality if that state or political subdivision receives federal economic development funds during the fiscal year. Makes a state or political subdivision that violates such prohibition ineligible for any such funds for two fiscal years. Prohibits the federal government from exercising its power of eminent domain over property of a religious or other nonprofit organization because of the organization's nonprofit or tax-exempt status or any related quality. (Sec. 14) Requires the head of each executive department and agency to review all rules, regulations, and procedures and report to the Attorney General on their activities to comply with this Act. (Sec. 15) Expresses the sense of Congress that all precautions should be taken to avoid the unfair or unreasonable taking of property from survivors of Hurricane Katrina for economic development or other private use.</summary>
</bill>
