<bill session="111" type="s" number="953" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Seasonal Influenza and Pandemic Preparation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the establishment of programs and activities to increase influenza vaccination rates through the provision of free vaccines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5019-5020"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2009--Introduced.
Seasonal Influenza and Pandemic Preparation Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a national voluntary influenza vaccination program for adults and children under which any individual may receive an influenza vaccine at no cost at any federally qualified health center, public or private hospital, physician office, clinic, or other entity determined appropriate by the Secretary. Sets forth provisions governing reimbursements for the costs of administering such vaccines. Declares that participation by an entity in such program is voluntary. Requires the Secretary to award grants to state and local health departments, public hospitals, and other entities to facilitate the establishment of influenza vaccination programs in partnerships with private entities, including pharmacies and private employers. Requires vaccines provided under a grant to be at no cost to the individual. Authorizes an entity participating in the grant program to seek reimbursement from the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to award grants to facilitate the development of influenza vaccination programs for students and families of students in partnership with local primary and secondary educational institutions. Directs the Secretary, under Medicare, Medicaid, and the State Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP), to develop an immunization plan with immunization target numbers for the respective populations served under such programs. Requires the Secretary to provide bonus payments to eligible health care providers and other entities who meet immunization targets established by the Secretary in such plans. Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to establish and implement a national public affairs campaign to increase influenza immunization rates.</summary>
</bill>
