<bill session="113" type="h" number="2363" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Innovation and Marketplace Technologies Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To foster further innovation and entrepreneurship in the health information technology sector.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400185"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/13/2013--Introduced.
Health Care Innovation and Marketplace Technologies Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a medical care provider to deduct from gross income the amount paid or incurred for qualified health information technology placed in service during the taxable year. Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to guarantee up to 90% of the amount of a loan, up to specified loan amounts, to a small business health professional to be used for the acquisition and installation of health information technology for the professional's medical practice. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology, to award grants for the development of an effective product, process, or structure that enhances the use, particularly by patients, of health information technology. Requires the Secretary, acting through the National Coordinator, to award prizes for development in areas of health information technology that are not adequately addressed by certified electronic health records (EHR) technologies and the use of such technologies. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish the Office of Wireless Health Technology. Requires the Health Information Technology Research Center to provide support for mobile health software application technology. Authorizes the National Coordinator to award grants for training health care workers in health information technology.</summary>
</bill>
