<bill session="110" type="h" number="7289" updated="2013-07-19T22:07:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financial Literacy Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide grants to promote financial literacy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="2671"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Personal budgets"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Student activities"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2008--Introduced.
Financial Literacy Improvement Act of 2008 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award formula matching grants to states or partnerships between states and experienced nonprofit providers of financial literacy or personal finance education programs. Requires grantees to use 25% of the grant funds to: (1) develop financial literacy standards and assessments for at least three grade levels; (2) create teacher training programs to embed financial literacy or personal finance education into core academic subjects; and (3) evaluate the impact such education has on students' financial literacy. Requires the remaining grant funds to be used for subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) or partnerships between LEAs and community organizations, local businesses, or other educational entities to implement such financial literacy activities, including student assessments and teacher training. Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) or partnerships between IHEs and experienced nonprofit providers of financial literacy or personal finance education programs for activities that increase student knowledge in consumer, economic, and personal financial concepts.</summary>
</bill>
