<bill session="112" type="h" number="786" updated="2013-07-20T01:17:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from gross income compensation received by employees consisting of qualified distributions of employer stock.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2011-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2011-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2011-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2011--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from the gross income of an employee: (1) shares of employer securities received in a qualified employee stock distribution as compensation for services that do not exceed the lowest number of employer securities received by any employee in such distribution; (2) any gain on such securities if held by an employee for not less than 10 years; and (3) in the case of any qualified disposition of an employer security that meets such 10-year holding requirement, any gain on so much stock acquired during the 60-day period beginning on the date of such disposition as does not exceed the fair market value of the employer security so disposed. Allows employers a tax deduction for the fair market value of securities transferred in a stock distribution. Requires an employee to recapture in gross income the amount of employer securities excluded from gross income if such securities are disposed of within five years after receipt.</summary>
</bill>
