<bill session="109" type="s" number="1462" updated="2013-07-19T20:26:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Darfur Peace and Accountability Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Darfur Peace and Accountability Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote peace and accountability in Sudan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2006-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2005-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2005-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2005-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2005-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2005-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2005-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2005-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2005-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="2005-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8681"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13413-13417" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2005-11-18" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13414-13417" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18T20:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18T21:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1424"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3127"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3127"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="495"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3884"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Alien property"/>
    <term name="Arabs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armistices"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Cults"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Government officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Logistics"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Military communications"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="Military intelligence"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Military transportation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Tankers"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations membership"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2674"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/18/2005--Passed Senate amended.
Darfur Peace and Accountability Act of 2005 - (Sec. 4) Expresses the sense of Congress with respect to the political and humanitarian situation in Darfur, Sudan. (Sec. 5) Amends the Comprehensive Peace in Sudan Act of 2004 to direct the President, with waiver authority including congressional notification, to block the assets and deny visas and entry to any individual (and family member) responsible for acts of genocide, war crimes, or crimes against humanity in Darfur. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the President to provide assistance to reinforce the deployment and operations of an expanded African Union Mission in Sudan (AMIS). Directs the President to instruct the U.S. Permanent Representative to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to advocate NATO reinforcement of AMIS, upon request of the African Union (AU). Directs the President to deny the government of Sudan access to oil revenues, including by prohibiting U.S. entry to cargo ships or oil tankers engaged in the oil sector of Sudan or involved in the shipment of goods for use by the armed forces of Sudan until such time as the government of Sudan has honored its commitments to cease attacks on civilians, demobilize the Janjaweed and associated militias, grant free access for deliveries of humanitarian assistance, and allow for the safe return of refugees and internally displaced persons. (Exempts from such restriction ships or tankers involved in an internationally-recognized demobilization program or the shipment of non-lethal assistance necessary to carry the Comprehensive Peace Agreement for Sudan.) Prohibits, with waiver authority, U.S. assistance to a country in violation of U.N. Security Council Resolutions 1556 and 1591(embargo on military assistance to Sudan). (Sec. 7) Directs the President to instruct the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations to urge the adoption of a Security Council resolution which: (1) supports AMIS' expansion; (2) reinforces AU efforts to negotiate peace talks between the government of Sudan, the Sudan Liberation Movement/Army (SLM/A), the Justice and Equality Movement (JEM), and associated armed groups in Darfur; (3) imposes sanctions against the government of Sudan, including sanctions against individual government members and entities controlled or owned by officials of the government of Sudan or the National Congress Party, until the government of Sudan has honored its commitments to cease civilian attacks, demobilize the Janjaweed and associated militias, grant free access for deliveries of humanitarian assistance, and allow for the safe return of refugees and internally displaced persons; (4) extends the military embargo established by Security Council Resolutions 1556 and 1591 to include a total prohibition on the supply of offensive military equipment to the government of Sudan, except for use in an internationally-recognized demobilization program or for non-lethal assistance necessary to carry out elements of the Comprehensive Peace Agreement for Sudan; (5) calls upon those U.N. member states that continue to undermine peace efforts in Sudan by providing military assistance and equipment to the government of Sudan, the SLM/A, the JEM, and associated armed groups in the Darfur to end such activities; and (6) calls for suspension of the government of Sudan's General Assembly membership until Sudan ends civilian attacks, demobilizes the Janjaweed and associated militias, grants free access for deliveries of humanitarian assistance in Darfur, and allows for safe return of refugees and internally displaced persons. (Sec. 8.) Continues specified restrictions on the government of Sudan until the President certifies that Sudan is acting in good faith to: (1) peacefully resolve the Darfur crisis; (2) disarm and demobilize the Janjaweed and all government-allied militias; (3) adhere to Security Council Resolutions 1556, 1564, 1591, and 1593; (4) negotiate a peaceful resolution to the crisis in eastern Sudan; (5) cooperate with efforts to disarm, demobilize, and deny safe haven to members of the Lord's Resistance Army; and (6) implement the Comprehensive Peace Agreement for Sudan. (Sec. 9) Amends the Assistance for International Malaria Control Act to: (1) make civil administrations eligible for assistance under such Act; (2) make such assistance available to eligible recipients in southern Sudan, southern Kordofan/Nuba Mountains State, Blue Nile State, and Abyei (current law refers to areas outside of control of the government of Sudan); (3) require congressional notification prior to obligation of assistance; and (4) revise sanctions applicable to Sudan set forth in Executive Order No. 13067 to except activities or related transactions with respect to southern Sudan, southern Kordofan/Nuba Mountains State, Blue Nile State, or Abyei, if the President determines that such activities or related transactions would directly benefit the economic recovery and development of those areas and people. (Sec. 10) Amends the Sudan Peace Act to direct the Secretary of State to report to the appropriate congressional committees respecting: (1) AMIS deployment and needs; (2) sanctions in support of peace in Darfur; and (3) individuals identified by the United Nations in connection with genocide, war crimes, and crimes against humanity or other violations of international humanitarian law in Darfur.</summary>
</bill>
