<bill session="112" type="h" number="6135" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transferring Credits for College Completion Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase transparency and reduce students' burdens related to transferring credits between institutions of higher education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2012--Introduced.
Transferring Credits for College Completion Act of 2012 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to include on the College Navigator website the percentage of undergraduates at an institution of higher education (IHE) who have transferred from another IHE and earned their degree or certificate in their program of study within: (1) the normal time for its completion, (2) 150% of the normal time for its completion, and (3) 200% of the normal time for its completion. Requires IHEs, to the extent practicable, to include in their course schedule publications information on whether each listed course or program of study is transferable for credit toward the completion of a degree at a public IHE located in their state. Requires each public IHE, by July 1, 2014, to enter into an articulation agreement with the other public IHEs located in its state. Requires those agreements to include: (1) a common general education core curriculum consisting of at least 30 credit hours or equivalent coursework that are fully transferable toward meeting specific degree or certificate requirements at other public IHEs in the state, (2) common course numbering for substantially similar courses in that curriculum, and (3) a guarantee that an associate degree in an academic major in the arts and sciences at a public IHE in the state will be credited as the first 2 years of a related baccalaureate program at other public IHEs in the state. Excepts Tribal Colleges or Universities from those articulation agreement requirements.</summary>
</bill>
