<bill session="110" type="h" number="4082" updated="2013-07-19T21:39:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Long-term Care Quality and Modernization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the quality of, and access to, long-term care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2007-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2007-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1980"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Ambulances"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Occupational therapy"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Physical therapy"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Speech disorders"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/6/2007--Introduced.
Long-term Care Quality and Modernization Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Service to conduct a demonstration program requiring a state to establish a process for joint training and education of surveyors and providers for skilled nursing facilities (SNFs) and nursing facilities at least annually. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) and title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to allow resumption of nursing aid training programs in SNFs after correction of deficiencies. Authorizes the Secretary to exclude from the Medicare prospective payment system (PPS) for SNFs: (1) certain (high cost and low probability) cancer treatment drugs, including antineoplastic drugs, antiemitics, and supportive medications; (2) all ambulance services, including those furnished to an individual in conjunction with renal dialysis services; and (3) other appropriate items and services. Authorizes a physician, nurse practitioner, or clinical nurse specialist to certify under Medicare that a prescribed series of blood glucose tests are medically required. Provides for: (1) counting of observation days in application of the Medicare post-hospital requirement for coverage of SNF care; (2) extension of the exceptions process for Medicare therapy caps; and (3) expansion of telehealth services to SNFs. Directs the Secretary to study and report to Congress on developing management alternatives to the Medicare payment cap for physical therapy, speech-language pathology, and occupational therapy services. Amends the Public Health Service Act to: (1) authorize the Secretary to make grants to, and contract with, physical therapy programs for projects to recruit and retain faculty and students, develop curriculum, and support the distribution of physical therapy practitioners in underserved areas; and (2) repeal the limitation to nonprofit entities only in the assignment of nurses under the nursing loan repayment program to private entities. Requires the Secretary to establish a national nursing database to predict future nursing shortages. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish the Long Term Care Quality Advisory Commission; and (2) make grants for five demonstration projects to implement and evaluate methods for improving the quality of health care in long-term care settings. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to set a 15-year recovery period for qualified long-term care improvement property.</summary>
</bill>
