<bill session="109" type="s" number="2230" updated="2013-07-19T20:32:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Servicemember Safety Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that members of the Armed Forces have complete personal armored protection necessary for their duties, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-01-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2006--Introduced.
Servicemember Safety Act of 2006 - Directs the Secretary of each military department to ensure that each Armed Forces member who is ordered, assigned, or deployed to a combat zone or a combat operation (covered member) is provided with interceptor body armor and such other appropriate protective gear so as to provide such covered member with complete personal armored protection. Sets forth an exception to such requirement if a unit commander of a covered member certifies that the provision of complete personal armored protection to the covered member would impose a greater risk of injury or death than if the member were provided with less than complete personal armored protection. Requires each relevant Secretary to provide an amount to a covered member for the purchase, or for the reimbursement of purchases made by others on behalf of the covered member, of such interceptor body armor and other appropriate protective gear. Limits the total payment to a covered member to no more than the lesser of $1,100 or the amount incurred by or on behalf of the covered member to purchase the body armor and other gear.</summary>
</bill>
