<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1380" updated="2013-07-19T21:02:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Commending Federal and local law enforcement for their efforts to crack down on illegal immigration in the Chicagoland suburbs and calling on the Governor of the State of Illinois to immediately implement employee verification technology to curb rising trends in illegal immigration in the State of Illinois.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412202"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2008-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2008--Introduced.
Commends local law enforcement officers participating in Operation Community Shield.Reaffirms the basic right of employers to verify the immigration status of prospective employees.Calls on the Illinois General Assembly to repeal Illinois Public Act 095-0138, which denies employers the right to verify the legal status of potential employees.Urges the Governor and legislature of Illinois to take every possible action to enforce existing immigration laws and address the growing illegal immigrant population in Illinois.</summary>
</bill>
