<bill session="111" type="h" number="5573" updated="2013-07-20T00:02:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeland Security Grant Review Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security to biennially review and evaluate the grants management and oversight practices of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412234"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM12" subcommittee="Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2010--Introduced.
Homeland Security Grant Review Act - Directs the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), one year after this Act's enactment and every two years thereafter, to review the grants management and oversight practices of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) with respect to the Urban Area Security Initiative grant program, the State Homeland Security Grant Program, public transportation security grants, railroad security grants, over-the-road bus security grants, and maritime transportation and facility security grants. Requires such review to assess: (1) the FEMA workforce that administers such grants; (2) any additional resources and staff necessary to carry out management and oversight; (3) coordination with other DHS components with a role in assisting FEMA in managing and administering the grants; and (4) the procedures that grant recipients must follow to obligate and expend their grant awards.</summary>
</bill>
