<bill session="113" type="s" number="729" updated="2013-11-02T06:58:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disarm Criminals and Protect Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect law abiding citizens by preventing criminals from obtaining firearms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412573"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2013-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-16" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="39">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 39.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2013--Introduced.
Disarm Criminals and Protect Communities Act - Establishes within the Department of Justice (DOJ) the Felon and Fugitive Firearm Task Force to strengthen DOJ efforts to investigate and prosecute cases of convicted felons and fugitives who illegally attempt to purchase a firearm. Requires the Task Force to provide direction for and recommendations to the Attorney General regarding such investigation and prosecution, including with respect to: (1) the allocation of DOJ resources; (2) enhancing cooperation among federal agencies and entities and among federal, state, and local authorities; (3) changes in rules, regulations, or policy to improve effectiveness; and (4) improvements through changes in rules, regulations, or policy. Makes specified sums in the DOJ Assets Forfeiture Fund available for: (1) the investigation and prosecution of cases of convicted felons and fugitives who illegally attempt to purchase a firearm, and (2) the Task Force.</summary>
</bill>
