<bill session="109" type="s" number="2463" updated="2013-07-19T20:34:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-19">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">New Hampshire Wilderness Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">New England Wilderness Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to designate as wilderness certain National Forest System land in the State of New Hampshire.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An act to designate certain land in New England as wilderness for inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation system and certain land as a National Recreation Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2006-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2470-2471"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2471" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-19">
      <text>Senate Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9732-9734" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-09-19" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9733-9734" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-19T20:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Dairy, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5059"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5062"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="4001"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5019"/>
    <amendment number="s5020"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/19/2006--Passed Senate amended.
New England Wilderness Act of 2006 - Title I: New Hampshire - Designates specified federal lands managed by the United States Forest Service in the White Mountain National Forest area of New Hampshire as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System (lands to be known as the Wild River Wilderness and lands to be incorporated in the Sandwich Range Wilderness). Title II: Vermont - Subtitle A: Designation of Wilderness Areas - Designates specified federal lands managed by the Forest Service in Vermont as wilderness areas and National Wilderness Preservation System components (lands to be known as the Glastenbury Wilderness, the Joseph Battell Wilderness, the Breadloaf Wilderness, the Lye Brook Wilderness, the Peru Peak Wilderness, and the Big Branch Wilderness). Requires the Forest Service to allow the continuance of the Appalachian National Scenic Trail, the Long Trail, the Catamount Trail, and the marking and maintenance of associated trails and trail structures consistent with the management direction established under the Green Mountain National Forest Land and Resource Management Plan. Subtitle B: Moosalamoo National Recreation Area - Designates specified federal lands managed by the Forest Service in Vermont as the Moosalamoo National Recreation Area. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, to administer the Area in accordance with laws applicable to National Forest System units and the management direction established for the Moosalamoo Recreation and Education Management Area under such Management Plan.</summary>
</bill>
