<bill session="112" type="h" number="4029" updated="2013-07-20T01:44:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common Sense Economic Recovery Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit certain current loans that would otherwise be treated as non-accrual loans as accrual loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412463" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2012-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1723"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2012--Introduced.
Common Sense Economic Recovery Act of 2012 - Cites circumstances under which, for purposes of determining capital requirements or measuring an insured depository institution's capital, such an institution may treat a non-accrual loan as an accrual loan. (Non-accrual [also known as non-performing or doubtful] loans are those on which interest is overdue and full collection of principal is uncertain, and so interest, if it has not been paid in over 90 days, cannot be credited to the bank's revenue account until it has actually been received.) Permits an insured depository institution to treat a non-accrual loan as an accrual loan if: (1) the loan is current, (2) no monthly payment has been more than 30 days delinquent during the previous 6-month period, and (3) loan payments are being made pursuant to the contract terms and all parties agree to any refinances and modifications. Prohibits a modified or restructured loan from being treated as a non-accrual loan if the borrower demonstrates the ability to perform on such a loan: (1) over a period of 6 months; or (2) over a period of 3 consecutive payments in the case of a quarterly, semi-annual, or longer repayment schedule. Prohibits the appropriate federal banking agency from: (1) imposing any additional accounting requirements upon an insured depository institution with respect to a loan treated as an accrual loan under this Act if the result of such requirement would adversely impact measurement of the institution's capital, or (2) requiring an insured depository institution to treat a loan as a non-accrual loan solely because the loan collateral has reduced in value. Excludes from the accounting requirements and prohibitions of this Act any issuer of a security registered under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934. Directs the Financial Stability Oversight Council to study how best to prevent the issuance of contradictory guidance to such institutions by federal banking agencies with respect to loan classifications and capital requirements.</summary>
</bill>
