<bill session="111" type="hr" number="157" updated="2013-07-19T22:57:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-12T13:27:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-02-12T13:27:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-11T18:43:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-14, by Mr. Perlmutter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-11T18:43:00-05:00">
      <text>The resolutions authorizes the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules at any time through the legislative day of February 13, 2009. The resolution also provides that the Speaker or her designee shall consult with the Minority Leader or his designee on the designation of any matter for consideration under suspension of the rules pursuant to the resolution. The resolution also provides that H. Res. 10 is amended to change the hour of daily meeting of the House to 9:00 a.m. for Fridays and Saturdays.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-02-11T18:44:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="9">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 9.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12T10:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1254-1260" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12T10:30:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 157.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12T11:27:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1260" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12T11:27:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 157, the Chair put the question on the agreeing to the resolution, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Foxx demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12T13:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1261" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-02-12T13:27:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="63" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 248 - 174 (Roll no. 63).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1255" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12T13:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="10"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2009--Introduced.
Makes it in order at any time through February 13, 2009, for the Speaker of the House of Representatives to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules. Amends H.Res.10, 111th Congress (fixing the daily hour of meeting for the House ) to revise the daily hour of meeting of the First Session of the 111th Congress, until Monday, May 18, 2009, to: (1) 2 p.m. on Mondays; (2) 12 noon on Tuesdays; (3) 10 a.m. on Wednesday and Thursday; and (4) 9 a.m. on all other days of the week. Continues the current daily hour of meeting from Monday, May 18, 2009, until the end of the first session.</summary>
</bill>
