<bill session="112" type="h" number="946" updated="2013-07-20T01:18:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Endangered Salmon Predation Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to reduce predation on endangered Columbia River salmon, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412486" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2011-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3069"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2011--Introduced.
Endangered Salmon Predation Prevention Act - Amends the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to authorize the Secretary of the department in which the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) is operating to issue one-year permits for the lethal taking of California sea lions on the waters of the Columbia River or its tributaries if the Secretary determines that alternative measures to reduce sea lion predation on salmonid stocks listed as threatened or endangered under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 do not adequately protect such stocks. Prohibits such a permit from authorizing the lethal taking of more than 10 California sea lions. Limits the cumulative annual taking of California sea lions each year under all such permits to 1% of the annual potential biological removal level. Requires the Secretary to determine whether alternative measures to reduce sea lion predation on such salmonid stocks will adequately protect them. Prohibits a California sea lion from being taken unless the permit holder has determined that: (1) such sea lion has preyed upon salmonid stocks in the Columbia River, and (2) nonlethal alternative measures have not been effective. Terminates such permitting authority after the earlier of five years after this Act's enactment or the date the Secretary determines that lethal removal authority is no longer necessary to protect such salmonid stocks. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) nonlethal means of preventing sea lion predation of salmonid stocks in the Columbia River is preferable to lethal means, (2) permit holders exercising lethal removal authority should be trained in wildlife management, and (3) the government should continue to support effective nonlethal alternatives.</summary>
</bill>
