<bill session="111" type="s" number="3499" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fiduciary Benefits Oversight Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to require fiduciaries of individuals receiving benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to authorize the Secretary to obtain financial records with respect to such individuals for purposes of administering such laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4993-4994"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4994" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2010--Introduced.
Fiduciary Benefits Oversight Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to require any person appointed or recognized as a fiduciary for a VA beneficiary to provide authorization for the Secretary to obtain from any financial institution any financial record with respect to the fiduciary or the beneficiary when necessary: (1) for the administration of a VA program; or (2) in order to safeguard the beneficiary's benefits against neglect, misappropriation, misuse, embezzlement, or fraud. Provides a conditional time limit on such authorization. Provides that if the fiduciary refuses to provide such authorization, the Secretary may revoke the fiduciary's appointment or recognition.</summary>
</bill>
