<bill session="113" type="h" number="146" updated="2013-11-02T06:20:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Collaborative Academic Research Efforts for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the expansion, intensification, and coordination of the programs and activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to Tourette syndrome.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412186"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2013-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2013-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412449" joined="2013-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2013-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="637"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/3/2013--Introduced.
Collaborative Academic Research Efforts for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2013 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to expand, intensify, and coordinate NIH programs and activities regarding Tourette syndrome. Requires the Director to develop a system to collect data on Tourette syndrome, including epidemiological information regarding its incidence and prevalence in the United States, primary data, and data on the availability of medical and social services for individuals with Tourette syndrome and their families. Requires the Director to award grants and contracts to public or nonprofit private entities to pay costs of planning, establishing, improving, and providing basic operating support for between four and six centers of excellence in different regions of the United States to conduct basic and clinical research on Tourette syndrome. Requires the Secretary to designate a portion of the amounts made available to carry out NIH programs and activities for a fiscal year to carry out programs and activities with respect to Tourette syndrome.</summary>
</bill>
