<bill session="111" type="h" number="5522" updated="2013-07-20T00:02:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 41 of title 5, United States Code, to provide for the establishment and authorization of funding for certain training programs for supervisors of Federal employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2010-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1089-1090"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="674"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/2010--Introduced.
Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2010 - Revises provisions relating to specific training programs for federal agency supervisors. Requires the head of each federal agency to establish: (1) a program to provide training to supervisors on developing and discussing relevant goals and objectives with the employee, communicating and discussing progress on performance goals and objectives and conducting performance appraisals, mentoring and motivating employees and improving employee performance and productivity, fostering a work environment characterized by fairness, respect, equal opportunity, and attention paid to the merit of the work of employees, effectively managing employees with unacceptable performance, and addressing reports of a hostile work environment, reprisal, or harassment; (2) a program to provide training to supervisors on prohibited personnel practices, employee collective bargaining and union participation rights, and processes to enforce employee rights; and (3) a program under which experienced supervisors mentor new supervisors. Requires: (1) an individual to complete all such programs within one year after being appointed as a supervisor; (2) supervisors to complete one of the first two programs every three years; (3) the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to regulate an appropriate schedule for an individual who cannot complete such programs within the established deadlines due to unforeseen circumstances; and (4) OPM to consult with the Small Agency Council regarding establishment of a supervisor training program for a small agency. Requires the Director of OPM to issue guidance to federal agencies on competencies supervisors are expected to possess in order to effectively manage, and be accountable for managing, the performance of employees. Requires each agency to: (1) assess the overall capacity of the supervisors in the agency, based on OPM's competency model; (2) develop and implement a supervisor training program to strengthen issues identified during such assessment; and (3) measure the effectiveness of that program in improving supervisor competence.</summary>
</bill>
