<bill session="110" type="s" number="3626" updated="2013-07-19T22:53:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family and Retirement Health Investment Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve access to health care through expanded health savings accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9708-9709"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2008--Introduced.
Family and Retirement Health Investment Act of 2008 - Amends Internal Revenue Code provisions relating to health savings accounts (HSAs) to: (1) permit holders of HSAs and their spouses who are age 55 or older to make an additional (catch-up) contribution to a joint HSA; (2) allow Medicare beneficiaries to continue to contribute to HSA accounts after reaching age 65 and to make contributions to medical savings accounts; (3) permit veterans with service-connected disabilities and Native Americans to contribute to an HSA regardless of utilization of Department of Veteran Affairs (VA) medical services or Indian Health Service or tribal medical services; (4) allow increased rollovers from flexible spending arrangements or health reimbursement arrangements into HSAs; (5) permit the payment of Medicare premiums for a spouse on Medicare from an HSA even though the HSA account holder is not age 65; (6) allow the payment of medical expenses from an HSA as long as the HSA is established by the tax return due date in the following taxable year; (7) expand the definition of "preventive care" to include medications that prevent the worsening of a chronic condition; and (8) treat as medical care for tax deduction and HSA purposes payments for exercise and physical fitness programs and certain nutritional and dietary supplements, up to $1,000 per year, and the payment of fees paid in advance to a primary physician for the right to receive medical services on an as-needed basis.</summary>
</bill>
