<bill session="111" type="s" number="2923" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Youth Jobs Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide funding for summer and year-round youth jobs and training programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2010-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13786-13787" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="267"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/22/2009--Introduced.
Youth Jobs Act of 2010 - Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of Labor for summer and year-round youth jobs and training programs for individuals aged 14 to 24 under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 which are directly linked to academic and occupational learning for the period January 1, 2010, through June 30, 2011. Prohibits the use of such funds for unpaid jobs, statewide workforce investment activities, or the award of certain youth opportunity grants. Requires local areas receiving such funds to give priority to providing: (1) work experiences in viable, emerging, or demand industries, or work experiences in the public or nonprofit sector that fulfill a community need; and (2) job referral services for youth for such jobs in which the employer agrees to pay the wages and benefits consistent with federal and state child labor laws. Authorizes such local areas to give priority to providing work experiences linked to academic and occupational learning to: (1) provide opportunities to youth to earn a short-term certificate or credential that has value in the labor market; and (2) encourage the likelihood of a participant's return to, or completion of, a program of study leading to a recognized secondary or postsecondary degree, certificate, or credential.</summary>
</bill>
