<bill session="111" type="h" number="5312" updated="2013-07-20T00:00:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reciprocal Government Procurement with China Creates American Jobs Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit the total value of Chinese goods that may be procured by the United States Government during a calendar year to not more than the total value of United States goods procured by the Chinese Government if any during the preceding calendar year, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412313"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412279" joined="2010-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2010-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO24" subcommittee="Government Management, Organization, and Procurement" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2010--Introduced.
Reciprocal Government Procurement with China Creates American Jobs Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to certify annually to Congress: (1) a determination of whether or not the Chinese government has prohibited its procurement of U.S. goods during the preceding calendar year; and (2) the total value of U.S. goods procured by the Chinesse government during that year, if the Chinese government has not prohibited such procurement. Prohibits the head of each executive agency from awarding a contract for the procurement of Chinese goods during the succeeding calendar year if the Chinese government has prohibited procurement of U.S. goods during the preceding calendar year. Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT), in such an instance, to prohibit a state or other entity from using funds made available to it from the Highway Trust Fund or the Airport and Airway Trust Fund for the award of a contract for the procurement of Chinese goods during the succeeding calendar year. Limits the total value of Chinese goods that may be procured by the U.S. government during the succeeding calendar year to the total value of U.S. goods procured by the Chinese Government during the preceding calendar year, if in fact the Chinese government has not prohibited its procurement of U.S. goods during that preceding calendar year. Directs the International Trade Administration to establish a program to: (1) identify annually the total value of U.S. goods procured by the Chinese government; and (2) provide notice in the Federal Register on or as soon as practicable after the date on which the total value of Chinese goods procured by the U.S. government equals 50%, 75%, and 100% of the total value of U.S. goods procured by the Chinese government during the preceding calendar year, for purposes of compliance with the limitation required by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
