<bill session="112" type="h" number="113" updated="2013-07-20T01:11:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Angeles and San Bernardino National Forests Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for additions to the Cucamonga and Sheep Mountain Wilderness Areas in the Angeles and San Bernardino National Forests and the protection of existing property rights in such additions, to require the Secretary of Agriculture to take steps to prevent and prepare for wildfires in the Cucamonga, Sheep Mountain, and San Gabriel Wilderness Areas and address the backlog of maintenance in the Angeles and San Bernardino National Forests, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2011-01-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E10-11"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
Angeles and San Bernardino National Forests Protection Act - Incorporates specified proposed wilderness additions into the Cucamonga and Sheep Mountain Wilderness Areas in the Angeles and San Bernardino National Forests in California. Sets forth provisions regarding private property and water rights protections and permissible activities in such additions. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to take such measures in the Cucamonga, Sheep Mountain, and San Gabriel Wilderness Areas that are necessary for the control of fire, insects, and diseases. Directs the Secretary to assess a specified maintenance backlog in the Angeles and San Bernardino National Forests. Requires completion of the studies regarding the potential addition of portions of the San Gabriel River, San Antonio Creek, and Middle Fork Lytle Creek in California to the national wild and scenic rivers system.</summary>
</bill>
