<bill session="112" type="s" number="2554" updated="2013-07-20T02:38:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bulletproof Vest Partnership Grant Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Bulletproof Vest Partnership Grant Program Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to extend the authorization of the Bulletproof Vest Partnership Grant Program through fiscal year 2017.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2012-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2930"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2930" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-05-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="404">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 404.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-12">
      <text>By Senator Leahy from Committee on the Judiciary filed written report. Report No. 112-182. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5742"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2012--Reported to Senate amended.
Bulletproof Vest Partnership Grant Program Reauthorization Act of 2012 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to: (1) extend through FY2017 the authorization of appropriations for the bulletproof vest partnership grant program; (2) transfer to the Treasury, no later than January 15, 2015, all previously appropriated funds for such program that are not expended by September 30, 2014; (3) prohibit a state, local government, or Indian tribe from using any funding under another grant program to pay or defer the cost of the matching fund requirement for the grant program; (4) require a grantee to comply with any established requirements for the use of such grants that an agency have a written policy requiring uniformed patrol officers to wear a bulletproof vest or body armor and use funds for purchasing bulletproof vests or body armor that meet performance standards established by the Bureau of Justice Assistance; and (5) allow preferential consideration in grant awards to jurisdictions that provide armor vests to law enforcement officers that are uniquely fitted for such officers, including individual female officers. Expresses the sense of Congress that amounts made available to carry out the Bulletproof Vest Partnership Grant Program should be made available through the end of the fiscal year following the one for which the amounts are appropriated and should not be made available until expended by the Department of Justice (DOJ).</summary>
</bill>
