<bill session="110" type="s" number="2840" updated="2013-07-19T22:46:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-10-09">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Personnel Citizenship Processing Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Military Personnel Citizenship Processing Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Military Personnel Citizenship Processing Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Military Personnel Citizenship Processing Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Military Personnel Citizenship Processing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a liaison with the Federal Bureau of Investigation in United States Citizenship and Immigration Services to expedite naturalization applications filed by members of the Armed Forces and to establish a deadline for processing such applications.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2008-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2008-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-05-08">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-440.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-08-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="936">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 936.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2008-09-24" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9433-9434" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9433-9434" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25T10:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Conyers moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10257-10258" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2840.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Smith (TX) objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28T20:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10309" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2008-09-28T21:03:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="668" type="vote2" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 416 - 0 (Roll no. 668).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/27/2008 H10257" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28T21:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2008-09-28">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2008-09-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2008-10-09">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2008-10-09" type="public" number="110-382">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 110-382.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="7057"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/9/2008--Public Law.
Military Personnel Citizenship Processing Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish an Office of the FBI Liaison in the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) which shall monitor and assist with Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) functions related to expeditiously processing naturalization applications filed by or on behalf of: (1) members and former members of the Armed Forces; (2) current spouses of active Armed Forces members and surviving spouses and children of U.S. citizens who died while on active duty; or (3) deceased individuals eligible for posthumous citizenship. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the the Immigration and Nationality Act to require that United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) within six months of receipt of a naturalization application filed by a member of the Armed Forces, or the spouse, surviving spouse, or child of such member: (1) process and adjudicate the application, including background checks; or (2) provide the applicant with an explanation for the inability to meet such deadline and an estimate of the adjudication date. Requires that: (1) the Director of USCIS report annually to the appropriate congressional subcommittees identifying all such naturalization applications that have not been processed and adjudicated within one year because of background check delays; and (2) the Comptroller General report to Congress regarding the average length of time taken by USCIS to process and adjudicate naturalization applications filed by members of the Armed Forces, deceased members of the Armed Forces, and their spouses and children. Repeals the provisions of this Act five years after the date of enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
