<bill session="111" type="h" number="5090" updated="2013-07-19T23:58:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">NEW Schools Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nutrition Education and Wellness in Schools Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to promote the health and well-being of schoolchildren in the United States through effective local wellness policies, technical assistance, training, and support for healthy school foods, nutrition promotion and education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2010-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400254" joined="2010-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2010-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2010--Introduced.
Nutrition Education and Wellness in Schools Act or NEW Schools Act - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to replace the nutrition promotion program with a program that requires local educational agencies (LEAs) to ensure that their local wellness policies: (1) include goals for nutrition and physical education, physical activity, on-campus food marketing and advertising, and other school-based activities that promote nutrition and wellness throughout the extended school day; (2) include plans for implementing, and measuring the implementation of, such policies; (3) require reimbursable school meals to meet certain nutritional guidelines; and (4) require the nutritional guidelines for nonreimbursable foods and beverages sold in schools to be in compliance with standards established by the Secretary of Agriculture. Requires each LEA, within two years of this Act's enactment and every three years thereafter, to complete and disseminate an assessment of their local wellness policy. Directs each LEA to designate a standing Local Wellness Policy Committee made up of education, health, and nutrition stakeholders to foster the integration of a local wellness policy that meets this Act's requirements with other health-related activities in the LEA's schools and community. Requires the Secretary to: (1) provide technical assistance and outreach to key state and local stakeholders to promote effective local wellness policies; and (2) prepare a report, in conjunction with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), on the implementation, strength, and effectiveness of local wellness policies. Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to replace the Team Nutrition Network program with The Wellness and Nutrition Network (TWNN) program providing grants to states to: (1) establish a comprehensive, integrated, and coordinated State Wellness and Nutrition Network; and (2) allocate grants to LEAs to promote and support healthy eating and physical activity programs, policies, or initiatives for children that participate in the child nutrition programs. Directs the Secretary to develop and implement a comprehensive and integrated national nutrition promotion and education strategy as part of TWNN.</summary>
</bill>
