<bill session="109" type="h" number="4814" updated="2013-07-19T19:46:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">SAFE PORTS bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe and Accountable Foreign Enterprises Proving Other Requirements To Secure (SAFE PORTS) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 721 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 to suspend all proposed mergers, acquisitions, or takeovers by foreign persons until certain determinations are made.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2006-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400642" joined="2006-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2006-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dubai Ports World aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2006--Introduced.
Safe and Accountable Foreign Enterprises Proving Other Requirements To Secure (SAFE PORTS) Act - Amends the Defense Production Act of 1950 to prohibit a proposed corporate merger, acquisition, or takeover (transaction) in the United States by or with a foreign interest which could result in foreign control unless the President has determined that: (1) there is no credible evidence to believe that the foreign interest might take action that would threaten to impair U.S. national security; and (2) provisions of law other than the Defense Production Act of 1950 and the International Emergency Economic Powers Act provide adequate and appropriate authority for the President to protect the national security with respect to the proposed transaction. States that: (1) if the President is unable to make such a determination, then an investigation of the proposed transaction shall be made; and (2) a presidential determination shall not be subject to judicial review. Requires quarterly reports from the President to Congress on actions taken with respect to proposed transactions.</summary>
</bill>
