<bill session="109" type="s" number="1398" updated="2013-07-19T20:25:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Lobbying Reform bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lobbying and Ethics Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide more rigorous requirements with respect to ethics and lobbying.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8310-8311"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8306-8310" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5677"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Charter airlines"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2005--Introduced.
Lobbying and Ethics Reform Act of 2005 - Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to require: (1) quarterly instead of semiannual filing of lobbying disclosure reports; (2) electronic filing; (3) maintenance of certain lobbying disclosure information in an electronic data base, available to the public free of charge over the Internet; (4) identification of each executive official and Member of Congress with whom lobbying contacts are made; (5) disclosure by registered lobbyists of all past executive and congressional employment; (6) disclosure of grassroots lobbying communications by paid lobbyists; (7) disclosure of lobbying activities by certain coalitions and associations; and (8) increased penalties for failure to comply with lobbying disclosure requirements. Extends from one to two years the ban on former very senior and senior executive personnel, former Members of Congress, and officers and employees of the legislative branch to engage in lobbying activities with any officer or employee of the entity in which such person served before his or her tenure terminated. Requires public disclosure by Members of Congress of employment negotiations. Subjects to fines and penalties a Member of Congress or an employee of the House who wrongfully influences, on a partisan basis, an entity's employment decisions or practices. Amends the Code of Official Conduct in the House to prohibit favoritism. Eliminates floor privileges and other perks for former Member lobbyists. Requires certification that congressional travel meets certain conditions, and establishes civil fines for false certifications. Requires Senators to provide full payment and specified disclosure of charter flights. Requires Members of Congress to provide increased disclosure of his or her official travel. Requires the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to develop and revise guidelines on reasonable expenses or expenditures for official government travel. Prohibits gifts by registered lobbyists to Members of Congress and to congressional employees, with certain exceptions. Prohibits Members of Congress from accepting gifts from lobbyists. Calls for reviews and semiannual reports by the Comptroller General on activities carried out by the Clerk of the House and the Secretary of the Senate under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
