<bill session="109" type="h" number="6246" updated="2013-07-19T19:59:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Physicians and Taxpayers Protection from Frivolous Litigation Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce the excessive burden the liability system places on the health care delivery system by establishing new rules for lawsuits related to health care provided pursuant to a Federal program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1904"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman .</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Accident insurance"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2006--Introduced.
Physicians and Taxpayers Protection from Frivolous Litigation Act of 2006 - Sets forth provisions regulating federal lawsuits for health care liability claims or actions concerning the provision of health care services or medical products pursuant to any federal program. Allows any such health care lawsuit brought in a state court to be removed to a federal court. Gives the U.S. district court jurisdiction over any health care lawsuit. Requires the court to impose sanctions for the filing of frivolous lawsuits. Sets a statute of limitations for commencing such a health care lawsuit in federal court of three years after the date of manifestation of injury or one year after the claimant discovers the injury, with certain exceptions. Provides that nothing in this Act limits recovery of the full amount of available economic damages. Limits noneconomic damages to $250,000. Makes each party liable only for the amount of damages directly proportional to such party's percentage of responsibility. Allows the introduction of collateral source benefits and the amount paid to secure such benefits as evidence. Prohibits a provider of such benefits from recovering any amount from an award in a health care lawsuit involving injury or wrongful death. Authorizes the award of punitive damages only where: (1) it is proven by clear and convincing evidence that a person acted with malicious intent to injure the claimant or deliberately failed to avoid unnecessary injury such person knew the claimant was substantially certain to suffer; and (2) compensatory damages are awarded. Limits punitive damages to the greater of two times the amount of economic damages or $250,000. Provides for periodic payments of future damage awards.</summary>
</bill>
