<bill session="109" type="h" number="4127" updated="2013-07-19T19:40:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Identity Theft bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Data Accountability and Trust Act (DATA)</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Data Accountability and Trust Act (DATA)</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Financial Data Protection Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect consumers by requiring reasonable security policies and procedures to protect computerized data containing personal information, and to provide for nationwide notice in the event of a security breach.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400019" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400132" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="2005-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2006-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2006-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2005-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 13 - 8.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 41 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 109-453, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred jointly and sequentially to the House Committee on Financial Services for a period ending not later than June 2, 2006 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(g), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred jointly and sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than June 2, 2006 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(1), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-05-26T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 109-453, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-02T15:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 109-453, Part III.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-06-02T15:45:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="270">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 270.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3502"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3997"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="2169"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Encryption"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/2/2006--Reported to House amended, Part III.
Financial Data Protection Act of 2006 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to prescribe guidelines for data security safeguards that require a consumer reporter who becomes aware of information suggesting a breach of data security immediately to investigate and notify authorities and consumers. Defines "consumer reporter" as any entity which regularly engages in assembling or evaluating consumer financial file and consumer reports to furnish consumer reports to third parties or to provide payment for products and services, or for employment purposes. Declares the policy of Congress concerning the obligations of each consumer reporter to protect the security and confidentiality of sensitive financial personal information. Prescribes investigation and consumer notification requirements. Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to coordinate with specified government entities to create a publicly available list of data security breaches that have triggered a notice to consumers within the last 12 months. Prohibits charging the related consumers for the cost of the notices and file monitoring regarding data security breaches. Requires a consumer reporter, upon the request of a consumer who is the focus of a security breach, to make available a free service that: (1) monitors nationwide credit activity about the consumer from a consumer reporting agency; and (2) provides nationwide identity-monitoring. Prescribes implementation guidelines for imposition of a security freeze, upon the request of a consumer who is a victim of identity theft, that places a notice in the consumer's credit report prohibiting the consumer reporting agency from releasing all or any part of the report without the consumer's express authorization. Prohibits a consumer reporting agency from imposing a fee for placing or removing a security freeze. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the FTC to promulgate jointly: (1) uniform data security safeguard regulations; and (2) model notice forms. Prescribes implementation and administrative enforcement procedures. Preempts state laws governing consumer reporter data security responsibilities, except any laws governing professional confidentiality or limiting the purposes for which information may be disclosed. (Sec. 3) Directs: (1) the President to convene a National Summit on Data Security Safeguards for Sensitive Personal Financial Information in the District of Columbia; and (2) the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress on a system that would provide notices of data breaches to consumers in languages other than English, and identify what barriers exist to its implementation. (Sec. 5) Directs the FTC to compile voluntary information on the race and ethnicity of consumers who are victims of identity theft, account fraud, and other types of financial fraud, in order to improve law enforcement efforts relating to data security breaches and fighting identity theft and account fraud. (Sec. 6) Amends the Credit Repair Organizations Act (CROA) to exempt from its coverage certain credit monitoring activities, including provision to a consumer of: (1) credit reports, credit monitoring notifications, credit scores and scoring algorithms, and other specified credit score-related tools; (2) any analysis, evaluation, and explanation of such actual or hypothetical credit scores or similar projections, forecasts, analyses, evaluations or explanations; or (3) materials or services to assist a consumer who is a victim of identity theft. Specifies conditions for application of such exemption. Requires the credit monitoring service to refrain from offering to alter or remove, or assist in the alteration or removal of, accurate, non-obsolete adverse information in a credit report. Requires the service also to present the sonsumer with a specified notice and statement of rights.</summary>
</bill>
