<bill session="110" type="s" number="1250" updated="2013-07-19T22:31:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the United States Trade Representative to conduct an investigation of the personal exemption allowance that Canada provides for merchandise purchased abroad by Canadian residents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5308-5309"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2007--Introduced.
Directs the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR) to initiate, under the Trade Act of 1974, an investigation into Canada's personal exemption allowance scheme (no personal exemption from duty for Canadian residents returning from foreign travel lasting less than 24 hours, but an exemption of $50 Canadian for foreign travel lasting between 24 and 48 hours) to: (1) determine whether U.S. rights under the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) with Canada are being denied by such scheme, or that such act, policy, or practice of Canada violates or otherwise denies benefits to the United States under such agreement or is unjustifiable and burdens or restricts U.S. commerce; and (2) report the results of such investigation to Congress, including action the USTR is taking to remedy such scheme. Waives provisions requiring the USTR to consult with private and non-federal sectors prior to initiating an investigation by means other than petition.</summary>
</bill>
