<bill session="111" type="h" number="1472" updated="2013-07-19T23:25:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TARP and ARRA Reporting and Waste Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish reporting requirements each time funds from Troubled Assets Relief Program or the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 are received or redistributed, and to establish a waste, fraud, and abuse hotline for such funds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2009-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2009-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412230" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2009-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2009-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3341"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2009--Introduced.
TARP and ARRA Reporting and Waste Prevention Act - Requires each public or private entity to provide a detailed report to the Secretary of the Treasury upon either: (1) receipt or redistribution of any funds under title I (Troubled Asset Relief Program [TARP]) of the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA) or the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (ARRA); or (2) entering into a contract for projects or services funded by TARP or ARRA. Requires a public or private entity that redistributes any TARP or ARRA funds to another public or private entity to give the redistributee notice that: (1) such funds are a redistribution of either TARP funds or ARRA funds; and (2) the redistributee may be required to report to the Secretary. Instructs the Secretary to: (1) establish a database to hold all such reported information; (2) make the database information available to the public on the website recovery.gov; and (3) establish a national toll-free telephone hotline number for the public to report waste, fraud, or abuse related to either TARP or ARRA funds. Sets forth whistleblower protections. Amends ARRA to require the Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board, if it requests that an inspector general conduct or refrain from conducting an audit investigation, to make such request available to the public on the website recovery.gov.</summary>
</bill>
