<bill session="111" type="s" number="3929" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cabin Fee Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to revise the Forest Service Recreation Residence Program as it applies to units of the National Forest System derived from the public domain by implementing a simple, equitable, and predictable procedure for determining cabin user fees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2010-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2010-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4888"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Cabin Fee Act of 2010 - Defines: (1) "cabin user fee" as the annual fee paid to the United States by a cabin owner pursuant to an authorization for the use and occupancy of a cabin on National Forest System land derived from the public domain; (2) "cabin owner" as a person authorized to use and occupy a cabin on National Forest System land derived from the public domain or a trust, or an heir or assignee of such a person; and (3) "cabin" as a privately built and owned recreation residence and related improvements on National Forest System land derived from the public domain that is authorized for private use and occupancy and may be sold or transferred between private parties. Requires the payment of an annual "cabin user fee" by a "cabin owner." Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to set such fee. Requires a reduction in the cabin use fee to $100 per year if access to a cabin is significantly impaired, whether by catastrophic events, natural causes or governmental actions, such that the cabin is rendered unsafe or unable to be occupied. Requires payment of a "cabin transfer fee" to the United States upon the transfer of a cabin between private parties for money or other consideration.</summary>
</bill>
