<bill session="110" type="s" number="3496" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Air and Health Quality Empowerment Zone Designation Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to address the health and economic development impact of nonattainment of federally mandated air quality standards in the San Joaquin Valley, California, by designating air quality empowerment zones.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3565"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Agricultural machinery"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Asthma"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2008--Introduced.
Air and Health Quality Empowerment Zone Designation Act of 2008 - Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to designate areas nominated by local air pollution control districts as air and health quality empowerment zones, which shall be eligible for grants for replacing or retrofitting polluting vehicles and/or engines in order to improve the health of the population living in the zones.Sets forth area eligibility requirements, including: (1) being in nonattainment of specified national ambient air quality standards for ozone or PM2.5 (particulate matter with a diameter that does not exceed 2.5 micrometers); (2) having specified emission levels from agricultural sources; (3) meeting or exceeding national averages for asthma, school days missed for ozone levels, and unemployment; and (4) being eligible for state or local matching funds.Prohibits an area from being designated unless the relevant district provides satisfactory assurances that the strategic plan (to be contained in its application) will be implemented. Authorizes the Administrator to revoke the designation if the relevant district: (1) has been designated as being in attainment with the air quality standards; or (2) is failing to comply with, or make progress in achieving the goals of, its strategic plan.</summary>
</bill>
