<bill session="111" type="s" number="3037" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhancing Oversight and Security at United States Missions Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to increase oversight of private security contractors and establish the proper ratio of United States Government security personnel to private security contractors at United States missions where the armed forces are engaged in combat operations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2010-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2010-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/24/2010--Introduced.
Enhancing Oversight and Security at United States Missions Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of State to submit a plan to Congress to increase oversight of private security contractors by U.S. government personnel at U.S. missions where the Armed Forces are engaged in combat operations in order to ensure that security functions are appropriately performed. Requires such plan to be implemented within 180 days after the enactment of this Act. Requires the Secretary to: (1) periodically review the performance of such contractors to ensure that security functions are performed in a manner that is consistent with plan requirements; and (2) report annually to Congress, in each of 2011 through 2015, on the results of the most recent performance review.</summary>
</bill>
