<bill session="109" type="s" number="1695" updated="2013-07-19T20:28:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hurricane Katrina Food Assistance Relief Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide the Secretary of Agriculture with additional authority and funding to provide emergency relief, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, to victims of Hurricane Katrina and related conditions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2005-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2005-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1643"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural surpluses"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Beverages"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Infant formulas"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2005--Introduced.
Hurricane Katrina Food Assistance Relief Act of 2005 - Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to provide expedited and increased food stamp benefits for households in areas affected by Hurricane Katrina (including areas that were disaster-designated as a result of Hurricane Katrina) or a related condition. Includes as an eligible household a household: (1) in an affected area; (2) in which a member worked in an affected area immediately prior to August 29, 2005; (3) that was displaced as a result of Hurricane Katrina or a related condition to other areas of the same or another state; (4) that the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary) determines should receive relief; or (5) containing one or more individuals displaced by Hurricane Katrina or a related condition. Treats lawful aliens in the same manner as refugees for food stamp household eligibility purposes. Authorizes the Secretary, under expedited procedures, to use specified food stamp program funds in FY2005-FY2006 for contracts with nonprofit organizations to support household and community efforts to address food assistance and related needs resulting from Hurricane Katrina or a related condition. Directs: (1) the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer to the Secretary specified amounts (which shall be available without further appropriation) for food assistance to eligible recipients, including special supplemental foods for pregnant women and infants (WIC) or for other individuals with special needs, infant formula, bottled water, and fruit juices; (2) the Secretary to use additional commodity distribution funds for food assistance to such recipients. Includes as an eligible recipient a person who: (1) is a victim of Hurricane Katrina or a related condition; (2) has been displaced by Hurricane Katrina or a related condition; or (3) is temporarily housing one or more individuals displaced by Hurricane Katrina or a related condition. Authorizes the Secretary to modify assistance conditions for programs under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 during the disaster recovery period for households that are victims of a disaster or in areas affected by the disaster if the households are in need of temporary food assistance. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer to the Secretary additional WIC and commodity supplemental food program funds (which shall be available without further appropriation) for persons victimized or displaced by Hurricane Katrina or a related condition.</summary>
</bill>
