<bill session="109" type="s" number="2384" updated="2013-07-19T20:34:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gulf Coast Protection and Restoration Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to offer the 181 Area of the Gulf of Mexico for oil and gas leasing and provide a portion of the revenues from that leasing to producing States and coastal political subdivisions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2006-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4908"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2253"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2420"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Submarine oil well drilling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2006--Introduced.
Gulf Coast Protection and Restoration Act of 2006 - Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to offer the 181 Area of the Gulf of Mexico for oil and gas leasing no later than one year after enactment of this Act. Prohibits the Secretary from offering for oil and gas leasing: (1) any area east of the Military Mission Line, unless the Secretary of Defense agrees in writing before the area is offered for lease that it can be developed in a manner that will not interfere with military activities; or (2) any area that is within 100 miles of the coastline of Florida. Requires the 181 Area to be offered for lease in spite of its omission from a specified leasing program under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act Requires the Secretary, without further appropriation, to disburse to producing states and coastal political subdivisions, 50% of the qualified outer Continental Shelf revenues generated from leases from the 181 Area during each fiscal year. Prescribes guidelines for allocation and authorized uses consistent with the coastal impact assistance program under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act.</summary>
</bill>
