<bill session="109" type="s" number="322" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Champlain Valley National Heritage Partnership Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Champlain Valley National Heritage Partnership in the States of Vermont and New York, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300057"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1136-1137"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1137-1138" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-28.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="203"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2005--Introduced.
Champlain Valley National Heritage Partnership Act of 2005 - Establishes the Champlain Valley National Heritage Partnership within the States of Vermont and New York. Directs the Partnership's management entity, the Lake Champlain Basin Program, to develop a management plan for the Partnership (for the Secretary of Interior's approval) that includes: (1) recommendations for funding, managing, and developing the Partnership; (2) a description of activities to be carried out by public and private organizations to protect the Partnership's resources; (3) an assessment of the organizational capacity of the Program to achieve the goals for implementation; and (4) recommendations for collaboration with Canada and the Province of Quebec in implementing this Act. Authorizes the Program to enter into partnerships with, and make grants to, various public and private entities to carry out this Act. Allows the Secretary to provide assistance to carry out this Act. Prohibits the Program from using Federal funds made available by this Act to acquire real property or any interest in real property. Prohibits Federal assistance under this Act after 15 years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
