<bill session="110" type="h" number="5576" updated="2013-07-19T21:52:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veteran Claims Backlog Reduction Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the claims processing of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2008--Introduced.
Veteran Claims Backlog Reduction Act of 2008 - Requires that, in order to be recognized as an agent or attorney of a veteran in the preparation, presentation, and prosecution of veterans' benefit claims, an individual must certify to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs that he or she will assist the Secretary with the Secretary's duties to notify claimants of required claim information and evidence and to assist claimants in obtaining evidence. Directs the Secretary to establish a training program to provide training to individuals recognized as veterans' agents, attorneys, or representatives. Requires a claim certified as fully developed and submitted by a veteran and a recognized agent, attorney, or representative who is a training graduate to be considered as fully developed and evaluated on the evidence provided. Directs the Secretary to: (1) at least once every fiscal year, conduct a quality control assessment of 1% of the ratings specialists and veterans service representatives employed by the Veterans Benefits Administration (VBA) of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA); (2) carry out a pilot program to develop and maintain a system for processing disability compensation claims using rules-based technology; (3) treat a veteran's beneficiary as a veteran claimant for incomplete claims as of the veteran's death; (4) evaluate training and assessment programs for VBA employees; (5) allow for the electronic monitoring of a veteran's claim status; and (6) carry out a pilot program allowing a veteran to submit a claim to any VA regional office. Establishes in the VA an Executive Management Fellowship Program to provide private sector claims processing training and experience for VBA employees.</summary>
</bill>
