<bill session="109" type="s" number="3702" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Farm and Forestry Worker Transportation Safety Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the safety of migrant seasonal agricultural workers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2006-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8062"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8062" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agricultural machinery"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Seasonal labor"/>
    <term name="Seat belts"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2006--Introduced.
Farm and Forestry Worker Transportation Safety Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor, in promulgating vehicle safety standards under the Migrant and Seasonal Agricultural Worker Protection Act, to ensure that designated seats with operational seat belts are provided for the transportation of agricultural workers, with an exception for buses otherwise not federally required to have seat belts. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to issue minimum performance requirements for the strength of seats and the attachment of seats and seat belts in vehicles that are converted, after being sold for purposes other than resale, for the purpose of transporting such workers. Requires, effective seven years after enactment of this Act, vehicles converted for transport of such workers to provide the same level of safety as vehicles manufactured or altered for such purpose prior to being sold for purposes other than resale.</summary>
</bill>
