<bill session="109" type="h" number="3178" updated="2013-07-19T19:32:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lead-Free Drinking Water Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to ensure that the District of Columbia and States are provided a safe, lead-free supply of drinking water.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2005-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2005-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="1328"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Corrosion"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Plumbing"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2005--Introduced.
Lead-Free Drinking Water Act of 2005 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to review and revise the national primary drinking water regulation for lead to provide the maximum feasible protection for individuals affected by lead contamination, particularly vulnerable populations (e.g., infants, children, and pregnant and lactating women). Requires the revised regulation to establish: (1) a maximum contaminant level for lead in drinking water as measured at the tap; or (2) a drinking water treatment technique that meets specified criteria. Directs community water systems or nontransient noncommunity water systems to: (1) annually replace a percentage of non-lead free service lines until all such lines are replaced; (2) provide notice in English and other appropriate languages to individuals and entities that may be exposed to lead contamination in the drinking water supply; (3) provide water lead test results to tested residences; (4) establish a public education program on lead in drinking water; and (5) provide water filters to residences, schools, and day care facilities. Requires the head of each federal agency to conduct water supply testing in federally-owned or occupied buildings. Directs each water system to test drinking water for lead contamination within one year. Requires the Administrator to revise monitoring requirements under the national primary drinking water regulation to incorporate specified criteria. Prohibits the use of lead pipes and plumbing equipment that is not lead free in public water systems or facilities that provide drinking water. Requires the Administrator to: (1) issue regulations to require states to establish programs to test and remediate lead contamination in school drinking water; and (2) carry out such programs in non-participating states.</summary>
</bill>
