<bill session="112" type="s" number="1435" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Children First Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act to exclude child care from the determination of the 5-year limit on assistance under the temporary assistance for needy families program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2012-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5019"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2686"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2011--Introduced.
Children First Act of 2011 - Amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to: (1) exclude child care assistance from the determination of the five-year limit on assistance under TANF, and (2) increase funding for child care. Requires the plans submitted to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) by eligible states to contain provisions for certification of procedures to ensure that child care providers comply with applicable state or local health and safety standards. Increases from 6 to 13 the maximum age allowed of a child under the care of a single custodial parent or other individual with custody who will not be subject to a reduction or termination of TANF assistance as a result of a refusal of the individual to engage in work. Subjects to the individual and case data reporting requirements of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 any TANF funds expended for child care, whether or not transferred to that Act, and exempts such funds from SSA reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
