<bill session="111" type="h" number="2362" updated="2013-07-19T23:33:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Renewable Energy Permitting Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Energy and Policy Act of 2005 to reauthorize a provision relating to geothermal lease revenue, to direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a pilot project to streamline certain Federal renewable energy permitting processes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2009-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="995"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2009--Introduced.
Renewable Energy Permitting Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish and carry out a pilot program in FY2009-FY2018 to improve federal renewable energy permit coordination. Provides for the distribution of solar and wind energy rental income collected by the Bureau of Land Management in specified percentages to: (1) certain states in which such income is derived; (2) the Renewable Energy Permit Processing Improvement Fund; and (3) the Solar Energy Land Reclamation, Restoration, and Mitigation Fund. Authorizes the Secretary to use amounts in such Funds for processing renewable energy permits and for reclaiming and restoring public land used for the production of solar energy. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to eliminate the five year limitation on the deposit and use of lease revenues under the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970.</summary>
</bill>
