<bill session="113" type="h" number="1526" updated="2013-11-02T06:31:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-20T12:20:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-09-20T12:20:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Healthy Forests for Healthy Communities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Restoring Healthy Forests for Healthy Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To restore employment and educational opportunities in, and improve the economic stability of, counties containing National Forest System land, while also reducing Forest Service management costs, by ensuring that such counties have a dependable source of revenue from National Forest System land, to provide a temporary extension of the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412508" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412549" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412485" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412486" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412568" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412408" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2013-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2013-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-213, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-18T21:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 351 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 687, H.R. 1526 and H.R. 3102. Measures will be considered read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 351.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5721-5755" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5733-5747" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 687, H.R. 1526 and H.R. 3102. Measures will be considered read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 351 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Rob Woodall to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T18:14:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1526.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T19:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 351, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Danes part C amendment no. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T19:21:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Daines part C amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Defazio demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T19:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 351, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Danes part C amendment no. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T19:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 351, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McClintock part C amendment no. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McClintock part C amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Defazio demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T19:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 351, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (MO) part C amendment no. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T19:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 351, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McClintock part C amendment no. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T19:57:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McClintock part C amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Defazio demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T19:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 351, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the LaMalfa part C amendment no. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 351, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the LaMalfa part C amendment no. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T20:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T20:08:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19T20:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1526 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20T11:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5788-5792" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20T11:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20T11:22:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1526.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20T11:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20T11:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Barber moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5790-5792" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5790" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20T11:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Barber motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add a section to the bill to provide funds to acquire the most advanced firefighting and safety equpment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5791" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20T12:12:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 190 - 228 (Roll no. 482).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5791" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="483" datetime="2013-09-20T12:20:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 244 - 173 (Roll No. 483).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="351"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="351"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h468"/>
    <amendment number="h469"/>
    <amendment number="h470"/>
    <amendment number="h471"/>
    <amendment number="h472"/>
    <amendment number="h473"/>
    <amendment number="h474"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/12/2013--Introduced.
Restoring Healthy Forests for Healthy Communities Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to establish at least one Forest Reserve Revenue Area within each unit of the National Forest System designated for sustainable forest management for the production of national forest materials (the sale of trees, portions of trees, or forest products from System lands) and forest reserve revenues (to be derived from the sale of such materials in such an Area). States that the purpose of an Area is to provide a dependable source of 25% payments and economic activity for each beneficiary county containing System land that was eligible to receive payments through its state under the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000. Instructs the Secretary to: (1) manage Areas in the manner necessary to achieve their annual volume requirement, and (2) conduct covered forest reserve projects within those Areas in accordance with this Act. Defines "annual volume requirement" and "covered forest reserve project." Requires a covered project to be implemented consistent with the land and resource management plan for the System unit in which the project will be carried out. Requires forest reserve revenues to be used to make: (1) deposits into the Knutson-Vandenburg Fund and the salvage sale fund in contributions equal to the monies collected under such Acts for projects conducted on System land, and (2) 25% payments to states for the benefit of public schools and public roads of beneficiary counties.</summary>
</bill>
