<bill session="109" type="s" number="3942" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Paterson Great Falls National Park Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Paterson Great Falls National Park in the State of New Jersey, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10190"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="6192"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stadiums"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2006--Introduced.
Paterson Great Falls National Park Act of 2006 - Establishes in Paterson, New Jersey, the Paterson Great Falls National Park as a unit of the National Park System. Requires the Park to be administered in partnership by the Secretary of the Interior, the state of New Jersey, the city of Paterson and its applicable subdivisions, and others. Establishes the Paterson Great Falls National Historical Park Partnership to coordinate the activities of federal, state, and local authorities and the private sector in the development, for the Secretary's approval, and implementation of an integrated resource management plan. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, to establish a Paterson Great Falls National Park Advisory Council. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire land or interests within the boundaries of the Park by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange.</summary>
</bill>
