<bill session="113" type="h" number="1604" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Map It Once, Use It Many Times Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the National Geospatial Technology Administration within the United States Geological Survey to enhance the use of geospatial data, products, technology, and services, to increase the economy and efficiency of Federal geospatial activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Science, Space, and Technology, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Environment" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Geography"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2013--Introduced.
Map It Once, Use It Many Times Act - Establishes the National Geospatial Technology Administration in the Department of the Interior. Directs the Administrator of the National Geospatial Technology Administration to: (1) establish a National Geospatial Database of all U.S. owned or managed lands (including public lands), Indian trust parcels, and non-federal lands in each state; (2) provide a return on investment analysis and an economic benefit assessment of the Database; and (3) provide data to heads of federal agencies to determine if any U.S. owned or managed property could be better managed through ownership by a non-federal entity. Requires the Administrator to implement the recommendations of the National Geospatial Data Plan developed by the National Geospatial Policy Commission established by this Act. Requires the Administrator to promulgate standards for ensuring the interoperability of geospatial data collected by or with the support of the federal government. Transfers to the Administrator all geospatial functions vested by law in the Department of the Interior, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) with respect to the National Forest System, and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). Sets forth provisions for the acquisition of geospatial data, as specified, from public and commercial sources. Requires the Commission to identify in the Plan each geospatial activity performed by the federal government that: (1) is unnecessary and provide for its elimination, or (2) may be converted to performance by a private geospatial firm or a state or local government. Specifies, subject to stated exceptions, that all federal contracts for the performance of a geospatial activity include: (1) a condition that the activity be performed in the United States, and (2) a written certification that the funding will not be used for activities performed outside the United States. Directs the Administrator to develop: (1) a strategy for encouraging the use of private geospatial firms by federal agencies and other entities that receive federal funding, including foreign governments; (2) a Geospatial Research Plan to provide for U.S. investment in geospatial research and development activities; and (3) policy directives for the implementation of such activities.</summary>
</bill>
