<bill session="113" type="h" number="2489" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oregon Caves Revitalization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the boundary of the Oregon Caves National Monument, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2013-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="354"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2013--Introduced.
Oregon Caves Revitalization Act of 2013 - Redesignates the Oregon Caves National Monument as the Oregon Caves National Monument and Preserve. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to transfer certain land identified as proposed addition lands to the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) and adjust the boundary of the Rogue River-Siskiyou National Forest to exclude such lands transferred by the Secretary. Directs the Secretaries to accept the donation of a grazing lease or permit from a lessee or permittee for the Big Grayback Grazing Allotment located in the Rogue River-Siskiyou National Forest or the Billy Mountain Grazing Allotment located on a parcel of BLM-managed land. Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate the subterranean segment of the Cave Creek in Oregon known as the River Styx as a component of the national wild and scenic rivers system and certain additional segments of the Monument and Preserve for study for potential addition to the system.</summary>
</bill>
