<bill session="113" type="h" number="996" updated="2013-11-02T06:27:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Invasive Fish and Wildlife Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an improved regulatory process for injurious wildlife to prevent the introduction and establishment in the United States of nonnative wildlife and wild animal pathogens and parasites that are likely to cause harm.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412546" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412297" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="408211" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412534" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2013-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E248"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Ways and Means, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-06">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1153"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Reptiles"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/2013--Introduced.
Invasive Fish and Wildlife Prevention Act - Authorizes any person, entity, or the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to propose the regulation of nonnative wildlife taxa. Requires the Director to determine whether the proposal should be approved within 180 days. Requires the Director to promulgate regulations to: (1) specify the criteria for regulating a nonnative taxon as an Injurious I taxon or Injurious II taxon that is injurious to humans, agriculture, horticulture, forestry, wildlife, or wildlife resources; (2) establish a process for assessing and analyzing the risks of taxa that may have been imported into or found in interstate commerce; and (3) designate a wildlife taxon that was previously designated as injurious by statue or the Secretary of the Interior as an Injurious I or Injurious II taxon. Requires the Secretary, not later than three years after enactment of this Act, to: (1) define the phrase "non-native wildlife taxa novel to the United States"; (2) establish a process to ensure that all such taxa are thereafter reviewed by the Director to determine whether they should be regulated as Injurious I or Injurious II taxa prior to allowing their importation; and (3) seek to avoid, in promulgating such regulation, creating a new incentive for animal importers to import novel taxa prior to the effective date of such regulation. Requires the Director, prior to designating a taxon as an Injurious I or Injurious II taxon, to prepare a risk determination. Authorizes the Director to immediately and temporarily designate a nonnative wildlife taxon as Injurious I if an emergency exists because such unregulated taxon poses an imminent threat of harm to individuals in, or wildlife of, the United States or to the U.S. economy or environment. Requires the Director to: (1) establish an electronic, publicly available database that describes all quantities of imports of all live wildlife and the regulatory status of such wildlife; (2) monitor and report on the identities and quantities of nonnative wildlife taxa being imported; and (3) make more rapid determinations on proposals for regulation of importations or shipments of injurious mammals, birds, fish, amphibia, and reptiles under the Lacey Act by requiring the Secretary to forego time-consuming optional administrative steps that are not essential and by authorizing the Secretary to forego economic impact analyses. Gives the Secretary the primary authority to prevent the importation of, and interstate commerce in, wildlife pathogens and harmful parasites. Requires the Secretary to promulgate regulations to impose import restrictions to prevent the importation of, and commerce in, such pathogens and parasites. Establishes exemptions to such requirement. Prohibits any person from: (1) importing or knowingly possessing such an Injurious I or Injurious II taxon, or the descendant of such an animal, that was imported in violation of this Act; (2) engaging in interstate commerce for or knowingly possessing such an animal that was transported in interstate commerce in violation of this Act; and (3) releasing any such taxon into the wild. Sets forth exemptions from such prohibitions. Authorizes the Director to issue permits to qualified institutions to authorize actions otherwise prohibited for such taxon. Establishes civil and criminal penalties for violations of this Act. Requires the Secretary to adopt a fee to be charged on imported live wildlife shipments, excluding shipments made by qualified institutions for scientific, veterinary, or medical research, education, conservation outreach, or display purposes. Establishes the Injurious Wildlife Prevention Fund to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
