<bill session="110" type="s" number="1558" updated="2013-07-19T22:33:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Agency Data Breach Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 44, United States Code, to strengthen requirements related to security breaches of data involving the disclosure of sensitive personal information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="2124"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Credit insurance"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/2007--Introduced.
Federal Agency Data Breach Protection Act - Amends federal law governing public printing and documents to instruct the Director of Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to establish policies, procedures, and standards for agencies to follow in the event of a breach of data security involving disclosure of sensitive personal information for which harm to an individual could reasonably be expected to result.Requires such policies and procedures to include: (1) timely notification to individuals whose sensitive personal information could be compromised as a result of a breach; (2) guidance on determining how to provide timely notice; and (3) guidance regarding whether additional special actions are necessary and appropriate, including data breach analysis, fraud resolution services, identity theft insurance, and credit protection or monitoring services.Authorizes each agency Chief Information Officer to: (1) enforce data breach policies; and (2) develop an inventory of all personal computers, laptops, or any other hardware containing sensitive personal information.Requires federal agency information security programs to include data breach notification procedures to alert individuals whose sensitive personal information is compromised.Makes it the duty of each agency Chief Human Capital Officer to prescribe policies and procedures for employee exit interviews, including a full accounting of all federal personal property assigned to the employee during the course of employment.</summary>
</bill>
