<bill session="112" type="h" number="5923" updated="2013-07-20T02:01:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stopping Non-Native Animals from Killing Endangered Species Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a grant program to eradicate non-native constrictor snakes from ecosystems in which they exist in sustainable populations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1008-1009"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Reptiles"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2012--Introduced.
Stopping Non-Native Animals from Killing Endangered Species Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a program to award grants to organizations that operate or will operate programs using dogs trained to detect non-native constrictor snakes in order to: (1) eradicate such snakes from ecosystems in which they exist in sustainable populations, and (2) prevent such snakes from establishing or expanding sustainable populations in ecosystems that can support such populations. Limits the federal share of the costs of any program operated by an organization that receives a grant to 50% of total program costs. Prohibits any such organization from reserving more than 5% of the grant funds for administrative expenses.</summary>
</bill>
