<bill session="112" type="hr" number="711" updated="2013-07-20T01:09:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-28T16:40:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-06-28T16:40:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recommending that the House of Representatives find Eric H. Holder, Jr., Attorney General, U.S. Department of Justice, in contempt of Congress for refusal to comply with a subpoena duly issued by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4402-4417" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 708, the House proceeded with fifty minutes of debate on H. Res. 711.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T15:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Dingell moved to refer to Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4412" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T15:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 708, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Dingell motion to refer.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T16:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to refer was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4416" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to refer to Oversight and Government and Reform Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 172 - 251 (Roll no. 440).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4416-4417" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-06-28T16:40:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="441" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 255 - 67, 1 Present (Roll no. 441).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4402" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28T16:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2012--Passed House without amendment.
Finds Eric H. Holder, Jr., Attorney General of the United States, to be in contempt of Congress for failure to comply with a congressional subpoena. Directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives to certify the report of the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, detailing the refusal of Mr. Holder to produce documents to the Committee as directed by subpoena, to the U.S. Attorney for the District of Columbia, to the end that Mr. Holder be proceeded against in the manner and form provided by law. Directs the Speaker to otherwise take all appropriate action to enforce the subpoena.</summary>
</bill>
