<bill session="110" type="s" number="1255" updated="2013-07-19T22:31:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-23">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Indian Arts and Crafts Amendments Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Indian Arts and Crafts Amendments Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Indian Arts and Crafts Amendments Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect Indian arts and crafts through the improvement of applicable criminal proceedings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2008-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2007-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300097" joined="2007-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5393"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-06-19">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-15">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Dorgan with amendments. With written report No. 110-460.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="961">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 961.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2008-09-23" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9336-9338" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9336-9337" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9337-9338" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24T10:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="7024"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2008--Passed Senate amended.
Indian Arts and Crafts Amendments Act of 2008 - Amends the Indian Arts and Crafts Act of 1990 to: (1) authorize any federal law enforcement officer to conduct an investigation of an offense involving the sale of any item that is misrepresented as an Indian produced good or product that occurs on land under the jurisdiction of the federal government; and (2) authorize the Indian Arts and Crafts Board to refer an alleged violation to any federal law enforcement officer (currently, just to the Federal Bureau of Investigation [FBI]) for appropriate investigation. Permits a federal law enforcement officer to investigate an alleged violation regardless of whether such officer receives a referral from the Board. Requires that the findings of an investigation of such an alleged violation by any federal department or agency be submitted to a federal or state prosecuting authority or the Board. Authorizes the Board, upon receiving the findings of such an investigation, to: (1) recommend to the Attorney General that criminal proceedings be initiated (current law); and (2) provide such support to the Attorney General relating to the criminal proceedings as the Attorney General determines to be appropriate. Allows the Board, in lieu of or in addition to any such criminal proceeding, to recommend that the Attorney General initiate a civil action. Revises the definitions and requirements relating to civil actions for mispresentation of Indian produced goods and products.Amends the federal criminal code to base criminal penalties for misrepresentation of Indian produced goods and products upon the value of such goods and products.</summary>
</bill>
