<bill session="109" type="h" number="2352" updated="2013-07-19T19:25:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumers' Access to Health Information Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to ensure that health claims for foods and dietary supplements include accurate statements of the curative, mitigation, treatment, and prevention effects of nutrients on disease or health-related conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E968-969"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Medicinal plants"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2005--Introduced.
Consumers' Access to Health Information Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to deem a food to be misbranded if the label of the food characterizes the curative, mitigation, treatment, or prevention effect of any nutrient on any disease or health-related condition unless the claim is made in accordance with specified regulations. (Currently, a label that characterizes the relationship of any nutrient to a disease or health-related condition is deemed to be misbranded.) Provides that a claim or a truthful and not misleading statement on the label or in the labeling of a food or dietary supplement shall not cause the food or dietary supplement to be a drug.</summary>
</bill>
