<bill session="109" type="s" number="4037" updated="2013-07-19T20:48:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rent-To-Own Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Rent-To-Own Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Consumer Credit Protection Act to protect consumers from inadequate disclosures and certain abusive practices in rent-to-own transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Credit insurance"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Finance charges"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Trade regulation"/>
    <term name="Warranties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Introduced.
Rent-To-Own Reform Act of 2006 - Amends the Consumer Credit Protection Act to prohibit a seller in a rent-to-own transaction from receiving or assessing any interest, finance charge, or other fee for the transaction that exceeds the interest, fees, or finance charges permissible under the laws of the state in which the seller is located which establish: (1) a maximum rate or amount of interest, finance charge, or time-price differential that may be charged in connection with a credit sale or retail installment sale for the same or a similar item; (2) the types of fees and the maximum amount of fees that a seller may so charge; or (3) the types of credit insurance and the maximum amount of premiums that can be charged for credit insurance in such a connection. Permits certain additional termination charges and fees. Cites federal laws which are applicable to a rent-to-own transaction. Sets forth required disclosures, prohibitions, and enforcement, as well as civil liability for failure to properly disclose the terms of a rent-to-own transaction. Declares this Act inapplicable to certain motor vehicles sales and leases otherwise subject to the Truth in Lending Act.</summary>
</bill>
