<bill session="109" type="h" number="4146" updated="2013-07-19T19:40:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hurricanes Rita and Wilma Financial Services Relief Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Hurricanes Rita and Wilma Financial Services Relief Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate recovery from the effects of Hurricane Rita and Hurricane Wilma by providing greater flexibility for, and temporary waivers of certain requirements and fees imposed on, depository institutions, credit unions, and Federal regulatory agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400012"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2005-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2005-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-10-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10T16:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 109-282.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-11-10T16:46:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="153">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 153.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3945"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/2005--Reported to House without amendment.
Hurricanes Rita and Wilma Financial Services Relief Act of 2005 - Expresses the sense of Congress that it is vital that insured depository institutions and insured credit unions continue to provide financial services to consumers displaced or otherwise affected by Hurricane Rita or Wilma, which includes the cashing of federal government assistance and benefit checks. Urges the Secretary of the Treasury and federal financial regulators to seek to educate insured depository institutions and insured credit unions on the proper application of the published guidance on the cashing of such checks. Urges the federal financial regulators to continue to work with such institutions and credit unions operating under extraordinary circumstances to facilitate the cashing of such checks. Requires a federal reserve bank to waive or rebate any transaction fee for wire transfer services that otherwise would be imposed on any insured depository institution or insured credit union that, as of September 24, 2005, or October 22, 2005, was headquartered in a specified qualified disaster area. Authorizes a federal financial regulator to forbear from taking any required action, on a case-by-case basis, with respect to any undercapitalized insured depository institution or credit union that is not significantly or critically undercapitalized, if the entity meets specified prerequisites, and the reduction in its capital or net worth category is directly attributable to the impact of Hurricane Rita or Hurricane Wilma. Authorizes a federal financial regulator to permit an insured depository institution or credit union to subtract specified amounts from its total assets in calculating compliance with the applicable leverage limit if it meets specified prerequisites and has an acceptable plan for managing the increase in its total assets and deposits. Identifies such an insured depository institution or credit union as one that: (1) derives more than 50% of its total deposits from persons who normally reside within, or whose principal place of business is normally within, a qualified disaster area; and (2) was adequately capitalized as of September 24, 2005, or October 22, 2005.</summary>
</bill>
