<bill session="110" type="s" number="1476" updated="2013-07-19T22:33:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-01-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tule Lake Segregation Center Special Resource Study Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Tule Lake Segregation Center Special Resource Study Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct special resources study of the Tule Lake Segregation Center in Modoc County, California, to determine suitability and feasibility of establishing a unit of the National Park System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-09-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6854-6855"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6855" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-266.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-01-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-296.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="648">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 648.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="2506"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2506"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Concentration camps"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Japanese Americans"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2008--Reported to Senate amended.
Tule Lake Segregation Center Special Resource Study Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of the national significance, suitability, and feasibility of including the Tule Lake Segregation Center in Modoc County, California, in the National Park System. Requires the Secretary to consult with Modoc County, the state of California, appropriate federal agencies, tribal and local government entities, private and nonprofit organizations, and private landowners in conducting the study. Specifies the scope of the study, including an evaluation of: (1) the significance of the Center as a part of the history of World War II; and (2) the potential impact on private landowners of designation of the Center as a unit of the National Park System.</summary>
</bill>
