<bill session="111" type="h" number="2596" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">No Child Left Unimmunized Against Influenza Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a demonstration program to test the feasibility of using the Nation's elementary and secondary schools as influenza vaccination centers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400160"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
No Child Left Unimmunized Against Influenza Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to carry out a multistate demonstration program designed to test the feasibility of using the nation's elementary and secondary schools as influenza vaccination centers in coordination with school nurses, school health care programs, local health departments, community health care providers, state insurance agencies, and private insurers. Prohibits the Secretary from using such program for children who are eligible under other federally funded programs for payment of the costs of purchasing and administering the influenza vaccine. Requires the Secretary to work with the Secretary of Labor, state insurance agencies, and private insurers to ensure that children who have private insurance have coverage for all reasonable and customary expenses, including the costs of purchasing and administering the vaccine, incurred when influenza vaccine is administered outside of the physician's office in a school or other related setting. Authorizes the Secretary to pay the cost of purchasing and administering the influenza vaccine for children to the extent such cost is not covered through other federally funded programs or through private insurance. Requires the program to be designed to administer vaccines consistent with recommendations of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices for the annual vaccination of all children aged 5 years through 19 years. Sets forth selection criteria for schools. Makes participation by a school or an individual voluntary. Requires the program to be conducted for the 2010-2011 and 2011-2012 influenza seasons.</summary>
</bill>
