<bill session="109" type="h" number="1546" updated="2013-07-19T19:17:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical Liability Procedural Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide grants to States for health care tribunals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400404"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2006-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Expert witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/2005--Introduced.
Medical Liability Procedural Reform Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to States to develop, implement, and evaluate health care tribunals. Defines "health care tribunal" to mean a trial court or administrative tribunal: (1) the sole function of which is to adjudicate disputes over injuries allegedly caused by health care providers; (2) to which all or a portion of such disputes within a jurisdiction are assigned; and (3) the judges for which have health care expertise and render decisions about the standard of care in dispute adjudication, with reliance on independent expert witnesses commissioned by the court. Permits the Attorney General to provide technical assistance to States to: (1) develop common definition, formats, and data collection infrastructure for States to use in reporting in order to facilitate aggregation and analysis of data both within and between States; and (2) provide guidance about the identification and selection of heath care tribunal judges and independent expert witnesses, compensation of injured patients, and clinical resources relating to the standard of care. Requires the Attorney General to contract with a research organization to evaluate and report on the effectiveness of grants awarded, to include an analysis of the effect of such grants on: (1) the number, nature, and costs of health care liability claims; (2) the liability environment; (3) health care quality; and (4) patient safety.</summary>
</bill>
