<bill session="110" type="s" number="2227" updated="2013-07-19T22:40:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Success in the Middle Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide grants to States to ensure that all students in the middle grades are taught an academically rigorous curriculum with effective supports so that students complete the middle grades prepared for success in high school and postsecondary endeavors, to improve State and district policies and programs relating to the academic achievement of students in the middle grades, to develop and implement effective middle school models for struggling students, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3406"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Citizenship education"/>
    <term name="Class size"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rating of teachers"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="School discipline"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/24/2007--Introduced.
Success in the Middle Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Education to make matching grants to states, based on their proportion of poor children aged 5 to 17, to: (1) implement state middle school needs analyses and, on the basis of such analyses, improvement plans that describe what students must master to successfully complete the middle grades and succeed in academically rigorous high school coursework; and (2) award competitive matching subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to implement a comprehensive middle school improvement plan for each eligible school. Favors LEAs with high proportions of poor children and eligible schools. Defines "eligible schools" as those where: (1) a majority of middle grade students matriculate to high schools with graduation rates below 60%; (2) more than 25% of the students who finish grade six, or the school's earliest middle grade level, exhibit key risk factors for failure; and (3) a majority of middle grade students are not rated proficient on required state assessments in mathematics, reading, or language arts. Permits states to make subgrants to LEAs that did not receive a competitive subgrant to assist them in applying for competitive subgrants and developing comprehensive middle school improvement plans. Provides the Secretary with funding to: (1) contract for studies that identify promising practices for, and review existing research to identify factors that might lead to, the improvement of middle school education; (2) create a national clearinghouse in best middle grade educational practices and a national database identifying factors that facilitate or impede middle grade student achievement; (3) require certain educational field research designed to enhance the performance of middle grade schools and students; (4) create a research and development center that addresses topics pertinent to middle grade schools; and (5) provide grants to entities that partner with states and LEAs to develop, adapt, or replicate effective models for turning around low-performing middle grade schools.</summary>
</bill>
