<bill session="110" type="s" number="1472" updated="2013-07-19T22:33:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">North Bay Water Reuse Program Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to create a Bureau of Reclamation partnership with the North Bay Water Reuse Authority and other regional partners to achieve objectives relating to water supply, water quality, and environmental restoration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6849-6850"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6850" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-170.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="236"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2007--Introduced.
North Bay Water Reuse Program Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to offer to enter into cooperative agreements with eligible entities in the North San Pablo Bay watershed located in Marin, Napa, Solano, and Sonoma Counties, California, for the planning, design, and construction of water reclamation and reuse projects. Directs the Secretary and such an entity to use the design work and environmental evaluations initiated by non-federal entities and the Corps of Engineers in that watershed to the maximum extent practicable. Requires such an agreement to specify the responsibilities of the Secretary and the entity regarding: (1) cost-share requirements; (2) needs assessment and project planning and design; (3) environmental compliance activity; (4) facilities construction; and (5) construction contract administration. Requires that any such project consist of two phases, during which the Secretary and an entity shall complete the planning, design, and construction of: (1) the main treatment and main conveyance system; and (2) the sub-regional distribution systems. Authorizes the Secretary to provide financial and technical assistance to an entity in planning, designing, conducting related pre-construction activities for, and constructing a project. Makes the entity responsible for the annual operation, maintenance, and replacement costs of the project. Requires the entity to develop an operation, maintenance, and replacement plan for the project.</summary>
</bill>
