<bill session="111" type="s" number="873" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nunn-Lugar Cooperative Threat Reduction Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to expand and improve Cooperative Threat Reduction Programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4673-4674"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/2009--Introduced.
Nunn-Lugar Cooperative Threat Reduction Improvement Act of 2009 - Prohibits more than 10% of amounts appropriated or otherwise made available in any fiscal year for Department of Defense (DOD) Cooperative Threat Reduction (CTR) programs from being expended to promote bilateral and multilateral activities relating to nonproliferation and disarmament. Requires the Secretary of Defense to notify the congressional defense, appropriations, and foreign relations committees at least 15 days before expending funds under such authority. Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) continued expansion of CTR programs requires increased cooperation with all unified combatant commands in which such activities are carried out; and (2) DOD should undertake a review of CTR contracting procedures, umbrella agreements, and program metrics to ensure that they are being undertaken consistently with CTR program urgency and necessity. Establishes in the Treasury the Cooperative Threat Reduction Partnership Account, to be used for CTR programs without further specific authorization in law.</summary>
</bill>
