<bill session="111" type="hj" number="75" updated="2013-07-20T00:12:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to balance the Federal budget.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412252"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2010-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hj" number="73"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hj" number="78"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hj" number="89"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="sj" number="22"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="sj" number="38"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/2010--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Prohibits outlays for a fiscal year (including those for debt service and other debt functions) from exceeding total receipts for that fiscal year (except those derived from borrowing) unless Congress, by a two-thirds roll call vote of each chamber, authorizes a specific excess of outlays over receipts. Requires a two-thirds roll call vote of each chamber to increase the public debt limit. Prohibits outlays for the total budget from exceeding the previous fiscal years' outlays plus population growth and inflation, unless a two-thirds roll call vote of each chamber, provides for such increase. Directs the President to submit a balanced budget to Congress annually. Prohibits any bill to increase revenue from becoming law unless approved by a two-thirds roll call vote of each chamber. Authorizes waivers of these provisions when a declaration of war is in effect only by a vote of a majority of both chambers. Requires all: (1) outlays above revenues from the previous fiscal year to be accounted for in the outlays and budgets of the following fiscal year; and (2) surplus revenues at the end of a fiscal year to be allocated to a fund to be returned to the taxpayers, determined by legislation before the end of the subsequent fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
