<bill session="112" type="h" number="5748" updated="2013-07-20T01:59:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Leadership to Eradicate Obstetric Fistula Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide assistance to sub-Saharan Africa to combat obstetric fistula.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2012-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E788"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2012--Introduced.
United States Leadership to Eradicate Obstetric Fistula Act of 2012 - Directs the President, through the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to establish a 10-year strategy to combat obstetric fistula in sub-Saharan Africa that strengthens the capacity of the United States to be an effective leader in the movement for international women's health and empowerment. Authorizes the President, through USAID, to provide grants to, or enter into contracts with, a university-based medical center in the United States to carry out activities to prevent, treat, and monitor obstetric fistula in sub-Saharan African countries. Provides for the establishment at such center of an International Obstetric Fistula Institute for Sub-Saharan Africa which shall: (1) serve as the primary administrative and medical-training hub; (2) initiate and oversee training and clinical activities of physicians, other health professionals, and educators serving at Centers of Clinical Excellence; (3) ensure an increase in health system and workforce capacity to prevent, treat, and monitor obstetric fistula in each country in which a Center of Clinical Excellence is located; (4) establish not less than eight Centers of Clinical Excellence for Obstetric Fistula Care; and (5) establish a United States Obstetric Fistula Treatment and Prevention Corps to provide volunteer medical services and train local surgeons and other health professionals in techniques of obstetric fistula repair and in other aspects of the care of women with obstetric fistula. Establishes the United States Advisory Committee for the Eradication of Obstetric Fistula.</summary>
</bill>
