<bill session="112" type="h" number="6358" updated="2013-07-20T02:04:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cell Phone Right to Know Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To examine, label, and communicate adverse human biological effects associated with exposure to electromagnetic fields from cell phones and other wireless devices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400227"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2012-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2012-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2012--Introduced.
Cell Phone Right to Know Act - Requires the Director of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) conduct or support a comprehensive research program to determine whether exposure to electromagnetic fields from mobile communication devices causes adverse biological effects in humans, including vulnerable subpopulations such as children, pregnant women, those with compromised immune systems and hypersensitivity reactions, men and women of reproductive age, and the elderly; (2) disseminate research results to the general public; and (3) report findings and conclusions to Congress. Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to promulgate regulations to allow a subscriber to access personally or to give consent to allow researchers with institutional review board approval to access specific usage data required to investigate the link between electromagnetic radiation exposure and potential adverse biological effects in humans. Directs the EPA to promulgate regulations establishing maximum exposure level goals and maximum exposure levels for exposure to electromagnetic fields generated by mobile communication devices. Directs the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (FDA) to promulgate regulations to provide for labeling (including exposure ratings and the maximum allowable exposure levels and goals) on mobile communication devices, packaging, instruction manuals, and at points of sale in stores and on websites. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to increase: (1) the number and size of grants to institutions for training scientists in the field of examining the relationship between electromagnetic fields and human health; and (2) the number of career development awards for such training for health professionals pursuing careers in pediatric basic and clinical research, including pediatric pharmacological research. Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish a graduate educational loan repayment program and authorize national awards for researchers in such fields. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 with respect to the prohibition on state or local government zoning regulation of personal wireless service facilities on the basis of the environmental effects of radiofrequency emissions. Excludes from such prohibition state or local regulation based on the adverse human health effects of emissions of radiofrequency electromagnetic fields.</summary>
</bill>
