<bill session="111" type="s" number="3618" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enabling the Nuclear Renaissance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to further enable a nuclear renaissance in the United States to improve energy security, reduce future pollution and greenhouse gas emissions, provide large, reliable sources of electricity, and create thousands of high-quality jobs for the citizens of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2010--Introduced.
Enabling the Nuclear Renaissance Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) nuclear energy shall be considered clean energy; (2) any provision of federal law relating to clean energy shall be considered to include nuclear energy as a form of clean energy; and (3) nuclear energy is a renewable-equivalent for purposes of a renewable energy standard. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to create: (1) a five-year accelerated depreciation period for tangible property used in the manufacturing of an advanced nuclear power facility; (2) a nuclear power facility construction credit; (3) advanced energy project tax credits for nuclear power facilities; and (4) an American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) nuclear certification credit. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to award a grant to each qualified public entity which places in service a qualified nuclear power facility in order to reimburse it for a portion of its nuclear power facility expenditures. Amends the Omnibus Appropriations Act, 2009 to increase the funding for loan guarantee commitments under the Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Program. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (EPA) to revise requirements for the loan guarantees. Amends EPA to direct the Secretary of Energy to offer to enter into cooperative agreements to develop and license specified small modular reactors with a rated capacity under 350 electrical megawatts. Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to: (1) modify licensing procedures; (2) direct the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to assume the availability of sufficient capacity to timely dispose of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste from the operation of the nuclear facility on a license application; and (3) prescribe environmental reviews for nuclear energy projects. Authorizes appropriations for training the next generation nuclear workforce. Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish: (1) the National Nuclear Energy Council; (2) the Energy Park Initiative; (3) the Advisory Committee on Energy Park Development; and (4) the N Prize Program. Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to establish a tax-exempt United States Nuclear Fuel Management Corporation to assume federal responsibility for spent nuclear fuel management. Establishes in the Treasury the United States Nuclear Fuel Management Corporation Fund.</summary>
</bill>
