<bill session="110" type="h" number="415" updated="2013-07-19T21:07:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-16T19:54:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-16T19:54:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the Taunton River in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2007-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2007-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2007-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-01-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2007-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2007-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2007-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2007-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-25">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-06-25">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-07-08T14:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-735.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-07-08T14:32:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="466">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 466.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-07-14T18:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1339 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 415 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except clauses 9 and 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T13:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1339 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1339.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6629-6648" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 415 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except clauses 9 and 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1339 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Michael R. McNulty to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 415.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T18:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1339, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Bishop (UT) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1339, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Shuler amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T18:18:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Shuler amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Shuler demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T18:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1339, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1339, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boyda (KS) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T18:30:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boyda (KS) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Boyda (KS) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T19:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 415.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T19:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T19:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Wittman (VA) moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6645-6647" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6645-6646" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T19:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wittman motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the bill back to the House with an amendment adding a new section entitled "Savings Clause."</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T19:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6647" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T19:47:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 188 - 227 (Roll no. 506).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-07-16T19:54:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="507" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 242 - 175 (Roll no. 507).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T19:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 415.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-07-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="887">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 887.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="1339"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="868"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="868"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="868"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1118"/>
    <amendment number="h1119"/>
    <amendment number="h1120"/>
    <amendment number="h1121"/>
    <amendment number="h1122"/>
    <amendment number="h1123"/>
    <amendment number="h1124"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/16/2008--Passed House amended.
Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (the Act) to designate specified segments of the Taunton River in Massachusetts as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. Requires the river segments to be managed in accordance with the Taunton River Stewardship Plan, dated July 2005, including any amendment to such Plan, that the Secretary of the Interior determines to be consistent with this Act. Authorizes the Secretary, in order to provide for the protection, preservation, and enhancement of each river segment, to enter into cooperative agreements, which may include provisions for financial and other assistance, with: (1) the Commonwealth of Massachusetts (including the political subdivisions of Massachusetts); (2) the Taunton River Stewardship Council; and (3) any appropriate nonprofit, as determined by the Secretary. Bars the river segments from being: (1) administered as a unit of the National Park System; or (2) subject to the laws (including regulations) that govern the administration of such System.Considers the zoning ordinances adopted by specified towns and cities, including any provision of the zoning ordinances related to the conservation of floodplains, wetlands, and watercourses associated with any river segment designated by this Act, to satisfy each standard and requirement under the Act regarding the prohibition on the federal acquisition of certain lands by condemnation for inclusion in any national, wild, scenic, or recreational river area. Authorizes the Secretary, respecting each river segment, to only acquire parcels of land by donation or with the owner's consent. Prohibits the acquisition of any parcel by condemnation. Requires the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and private industry, to complete a report regarding the energy resources available on the lands and waters included in the segments of the Taunton River designated by this Act. Prohibits anything in this Act from: (1) being construed as affecting the authority or responsibility of Massachusetts to manage or regulate fish and resident wildlife, including the authority to regulate hunting, fishing, trapping, and recreational shooting; (2) being construed as limiting access for hunting, fishing, trapping, or recreational shooting; or (3) impacting the supply of domestically-produced energy resources.</summary>
</bill>
