<bill session="111" type="h" number="5732" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Part D Off-Label Prescription Parity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to permit coverage of certain covered part D drugs for uses that are determined to be for medically accepted indications based upon clinical evidence in peer reviewed medical literature.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2010-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2010--Introduced.
Part D Off-Label Prescription Parity Act - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to permit a prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsor offering a PDP or a MedicareAdvantage (MA) organization offering an MA-PD plan to offer coverage of covered part D drugs for uses that are determined to be for medically accepted indications based upon: (1) guidance provided by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) for determining accepted uses of covered part D drugs; and (2) supportive clinical evidence in peer reviewed medical literature.</summary>
</bill>
