<bill session="110" type="h" number="3775" updated="2013-07-19T21:36:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-22T19:30:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-10-22T19:30:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Industrial Energy Efficiency Research and Development Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Industrial Energy Efficiency Research and Development Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To support research and development of new industrial processes and technologies that optimize energy efficiency and environmental performance, utilize diverse sources of energy, and increase economic competitiveness.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400229"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-10-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22T16:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science and Technology. H. Rept. 110-401.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-10-22T16:34:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="255">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 255.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22T19:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lampson moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22T19:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11820-11822" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22T19:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3775.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-10-22T19:30:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11821" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22T19:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-17">
      <text>Hearing Held by Subcommittee on Energy and Environment Prior to Introduction and Referral (September 25, 2007)..</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Science and Technology"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Community colleges"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Feedstock"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial engineering"/>
    <term name="Industrial research"/>
    <term name="Industry-university relations"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Inventors"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Trade associations"/>
    <term name="Waste reduction"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/22/2007--Passed House amended.
Industrial Energy Efficiency Research and Development Act of 2007 - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish a program to conduct: (1) energy research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities with respect to new industrial and commercial processes, technologies, and methods to achieve improvements in energy efficiency and enhance the economic competitiveness of the U.S. industrial sector; and (2) environmental research and development with respect to new industrial and commercial processes, technologies, and methods to achieve environmental performance improvements such as waste reduction, emissions reductions, and more efficient water use.Authorizes such activities to include: (1) activities to support the development and use of technologies and processes that improve the quality and quantity of feedstocks recovered or recycled from process and waste streams; (2) research to meet manufacturing feedstock requirements with alternative resources; (3) research to develop and demonstrate technologies and processes that utilize alternative energy sources to supply heat, power, and new feedstocks for energy-intensive industries; (4) research to achieve energy efficiency in steam, power, control system, and process heat technologies and in other manufacturing processes; and (5) a program to fund research, development, and demonstration relating to inventors' and small companies' technology proposals, based on energy savings potential, commercial viability, and technical merit. Requires all awards given under such program to made on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis.Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on such activities.(Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to provide funding to university-based industrial research and assessment centers to: (1) identify opportunities for optimizing energy efficiency and environmental performance; (2) promote application of emerging concepts and technologies in small and medium-sized manufacturers; (3) promote the research and development for use of alternative energy sources for energy intensive industries; (4) coordinate with state research offices and provide a clearinghouse for industrial process and energy efficiency technical assistance resources; and (5) coordinate with state-accredited technical training centers and community colleges, while ensuring appropriate services to all regions of the United States.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
