<bill session="111" type="hr" number="953" updated="2013-07-19T23:04:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Government of the People's Republic of China has violated internationally recognized human rights and legal due process standards by carrying out executions after trials marred by procedural abuses and by carrying out arbitrary detentions targeting Uyghurs and other individuals in Xinjiang in the aftermath of a suppressed demonstration and ensuing mob violence on July 5 to 7, 2009.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400263"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412268" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Tibet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2009--Introduced.
Condemns any violence against innocent individuals regardless of their ethnicity, gender, or religious beliefs. Calls on the government of the Peoples Republic of China (PRC) to: (1) desist from further executions based on trials that violate human rights and due process standards; (2) allow international observers and the media to attend such trials; (3) provide a list of individuals detained in the aftermath of the July 2009 events in Xinjiang to the International Committee of the Red Cross and the public; and (4) cease all crackdowns in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region. Calls on the President of the United States to: (1) state the strong U.S. opposition to these legally flawed trials and executions; (2) raise human rights concerns publicly and in all meetings with Chinese officials; (3) restate U.S. interest to open consulates in Lhasa, Tibet, and in Urumqi, Xinjiang; and (4) direct the U.S. Embassy in Beijing to automatically request permission from Chinese authorities for Embassy staff to observe trials if credible reasons exist that such trials may not meet human rights and legal standards.</summary>
</bill>
