<bill session="109" type="s" number="2779" updated="2013-07-19T20:37:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Military Funeral Demonstrations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Respect for America's Fallen Heroes Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend titles 38 and 18, United States Code, to prohibit certain demonstrations at cemeteries under the control of the National Cemetery Administration and at Arlington National Cemetery, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300003" joined="2006-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2006-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2006-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="5037"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2452"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="4042"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Picketing"/>
    <term name="Public demonstrations"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2006--Introduced.
Respect for America's Fallen Heroes Act - Prohibits a person from carrying out a demonstration: (1) at a cemetery under the control of the National Cemetery Administration or at Arlington National Cemetery, unless the demonstration has been approved by the cemetery superintendent or director; or (2) within 500 feet of a cemetery at which a funeral or memorial service is to be held, for a period beginning 60 minutes before and ending 60 minutes after the funeral or service, if such demonstration includes any individual making noise or a diversion that disturbs the peace or good order of the funeral or service. Amends the federal criminal code to provide criminal penalties for violations of such prohibitions. Expresses the sense of Congress that each state should enact legislation to restrict demonstrations near any military funeral.</summary>
</bill>
