<bill session="110" type="h" number="6771" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chesapeake Bay Accountability and Recovery Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Office of Management and Budget to prepare a crosscut budget for restoration activities in the Chesapeake Bay watershed, to require the Environmental Protection Agency to develop and implement an adaptive management plan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400658" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2008-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2008-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Chesapeake Bay"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2008--Introduced.
Chesapeake Bay Accountability and Recovery Act of 2008 - Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), in consultation with the Chesapeake Executive Council, the chief executive of each Chesapeake Bay state, and the Chesapeake Bay Commission, to submit to Congress a financial report containing: (1) an interagency crosscut budget for restoration activities that protect, conserve, or restore living resources, habitat, water resources, or water quality in the Chesapeake Bay watershed; (2) an accounting of funds received and obligated by all federal agencies for restoration activities; (3) an accounting from each state of all funds received and obligated from a federal agency for restoration activities; and (4) a description of each of the proposed federal and state restoration activities. Requires: (1) such report to describe only federal restoration activities that have funding amounts of at least $100,000 and state restoration activities that have funding amounts of at least $50,000; and (2) the Director to submit the report no later than 30 days after the submission of the President's annual budget to Congress.Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to develop and update every three years an adaptive management plan for the Chesapeake Bay Program and restoration activities that includes: (1) a definition of specific and measurable objectives to improve water quality, habitat, and fisheries; (2) a process for stakeholder participation; (3) monitoring, modeling, experimentation, and other research and evaluation practices; (4) a process for modification of restoration activities that have not attained or will not attain such objectives; and (5) a process for prioritizing restoration activities and programs to which adaptive management shall be applied. Sets forth reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
