<bill session="110" type="h" number="6192" updated="2013-07-19T21:57:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Illegal Alien Crime Reporting Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make payments by the Department of Homeland Security to a State contingent on a State providing the Federal Bureau of Investigation with certain statistics, to require Federal agencies, departments, and courts to provide such statistics to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and to require the Federal Bureau of Investigation to publish such statistics.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400209"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2008-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412011" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2008-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="2008-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-05">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Management, Investigations, and Oversight.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM09" subcommittee="Management, Investigations, and Oversight" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2008--Introduced.
Illegal Alien Crime Reporting Act of 2008 - Prohibits a state or political subdivision thereof from receiving funds under any program or activity administered by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) unless the state: (1) compiles statistics on each person who is arrested, charged with a crime, convicted, or incarcerated after being convicted of a crime by the state or political subdivision, including each person's crime, immigration status, and country of origin; (2) reports such statistics monthly to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); and (3) certifies compliance with these requirements monthly to the Secretary of Homeland Security. Requires each federal agency to: (1) compile such statistics for any person it arrests, charges, prosecutes to conviction, or incarcerates after conviction of a crime; and (2) report such statistics monthly to the FBI. Directs the FBI to publish all statistics reported under this Act annually as a separate data collection of the FBI's Uniform Crime Reports.</summary>
</bill>
