<bill session="111" type="s" number="3948" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regulated Investment Company Modernization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify certain rules applicable to regulated investment companies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4337"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2010--Introduced.
Regulated Investment Company Modernization Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to regulated investment companies (RICs), to: (1) allow an unlimited carryforward of the net capital losses of RICs; (2) eliminate restrictions on the investment of RICs in commodities; (3) limit penalties for the failure of RICs to satisfy gross income and asset tests; (4) modify rules for allocating RIC capital gain dividend distributions; (5) include certain nondeductible items of RIC income in earnings and profit calculations; (6) allow RICs that invest exclusively in the shares of other RICs to pass through to their shareholders tax-exempt interest and foreign tax credits, without regard to certain investment limitations; (7) modify rules relating to the declaration of RIC dividends, return of capital distributions, and stock redemptions; (8) allow certain RICs with shares that are redeemable upon demand to treat distributions in redemption of stock as an exchange of fund shares or a dividend for tax purposes; (9) allow a deferral of end-of-year losses of RICs; (10) exempt certain regularly declared exempt-interest dividends of RICs from holding period requirements; (11) increase the annual amount of capital gain net income of RICs required to be distributed; and (12) modify excise tax and penalty rules applicable to RICs.</summary>
</bill>
