<bill session="112" type="s" number="1354" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Media for Youth Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize grants to promote media literacy and youth empowerment programs, to authorize research on the role and impact of depictions of girls and women in the media, to provide for the establishment of a National Task Force on Girls and Women in the Media, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2011-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2012-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2513"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Books and print media"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2011--Introduced.
Healthy Media for Youth Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to nonprofit organizations to provide for the establishment, operation, coordination, and evaluation of programs to: (1) increase the media literacy of girls and boys; and (2) support the empowerment of girls or boys, including through extracurricular activities and programs. Permits grants to nonprofit organizations only if the organization agrees to make nonfederal contributions available toward the costs of the program (at least $1 for every $5 of awarded federal funds). Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) and in coordination with the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and the Director of the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, to review, synthesize, and conduct or support research on the role and impact of depictions of girls and women in the media on the psychological, sexual, physical, and interpersonal development of youth. Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to convene a task force, to be known as the National Task Force on Girls and Women in the Media, to develop voluntary steps and goals for promoting healthy and positive depictions of girls and women in the media for the benefit of all youth.</summary>
</bill>
