<bill session="111" type="h" number="3197" updated="2013-07-19T23:40:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Kids With Healthy Hearts Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Education to provide grants to local educational agencies to conduct demonstration projects to screen the blood pressure of children in kindergarten through grade 6.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400659"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2009-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2009--Introduced.
Kids with Healthy Hearts Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Education to make five grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to conduct demonstration projects to screen children in kindergarten through grade six for high blood pressure. Requires screening programs, subject to parental consent, to screen children every six months during the school year, but to screen children one month after their initial screening if they fall in the 95th percentile or above for students with high blood pressure. Requires grantees to provide parents of children who remain in such range after their second screening with: (1) referrals to health care providers for consultations about high blood pressure; and (2) written information from the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) regarding hypertension risks and lifestyle changes related to diet and exercise that can improve overall health. Directs the Secretary to give grant preference to at least one LEA serving a high percentage of Native American, Latino, or African-American students.</summary>
</bill>
