<bill session="110" type="s" number="2380" updated="2013-07-19T22:41:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modernize the application of the subpart F rules to computer software, to expand the subpart F de minimis rule, and to extend certain expiring provisions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Holding companies"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/2007--Introduced.
Amends Internal Revenue Code provisions relating to taxation of U.S. shareholders of controlled foreign corporations to: (1) exclude from foreign personal holding company income rents and royalties attributable to computer software that is leased or licensed for use outside the United States and that was developed or marketed by a controlled foreign corporation or related person; (2) increase to $5 million (currently, $1 million) the de minimis dollar amount for determinations of foreign base company income; (3) permanently extend the look-thru rule for for the tax treatment of income received or accrued from a controlled foreign corporation; and (4) permanently extend the exemption from foreign personal holding company income for active financing income (income from insurance, banking, financing, or similar businesses) earned on business operations overseas.</summary>
</bill>
