<bill session="111" type="h" number="6351" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening Cybersecurity for Critical Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Executive Cyber Director in the Executive Office of the President, to clarify the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Executive Cyber Director with respect to critical information infrastructure policy creation, verification, and enforcement measures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM08" subcommittee="Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Strengthening Cybersecurity for Critical Infrastructure Act - Grants the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) primary authority in the executive branch in the creation, verification, and enforcement of measures for the protection of critical information infrastructure, including the promulgation of risk-informed information security practices and standards applicable to critical information infrastructures that are not owned by or under the direct control of the federal government. Directs the Secretary to: (1) consult with sector specific federal regulatory agencies in exercising such authority; and (2) coordinate with such agencies, through the Executive Office of the President, in establishing enforcement mechanisms. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) conduct audits to ensure that appropriate measures are taken to secure critical information infrastructure; (2) issue subpoenas to determine compliance with federal regulatory requirements for securing such infrastructure; and (3) authorize sector specific federal regulatory agencies to undertake such audits. Establishes within the Executive Office of the President a National Office for Cyberspace, headed by an Executive Cyber Director, who shall have primary authority in the executive branch in leading interagency coordination on security policies relating to the creation, verification, and enforcement of measures regarding the protection of critical information infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
