<bill session="110" type="h" number="5522" updated="2013-07-19T21:52:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-30T18:56:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-04-30T18:56:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Combustible Dust Explosion and Fire Prevention Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Combustible Dust Explosion and Fire Prevention Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Worker Protection Against Combustible Dust Explosions and Fires Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Labor to issue interim and final occupational safety and health standards regarding worker exposure to combustible dust, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2008-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-04-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-22T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and Labor. H. Rept. 110-601.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-04-22T15:09:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="374">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 374.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-04-29T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1157 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5522 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and Labor now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T16:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1157 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1157.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2909-2922" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5522 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and Labor now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1157 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Donna M. Christensen to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T16:47:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 5522.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1157, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the George Miller amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T17:22:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the George Miller amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. George Miller demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1157, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Wilson (SC) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Wilson (SC) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Wilson (SC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T17:40:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 5522.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2919" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2913-2914" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T18:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walberg moved to recommit with instructions to Education and Labor.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2919-2921" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2919" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T18:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Walberg motion to recommit. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to require an exemption for grain pending determination of impact on the prices.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T18:49:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 187 - 225 (Roll no. 232).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-04-30T18:56:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="233" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 247 - 165 (Roll no. 233).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 5522.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="1157"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Dyes and dyeing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Explosions"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Fibers"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Flammable materials"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Furniture industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Plastics"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Rubber"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Sulphur"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Waste products"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1037"/>
    <amendment number="h1038"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/30/2008--Passed House amended.
Worker Protection Against Combustible Dust Explosions and Fires Act of 2008 - (Sec. 3) Requires the Secretary of Labor, within 90 days, to promulgate an interim final standard regulating combustible dusts, which shall apply to manufacturing, processing, blending, conveying, repackaging, and handling of combustible particulate solids and their dusts (including organic dusts, plastics, sulfur, wood, rubber, furniture, textiles, pesticides, pharmaceuticals, fibers, dyes, coal, metals, and fossil fuels), but shall not apply to processes already covered by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration's (OSHA) standard on grain facilities.Requires such standard to provide requirements for: (1) a hazard assessment to identify, evaluate, and control combustible dust hazards; (2) a written program that includes provisions for hazardous dust inspection, testing, hot work, ignition control, and housekeeping, including the frequency and methods used to minimize accumulations of combustible dust on ledges, floors, equipment, and other exposed surfaces; (3) engineering (which requirements shall be effective six months after the date on which the interim standard is issued), administrative controls and operating procedures, such as means to control fugitive dust emissions and ignition sources, the safe use and maintenance of dust producing and dust collection systems and filters, minimizing horizontal surfaces where dust can accumulate, and sealing of areas inaccessible to housekeeping; (4) housekeeping to prevent accumulation of combustible dust in places of employment in depths that can present explosion, deflagration, or other fire hazards, including safe methods of dust removal; (5) employee participation in hazard assessment, development of and compliance with the written program, and other elements of hazard management; and (6) providing safety and health information and annual training to employees, including housekeeping procedures, hot work procedures, preventive maintenance procedures, common ignition sources, and lock-out, tag-out procedures.Provides an exemption from otherwise applicable rulemaking requirements for the interim standard but not for the final standard.Provides that such interim standard shall have the legal effect of an occupational safety and health standard and shall apply until a final standard becomes effective.Requires the Secretary of Labor, within 18 months, to promulgate a final occupational safety and health standard regulating combustible dust explosions that has the same scope and worker protection provisions as the interim rule and provides requirements for: (1) managing change of dust producing materials, technology, equipment, staffing, and procedures; (2) building design such as explosion venting, ducting, and sprinklers; and (3) explosion protection, including separation and segregation of the hazard. Requires the final rule to include relevant and appropriate provisions of the National Fire Protection Association combustible dust standards.(Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary to revise the hazard communications standard to amend the definition of "physical hazard" to include "a combustible dust" as an additional example of such a hazard.</summary>
</bill>
