<bill session="112" type="s" number="3584" updated="2013-07-20T02:47:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drought Information Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the National Integrated Drought Information System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2012-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2012-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6489"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2012--Introduced.
Drought Information Act of 2012 - Amends the National Integrated Drought Information System Act of 2006 to specify that: (1) the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere shall continue to support the National Integrated Drought Information System (NIDIS) Program, and (2) the program's purpose shall be to better inform and provide for more timely decisionmaking to reduce drought related impacts and costs. Revises NIDIS functions to require the NIDIS to, among other things: (1) provide certain information, forecasts, and assessments described in the Act on both national and regional levels; (2) build upon existing forecasting and assessment programs and partnerships, such as those with specified programs of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), extension system and economist offices of the Department of Agriculture (USDA), the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, and the Farm Service Agency; and (3) continue ongoing research activities related to drought and the role of extreme weather events and climate variability in drought. Requires the Under Secretary to provide a report to Congress concerning the NIDIS Program that includes a list of persons in the private sector with whom the Under Secretary collaborates on NIDIS implementation and a description of NIDIS outreach activities. Authorizes appropriations to carry out the Act through FY2017.</summary>
</bill>
