<bill session="113" type="h" number="405" updated="2013-11-02T06:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To permit Members of Congress to administer the oath of allegiance to applicants for naturalization.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400366"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration And Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/23/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to permit each applicant for naturalization to choose to have the oath of allegiance for naturalization administered by a Member of Congress, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner (Member). Limits the administration of the oath: (1) by a Senator to individuals who reside in the Senator's state; and (2) by a Member of the House of Representatives, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner to individuals who reside in the respective congressional district. Limits the Member's authority solely to the administration of such oath. Prohibits a Member from administering the oath during the 90-day period before any election for federal, state, or local office in which the Member is a candidate. Requires a Member to administer the oath only at times and places designated by the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS). Prohibits a Member from administering the oath during any period in which exclusive authority to administer it may be exercised by an eligible court for the person concerned, unless the court has waived such exclusive authority.</summary>
</bill>
