<bill session="112" type="s" number="1615" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financial Regulatory Responsibility Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require enhanced economic analysis and justification of regulations proposed by certain Federal banking, housing, securities, and commodity regulators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300089"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2011-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Economic theory"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Housing Finance Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial Stability Oversight Council"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2011--Introduced.
Financial Regulatory Responsibility Act of 2011- Prohibits a federal financial regulatory agency from issuing notices of proposed or final rulemakings unless specified analyses have been included in them. Prohibits an agency from publishing a notice of final rulemaking if it determines that the quantified costs are greater than the quantified benefits. Requires an agency to make available on its public website sufficient information about the data, methodologies, and assumptions underlying its analyses so that its analytical results are capable of being substantially reproduced. Requires the chief economist of an agency, within five years after publication in the Federal Register of a notice of final rulemaking, to report to certain congressional committees on the economic impact of the subject regulation, including its direct and indirect costs and benefits. Requires each federal agency to develop, report to certain congressional committees, and post on its public website a plan to modify, streamline, expand, or repeal existing regulations so as to make the agency's regulatory program more effective or less burdensome in achieving its regulatory objectives. Authorizes judicial review for a person adversely affected or aggrieved by a regulation. Establishes the Chief Economists Council to report to certain congressional committees on activities of the financial regulatory agencies. Requires the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) to report separately to certain congressional committees their plans for subjecting to the requirements of this Act the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board, the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board, and registered national securities associations on the one hand, and registered futures associations on the other.</summary>
</bill>
