<bill session="111" type="h" number="2085" updated="2013-07-19T23:30:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Religious Freedom Peace Tax Fund Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To affirm the religious freedom of taxpayers who are conscientiously opposed to participation in war, to provide that the income, estate, or gift tax payments of such taxpayers be used for nonmilitary purposes, to create the Religious Freedom Peace Tax Fund to receive such tax payments, to improve revenue collection, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400240"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/2009--Introduced.
Religious Freedom Peace Tax Fund Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish in the Treasury the Religious Freedom Peace Tax Fund for the deposit of income, gift, and estate taxes paid by or on behalf of taxpayers: (1) who are designated conscientious objectors opposed to participation in war in any form based upon their deeply held moral, ethical, or religious beliefs or training (within the meaning of the Military Selective Service Act); and (2) who have certified their beliefs in writing to the Secretary. Requires that: (1) amounts deposited in the Fund be allocated annually to any appropriation not for a military purpose; (2) the Secretary report to the House and Senate Appropriations Committees on the total amount transferred into the Fund during the preceding fiscal year and the purposes for which such amount was allocated; and (3) the privacy of individuals using the Fund be protected. Expresses the sense of Congress that any revenue increase resulting from the creation of the Fund be allocated in a manner consistent with its purposes.</summary>
</bill>
