<bill session="113" type="h" number="1606" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crop Risk Options Plan Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to make available to producers a supplemental coverage option based on both an individual yield and loss basis and an area yield and loss basis in order to allow producers to cover all or a portion of their deductible under the individual yield and loss policy, to improve the accuracy of actual production history determinations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400441"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG16" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities and Risk Management" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1947"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="677"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2013--Introduced.
Crop Risk Options Plan Act of 2013 - Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to make available to crop producers additional coverage to cover part of a crop insurance policy deductible based upon: (1) an individual or area yield and loss basis, (2) an individual yield and loss basis supplemented with coverage based on an area yield and loss basis (supplemental coverage option), or (3) a margin basis alone or in combination with the coverages available in (1) or (2). Triggers the supplemental coverage option only if area losses exceed 10% of normal levels. Provides for: (1) 60% premium coverage plus operating and administrative costs paid by the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation (FCIC), and (2) coverage to begin no later than crop year 2014. Provides that in the case of the supplemental coverage option, FCIC shall offer producers the opportunity to purchase coverage that pays indemnities on a county-wide level or on a larger geographical area level in counties that lack sufficient data. Directs FCIC, in developing yield guarantees, to use county data collected by the Risk Management Agency and/or the National Agricultural Statistics Service.</summary>
</bill>
