<bill session="109" type="h" number="3562" updated="2013-07-19T19:35:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Specialty Crop and Value-Added Agriculture Promotion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Specialty Crops Competitiveness Act of 2004 to increase the authorization of appropriations for grants to support the competitiveness of specialty crops, to amend the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000 to improve the program of value-added agricultural product market development grants by routing funds through State departments of agriculture, to amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to require a nationwide expansion of the adjusted gross revenue insurance program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400186"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Education Reform" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1556"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1556"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agribusiness"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Farm produce"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery products"/>
    <term name="Flowers"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Horticulture"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Nuts"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Organic farming"/>
    <term name="Produce trade"/>
    <term name="Quality control"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Shellfish"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2005--Introduced.
Specialty Crop and Value-Added Agriculture Promotion Act - Amends the Specialty Crops Competitiveness Act of 2004 to include within the definition of specialty crop: (1) farm-raised or wild-harvested fish and shellfish; and (2) organically produced specialty crops. Makes the authorization of appropriations for state specialty crop block grants permanent. Amends the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000 to replace the agricultural marketing resource center pilot project with a state block grant program for value-added agricultural product market development. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish an incentive program for third-party certification of agricultural producers and processors for quality and production practices that increase agricultural commodity marketability or value. Provides for up 50% reimbursement of participant certification costs. Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to direct the Commodity Credit Corporation to carry out the adjusted gross revenue insurance pilot program as a permanent program. Authorizes the Corporation to: (1) expand the program to cover any county in which crops are produced; and (2) grant temporary policy subsidies for producers located in a county that has a high level of specialty crop production and has not had a high level of crop insurance coverage coverage. Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to direct the Secretary to: (1) make available to students in not more than 100 schools in each state, and in elementary and secondary schools on one Indian reservation, free fresh and dried fruits and vegetables throughout the school day in one or more school-designated areas; and (2) give priority to states that produce large quantities of specialty crops. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to increase operating loan limits for loans guaranteed other than by the Secretary. Revises the related inflation percentage determination. Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to establish the position of Assistant United States Trade Representative for Specialty Crops. Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to increase the authorization of appropriations for specialty crop technical assistance.</summary>
</bill>
