<bill session="109" type="s" number="2633" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bitterroot National Forest Dam and Reservoir Maintenance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to grant rights-of-way to owners of dams located in the Bitterroot National Forest in the State of Montana, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300015"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3424"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2006--Introduced.
Bitterroot National Forest Dam and Reservoir Maintenance Act - Directs the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior to grant to the owner of a dam, a water storage right for a dam, or a right-of-way, for no consideration, rights-of-way to: (1) the trails, access routes, or primitive roads in the Bitterroot National Forest, Montana, for purposes of providing access to such dam; and (2) areas of that Forest adjacent to such dam for purposes of dam construction, reconstruction, maintenance, repair, and operation. Requires such owners to prepare a map establishing the boundaries of the rights-of-way granted, which shall extend at least eight feet but not more than 60 feet in width from the center of the trail. Authorizes an owner to: (1) use mechanized transport on the rights-of-way and at the owner's dam; and (2) operate aircraft in the airspace over the Forest to access the dam; and (3) land the aircraft on the rights-of-way. Provides that any activities carried out by an owner in a right-of-way granted under this Act shall be regulated by the state and shall not be subject to specified federal law, including the Wilderness Act and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</summary>
</bill>
