<bill session="111" type="h" number="4826" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Responsible Homeowner Relief Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote neighborhood stabilization by incentivizing short sales, as a preferable alternative to foreclosure, through the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412257"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2010--Introduced.
Responsible Homeowner Relief Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an individual taxpayer a deduction from gross income for loss from the sale or exchange of a principal residence in which such taxpayer resided for at least two years during the five-year period prior to the sale. Limits the aggregate amount of such deduction to $9,000, allowable in three annual installments of $3,000. Terminates such deduction after 2012. Requires the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) to waive any short sale waiting period requirement for certain mortgagors who refinance their mortgage in a short sale. Terminates such waiver authority on January 1, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
