<bill session="109" type="s" number="2686" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Network Neutrality bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Communications, Consumer's Choice, and Broadband Deployment Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Community Broadband Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Digital Content Protection Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Internet and Universal Service Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Sports Freedom Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Video Competition and Savings for Consumers Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Video Content Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">WIN Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Wireless Innovation Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2006-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3803-3804"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-1128, pt. 1.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-1128, pt. 2.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-1128, pt. 3.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5252"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication satellites"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Educational television"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting of sports"/>
    <term name="Television frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Television relay systems"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2006--Introduced.
Communications, Consumer's Choice, and Broadband Deployment Act of 2006 - Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to reduce the cost of calling home for U.S. military personnel stationed outside the United States in support of military operations, training exercises, or other approved purposes. Amends the Digital Television Transition and Public Safety Act of 2005 to direct the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to allocate a portion of the funds available under such Act for: (1) making interoperable communications system equipment grants for equipment that can utilize reallocated public safety spectrum; and (2) establishing and implementing a strategic technology reserves initiative. Internet and Universal Service Act of 2006 - Requires each communications service provider to contribute to support universal service (the provision of communications service in rural, insular, and high-cost areas). Outlines requirements for distribution of universal service support to eligible communications carriers. Establishes a Broadband for Unserved Areas Account. Video Competition and Savings for Consumers Act of 2006 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to provide regulatory and franchising requirements for video services and video service providers similar to those currently applicable to cable communications operators. Requires the provision of channels for public, educational, and governmental use. Prohibits the denial of video service access because of income, race, or religion. Video Content Act - Sports Freedom Act of 2006 - Prohibits multichannel video programming distributors (MVPDs) from engaging in unfair or deceptive acts or practices to hinder or prevent other MVPDs from providing such programming or satellite broadcast programming to consumers. Digital Content Protection Act of 2006 - Directs the FCC to implement its Report and Order in the matters of: (1) Digital Broadcast Content Protection; and (2) Digital Output Protection Technology and Recording Method Certifications. Authorizes the FCC to promulgate regulations governing the indiscriminate redistribution of audio content with respect to digital and satellite radio broadcasts. Requires the FCC to establish the Digital Audio Review Board. Community Broadband Act - Amends the Telecommunications Act of 1996 to prohibit any state or local government statute, regulation, or other legal requirement from prohibiting any public provider from providing, to any person or any public or private entity, advanced communications capability or any service that utilizes the advanced communications capability provided by such provider. Provides safeguards, including that a public provider may not provide advanced communications capability to the public unless the provision of such capability by that public provider is subject to the same laws and regulations that would apply if the advanced communications capability were being provided by a nongovernmental entity. Wireless Innovation Act of 2006 or WIN Act of 2006 - Makes eligible television spectrum available for wireless use. Outlines consumer education requirements for analog television receivers, as well as requirements to reduce the government cost of the converter box program. Outlines requirements for: (1) the protection of children with respect to the video transmission of child pornography; and (2) the free flow of information over the Internet.</summary>
</bill>
