<bill session="109" type="h" number="6249" updated="2013-07-19T19:59:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Energy to make price floor loans to certain low-carbon coal-to-liquid fuel projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400373"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2006-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Options (Contract)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2006--Introduced.
Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to authorize the Secretary of Energy to enter into agreements, in the form of price floor loans, with up to six low-carbon CTL projects (that convert coal to liquid or gaseous transportation fuels) to guarantee each project a minimum price for its output of liquid or gaseous transportation fuels in return for: (1) payment to the United States of the cost of such loan; or (2) at the borrower's election, a call option for the United States equivalent in value to such payment. Prohibits any agreement for a price floor loan unless the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) determines that the loan cost is fully offset by either certain payments or by the value of a call option.</summary>
</bill>
