<bill session="111" type="h" number="4227" updated="2013-07-19T23:50:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Incentives to Increase Use of Renewable Biomass Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to provide loans to support the conversion of energy generation or heating and cooling systems to the use of renewable biomass and to support the installation of new equipment to use renewable biomass for such systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412315"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400092" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412300" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2009-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2170"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2009--Introduced.
Incentives to Increase Use of Renewable Biomass Act of 2009 - Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) establish a program to provide interest-free loans to eligible institutions (i.e., an institution of higher education, an elementary or secondary school, a hospital, a local government building, or a governmental, community, health, or educational building owned or leased and occupied by an Indian tribe, except any building used for gaming) for capital costs for converting existing equipment, or installing new equipment, to use renewable biomass for energy generation, heating, or cooling systems; and (2) ensure that an institution receiving such a loan will use renewable biomass for no less than 75% of the energy generation, heating, or cooling needs of the facility for which the loan is received. Establishes in the Treasury a revolving fund for such program. Requires the Secretary to: (1) deposit amounts received as payment on loans provided under such program into such revolving fund; and (2) make available $100 million of the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation to such revolving fund.</summary>
</bill>
