<bill session="111" type="h" number="1935" updated="2013-07-19T23:29:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the treatment of partnership interests held by partners providing services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400238"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4213"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) to set forth a special rule for the inclusion in gross income of partnership interests transferred in connection with the performance of services; (2) treat as ordinary income or loss net income or loss from an investment services partnership interest; (3) include income and loss from an investment services partnership interest for purposes of determining net earnings from self-employment; (4) apply the rule treating gain from sales between related persons as ordinary income to certain partnership interests; and (5) exempt income from investment services partnership interests from treatment as qualifying income of publicly traded partnerships. Defines "investment services partnership interest" as any interest in a partnership held by a person who provides services to a partnership by: (1) advising the partnership about investing in, purchasing, or selling specified assets; (2) managing, acquiring, or disposing of specified assets; or (3) arranging financing with respect to acquiring specified assets.</summary>
</bill>
