<bill session="110" type="s" number="3373" updated="2013-07-19T22:51:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization and Expansion Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize and expand the Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act to promote the protection of the resources of the Northwest Straits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7909"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="6746"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2008--Introduced.
Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization and Expansion Act of 2008 - Amends the Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act to: (1) set forth the membership of the Northwest Straits Advisory Commission; (2) state the goal of the Commission as the protection and restoration of the marine waters, habitats, and species of the Northwest Straits region in the state of Washington to achieve ecosystem health and sustainable resource use; and (3) enumerate the duties of the Commission and establish benchmarks for its work. Provides for the appointment of a Director of the Commission and the establishment of marine resources committees in specified counties of the state of Washington. Authorizes the Director of the Commission and the Director of the Padilla Bay National Estuarine Research Reserve to establish the Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Foundation as a nonprofit foundation to support the Commission and the marine resources committees established by this Act. Authorizes appropriations for the Commission.</summary>
</bill>
