<bill session="109" type="h" number="2201" updated="2013-07-19T19:23:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Debt Prevention and Education Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 7 of title 11 of the United States Code, to exclude medically distress debtors from the application of the means test, to amend the Truth in Lending Act to require certain disclosures in connection with credit card applications and solicitations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400349"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alimony"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Direct mail advertising"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Support of dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2005--Introduced.
Consumer Debt Prevention and Education Act of 2005 - Amends the Bankruptcy Abuse Prevention and Consumer Protection Act of 2005 to prohibit a judge, U.S. trustee, or other party in interest from filing a presumption-of-abuse motion if the debtor is a medically distressed debtor. Amends the Truth in Lending Act to require credit card disclosures under an open end consumer credit plan to include an explanation of: (1) credit scores and the negative effects that low credit scores can have on the consumer; (2) how being over a credit limit hurts the consumer; and (3) how long it would take paying off a credit balance by just making the minimum payments required, and the effect that negative amortization may have in extending such time.</summary>
</bill>
