<bill session="112" type="hr" number="419" updated="2013-07-20T01:06:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-04T14:15:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-10-04T14:15:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2681) to provide additional time for the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue achievable standards for cement manufacturing facilities, and for other purposes, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2250) to provide additional time for the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue achievable standards for industrial, commercial, and institutional boilers, process heaters, and incinerators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-03T18:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-231, by Mr. Nugent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-03T18:59:00-04:00">
      <text>No amendment to the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those received for printing in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII in a daily issue dated October 4, 2011, or earlier and except pro forma amendments for the purpose of debate. No amendment to the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those received for printing in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII in a daily issue dated October 4, 2011, or earlier and except pro forma amendments for the purpose of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-10-03T18:59:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="78">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 78.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-04T12:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6523-6528" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-04T12:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 419.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-04T13:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6528" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-04T13:32:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 419, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the resolution and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Nugent demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-04T14:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6532-6533" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-10-04T14:15:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="746" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 257 - 165 (Roll no. 746).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6523" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-10-04T14:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="2250"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2681"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="2681"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2011--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2681) to provide additional time for the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue achievable standards for cement manufacturing facilities, and for other purposes, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2250) to provide additional time for the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue achievable standards for industrial, commercial, and institutional boilers, process heaters, and incinerators.</summary>
</bill>
