<bill session="111" type="hr" number="14" updated="2013-07-19T22:55:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-07T11:54:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-07T11:54:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing the importance of the Border Patrol in combating human smuggling and commending the Department of Justice for increasing the rate of human smuggler prosecutions.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">Recognizing the importance of the Department of Homeland Security, including U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, in combating human smuggling and trafficking in persons, and commending the Department of Justice for increasing the rate of human smuggling and trafficking prosecutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T14:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cohen moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T14:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5258-5260" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T14:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06T14:21:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Cohen objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5324-5325" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-05-07T11:54:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/6/2009 H5258" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2009--Passed House amended.
Reaffirms support for the Border Patrol's importance in combating human smuggling. Commends the Department of Justice (DOJ) for increasing the rate of human smuggler prosecutions.</summary>
</bill>
