<bill session="111" type="s" number="3747" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reduce and Cap the Federal Workforce Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for a reduction and limitation on the total number of Federal employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2010-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6900"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6900"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5348"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Reduce and Cap the Federal Workforce Act of 2010 - Requires the head of each executive agency: (1) to determine the number of full-time agency employees on February 16, 2009 (2009 number) and the number of full-time agency employees on the date occurring 90 days after enactment of this Act (current number); (2) if the 2009 number is lower, to ensure that no new employee is appointed until the 2009 number is attained through attrition; and (3) if the current number is lower or once the 2009 number is attained, to maintain that number by offsetting each new appointment by a reduction. Excludes the Department of Defense (DOD), the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), the Executive Office of the President, the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), and the Secret Service. Requires the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) determine the current number of full-time employees of DOD and DHS; and (2) maintain that number by offsetting each new appointment by a reduction. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to: (1) publicly disclose the total number of federal employees, the number of federal employees in each agency, and the annual rate of pay by title of each federal employee at each agency; and (2) update such information at least once a year. Authorizes the Director of National Intelligence to exclude any employee from such information for purposes of national security.</summary>
</bill>
