<bill session="109" type="h" number="2067" updated="2013-07-19T19:22:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Acquisition System Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for an improved acquisition system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="2005-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law judges"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication systems"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="United States Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2005--Introduced.
Acquisition System Improvement Act - Authorizes the assignment from a Federal agency to a private sector organization, or from a private sector to a Federal agency, of employees who work in Federal acquisition or acquisition management, who are considered exceptional performers, and who are expected to assume increased acquisition management responsibilities. Makes permanent agency authority for entering into share-in-savings contracts for information technology with respect to defense contracts and under the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949. Requires that the Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) be revised to include provisions requiring agencies to use commercially available online procurement services to purchase commercial items, including those services that allow agencies to conduct reverse auctions. Extends the deadline for submission of the report from the statutory and regulatory advisory panel. Raises the threshold required before the cost accounting standards of the Cost Accounting Board must be used by executive agencies and contractors and subcontractors in estimating, accumulating, and reporting costs in connection with all negotiated prime contract and subcontract procurements. Authorizes use by State and local governments of Federal supply schedules for goods and services for defense against or recovery from terrorism or nuclear, biological, chemical, or radiological attack. Mandates that the FAR be revised to establish payment terms for contract financing payments that are not otherwise subject to other laws governing payment terms. Establishes in: (1) the Department of Defense (DOD) the Department of Defense Board of Contract Appeals; and (2) the General Services Administration (GSA) the Civilian Board of Contract Appeals to resolve Federal contract disputes. Requires procedures for expediting the disposition of appeals in cases of small business concerns where the disputed amount is $150,000 or less. Makes the authority of the Defense and Civilian Boards applicable to: (1) contracts at or below the simplified acquisition threshold; and (2) contracts for the procurement of commercial items. Transfers personnel, funds, and property of the: (1) Armed Services Board of Contract Appeals to the Defense Board of Contract Appeals; and (2) other Boards of Contract Appeals (with exceptions) to the Civilian Board of Contract Appeals. Specifies the jurisdiction of the Defense and Civilian Boards. Establishes the Postal Service Board of Contract Appeals (having jurisdiction respecting the U.S. Postal Service and the Postal Rate Commission).</summary>
</bill>
