<bill session="110" type="s" number="1997" updated="2013-07-19T22:37:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FAIR Fuel Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Future Accountability in Retail Fuel Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require all new and upgraded fuel pumps to be equipped with automatic temperature compensation equipment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2007--Introduced.
Future Accountability in Retail Fuel Act or the FAIR Fuel Act - Requires, after a specified period, all new and existing motor fuel dispensers at retail fuel stations to be equipped with automatic temperature compensation equipment. Requires state inspectors to conduct annual inspections of motor fuel dispensers at such stations and to notify the Federal Trade Commission of any noncompliance with the requirements of this Act. Subjects owners or operators of retail fuel stations who are not in compliance to certain fines. Establishes the Automatic Temperature Compensation Equipment Trust Fund. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to use amounts in the Trust Fund to award grants to owners and operators of retail fuel stations to offset the costs for the installation of automatic temperature compensation equipment on motor fuel dispensers.</summary>
</bill>
