<bill session="109" type="h" number="5622" updated="2013-07-19T19:54:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coral Reef Conservation Legacy Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Coral Reef Conservation Legacy Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400322"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1167-1168"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-19T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-665.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-19T14:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="396">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 396.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4788"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1390"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1390"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Coral reefs"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Salvage"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2006--Reported to House amended.
Coral Reef Conservation Legacy Act of 2006 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 to extend the award of remaining coral reef conservation program grant funds, in addition to projects addressing emerging priorities or threats, to other appropriate projects, as determined by the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), including monitoring and assessment, research, pollution reduction, education, and technical support. Establishes as additional coral reef conservation project approval criteria: (1) the minimization of the likelihood of damage to coral reefs; and (2) promoting and assisting entities to work with local communities, and appropriate governmental and nongovernmental organizations, to support community-based planning and management initiatives for the protection of coral reef systems. (Sec. 3) Authorizes the Administrator and the Secretary of the Interior to undertake or authorize emergency response actions to prevent or minimize the destruction or loss of, or injury to, coral reefs or coral ecosystems from vessel impacts or other physical damage to coral reefs, including damage from unforeseen or disaster-related circumstances. Allows actions to include vessel removal and emergency restabilization of the vessel and any impacted coral reef. (Sec. 4) Requires the Administrator to report every three years to specified congressional committees on: (1) all activities undertaken to implement the national coral reef action strategy; and (2) the condition of United States coral reefs. (Sec. 5) Allows coral reef conservation fund amounts to be used for emergency response actions. Authorizes the Administrator to make community-based planning grants to certain persons to work with local communities and appropriate federal and state entities to implement plans for increased protection of high priority coral reefs. Establishes the United States Coral Reef Task Force to coordinate federal actions to better preserve and protect coral reef ecosystems. (Sec. 6) Reauthorizes the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 and authorizes appropriations through FY2010 for: (1) the coral reef conservation program; and (2) community-based planning grants. (Sec. 7) Authorizes appropriations to: (1) the University of Hawaii Sea Grant College program to administer a marine science laboratory for coral reef research and protection, and coastal ecology and development, at the American Samoa Community College; and (2) the University of Guam for coral reef research and protection and the University of Guam Marine Laboratory.</summary>
</bill>
