<bill session="111" type="s" number="804" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">School Day Factor Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend subpart 2 of part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish incentives for States to extend the minimum length of the school year to 200 full days by 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4353-4354"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4354-4355" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
School Day Factor Act of 2009 - Modifies the calculation of basic, concentration, targeted, and education finance incentive grants under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to reward states that increase the minimum number of days in their school year and minimum number of instructional hours in their school day. Makes such modification by factoring into such calculation the extent to which a state's minimum: (1) school year exceeds or falls below a base level school year which is set at 180 days for the 2009-2010 school year and rises five school days for each succeeding school year until it reaches 200 days for the 2013-2014 school year; and (2) instructional hours per school day exceed or fall below five and one-half hours. Removes any advantage gained by states that extend their school year, but reduce their minimum instructional hours per school day.</summary>
</bill>
