<bill session="112" type="s" number="899" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nutria Eradication and Control Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Nutria Eradication and Control Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the eradication and control of nutria.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2011-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2738-2739"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2739-2740" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer with an amendment. With written report No. 112-94.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-11-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="231">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 231.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1829"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3525"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Chesapeake Bay"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2011--Reported to Senate amended.
Nutria Eradication and Control Act of 2011 - Amends the Nutria Eradication and Control Act of 2003 to revise the nutria eradication program&#160;by authorizing&#160;the Secretary of the Interior to&#160; provide financial assistance to Delaware, Louisiana, Maryland, North Carolina, Oregon, Virginia, and Washington (currently, only to Maryland and Louisiana). Establishes the goals of such Program as: (1) eradicating nutria in Maryland; (2) eradicating or controlling nutria in Louisiana, Delaware, North Carolina, Oregon, Virginia, and Washington; and (3) restoring&#160;wetlands damaged by nutria. Requires that the Maryland program consist of management, research, and public education activities carried out in accordance with the United States Fish and Wildlife Service's document entitled "Eradication Strategies for Nutria in the Chesapeake and Delaware Bay Watersheds," dated March 2002 and&#160;updated in March 2009. Authorizes appropriations for such program for FY2012-FY2016 for financial assistance to the state of Maryland, the state of Louisiana, and on a competitive basis, to other coastal states. Requires the Secretary and the National Invasive Species Council to develop long-term nutria control or eradication programs to: (1) significantly reduce and restore nutria damaged wetlands in&#160;Delaware, Oregon, North Carolina, Virginia, and Washington; and (2) promote voluntary, public-private partnerships to eradicate or control nutria and restore nutria-damaged wetlands in such states.</summary>
</bill>
