<bill session="109" type="sr" number="146" updated="2013-07-19T20:08:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-18">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution recognizing the 25th anniversary of the eruption of Mount St. Helens.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2005-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2005-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-05-18" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5450" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5450" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5449" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seismology"/>
    <term name="Volcanoes"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/2005--Passed Senate without amendment.
Recognizes the 25th anniversary of the eruption of the volcano of Mount St. Helens, Washington, (Mount St. Helens) on May 18, 2005. Acknowledges the importance of monitoring all 169 volcanoes in the United States and its territories. Recognizes the work of the Department of the Interior, the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), the U.S. Forest Service, the Directorate of Emergency Preparedness and Response of the Department of Homeland Security, and the USGS David A. Johnston Cascades Volcano Observatory, Vancouver, Washington, in monitoring the activities of Mount St. Helens. Acknowledges the progress in science that has led to a more comprehensive understanding of volcanology, seismology, and plate tectonics, thus enhancing the ability to predict volcanic activity and eruptions. Supports monitoring volcanoes and helping to develop emergency response plans to ensure that the people and communities of the United States are safe.</summary>
</bill>
