<bill session="110" type="hr" number="552" updated="2013-07-19T20:55:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-05T14:15:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-09-05T14:15:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Calling on the Government of the People's Republic of China to remove barriers to United States financial services firms doing business in China.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400254"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2007-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-04T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Marshall moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-04T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10032-10036" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-04T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 552.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-04T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-05T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10111" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2007-09-05T14:15:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="850" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 401 - 4 (Roll no. 850).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/4/2007 H10032" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-09-05T14:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International banking"/>
    <term name="Life insurance"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/5/2007--Passed House without amendment.
Declares the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) the government of the People's Republic of China should immediately implement all of its World Trade Organization (WTO) commitments to date in financial services; and (2) it should immediately implement all of its commitments to date made under the auspices of the Strategic Economic Dialogue (SED) initiated by the Secretary of the Treasury. States that U.S. goals for the next SED meeting should be to achieve Chinese commitments toward: (1) removal of all foreign investment ownership caps on banking, life insurance, asset management, and securities; and (2) nondiscriminatory treatment of U.S. financial services firms with regard to licensing, corporate form, and permitted products and services, as well as regulation and supervision. Urges U.S. financial service regulators, in assessing whether applications from Chinese financial institutions meet comprehensive consolidated supervision standards, to consider: (1) whether such applications are for operations and activities in the United States that are currently prohibited for U.S. financial institutions in China; and (2) the extent to which such prohibitions reflect problems with the quality of home country supervision.</summary>
</bill>
