<bill session="111" type="h" number="5399" updated="2013-07-20T00:01:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a National Remote Teacher Corps, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412312"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2010--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of Education to establish the National Remote Teacher Corps of elementary and secondary school teachers to fill vacancies, reduce class sizes, and improve educational quality in certain remote areas in the U.S. territories. Requires Corps applicants to have at least a bachelor's degree from an institution of higher education (IHE), but gives priority to individuals who: (1) have at least a master's degree in education, science, technology, engineering, or mathematics; or (2) are highly qualified teachers with at least ten years of experience teaching elementary or secondary school students, or equivalent qualifications. Directs the Secretary to place Corps teachers with local educational agencies or charter schools that have been designated as Corps sites. Requires Corps teachers to agree to obtain certification or licensing as an elementary or secondary school teacher within such time as the Secretary may require and accept an offer to serve as a full-time teacher for at least three years at a Corps site. Requires Corps sites to compensate Corps teachers as they would compensate other teachers having similar qualifications. Authorizes the Secretary to compensate Corps teachers for certain travel costs and award them annual or one-time cash bonuses. Directs the Secretary and each Corps site to develop jointly and implement a high-quality alternative certification route for Corps teachers who are not certified teachers, unless the Corps site has an existing alternative certification program that is acceptable to the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop a professional development and distance-learning certificate or degree program to assist individuals located in remote territorial areas in becoming highly qualified teachers; and (2) award grants to IHEs to implement such program and cover the program's tuition for teachers at Corps sites.</summary>
</bill>
