<bill session="113" type="h" number="1080" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Sikes Act to promote the use of cooperative agreements under such Act for land management related to Department of Defense readiness activities and to amend title 10, United States Code, to facilitate interagency cooperation in conservation programs to avoid or reduce adverse impacts on military readiness activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E277"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17T19:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-115, Part I.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2013--Reported to House amended, Part I.
(Sec. 1) Amends the Sikes Act (conservation programs on federal lands) to allow funds appropriated to the Department of Defense (DOD) that are obligated to cooperative agreements with states, local governments, Indian tribes, nongovernmental organizations, and individuals for maintenance and improvement of natural resources located off of military or state-owned National Guard installations (but that are related to current or anticipated military activities) to be: (1) paid in a lump sum and include an amount intended to cover the future costs of the activities under the agreement; and (2) invested by the recipient in accordance with the recipient's own investment management guidelines, with any investment interest or income permitted to be applied for the same purposes as the principal. Allows such cooperative agreements to be used to acquire property or services for the direct benefit or use of the U.S. government. Permits amounts available to the DOD that are provided to any federal, state, local, or nongovernmental entity for conservation and rehabilitation of natural resources in an area that is not on a military installation to be used only for payment of direct costs associated with the management of such area. Authorizes payment of up to 3% of total project administrative costs, fees, and management charges. Prohibits amounts available to the DOD from being used under such Act to acquire fee title interest in real property for such natural resources projects that are not on a military installation. Requires the DOD Inspector General to conduct annual audits of natural resources projects funded with amounts available to DOD under such Act that are not on a military installation. (Sec. 2) Allows the recipient of funds in agreements under the Sikes Act, or other specified agreements with states, political subdivisions, or private entities pursuant to military laws addressing the use or development of real property near or ecologically related to military installations or airspace, to use such funds to satisfy any matching funds or cost-sharing requirement of the Departments of Agriculture (USDA) or the Interior. (Sec. 3) Declares that this Act expires on October 1, 2019, except that cooperative agreements entered into before such date shall continue as if this Act has not expired.</summary>
</bill>
