<bill session="113" type="h" number="1650" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Weapons Abolition and Economic and Energy Conversion Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for nuclear weapons abolition and economic conversion in accordance with District of Columbia Initiative Measure Number 37 of 1992, while ensuring environmental restoration and clean-energy conversion.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E499"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-18">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS29" subcommittee="Strategic Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/2013--Introduced.
Nuclear Weapons Abolition and Economic and Energy Conversion Act of 2013 - Requires the government: (1) to provide leadership to negotiate and enter into a multilateral treaty or other international agreement that provides for the dismantlement and elimination, under strict international control, of all nuclear weapons in every country by 2020; (2) once the President certifies that all countries have eliminated such weapons or begun such elimination under established legal requirements, to redirect resources that are being used for nuclear weapons programs to addressing human and infrastructure needs and to converting nuclear weapons industry employees, processes, plants, and programs to constructive, ecologically beneficial peacetime activities; (3) to undertake efforts to eliminate war, armed conflict, and all military operations; and (4) to promote policies to induce all other countries to join in such commitments.</summary>
</bill>
