<bill session="109" type="s" number="3869" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving the Quality of and Access to Supplemental Educational Services Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">IQ Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the quality of, and access to, supplemental educational services in effort to increase student achievement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9131"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2006--Introduced.
Improving the Quality of and Access to Supplemental Educational Services Act, or the IQ Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require local educational agencies (LEAs) to make supplemental educational services (SES) (after-school tutoring programs) available to disadvantaged students by the beginning of the first full school year, rather than after an additional school year, after their school has been identified as needing improvement because of having failed, for two consecutive years, to make adequate yearly progress (AYP) pursuant to state academic performance standards. Directs each state to: (1) establish a system that evaluates each SES provider primarily by the extent to which the provider improves the academic performance of all students receiving SES, even those not in a grade subject to a state academic assessment; (2) establish a process for removing providers subject to repeat complaints; (3) publicize data concerning SES evaluations, cost, attendance, and timeliness; (4) assist LEAs in creating a streamlined enrollment process and providing timely services; (5) provide LEAs with a choice of providers capable of serving children who are disabled or have limited English proficiency; and (6) offer incentives, where appropriate, to providers to service rural areas. Requires an LEA to: (1) permit approved and successful SES providers access, at a fair rent, to its public schools if other external groups are given such access; (2) ensure that the SES registration process is uncomplicated and easily accessible to parents; (3) report to the state on SES spending and progress toward increasing student participation; and (4) ensure the beginning of SES as soon as possible after the beginning of the school year. Directs the Secretary of Education to study the impact differences in the provision of SES, the use of highly qualified teachers as tutors, and provider incentives have on improving student performance and SES attendance. Allows LEAs identified as needing improvement and schools not so identified to provide SES. Prohibits providers from offering material selection incentives to schools, LEAs, states, parents, or students.</summary>
</bill>
