<bill session="111" type="h" number="2205" updated="2013-07-19T23:31:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Education Begins at Home Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand quality programs of early childhood home visitation that increase school readiness, child abuse and neglect prevention, and early identification of developmental and health delays, including potential mental health concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2009-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2009--Introduced.
Education Begins at Home Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make matching grants to states, Indians, territories, and possessions to establish or expand quality early childhood home visitation programs for families that are expecting a child or have pre-kindergarten children. Allots funds among state grantees on the basis of their share of children from birth through age five who are from impoverished families. Directs the Secretary to award competitive grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) and experienced public or private community-based entities to support and expand quality, local early childhood home visitation programs for families that have English language learners and are expecting a child or have pre-kindergarten children. Directs the Secretary of Defense to make competitive grants to LEAs, schools, and community-based organizations that serve military dependents to support and expand high quality early childhood home visitation programs for military families that are expecting a child or have pre-kindergarten children. Requires each grantee to provide: (1) voluntary early childhood home visitation at least once a month to as many eligible families as is practicable; (2) training and technical assistance to program staff; and (3) program participants with access to other early childhood and family services. Directs the Secretary to develop and implement a public information and educational campaign to inform the public and new parents about the importance of proper care for infants and children under five years of age.</summary>
</bill>
