<bill session="111" type="h" number="3895" updated="2013-07-19T23:47:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct or support research and demonstration projects on the use of financial and in-kind subsidies and rewards to encourage individuals and communities to promote wellness, adopt healthy behaviors, and use evidence-based preventive health services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412273"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/21/2009--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to conduct, or award grants for, research and demonstration projects on the use of financial and in-kind subsidies and rewards to encourage individuals and communities to promote wellness, adopt healthy behaviors, and use evidence-based preventive health services. Requires such projects to focus on: (1) tobacco use, obesity, and other prevention and wellness priorities identified by the Secretary in the national prevention and wellness strategy; (2) the initiation, maintenance, and long-term sustainability of wellness promotion, adoption of healthy behaviors, and use of evidence-based preventive health services; and (3) populations at high risk of preventable diseases and conditions. Directs the Secretary to submit the findings of such projects to the Task Force on Clinical Preventive Services or the Task Force on Community Preventive Services, and to the Health Benefits Advisory Committee. Directs the Secretary to ensure that a subsidy or reward that: (1) the Task Force on Clinical Preventive Services determines meets its standards for a grade A or B is included in the essential benefits package under the America's Affordable Health Choices Act of 2009; and (2) the Task Force on Community Preventive Service determines is effective becomes an allowable use of community prevention and wellness services grants. Requires the Secretary to ensure that any subsidy or reward: (1) does not have a discriminatory effect on the basis of any personal characteristic extraneous to the provision of high-quality health care or related services; and (2) is not tied to the premium or cost sharing of an individual under any qualified health benefits plan.</summary>
</bill>
