<bill session="110" type="h" number="3178" updated="2013-07-19T21:31:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit the length of deployment of members of the Armed Forces for Operation Iraqi Freedom.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="2007-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3159"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Marines"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2007--Introduced.
Requires that, commencing 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the deployment of a unit or individual of the Armed Forces for Operation Iraqi Freedom shall be limited as follows: (1) in the case of a unit or individual of the Army (including the Army National Guard or Army Reserve), the unit or individual may not be deployed, or continued or extended on deployment, for more than 12 consecutive months; and (2) in the case of a unit or individual of the Marine Corps (including the Marine Corps Reserve), the unit or individual may not be deployed, or continued or extended on deployment, for more than seven consecutive months. Authorizes the President to waive the limitation in the event of a requirement for the use of military force in time of national emergency, following consultation with the congressional defense committees.</summary>
</bill>
