<bill session="113" type="hr" number="216" updated="2013-11-02T06:17:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-17T10:57:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-05-17T10:57:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1062) to improve the consideration by the Securities and Exchange Commission of the costs and benefits of its regulations and orders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15T18:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-60, by Mr. Sessions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15T18:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. The resolution makes in order as original text for purpose of amendment an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 113-10 and provides that it shall be considered as read. The resolution waives all points of order against the amendment in the nature of a substitute. Each amendment may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-15T18:12:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="25">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 25.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T09:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2723-2731" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T09:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 216.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T10:49:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 222 - 181 (Roll no. 155).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2730-2731" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="156" datetime="2013-05-17T10:57:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 223 - 180 (Roll no. 156).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2723" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T10:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="h" number="1062"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2013--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1062) to improve the consideration by the Securities and Exchange Commission of the costs and benefits of its regulations and orders.</summary>
</bill>
