<bill session="109" type="h" number="2744" updated="2013-07-19T19:28:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-10">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Agriculture Department FY2006 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2006, Agriculture</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2006, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400037"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-02T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 109-102, by Mr. Bonilla.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-06-02T16:17:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="57">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 57.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-06-07T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 303 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2744 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T12:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 303 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 303.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4201-4208, H4208-4251" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4223, H4226, H4227-4230" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4230-4231" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4231-4232" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4232-4233" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4233, H4233-4234" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4234" label="text of Title VI as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4234-4237" label="text of Title VII as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2744 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 303 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Paul Ryan to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T12:21:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2744.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Bonilla amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Butterfield amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T13:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hinojosa amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Weiner amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Weiner amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Weiner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Weiner amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T13:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Platts amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Goodlatte stated that the proviso beginning on page 54, line 4 and ending on line 9 on the same page constituted legislation in an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T13:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Goodlatte stated that section 749 of the bill constituted legislation in an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Goodlatte stated that section 760 of the bill constituted legislation in an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T13:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Bonilla amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Moran (KS) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T13:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Rehberg amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T14:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with further debate on the Rehberg amendment with time limited to 30 minutes, equally divided and controlled.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T14:38:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rehberg amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rehberg demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Rehberg amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T14:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hinchey amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Hinchey amendment, equally divided and controlled.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hinchey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hinchey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Hinchey amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Sweeney amendment, equally divided and controlled.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T15:52:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sweeney amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Sweeney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Sweeney amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bonilla moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2744 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T15:54:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Bonilla asked unanimous consent to limit further amendments to the bill to a list which he had submitted to the desk. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T15:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4251-4273" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T15:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Blumenauer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Blumenauer amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Chabot amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T16:50:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Chabot amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Chabot demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Chabot amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T18:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stupak amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hefley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hefley amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hefley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Hefley amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T18:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kucinich amendment pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T18:37:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garrett (NJ) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Garrett (NJ) amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T18:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stupak amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T18:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tiahrt amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T18:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brown (OH) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T18:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kucinich amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T19:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Weiner amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T19:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bonilla moved for the Committee of the Whole to rise and report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T19:47:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to rise and report Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T19:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2744.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T19:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4273" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T19:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-06-08T20:05:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="238" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 408 - 18 (Roll no. 238).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08T20:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Agriculture, Rural Development, and Related Agencies. Approved for full committee consideration without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Appropriations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported by Senator Bennett with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-92.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-06-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="141">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 141.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10080-10103" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10080-10100" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>The committee substitute agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10173-10176, S10183" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-20">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10210-10214, S10215-10227" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10264-10287" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10327-10332" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2005-09-22" how="roll" result="pass" roll="241" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 97 - 2. Record Vote Number: 241.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/26/2005 S10441-10453" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Bennett; Cochran; Specter; Bond; McConnell; Burns; Craig; Brownback; Stevens; Kohl; Harkin; Dorgan; Feinstein; Durbin; Johnson; Landrieu; Byrd.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bonilla moved that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8940-8946" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19T13:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. DeLauro moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8946" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19T13:17:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Delauro motion to instruct conferees the Chari put the question on the motion and announced by voice vote that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Delauro demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion to instruct conferees until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19T13:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Delauro motion to instruct conferees. The instructions contained within the motion seek to require the managers on the part of the House to recede to the Senate on Section 785 of the Senate amendment and agree to a provision that availability of funds to reimburse administrative costs under the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to a State agency based on the percentage of the costs (other than costs for issuance of benefits or nutrition education) obtained under contract.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 209 - 216 (Roll no. 535).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9011" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Bonilla, Kingston, Latham, Emerson, Goode, LaHood, Doolittle, Alexander, Lewis (CA), DeLauro, Hinchey, Farr, Boyd, Kaptur, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-25">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-26T18:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 109-255 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9204-9240" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-26">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9204-9240" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 520 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2744 with 1 hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-28T09:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 520 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-28T10:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bonilla brought up conference report H. Rept. 109-255 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 520.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9381-9394" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-28T10:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 2744.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="2005-10-28T11:33:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="555" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 318 - 63 (Roll no. 555).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9394" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-10-28T11:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-31">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-02">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12287-12291" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-11-03" how="roll" result="pass" roll="282" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 81 - 18. Record Vote Number: 282.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-11-03">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2005-11-04">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-11-10" type="public" number="109-97">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-97.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP01" subcommittee="Agriculture, Rural Development, and Related Agencies" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="303"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="303"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="520"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="520"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural colleges"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural estimating and reporting"/>
    <term name="Agricultural experiment stations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agricultural machinery"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural statistics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Breast feeding"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Cargo preference"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Citrus fruits"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Clergy"/>
    <term name="Colonias"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commodity Credit Corporation"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional fellows"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contact lenses"/>
    <term name="Cooperative societies"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Cotton"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Dairy products"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electrification"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Farm Credit Administration"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Federal Crop Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Goats"/>
    <term name="Government aircraft"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Grain"/>
    <term name="Grassland ecology"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Hunger"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Laboratory animals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Meat inspection"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Organic farming"/>
    <term name="Orphans"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Plant diseases"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Protection of animals"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rural Telephone Bank"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Sewerage"/>
    <term name="Sheep"/>
    <term name="Shipping rates"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Skin cancer"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Sustainable agriculture"/>
    <term name="Swine"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Tobacco research"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tree diseases"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h224"/>
    <amendment number="h225"/>
    <amendment number="h226"/>
    <amendment number="h227"/>
    <amendment number="h228"/>
    <amendment number="h229"/>
    <amendment number="h230"/>
    <amendment number="h231"/>
    <amendment number="h232"/>
    <amendment number="h233"/>
    <amendment number="h234"/>
    <amendment number="h235"/>
    <amendment number="h236"/>
    <amendment number="h237"/>
    <amendment number="h238"/>
    <amendment number="h239"/>
    <amendment number="h240"/>
    <amendment number="h241"/>
    <amendment number="h242"/>
    <amendment number="h243"/>
    <amendment number="h244"/>
    <amendment number="h245"/>
    <amendment number="h246"/>
    <amendment number="h247"/>
    <amendment number="s1726"/>
    <amendment number="s1729"/>
    <amendment number="s1730"/>
    <amendment number="s1731"/>
    <amendment number="s1732"/>
    <amendment number="s1734"/>
    <amendment number="s1735"/>
    <amendment number="s1736"/>
    <amendment number="s1737"/>
    <amendment number="s1738"/>
    <amendment number="s1739"/>
    <amendment number="s1740"/>
    <amendment number="s1741"/>
    <amendment number="s1742"/>
    <amendment number="s1743"/>
    <amendment number="s1744"/>
    <amendment number="s1745"/>
    <amendment number="s1746"/>
    <amendment number="s1747"/>
    <amendment number="s1748"/>
    <amendment number="s1749"/>
    <amendment number="s1750"/>
    <amendment number="s1751"/>
    <amendment number="s1752"/>
    <amendment number="s1753"/>
    <amendment number="s1754"/>
    <amendment number="s1755"/>
    <amendment number="s1756"/>
    <amendment number="s1757"/>
    <amendment number="s1758"/>
    <amendment number="s1759"/>
    <amendment number="s1760"/>
    <amendment number="s1761"/>
    <amendment number="s1762"/>
    <amendment number="s1763"/>
    <amendment number="s1764"/>
    <amendment number="s1765"/>
    <amendment number="s1766"/>
    <amendment number="s1767"/>
    <amendment number="s1768"/>
    <amendment number="s1769"/>
    <amendment number="s1770"/>
    <amendment number="s1771"/>
    <amendment number="s1772"/>
    <amendment number="s1773"/>
    <amendment number="s1774"/>
    <amendment number="s1775"/>
    <amendment number="s1776"/>
    <amendment number="s1777"/>
    <amendment number="s1778"/>
    <amendment number="s1779"/>
    <amendment number="s1780"/>
    <amendment number="s1781"/>
    <amendment number="s1782"/>
    <amendment number="s1783"/>
    <amendment number="s1784"/>
    <amendment number="s1785"/>
    <amendment number="s1786"/>
    <amendment number="s1787"/>
    <amendment number="s1788"/>
    <amendment number="s1789"/>
    <amendment number="s1790"/>
    <amendment number="s1791"/>
    <amendment number="s1792"/>
    <amendment number="s1793"/>
    <amendment number="s1794"/>
    <amendment number="s1795"/>
    <amendment number="s1796"/>
    <amendment number="s1797"/>
    <amendment number="s1798"/>
    <amendment number="s1799"/>
    <amendment number="s1800"/>
    <amendment number="s1801"/>
    <amendment number="s1802"/>
    <amendment number="s1803"/>
    <amendment number="s1804"/>
    <amendment number="s1805"/>
    <amendment number="s1806"/>
    <amendment number="s1807"/>
    <amendment number="s1808"/>
    <amendment number="s1809"/>
    <amendment number="s1810"/>
    <amendment number="s1811"/>
    <amendment number="s1812"/>
    <amendment number="s1813"/>
    <amendment number="s1814"/>
    <amendment number="s1815"/>
    <amendment number="s1816"/>
    <amendment number="s1817"/>
    <amendment number="s1818"/>
    <amendment number="s1819"/>
    <amendment number="s1820"/>
    <amendment number="s1821"/>
    <amendment number="s1822"/>
    <amendment number="s1823"/>
    <amendment number="s1824"/>
    <amendment number="s1825"/>
    <amendment number="s1826"/>
    <amendment number="s1827"/>
    <amendment number="s1828"/>
    <amendment number="s1829"/>
    <amendment number="s1830"/>
    <amendment number="s1831"/>
    <amendment number="s1832"/>
    <amendment number="s1833"/>
    <amendment number="s1834"/>
    <amendment number="s1835"/>
    <amendment number="s1836"/>
    <amendment number="s1837"/>
    <amendment number="s1838"/>
    <amendment number="s1839"/>
    <amendment number="s1840"/>
    <amendment number="s1841"/>
    <amendment number="s1842"/>
    <amendment number="s1843"/>
    <amendment number="s1844"/>
    <amendment number="s1845"/>
    <amendment number="s1846"/>
    <amendment number="s1847"/>
    <amendment number="s1848"/>
    <amendment number="s1849"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/10/2005--Public Law.
Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006 - Title I: Agricultural Programs - Appropriates FY2006 funds for the following Department of Agriculture (Department) programs and services: (1) Office of the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary); (2) executive operations; (3) National Appeals Division; (4) Office of Budget and Program Analysis; (5) Homeland Security Staff; (6) Office of the Chief Information Officer; (7) Common Computing Environment; (8) Office of the Chief Financial Officer; (9) Office of the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights; (10) Office of Civil Rights; (11) Office of the Assistant Secretary for Administration; (12) agriculture buildings and facilities and rental payments; (13) hazardous materials management; (14) departmental administration; (15) Office of the Assistant Secretary for Congressional Relations; (16) Office of Communications; (17) Office of the Inspector General; (18) Office of the General Counsel; (19) Office of the Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics; (20) Economic Research Service; (21) National Agricultural Statistics Service; (22) Agricultural Research Service; (23) Cooperative State Research, Education, and Extension Service; (24) Native American Institutions Endowment Fund; (25) outreach for socially disadvantaged farmers; (26) Office of the Under Secretary for Marketing and Regulatory Programs; (27) Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service; (28) Agricultural Marketing Service; (29) Grain Inspection, Packers and Stockyards Administration; (30) Office of the Under Secretary for Food Safety; (31) Food Safety and Inspection Service; (32) Office of the Under Secretary for Farm and Foreign Agricultural Services; (33) Farm Service Agency; (34) Risk Management Agency; (35) Federal Crop Insurance Corporation Fund; and (36) Commodity Credit Corporation Fund. Title II: Conservation Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Natural Resources and Environment; and (2) Natural Resources Conservation Service. Title III: Rural Development Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Rural Development; (2) Rural Community Advancement Program; (3) rural development salaries and expenses; (4) Rural Housing Service; (5) Rural Business-Cooperative Service; and (6) Rural Utilities Service. Title IV: Domestic Food Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Food, Nutrition and Consumer Services; and (2) Food and Nutrition Service. Title V: Foreign Assistance and Related Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Foreign Agricultural Service; (2) Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 (P.L. 480) program account, title I ocean freight differential grants, and title II grants; (3) Commodity Credit Corporation export loans program account; and (4) McGovern-Dole international food for education and child nutrition program grants. Title VI: Related Agencies and Food and Drug Administration - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Food and Drug Administration (FDA); (2) Commodity Futures Trading Commission; and (3) Farm Credit Administration. Title VII: General Provisions - Specifies certain uses and limits on or prohibitions against the use of funds appropriated by this Act. (Sec. 709) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used to pay indirect costs charged against competitive agricultural research, education, or extension grant awards issued by the Cooperative State Research, Education, and Extension Service that exceed 20% of total federal funds provided under each award. (Sec. 713) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used for the Safe Meat and Poultry Inspection Panel. (Sec. 720) Prohibits funds from being used to relocate a State Rural Development office until cost and operation effectiveness have been determined. (Sec. 721) Makes additional appropriations for Bill Emerson and Mickey Leland Hunger Fellowships. (Sec. 722) Provides that any balances and recoveries available to carry out title III of P.L. 480 may be used to carry out title II of such Act. (Sec. 723) Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to increase obligated funding for the national sheep industry improvement center revolving fund. (Sec. 724) Directs The Secretary to evaluate and report on any impacts of the decision in Harvey v. Veneman, 396 F.3d 28 (1st Cir. Me. 2005), including determinations: (1) on whether restoring the National Organic Program would adversely affect organic farmers, organic food processors, and consumers; (2) regarding the use of synthetic ingredients in processing and handling; (3) regarding expedited petitions for commercially unavailable agricultural commodities and products; and (4) regarding the use of crops and forage from land included in the organic system plan of dairy farms in their third year of organic management. (Sec. 725) Obligates specified amounts of agricultural commodities to assist foreign countries mitigate the effects of HIV and AIDS, particularly for individuals caring for orphaned children. (Sec. 726) Directs the Natural Resources Conservation Service to provide financial and technical assistance through the watershed and flood prevention operations program to: (1) the Kane County, Illinois, Indian Creek watershed flood prevention project; (2) the Hickory Creek Special Drainage District, Bureau County, Illinois; (3) the Muskingam River Watershed, Mohican River, Jerome and Muddy Fork, Ohio, for obstruction removal projects; (4) the Little Red River irrigation project, Arkansas; (5) the Matanuska River erosion control project in Alaska; (6) the Little Otter Creek project in Missouri; (7) the Manoa Watershed project in Hawaii; (8) the West Tarkio project in Iowa; (9) the Steeple Run and West Branch DuPage River watershed projects in DuPage County, Illinois; (10) the Coal Creek project in Utah; and (11) the East Locust Creek watershed plan revision in Missouri. Directs the Service to provide financial and technical assistance through the conservation operations program for the Utah Conservation Initiative for completion of the American Fork water quality and habitat restoration project in Utah. (Sec. 727) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being transferred to any federal entity unless authorized by an appropriations Act. (Sec. 728) Authorizes the Secretary to use up to 22% of competitive research funds under this Act for a competitive grants program similar to the initiative for future agriculture and food systems. (Sec. 729) Prohibits funds from being used to carry out Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC)-funded rehabilitation of certain dams. (Sec. 730) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used to close or relocate the FDA Division of Pharmaceutical Analysis in Saint Louis, Missouri, outside the city or county limits. (Sec. 731) Prohibits funds from being used to carry out the rural strategic investment program. (Sec. 732) Authorizes the Department to use any unobligated salaries and expense funds to reimburse the Office of General Counsel for representing its agencies and offices in employee complaints before the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, or the Merit Systems Protection Board. (Sec. 733) Prohibits funds from being used to carry out the rural firefighters and emergency personnel grant program. (Sec. 734) Limits wetlands reserve program enrollment acreage for 2006. (Sec. 735) Limits fund use for the environmental quality incentives program. (Sec. 736) Prohibits funds from being used for renewable energy system and energy efficiency improvements assistance. (Sec. 737) Limits fund use for access to broadband telecommunications in rural areas. (Sec. 738) Limits funds made available in FY2006 or preceding fiscal years under P.L. 480 to reimburse CCC for the release of certain commodities under the Bill Emerson Humanitarian Trust Act. (Sec. 739) Prohibits funds from being used to carry out the value-added market development grant program. (Sec. 740) Directs the Secretary, with lender consent, to structure the annual fee payment schedule for rural electrification and telephone bond and loan guarantees so as not to exceed an average of 30 basis points per year for the term of the loan in order to ensure fund availability to pay related subsidy costs. (Sec. 741) Limits fund use for the conservation security program. (Sec. 742) Limits fund use for the grazing, wildlife habitat incentive, source water protection, and Great Lakes Basin programs. (Sec. 743) Rescinds specified unobligated funds in the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC) reserve account. (Sec. 744) Limits fund use for the farmland protection program. (Sec. 745) Prohibits, with a FY2005 exception, fund use for the rural business investment program. (Sec. 746) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act in violation of the Travel and Transportation Reform Act of 1998. (Sec. 747) Limits fund use for the ground and surface water conservation program. (Sec. 748) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used to revise a proposed rule (July 8, 2003) respecting cost-sharing for animal and plant health emergency programs of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service. (Sec. 749) Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative aircraft lease agreements under the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, Wildlife Services. (Sec. 750) Limits funds for the bioenergy program. (Sec. 751) Authorizes Department agencies and offices to use available discretionary funds to prepare for final employment discrimination decisions. (Sec. 752) Requires that funds made available in the current fiscal year be used to cover only current fiscal year obligations for the following Food Security Act of 1985 programs: (1) ground and surface water conservation program; (2) conservation reserve program; (3) wetlands reserve program; (4) conservation security program; (5) farmland protection program; (6) grassland reserve program; (7) environmental quality incentives program; and (8) wildlife habitat incentives program. (Sec. 753) Appropriates funds to the Denali Commission to address solid waste disposal problems which threaten to contaminate rural drinking water supplies. (Sec. 754) Provides that: (1) Palmer, Alaska, shall be eligible for a water and waste disposal grant of not more than 75% of the cost of providing water and sewer service to the proposed hospital in the Matanuska-Susitna Borough, Alaska, and (2) the Alaska Department of Community and Economic Development shall be allowed to pass the grant funds through to the local government entity that will provide water and sewer service to the hospital. Provides that the construction projects known as the Tri-Valley Community Center addition in Healy, Alaska, the Cold Climate Housing Research Center (to be designated an "essential community facility") in Fairbanks, Alaska, and the University of Alaska-Fairbanks Allied Health Learning Center skill labs/classrooms shall be eligible for community facilities grants in amounts that are equal to not more than 75% of the total facility costs. Provides, in the case of a high cost isolated rural area in Alaska that is not connected to a road system, that the maximum level for the single family housing assistance shall be 150% of the median household income level in the nonmetropolitan areas of the state and 115% of all other eligible areas of the state. Provides that any former Rural Utilities Service borrower that has repaid or prepaid an insured, direct or guaranteed loan under the Rural Electrification Act, or any not-for-profit utility that is eligible to receive an insured or direct loan under such Act, shall be eligible for economic development and job creation assistance under such Act in the same manner as a borrower (under such Act). (Sec. 755) Appropriates funds for the Ohio Livestock Expo Center, Springfield, Ohio. (Sec. 756) Authorizes community facility program borrowers and grantees to enter into service contracts with not-for-profit third parties. (Sec. 757) Limits fund use for the agricultural management assistance program. (Sec. 758) Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) make funding and other assistance available through the emergency watershed protection program to repair and prevent damage to nonfederal land in watersheds that have been impaired by fires initiated by the federal government; and (2) waive related cost sharing requirements. (Sec. 759) Limits fund use for the biomass research and development program. (Sec. 760) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used to make certain previously-enrolled land planted to hardwood trees ineligible for the conservation reserve program. (Sec. 761) Authorizes the Secretary to sell the U.S. Water Conservation Laboratory, and the Cotton Research Center, Phoenix, Arizona, and use the proceeds through September 30, 2007, to replace such facilities and to improve other Department facilities. (Sec. 762) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used to require rural status recertification for rural electrification and telecommunication loan program borrowers. (Sec. 763) Authorizes the Secretary to use any unobligated carryover funds (with an exception) from any Rural Utilities Service program to carry out 911 access improvements. (Sec. 764) Appropriates funds for the Alaska dairy industry. (Sec. 765) Considers until receipt of the 2010 Census: (1) Bridgeton, New Jersey, Kinston, North Carolina, and Portsmouth, Ohio, as rural areas for purposes of Rural Housing Service community facilities program loans and grants; (2) the Township of Bloomington, Illinois, (including individuals and entities with projects within the Township) eligible for Rural Housing Service community facilities programs loans and grants; (3) Lone Grove, Oklahoma, (including individuals and entities with projects within the city) eligible for Rural Housing Service community facilities program loans and grants; (4) Butte/Silverbow, Montana, rural areas for purposes of eligibility for Rural Utilities Service water and waste water loans and grants and Rural Housing Service community facilities program loans and grants; (5) Cleburne County, Arkansas, rural areas for purposes of eligibility of Rural Utilities Service water and waste water loans and grants; (6) the designated Census track areas for the Upper Kanawha Valley Enterprise Community, West Virginia, rural areas for purposes of eligibility for rural empowerment zones and enterprise community programs in the rural development mission area; (7) the Municipality of Carolina, Puerto Rico, as meeting the eligibility requirements for Rural Utilities Service water and waste water loans and grants; (8) the Municipalities of Vega Baja, Manati, Guayama, Fajardo, Humacao, and Naguabo, Puerto Rico, (including individuals and entities with projects within the Municipalities) eligible for Rural Community Advancement Program loans and grants and intermediate relending programs; (9) Hidalgo, Texas as a rural area for the purpose of the Rural Business-Cooperative Service rural business enterprise grant program; (10) Elgin, Oklahoma (including individuals and entities with projects within the city) eligible for Rural Utilities Service water and waste water loans and grants; and (11) Lodi, California, Atchison, Kansas, and Belle Glade, Florida as rural areas for the purposes of the Rural Utilities Service water and waste water loans and grants. (Sec. 766) Appropriates funds for: (1) the Alaska Village Initiatives for administering a private lands wildlife management program in Alaska; and (2) the Wisconsin Federation of Cooperatives for pilot Wisconsin-Minnesota health care cooperative purchasing alliances. (Sec. 768) Makes Burlington and Camden counties, New Jersey, eligible for FY2006 rural community advancement program loans and grants at FY2005 levels. (Sec. 769) Authorizes the reallocation and audit use of certain unused funds for audits under the child and adult care food program. (Sec. 770) Authorizes and directs the Secretary to quitclaim to Elkhart, Kansas, all rights, title and interests to a specified tract of land in Morton County, Kansas. (Sec. 771) Appropriates funds for the healthy forests reserve program. (Sec. 772) Prohibits fund use under this Act by any executive branch entity to produce a prepackaged news story for U.S. broadcast or distribution unless it contains audio or text notice that it was produced or funded by such executive entity. (Sec. 773) Appropriates additional funds for specialty crop block grants, of which up to 5% may be used for administrative expenses. (Sec. 774) Amends the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to authorize the borrower of a loan made by the Federal Financing Bank and guaranteed under this Act to request an extension of the outstanding principal balance's maturity (including guarantee) or any loan advance. States that extensions shall: (1) not be granted without feasibility and security determinations; (2) not be granted if the principal balance extended exceeds the appraised value of the generating plant or transmission line; (3) not result in a final maturity greater than 55 years from the time of original disbursement and shall not result in a final maturity greater than a plant's useful life; and (4) not be granted more than once per loan advance. Provides for a borrower fee which shall be credited to the rural electrification and telecommunications loans program account. (Sec. 775) Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to relinquish to Arkansas all or part of the lands and properties encompassing the Jefferson Labs campus (the National Center for Toxicological Research and the Arkansas Regional Laboratory), Arkansas, that are under the Secretary's supervision. (Sec. 776) Amends the Child Nutrition and WIC Reauthorization Act of 2004 to direct that certain funds for school nutrition technical assistance be transferred to the Secretary on October 1, 2005 (currently on July 1, 2006). (Sec. 777) Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to revise the definition of an "eligible state" for simplified summer food program purposes. (Sec. 778) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used to retire more than 5% of rural telephone bank class A stock, except in the event of the bank's liquidation or dissolution in FY2006, or to maintain any account or subaccount within the bank's accounting records whose creation has not been authorized by statute. (Sec. 779) Appropriates funds to carry out elementary and secondary school fresh fruit and vegetable programs in Utah, Wisconsin, New Mexico, Texas, Connecticut, and Idaho. (Sec. 780) Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to permit data from similar crops to be used in obtaining crop insurance coverage agreements. (Sec. 781) Authorizes the National Dairy Promotion and Research Board during FY2006 to expend funds for any activity to improve the environment and public health. Directs the Secretary to review such expenditures and include the information in the 2007 dairy promotion program report. (Sec. 782) Designates the federal facility located at the South Mississippi Branch Experiment Station, Poplarville, Mississippi, as the "Thad Cochran Southern Horticultural Laboratory." (Sec. 783) Directs the Secretary to convey without consideration the Western Cotton Research Laboratory, 4135 East Broadway Road, Phoenix, Arizona, to the Arizona Cotton Growers Association and Supima. (Sec. 784) Directs the Secretary to include horses and deer within a livestock assistance, compensation, or feed program. Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 to include horses and deer (eliminates equines used for food or food production) under the emergency livestock feed assistance program. Amends the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001 to make losses to producers of deer, elk, reindeer, bison, and horses eligible for assistance under such Act. Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to include horses and deer under the livestock assistance provisions of such Act. Amends the Agricultural Assistance Act of 2003 to include horses and deer under the livestock disaster assistance provisions of such Act. Limits the applicability of the amendments made by this section to losses resulting from a disaster occurring on or after July 28, 2005. (Sec. 785) States that specified conservation amounts for the Plant Materials Center, Fallon, Nevada, shall remain available until expended. (Sec. 786) Prohibits, without specific congressional authorization, funds made available by this Act from being used to study, or enter into a contract with, a private party for competitive sourcing activities relating to rural development or farm loan programs. (Sec. 787) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used to pay administrative costs of a state that authorizes any new for-profit vendor to transact food instruments under WIC if it is expected that more than 50% of the vendor's annual food sale revenues will be derived from supplemental food items obtained with WIC food instruments (except that the Secretary may approve such vendor's authorization if necessary to assure participant access to program benefits). (Sec. 788) Rescinds specified unobligated amounts under the the Act of August 24, 1935. (Sec. 789) Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of funds under this Act from being used to require a recipient of certain rural housing for domestic farm labor grants funded in response to Hurricane Andrew to pay the United States any interest earned with respect to such grants if the funds are expended by the grantee to provide such housing within 18 months of the date of enactment of this section. (Sec. 790) Appropriates funds for: (1) the University of Nevada at Reno, Nevada; (2) the Ohio Center for Farmland Policy Innovation at Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio; (3) Utah State University for a farming and dairy training initiative; (4) the Nueces County, Texas Regional Fairground; and (5) administrative support for a world hunger organization. Stipulates that none of the funds may be used for a monetary award to an individual. (Sec. 791) Appropriates funds to establish a demonstration relending program for housing construction and rehabilitation for the Mississippi Band of Choctaw Indians. (States that the loan rate shall be 1%.) (Sec. 792) Amends the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 to extend country of origin labeling provisions for a covered commodity through September 30, 2008. (Sec. 793) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used for the 2007 reinsurance year to implement specified provider-initiated federal crop insurance premium reductions. (Sec. 794) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used to inspect horses under the Meat Inspection Act or under certain Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 guidelines. (Sec. 795) Prohibits, with specified exceptions, funds made available by this Act from being used to: (1) grant a waiver of a financial conflict of interest requirement under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act for any voting member of an FDA advisory committee or panel; or (2) make a certification that the need for an individual's services outweighs the potential for a conflict of interest for any such voting member. Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used to make a new appointment to an FDA advisory committee or panel unless the Commissioner of Food and Drugs reports to the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services respecting efforts made to identify appointees with minimal or no potential conflicts of interest. (Sec. 796) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to exempt from specified provisions providing criminal penalties for bringing in and harboring certain aliens a bona fide nonprofit, religious organization in the United States (or its agents or officers) that encourages, invites, calls, allows, or enables an alien who is present in the United States to serve as a volunteer minister or missionary for such organization in the United States, provided the minister or missionary has been a member of the denomination for at least one year. (Specifies that such exemption shall not permit the organization to encourage or induce an alien to come to, or enter, the United States.) (Sec. 797) Amends the Organic Foods Production Act of 1990 to: (1) authorize the Secretary to develop emergency procedures for designating agricultural products that are commercially unavailable in organic form for placement on the National List (approved and prohibited substances for organic production and handling standards) for up to 12 months; and (2) permit milk or dairy products to be labeled as organically produced if crops and forage from land included in the organic system plan of a dairy farm that is in the third year of organic management are consumed by the dairy animals during the 12- month period immediately prior to such products' sale. (Sec. 798) Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act to replace references to "cattle, sheep, swine, goats, horses, mules, and other equines'' with a reference to "amenable species." Defines "amenable species" as: (1) those species subject to the provisions of this Act on the day before the date of the enactment of the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006; and (2) any additional livestock species that the Secretary considers appropriate. (Sec. 799) Amends the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006 to: (1) eliminate the "available until expenditure" reference respecting appropriations for the National Park Service-construction; (2) permit the Blue Ridge Parkway Regional Destination Visitor Center to use procurements for the full scope of the facility; (3) reduce appropriations for the National Park Service-land acquisition and state assistance; (4) reduce appropriations for the Department of the Interior salaries; (5) obligate funds under the Environmental Protection Agency-state and tribal assistance grants for the Haleyville, Alabama, North Industrial Area Water Storage Tank project; (6) under the Environmental Protection Agency-state and tribal assistance heading of the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002, reduce funds for Florence, Montana, obligate funds for Sheridan, Montana, for water system improvements, obligate funds for Bozeman, Montana, for the Hyalite Waterline and Intake, and obligate funds for Meagher County/Martinsdale Water and Sewer District, Montana, for Martinsdale water system improvements; and (7) amend the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005 to redesignate the "Gaylord A. Nelson National Wilderness" as the "Gaylord A. Nelson Wilderness."</summary>
</bill>
