<bill session="111" type="hr" number="28" updated="2013-07-19T22:56:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-03T12:08:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-03T12:08:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Transportation Security Administration should, in accordance with the congressional mandate provided for in the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007, enhance security against terrorist attack and other security threats to our Nation's rail and mass transit lines.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Transportation Security Administration should, in accordance with the congressional mandate provided for in the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 as well as other statutes, enhance security against terrorist attack and other security threats to our Nation's rail and mass transit systems and other modes of surface transportation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-11-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-12-01T18:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 111-347.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-12-01T18:41:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="135">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 135.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T13:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Jackson-Lee moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T13:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13413-13415" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T13:23:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 28.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T13:31:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03T12:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13481-13482" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-12-03T12:08:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="926" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 417 - 3 (Roll no. 926).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/2/2009 H13413-13414" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03T12:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03T12:15:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2009--Passed House amended.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) should: (1) continue to enhance security against terrorist attack and other security threats to our nation's rail and mass transit systems and other modes of surface transportation; (2) continue development of the National Explosives Detection Canine Team Program; and (3) improve upon the success of the Online Learning Center by providing increased person-to-person professional development programs for persons responsible for securing our surface transportation systems against such attacks.</summary>
</bill>
