<bill session="110" type="h" number="4261" updated="2013-07-19T21:41:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Toys Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide the Consumer Product Safety Commission with greater flexibility in addressing consumer concerns.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Toys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2007--Introduced.
Safe Toys Act - Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act, the Federal Hazardous Substances Act, and the Flammable Fabrics Act to increase civil penalties for various violations under those Acts. Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to expand: (1) the requirement that manufacturers certify conformity to all applicable consumer product safety standards under the Act or under other Acts enforced by the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC); and (2) the authorization of the CPSC to prescribe reasonable testing programs for consumer products subject to standards under the Act or under Acts enforced by the CPSC. (Current law requires certification and allows testing programs under the Act, but makes no reference to other Acts enforced by the CPSC.) Requires the CPSC to maintain on its website a current list of all products with such certificates and allows the CPSC to publish such a list.</summary>
</bill>
