<bill session="112" type="sr" number="575" updated="2013-07-20T02:15:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution commending the 4 American public servants who died in Benghazi, Libya, United States Ambassador to Libya John Christopher Stevens, Sean Smith, Tyrone Woods, and Glen Doherty, for their tireless efforts on behalf of the American people, and condemning the violent attack on the United States consulate in Benghazi.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6629-6630" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sr" number="551"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="sr" number="588"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
Recognizes the dedicated service and commitment of Ambassador John Christopher Stevens, Sean Smith, Tyrone Woods, and Glen Doherty in assisting the Libyan people as they navigate the complex currents of democratic transition marked in this case by profound instability. Praises Ambassador Stevens, who represented the highest tradition of American public service, for his extraordinary record of dedication to the interests of he Unites States in some of the most difficult and dangerous posts around the globe. Sends the Senate's condolences to the families of those American public servants killed in Benghazi. Commends the bravery of Foreign Service Officers, U.S. Armed Forces, and public servants serving in harm's way around the globe and recognizes the deep sacrifices made by their families. Condemns the despicable attacks on American diplomats and public servants in Benghazi and calls for the perpetrators to be brought to justice.</summary>
</bill>
