<bill session="110" type="s" number="3713" updated="2013-07-19T22:54:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Captain James A. Lovell Federal Health Care Center of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the integration of the Captain James A. Lovell Federal Health Care Center and the Great Lakes Naval Health Clinic, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2008-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-11-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10746-10747" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Navy"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2008--Introduced.
Captain James A. Lovell Federal Health Care Center Act of 2008 - Authorizes the Secretary of Defense (Secretary), upon the conclusion of a resource-sharing agreement between the Secretary and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, to transfer to the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) the Navy ambulatory care center, parking structure, supporting facilities, and related medical personal property and equipment in Great Lakes, Illinois. Designates such facility and supporting facilities as the Captain James A. Lovell Federal Health Care Center (Center). Provides a reversionary interest to the Secretary if the property is not used in accordance with the resource-sharing agreement or in the event of lack of facilities integration. Authorizes the Secretary to transfer to the VA functions necessary for Center operation. Extends through FY2020 a joint Department of Defense (DOD)-VA program to identify, implement, and evaluate creative health care coordination and sharing initiatives at the facility, intraregional, and nationwide levels. Deems the Center a military facility for purposes of the eligibility of members of the Armed Forces to receive care and services there.</summary>
</bill>
