<bill session="113" type="h" number="3319" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equal Healthcare Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modernize the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412400" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400626" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412572" joined="2013-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/2013--Introduced.
Equal Healthcare Access Act - Requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to administer a health insurance program for non-federal employees under the existing Federal Employees Health Benefits (FEHB) Program. Extends eligibility for such program to any qualified individual (i.e., any individual other than an individual who is enrolled or eligible to be enrolled in FEHB, including as a family member). Authorizes employers, under arrangements satisfactory to OPM, to: (1) offer their employees coverage under such program, and (2) make a contribution toward the cost of such coverage. Deems a health care plan under such program to be a plan offered through an Exchange established under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act for purposes of complying with the individual mandate to purchase health insurance.</summary>
</bill>
