<bill session="110" type="s" number="3613" updated="2013-07-19T22:53:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Independence at Home Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide certain high cost Medicare beneficiaries suffering from multiple chronic conditions with access to Independence at Home services in lower cost treatment settings, such as their residences, under a plan of care developed by an Independence at Home physician or Independence at Home nurse practitioner.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9676"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9676-9680" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="7114"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2008--Introduced.
Independence at Home Act of 2008 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to establish a voluntary Independence at Home chronic care coordination demonstration project under the Medicare fee-for-service program for high-cost Medicare beneficiaries with multiple chronic conditions. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into agreements with at least two unaffiliated Independence at Home organizations to provide chronic care coordination services for a period of three years in: (1) each of the 13 highest cost states and the District of Columbia; and (2) 13 additional states representative of other regions of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
