<bill session="111" type="h" number="730" updated="2013-07-19T23:18:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-16">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Forensics and Attribution Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Nuclear Forensics and Attribution Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Nuclear Forensics and Attribution Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Nuclear Forensics and Attribution Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Nuclear Forensics and Attribution Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen efforts in the Department of Homeland Security to develop nuclear forensics capabilities to permit attribution of the source of nuclear material, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2009-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2009-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-27">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-27">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Carney moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3765-3769" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 730.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24T13:08:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3772-3773" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-03-24T14:02:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="148" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 402 - 16 (Roll no. 148).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3765-3766" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-12-17">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-12-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="244">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 244.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2009-12-23" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13886-13887" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="S13886-13887" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-12-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-20T13:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Clarke moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H226-229" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-20T13:46:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 730.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-20T14:00:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21T12:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H300-301" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-01-21T13:06:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="16" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 397 - 10 (Roll no. 16).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 1/20/2010 H226-227" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21T13:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-02-04">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-02-16">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-02-16" type="public" number="111-140">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-140.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM08" subcommittee="Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2010--Public Law.
Nuclear Forensics and Attribution Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should: (1) pursue bilateral and multilateral international agreements to establish an international framework for determining the source of any confiscated nuclear or radiological material or weapon, as well as the source of any detonated weapon and the nuclear or radiological material used in such a weapon; (2) develop protocols for the data exchange and dissemination of sensitive information relating to nuclear or radiological materials and samples of controlled nuclear or radiological materials to the extent required by such agreements; and (3) develop expedited protocols for the data exchange and dissemination of sensitive information needed to publicly identify the source of a nuclear detonation. Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to include within the mission of the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office to: (1) lead the development and implementation of the national strategic five-year plan for improving U.S. nuclear forensic and attribution capabilities required under the National Defense Authorization Act for FY2010; (2) establish within the Office a National Technical Nuclear Forensics Center to provide centralized stewardship, planning, assessment, gap analysis, exercises, improvement, and integration for all federal nuclear forensics and attribution activities; (3) establish a National Nuclear Forensics Expertise Development Program that is devoted to developing and maintaining a vibrant and enduring academic pathway from undergraduate to post-doctorate study in nuclear and geochemical science specialties directly relevant to technical nuclear forensics and that shall provide undergraduate and doctoral student scholarships and awards to ensure that faculty and their graduate students have a sustained funding stream; and (4) report to Congress annually on such activities. Requires the Director of the Office and each of the relevant departments that are partners in the Center to: (1) include, as part of required assessments, evaluations, and reviews, each office's or department's activities and investments in support of nuclear forensics and attribution activities and specific goals and objectives accomplished during the previous year pursuant to the national strategic five-year plan for improving U.S. nuclear forensic and attribution capabilities; (2) attach, as an appendix to the Joint Interagency Annual Review, the most current version of such strategy and plan; and (3) include a description of new or amended bilateral and multilateral agreements and efforts in support of nuclear forensics and attribution activities accomplished during the previous year.</summary>
</bill>
