<bill session="113" type="sj" number="11" updated="2013-11-02T06:49:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to restore the rights of the American people that were taken away by the Supreme Court's decision in the Citizens United case and related decisions, to protect the integrity of our elections, and to limit the corrosive influence of money in our democratic process.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="hj" number="34"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="525"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2013--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Declares that, whereas the right to vote in public elections belongs only to natural persons as U.S. citizens, so shall the ability to make contributions and expenditures to influence the outcome of public elections belong only to natural persons. Declares that nothing in this Constitution shall be construed to restrict the power of Congress and the states to protect the integrity and fairness of the electoral process, limit the corrupting influence of private wealth in public elections, and guarantee the dependence of elected officials on the people alone by taking certainactions. Includes among such actions: (1) the establishment of systems of public financing for elections; (2) the imposition of requirements to ensure the disclosure of contributions and expenditures made to influence the outcome of a public election by candidates, individuals, and associations of individuals; and (3) the imposition of content neutral limitations on all such contributions and expenditures. Declares that nothing in this Article shall be construed to alter freedom of the press. Grants Congress and the states power to enforce this Amendment through appropriate legislation.</summary>
</bill>
