<bill session="112" type="s" number="1444" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Civilian Service Recognition Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the presentation of a United States flag on behalf of Federal civilian employees who are killed while performing official duties or because of their status as Federal employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2011-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5022-5023"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5023" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2061"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="National symbols"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2011--Introduced.
Civilian Service Recognition Act of 2011 - Requires the head of an executive agency to: (1) pay the cost of presenting a U.S. flag for an individual who was an agency employee and died of injuries incurred while serving as a federal employee,&#160;(2) furnish such flag upon the request of the employee's next of kin or any other individual as determined by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), and (3) provide notice to agency employees of the flag benefit provided by this Act.&#160; Allows an exemption from the requirements of this Act if an agency head determines that fulfilling such requirements would endanger U.S. national security or require the disclosure of classified information, or that the employee is not entitled to death benefits due to willful misconduct.</summary>
</bill>
