<bill session="113" type="h" number="746" updated="2013-11-02T06:25:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Small Business Jobs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide small businesses with a grace period for a regulatory violation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412547"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412476" joined="2013-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412422" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412551" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412515" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2013-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2013--Introduced.
Protect Small Business Jobs Act of 2013 - Requires a federal agency, before any enforcement action is taken on any sanction on a small business for any violation of a rule or pursuant to an adjudication, to: (1) notify the small business that it may be subject to a sanction at the end of a six-month grace period following such notification; (2) delay further action for 15 days after such notification; (3) defer further action for the six-month period (allowing an additional three-month period upon application by the small business demonstrating reasonable good-faith efforts to remedy the violation or other conduct giving rise to the sanction); (4) make a further determination at the end of the applicable grace period as to whether the small business would still be subject to the sanction; and (5) upon a negative determination, waive the sanction. Makes the grace period inapplicable with respect to a violation that puts anyone in imminent danger, as defined by the Occupational Safety and Health Act. Makes null and void any sanction imposed in violation of such requirements. Requires: (1) federal agencies to report annually to the Small Business and Agriculture Regulatory Enforcement Ombudsman on the utilization of this directive and to disclose the penalty mitigation for small businesses, and (2) the Ombudsman to include such information in a currently-required annual report to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
