<bill session="109" type="h" number="2795" updated="2013-07-19T19:28:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patent Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 35, United States Code, relating to the procurement, enforcement, and validity of patents.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2005-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Hearings Held on Issue by Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property. The Amendment in the Nature of a Substitute to H.R. 2795.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3818"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Inventions"/>
    <term name="Inventors"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Patent infringement"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2005--Introduced.
Patent Reform Act of 2005 - Revises conditions under which a patent may be obtained for an invention, including by: (1) providing for joint research agreements; (2) giving patent priority to the first filed patent application (currently, priority is given to the first invention); and (3) amending provisions related to patents internationally. Gives an inventor a right to apply for and obtain a patent, subject to conditions and regulations. (Current law allows inventors to obtain a patent.) Requires the Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) to: (1) impose a duty of candor and good faith on individuals associated with the filing and prosecution of an application and on individuals who are parties adverse to a patent or application for patent in contested cases before USPTO; and (2) establish a special office to investigation violations of such duty. Revises provisions regarding treble damages for willful infringement of a patent. Allows the Director to limit the ability of patent applicants to get the benefit of the filing date of a prior-filed application. Expands the publication of patent applications. Revises provisions regarding the infringement defense based on prior use of the subject matter of a patent before the effective filing dates. Sets forth procedures and requirements for opposing a patent grant. Allows third parties to submit relevant information for inclusion in the record of a patent application.</summary>
</bill>
