<bill session="109" type="s" number="2322" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-12-06">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Assurance of Radiologic Excellence Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Consumer Assurance of Radiologic Excellence Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Consumer Assurance of Radiologic Excellence Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to make the provision of technical services for medical imaging examinations and radiation therapy treatments safer, more accurate, and less costly.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2006-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2006-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2006-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2006-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="2006-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2006-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2006-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2006-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2006-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2006-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300069" joined="2006-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2006-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1462-1463"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1463-1464" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-09-20">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-12-05">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Enzi with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-363.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-12-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="668">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 668.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-12-06" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/7/2006 S11389-11391" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 12/7/2006 S11389-11391" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-12-07T14:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Education)"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Imaging systems in medicine"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Radiotherapy"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="X-rays"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/6/2006--Passed Senate amended.
Consumer Assurance of Radiologic Excellence Act of 2006 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish standards to ensure the safety and accuracy of medical imaging studies and radiation therapy treatments. Imposes such standards on personnel who perform, plan, or evaluate, or verify patient doses for, medical imaging studies and radiation therapy procedures and not on the equipment used. Exempts physicians, nurse practitioners, and physician assistants. Directs the Secretary to ensure that individuals demonstrate compliance through successful completion of certification by a professional organization, licensure, completion of an examination, pertinent coursework or degree program, or verified pertinent experience. Allows the standards to: (1) vary from discipline to discipline, represent expert consensus as to what constitutes excellence in practice, and be appropriate to the particular scope of care involved; (2) vary in form for each of the covered disciplines; and (3) exempt individual providers from meeting certain standards based on their scope of practice. Requires the Secretary to provide a method for the recognition of individuals whose training and experience are determined to equal or exceed that of: (1) a graduate of an accredited educational program in that specialty; or (2) an individual who is regularly eligible to take the licensure or certification examination for that discipline. Directs the Secretary to certify bodies for accreditation of various mechanisms by which an individual can demonstrate compliance with the standards. Requires the Secretary to establish minimum standards for certification, including assurances that the body will: (1) be a nonprofit organization; (2) comply with the established standards; and (3) notify the Secretary in a timely manner if it fails to comply. Allows the Secretary to withdraw certification upon determining the body does not meet the required standards. Deems state standards for licensure or certification of personnel, accreditation of educational programs, or administration of examinations to be in compliance with standards under this Act unless the Secretary determines they do not meet minimum standards or are inconsistent with this Act. Requires the Secretary to establish an appeal process. Requires the Secretary to: (1) evaluate the performance of each approved body; (2) ensure that programs that involve the performance of or payment for medical imaging or radiation therapy meet such standards; and (3) determine whether such standards must be met in their entirety in rural areas. Authorizes the Secretary to develop alternative standards for rural areas or health professional shortage areas to assure access to quality medical imaging. Sets forth a timeline for the implementation of the standards under this Act. (Sec. 4) Sets forth reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
