<bill session="113" type="h" number="323" updated="2013-11-02T06:21:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Muscogee Nation of Florida Federal Recognition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend Federal recognition to the Muscogee Nation of Florida.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400279"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/18/2013--Introduced.
Muscogee Nation of Florida Federal Recognition Act - Extends federal recognition to the Muscogee Nation of Florida (the Nation), which makes its members eligible for the services and benefits provided to Indians due to their status as members of a federally recognized tribe. Considers the service area of the Nation, for the purpose of delivering federal services to members, to be: (1) the community of Bruce in Walton County, Florida; and (2) an area in Florida in which members reside that is bordered on the west by the Escambia River and on the east by the St. Marks River. Requires that the constitution and bylaws of the Nation be the constitution and bylaws of the Nation's Tribal Council dated January 21, 2001 (including amendments). Instructs the Secretary of the Interior, upon receipt of a written request of the Tribal Council, to hold a referendum for members to adopt a new constitution and bylaws. Specifies the role and duties of the Tribal Council. Requires that the membership roll of the Nation be determined in accordance with the membership criteria established by the ordinance of the Nation numbered 04-01-100 and dated February 7, 2004. Authorizes the Secretary to take land into trust on behalf of the Nation.</summary>
</bill>
