<bill session="112" type="s" number="762" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Acquisition Institute Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Federal Acquisition Institute Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the Federal Acquisition Institute.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2011-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2011-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2270-2271"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2272-2273" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman without amendment. With written report No. 112-21.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-06-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="73">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 73.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1424"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2011--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Federal Acquisition Institute Improvement Act of 2011 - Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 to provide that the Associate Administrator for Acquisition Workforce Programs shall: (1) be chosen on the basis of demonstrated knowledge and expertise in acquisition, human capital, and management; (2) be located in the Office of Federal Procurement Policy; and (3) implement acquisition workforce programs. Establishes a Federal Acquisition Institute (FAI) and enumerates its purposes with respect to the development of a professional acquisition workforce. Requires: (1) the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy to recommend to the Administrator of General Services (GSA) sufficient budget resources and authority for the FAI to support government-wide training standards and certification requirements necessary to enhance the mobility and career opportunities of the federal acquisition workforce, and (2) the GSA Administrator to provide FAI with amounts from the acquisition training fund sufficient to meet the annual budget for FAI requested by the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy. Directs: (1) the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, acting through FAI, to provide and update government-wide training standards and certification requirements; and (2) all federal civilian agency acquisition internship or acquisition training programs to follow guidelines provided by the Office of Federal Procurement Policy to ensure consistent training standards necessary to develop uniform core competencies throughout the federal government. Directs the GSA Administrator to manage the acquisition workforce training fund through FAI to support FAI activities and to ensure that funds collected are only used for such purposes.</summary>
</bill>
