<bill session="113" type="s" number="330" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-17">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HIV Organ Policy Equity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">HIV Organ Policy Equity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">HIV Organ Policy Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish safeguards and standards of quality for research and transplantation of organs infected with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2013-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2013-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2013-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-03-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-21">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Harkin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="75">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 75.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4533-4534" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4533-4534" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-17">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2013-06-17" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4534" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18T12:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="698"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="698"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1315"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/17/2013--Passed Senate amended.
HIV Organ Policy Equity Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to repeal the requirement that the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network adopt and use standards of quality for the acquisition and transportation of donated organs that include standards for preventing the acquisition of organs infected with the etiologic agent for acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS). Replaces this requirement with authorization for the Network to adopt and use such standards with respect to organs infected with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), provided that any such standards ensure that organs infected with HIV may be transplanted only into individuals who are: (1) infected with such virus before receiving such an organ; and (2) participating in clinical research approved by an institutional review board under the criteria, standards, and regulations regarding organs infected with HIV developed under this Act or, if participation in such research is no longer warranted, receiving a transplant under such standards and regulations. Revises similarly the requirement that organ procurement organizations arrange for testing to prevent the acquisition of organs infected with the AIDS etiologic agent to require that they arrange for testing to identify organs infected with HIV. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop and publish guidelines for the conduct of research relating to transplantation of organs from HIV-infected donors. Requires the Network to revise its standards of quality regarding HIV-infected organs and the Secretary to revise related regulations. Requires the Secretary to: (1) review annually the results of scientific research in conjunction with the Network to determine whether they warrant revision of quality standards relating to donated HIV-infected organs and to the safety of transplantation of organs with a particular strain of HIV into a recipient with a different strain; and (2) direct the Network, if the review so warrants, to revise its standards in a way that ensures the changes will not reduce the safety of organ transplantation. Amends the federal criminal code to declare that an organ donation does not violate the prohibition against a knowing organ donation by an HIV-infected individual if the donation is made in accordance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
