<bill session="111" type="s" number="2960" updated="2013-07-20T00:52:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Refugee Opportunity Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Refugee Opportunity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to exempt aliens who are admitted as refugees or granted asylum and are employed overseas by the Federal Government from the 1-year physical presence requirement for adjustment of status to that of aliens lawfully admitted for permanent residence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2010-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2010-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S342"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-26">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="337">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 337.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Refugee Opportunity Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize the waiver of the continuous one-year presence requirement for permanent resident status adjustment for a refugee/asylee who: (1) is or was employed by the U.S. government or a U.S. government contractor overseas and worked on behalf of the U.S. government for the entire period of absence, which may not exceed one year; or (2) is or was employed by the U.S. government or a U.S. government contractor in the alien's country of nationality or last habitual residence for the entire period of absence, which may not exceed one year, and was under U.S. government or contractor protection while working on behalf of the U.S. government during the entire period of employment; and (3) returns immediately to the United States upon such employment's conclusion.</summary>
</bill>
