<bill session="111" type="s" number="1067" updated="2013-07-20T00:33:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-24">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lord's Resistance Army Disarmament and Northern Uganda Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Lord's Resistance Army Disarmament and Northern Uganda Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Lord's Resistance Army Disarmament and Northern Uganda Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Lord's Resistance Army Disarmament and Northern Uganda Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Lord's Resistance Army Disarmament and Northern Uganda Recovery Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to support stabilization and lasting peace in northern Uganda and areas affected by the Lord's Resistance Army through development of a regional strategy to support multilateral efforts to successfully protect civilians and eliminate the threat posed by the Lord's Resistance Army and to authorize funds for humanitarian relief and reconstruction, reconciliation, and transitional justice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2009-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2010-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2009-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2009-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2010-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2010-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2009-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2010-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2009-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2010-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2009-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2009-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2010-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2009-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2009-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2010-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2009-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2009-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2009-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2010-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2009-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-12-11" withdrawn="2009-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5616-5617"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-11-17">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-12-15">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-108.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-12-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="228">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 228.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1409-1412" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1411-1412" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>The committee substitute agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2010-03-10" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1411-1412" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11T10:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Engel moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3409-3416" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1067.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-05-12T19:02:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3409-3411" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-05-12">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-05-17">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-05-24" type="public" number="111-172">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-172.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2478"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Burundi"/>
    <term name="Central African Republic"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Democratic Republic of the Congo"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Rwanda"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Uganda"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3461"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/24/2010--Public Law.
Lord's Resistance Army Disarmament and Northern Uganda Recovery Act of 2009 - (Sec. 4) Directs the President to submit to Congress a regional strategy to guide U.S. support for multilateral efforts to eliminate the threat to civilians and regional stability posed by the Lord's Resistance Army (LRA). Requires the strategy to include: (1) a plan to help strengthen efforts by the United Nations (U.N.) and regional governments to protect civilians from attacks by the LRA; (2) an assessment of viable options through which the United States could help develop and support multilateral efforts to eliminate the threat posed by the LRA; (3) an interagency framework to plan, coordinate, and review diplomatic, economic, intelligence, and military elements of U.S. policy across the region regarding the LRA; (4) a description of the type and form of diplomatic engagement across the region undertaken to coordinate and implement U.S. policy regarding the LRA and to work multilaterally with regional mechanisms, including the Tripartite Plus Commission and the Great Lakes Pact; and (5) a description of how this engagement will fit within the context of broader efforts and policy objectives in the Great Lakes Region. (Sec. 5) Authorizes the President to provide additional assistance to respond to the humanitarian needs of populations the Democratic Republic of Congo, southern Sudan, and Central African Republic affected by LRA activity. (Sec. 6) Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should support efforts by the people of northern Uganda and the government of Uganda to: (1) assist internally displaced people in transition and returnees by spurring economic revitalization and advancing access to basic services at return sites; (2) enhance the accountability and administrative competency of local governance institutions and public agencies in northern Uganda; (3) strengthen the operational capacity of the civilian police and the justice system in northern Uganda; (4) establish mechanisms for the disarmament and reintegration of former combatants and those abducted by the LRA; and (5) promote programs to address psychosocial trauma. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) should work with Congress to increase future assistance to Uganda if the government of Uganda demonstrates a commitment to reconstruction in war-affected areas of northern Uganda; and (2) the Secretary should withhold non-humanitarian assistance to Uganda if the government of Uganda is not committed to reconstruction and reconciliation in the war-affected areas of northern Uganda and is not taking steps to ensure this process moves forward in a transparent and accountable manner. (Sec. 7) Expresses the sense of Congress that a continued failure to take meaningful steps toward national reconciliation and accountability risks perpetuating political grievances and fueling new conflicts. Authorizes the President to support efforts by the people of northern Uganda and the government of Uganda to promote transitional justice and reconciliation on both local and national levels, including to encourage implementation of the mechanisms in the Annexure to the Agreement on Accountability and Reconciliation between the government of Uganda and the LRA. (Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on implementation of the strategy and evaluation of the assistance under this Act. (Sec. 9) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) of the total amounts to be appropriated for FY2011 for the Department of State and foreign operations, up to $10 million should be used to carry out activities under section 5; and (2) of the total amounts to be appropriated for FY2011-FY2013 for the Department of State and foreign operations, up to $10 million in each such fiscal year should be used to carry out activities under section 7. (Sec. 10) Defines: (1) "Great Lakes Region" as the region comprising Burundi, Democratic Republic of Congo, Rwanda, southern Sudan, and Uganda; and (2) "LRA-affected areas" as those portions of northern Uganda, southern Sudan, northeastern Democratic Republic of Congo, and southeastern Central African Republic affected by the LRA.</summary>
</bill>
