<bill session="113" type="h" number="2648" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the sale or other disposition of a firearm to, and the possession, shipment, transportation, or receipt of a firearm by, certain classes of high-risk individuals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5053"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to prohibit the sale or other disposition of a firearm or ammunition to any person knowing or having reasonable cause to believe that such person: (1) has been convicted of a crime of violence in the previous 10 years; (2) is under age 25 and has been adjudicated as having committed an offense that would have been a crime of violence if committed by an adult; (3) has been convicted on 2 separate occasions in any period of 3 consecutive years in the last 10 of an offense that has the possession or distribution of alcohol or a controlled substance as an element; or (4) has been convicted of stalking. Prohibits any such person from: (1) shipping or transporting in interstate or foreign commerce, or possessing in or affecting commerce, any firearm or ammunition; or (2) receiving any firearm or ammunition which has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce.</summary>
</bill>
