<bill session="112" type="h" number="556" updated="2013-07-20T01:15:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preserving Patients' Choices Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal certain provisions in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act related to patient centered outcomes research and rescind unobligated appropriations related to such provisions and to repeal certain health care-related provisions in the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 and rescind unobligated appropriations related to such provisions for purposes of reducing the national debt.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400260"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2012-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2011-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Appropriations, Ways and Means, Science, Space, and Technology, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2011--Introduced.
Preserving Patients' Choices Act - Repeals provisions of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act providing for the establishment and funding of the Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Institute to identify priorities for, and establish, update, and carry out, a national comparative outcomes research project agenda. Restores provisions of law as if such provisions had not been enacted. Rescinds the unobligated balance of funds made available for such Institute. Repeals the health information technology provisions of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (ARRA). Restores provisions of law as if such provisions had not been enacted. Rescinds all unobligated balances remaining available for the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology. Requires the total amount rescinded by this Act to be deposited in the Treasury to pay down the national debt.</summary>
</bill>
