<bill session="110" type="h" number="4232" updated="2013-07-19T21:40:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving the Quality of Mental and Substance Use Health Care Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve mental and substance use health care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2007-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2007--Introduced.
Improving the Quality of Mental and Substance Use Health Care Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) establish a Commission for Evidence-Based Mental and Substance Use Health Care; (2) convene an interagency collaborative group to provide for the coordination of mental health and substance use services and primary care services funded through the Departments of Health and Human Services (HHS), Justice, Veterans Affairs, Defense, and Education; (3) implement a plan for ensuring that HHS activities to promote information technology use by health care providers include promotion of technology that is accessible and pertinent to mental health and substance use health care providers and consumers; (4) establish the Council on Mental Health and Substance Use Health Care Workforce; (5) develop uniform methodologies regarding qualifications for eligibility for payment, financial auditing, and claims payment with respect to medical assistance, related services, and administrative costs furnished to individuals with mental illnesses and substance use disorders in community-based and residential settings; and (6) establish a five-year project designed to demonstrate the impact of creating delivery and financing structures that deliver high-quality, integrated mental health and substance use health care.Requires: (1) the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to make grants to entities to fund a network of national centers of excellence in mental health and substance use health care; and (2) the Comptroller General to study the use of publicly supported mental health and addiction services by individuals who have any level of private health insurance coverage.Amends the Social Security Act to establish a Medicaid requirement that states receiving assistance prohibit the denial of covered services and benefits based on intoxication.</summary>
</bill>
