<bill session="109" type="h" number="3431" updated="2013-07-19T19:34:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Limitation of Tribal Gambling to Existing Tribal Lands Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act to limit casino expansion.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400648"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400005" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400060" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2006-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400637" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2005-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="State legislatures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2005--Introduced.
Limitation of Tribal Gambling to Existing Tribal Lands Act of 2005 - Amends the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act to limit the Indian land eligible for gaming. Revises the prohibition against gaming on lands acquired by the Secretary of the Interior in trust for the benefit of an Indian tribe after October 17, 1988, by repealing the exception to such prohibition for lands taken into trust as part of: (1) a settlement of a land claim; (2) the initial reservation of an Indian tribe acknowledged by the Secretary under the Federal acknowledgment process; or (3) the restoration of lands for an Indian tribe that is restored to Federal recognition. Requires joint approval by the legislature of a state as well as by its Governor of gaming on other lands otherwise excepted from the prohibition when the Secretary determines that a gaming establishment on newly acquired lands would be in the best interest of the Indian tribe and its members, and would not be detrimental to the surrounding community.</summary>
</bill>
