<bill session="109" type="s" number="2070" updated="2013-07-19T20:31:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mohawk River Hydroelectric Projects Licensing Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide certain requirements for hydroelectric projects on the Mohawk River in the State of New York.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-781.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="4375"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2005--Introduced.
Mohawk River Hydroelectric Projects Licensing Act of 2005 - Prohibits the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) from issuing a new license for a hydroelectric project on the Mohawk River in New York if the project has been operating under annual licenses for 10 or more years, unless FERC: (1) issues a public notice that it will accept other valid license applications to develop the project works or water resource; and (2) approves a license application, according to the requirements of this Act, if other valid license applications are submitted. Sets forth processing and approval procedures. Requires any new power license issued for such project to include the same license conditions relating to the use of affected waters as provided in the license for a specified Potomac Light &amp; Power Company Project.</summary>
</bill>
