<bill session="111" type="h" number="1719" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Voter Registration Modernization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 and the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to promote the use of the Internet by State and local election officials in carrying out voter registration activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400245"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2009-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2009--Introduced.
Voter Registration Modernization Act of 2009 - Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (NVRA) to direct states to ensure the availability of the Internet for online voter registration. Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (HAVA) to direct the appropriate state or local election official to ensure the availability of the Internet for updating voter registration information. Amends NVRA to allow a voter registration applicant to provide his or her email address on the appropriate form to receive voting information. Requires states to consider an applicant to have provided a valid voter registration form if he or she has provided all necessary information to demonstrate eligibility to vote. Allows a state to use a HAVA requirements payment to carry out the new NVRA requirements imposed by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
