<bill session="110" type="s" number="498" updated="2013-07-19T22:24:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Medicare Equity Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve the Medicare program for beneficiaries residing in rural areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2007-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1638-1639"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1639-1640" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare Payment Advisory Commission"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2007--Introduced.
Rural Medicare Equity Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to eliminate the geographic physician work adjustment factor from the geographic indices used to adjust payments under the physician fee schedule. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a demonstration grants project designed to provide financial or other incentives to hospitals to attract educators and clinical practitioners so that hospitals that serve Medicare beneficiaries residing in underserved areas may host clinical rotations. Directs the Secretary to establish up to 10 demonstration projects to provide for improvements, as recommended by the Institute of Medicine, in the quality of health care provided to individuals residing in rural areas. Amends SSA title XVIII to require proportional representation of rural area interests on the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MEDPAC). Directs the Secretary to implement the recommendations contained in the March 2005 GAO report 05-119 entitled "Medicare Physician Fees: Geographic Adjustment Indices are Valid in Design, but Data and Methods Need Refinement."</summary>
</bill>
