<bill session="110" type="h" number="3078" updated="2013-07-19T21:30:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patient Safety and Abuse Prevention Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to require screening, including national criminal history background checks, of direct patient access employees of skilled nursing facilities, nursing facilities, and other long-term care facilities and providers, and to provide for nationwide expansion of the pilot program for national and State background checks on direct patient access employees of long-term care facilities or providers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2007-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-18">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="1577"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Elder abuse"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2007--Introduced.
Patient Safety and Abuse Prevention Act of 2007 - Amends the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 to provide for nationwide expansion of the pilot program for national and state background checks on direct patient access employees of long-term care facilities or providers. Amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to: (1) require screening, including national criminal history background checks, of direct patient access employees of skilled nursing facilities, nursing facilities, and other long-term care facilities and providers; and (2) prohibit hiring of abusive workers. Requires the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to ensure that the Integrated Automated Fingerprint Identification System of the FBI has the capacity to store and retrieve fingerprints from its database. Provides that, in the case where a direct patient access employee is convicted of a crime following the initial national criminal history background check, and the employee's fingerprint matches the prints on file with the FBI, the FBI shall inform the state law enforcement department in order for the state to inform the skilled nursing facility, nursing facility, or long-term care facility or provider of such conviction.</summary>
</bill>
