<bill session="110" type="h" number="6715" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fast Track Shale Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To open Federal Bureau of Land Management and National Forest lands to leasing for exploration, development, and production of oil shale resources, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412216"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2008--Introduced.
Fast Track Shale Act - Repeals the prohibition under the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2008 on the use of funds to: (1) prepare or publish final regulations regarding a commercial leasing program for oil shale (and tar sands) resources on public lands; or (2) conduct an oil shale lease sale pursuant to such Act. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to issue all regulations necessary to implement the Oil Share, Tar Sands, and Other Strategic Unconventional Fuels Act of 2005 with respect to oil shale. Directs the Secretary, immediately after issuing such regulations, to offer for leasing: (1) additional 160-acre tracts of lands the Secretary considers necessary for research and development of oil shale resources; and (2) public lands, for commercial exploration, development, and production of oil shale resources, in states for which the Secretary finds sufficient support and interest.</summary>
</bill>
