<bill session="112" type="h" number="6715" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, to make grants to State and local governments to assist in preparing for and responding to mass casualty incidents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-27">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-27">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Drug and radiation therapy"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/27/2012--Introduced.
Protecting Our Protectors Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), to make grants to state and local governments to assist in preparing for and responding to mass casualty incidents resulting from natural disasters and acts of terrorism and other man-made disasters. Requires the grants to be used to: (1) strengthen medical surge capacity; (2) strengthen mass prophylaxis capabilities, including the development and maintenance of an initial pharmaceutical stockpile sufficient to protect first responders, their families, and immediate victims from a chemical or biological event; and (3) procure home medical kits that are approved pursuant to the Federal Food, Drug, Cosmetic Act or the Public Health Service Act. Requires: (1) the Administrator to issue guidance on anthrax exposure and proper administration of the anthrax vaccine, and (2) the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to issue an annual report on the vaccination levels of emergency service providers.</summary>
</bill>
