<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1487" updated="2013-07-19T23:09:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-30T13:23:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-30T13:23:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400263"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T17:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-516, by Mr. McGovern.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29T17:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution waives clause 6(a) of rule XIII (requiring a two-thirds vote to consider the rule on the same day it is reported from the Rules Committee) against certain resolutions reported from the Rules Committee. The resolution applies the waiver to any resolution reported from the Rules Committee through the legislative day of July 3, 2010.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-06-29T17:26:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="207">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 207.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30T11:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5212-5222" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30T11:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1487.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30T11:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H.Res. 1487.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 243 - 182 (Roll no. 406).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5221" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-06-30T13:23:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="407" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 237 - 189 (Roll no. 407).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5212" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2010--Introduced.
Waives a specified requirement of Rule XIII (Calendar and Committee Reports) to allow consideration or disposition of the following legislation on the same day it is presented to the House: (1) a conference report to accompany H.R. 4173 (Restoring American Financial Stability Act of 2010); and (2) a measure that includes a subject matter addressed by H.R. 4213 (American Jobs and Closing Tax Loopholes Act of 2010) or any amendment pertaining to it. Makes it in order: (1) at any time through the legislative day of July 3, 2010, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules; and (2) without intervention of any point of order to consider concurrent resolutions providing for adjournment during July.</summary>
</bill>
