<bill session="109" type="h" number="5553" updated="2013-07-19T19:53:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Section 115 Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 115 of title 17, United States Code, to provide for licensing of digital delivery of musical works, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2006-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Publishers and publishing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2006--Introduced.
Section 115 Reform Act of 2006 - Sets forth provisions governing compulsory licenses for digital phonorecord deliveries and hybrid offerings that cover the making and distribution of general and incidental digital phonorecord deliveries in the form of full downloads, limited downloads, interactive streams, and any other form constituting a digital phonorecord delivery or hybrid offering. Allows a digital music provider to obtain a compulsory license only from a designated agent. Requires a designated agent to grant a license for the making of server and incidental reproduction to facilitate noninteractive streaming at a royalty-free rate. Excludes from such license any server or incidental reproductions used to enable a streaming service (or any other type of service) that takes affirmative steps to authorize, enable, cause, or induce the making of reproductions of musical works by or for end users for future listening. Allows a digital music provider that receives a license for the making and distribution of limited downloads or interactive streams to report activity and make payments for the activity retroactively beginning January 1, 2001, to avoid being subject to an action for copyright infringement alleging violation of reproduction or distribution rights. Sets forth procedures for the setting of royalty rates and terms. Requires the Register of Copyrights to designate a General Designated Agent to grant and administer licenses and collect and distribute royalties payable for the use of musical works licensed under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
