<bill session="112" type="h" number="1213" updated="2013-07-20T01:20:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-03T18:21:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-05-03T18:21:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal mandatory funding provided to States in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to establish American Health Benefit Exchanges.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400414"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2011-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2011-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-27T18:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 112-65.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-04-27T18:34:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="33">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 33.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-05-02T19:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 236 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1213 and H.R. 1214 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against provisions in the bills are waived. In the case of H.R. 1214, the resolution makes in order only those amendments that are received for printing in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII in a daily issue dated May 2, 2011, and pro forma amendments for the purpose of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T13:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 236.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2952-2969" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2961" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T13:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1213 and H.R. 1214 with 1 hour of general debate for each bill. In both cases, the previous question shall be considered as ordered except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The measures will be considered read. In the case of H.R. 1213, specified amendments are in order. In the case of H.R. 1214, the resolution makes in order only those amendments that are received for printing in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII in a daily issue dated May 2, 2011, and pro forma amendments for the purpose of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 236 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steven C. LaTourette to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1213.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 236, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment no. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Jackson Lee (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 236, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waters amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Waters amendment no. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Waters demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 236, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ellison amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ellison amendment no. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Ellison demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 236, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pallone amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 236, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Welch (VT) substitute amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Burgess moved that the Committee now rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:54:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1213 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2977-2982" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T17:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1213.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T17:46:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2980" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T17:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Boswell moved to recommit with instructions to Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2980-2981" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2980" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T17:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment inserting a provision that would require health insurance issuers to disclose the extent to which coverage has been denied or premiums have been increased for an individual. A point of order was reserved, but was subsequently withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T18:14:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 190 - 233 (Roll no. 284).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-05-03T18:21:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="285" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 238 - 183 (Roll no. 285).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T18:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-05-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="39">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 39.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h260"/>
    <amendment number="h261"/>
    <amendment number="h262"/>
    <amendment number="h263"/>
    <amendment number="h264"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/3/2011--Passed House without amendment.
Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to repeal provisions appropriating funds to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to states for activities (including planning activities) related to establishing an American Health Benefit Exchange (a state health insurance exchange). Rescinds any unobligated funds made available under such provisions.</summary>
</bill>
