<bill session="109" type="hr" number="126" updated="2013-07-19T18:55:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-02T15:41:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-03-02T15:41:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 27) to enhance the workforce investment system of the Nation by strengthening one-stop career centers, providing for more effective governance arrangements, promoting access to a more comprehensive array of employment, training, and related services, establishing a targeted approach to serving youth, and improving performance accountability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-01T20:08:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 109-11, by Mr. Bishop (UT).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-01T20:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 27 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-03-01T20:13:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="8">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 8.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02T14:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H859-866" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02T14:05:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 126.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02T14:55:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02T14:56:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED ROLL CALL VOTE - At conclusion of debate on H. Res. 126 the Chair put the question of agreeing to the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hastings (FL) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02T15:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H866-867" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-03-02T15:41:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="42" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 191 (Roll no. 42).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H859" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02T15:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="109" type="h" number="27"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2005--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 27) to enhance the workforce investment system of the Nation by strengthening one-stop career centers, providing for more effective governance arrangements, promoting access to a more comprehensive array of employment, training, and related services, establishing a targeted approach to serving youth, and improving performance accountability.</summary>
</bill>
