<bill session="113" type="s" number="901" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Witness Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect State and local witnesses from tampering and retaliation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2013--Introduced.
State Witness Protection Act of 2013 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose criminal penalties on any person who kills, or attempts to kill, a witness in a state or local judicial proceeding, who uses physical force or the threat of force against such a witness, or who offers such witness anything of value with the intent to: (1) influence, delay, or prevent the testimony or attendance of such witness at a state or local judicial proceeding; (2) prevent the production of a record or document in a state or local judicial proceeding; (3) cause or induce any person to withhold testimony or evidence, destroy evidence, evade legal process, or be absent from a state or local judicial proceeding; (4) hinder, delay, or prevent any person from providing information to a state or local law enforcement officer or judge; or (5) retaliate against any person for attending a state or local judicial proceeding or providing information to a law enforcement officer. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to amend guidelines to increase the sentencing range for obstruction of justice if such crime involved threatening, harming, or bribing a witness or the destruction of evidence. Directs the Attorney General to make competitive grants to eligible state, tribal, and local governments to establish or maintain programs that provide: (1) protection or assistance to witnesses in court proceedings involving homicide, a serious violent felony or drug offense, gangs, or organized crime; and (2) information and outreach to the public about witness intimidation. Sets forth criteria by which the Attorney General shall evaluate applicants, including the extent to which: (1) an applicant has a lack of infrastructure to support a witness assistance program, and (2) witness intimidation is present with respect to the applicant.</summary>
</bill>
