<bill session="110" type="sr" number="564" updated="2013-07-19T22:17:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding oversight of the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2008-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2008-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-05-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4185-4186"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4184-4185" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2008--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) it is critical that more progress be made by the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN) in transparency, accountability, and security; (2) the private sector's success in Internet development is unparalleled and industry self-regulation must be assured through more effective ICANN contract compliance efforts; (3) WHOIS databases provide a vital tool for businesses, the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), and other law enforcement agencies to track down brand infringement, online fraud, identity theft, and other online illegal activity, as well as for consumers to determine the availability of domain names and communicate with online businesses; (4) increased international private sector participation in various ICANN processes should be encouraged; (5) the United States and other countries should continue to allow the marketplace to work and private industries to lead in Domain Name and Addressing System (DNS) management and coordination; (6) the performance of the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA) functions contract, including updates of the root zone file, should remain physically located in the United States and the Secretary of Commerce should maintain contract oversight; and (7) ICANN should continue to manage the day-to-day operation of the DNS.</summary>
</bill>
