<bill session="109" type="h" number="4845" updated="2013-07-19T19:47:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Innovation and Competitiveness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Business Activity Tax Simplification Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Health Care Choice Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Health Information Technology Promotion Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Investment in America Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Lawsuit Abuse Reduction Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To better prepare and develop the United States workforce for the global economy, and remove barriers that stifle innovation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="2006-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400328" joined="2006-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2006-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400393" joined="2006-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="2006-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E261-262"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Science, Education and the Workforce, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5502"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contempt of court"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Industrial research"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Life sciences"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Practice of law"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2006--Introduced.
Innovation and Competitiveness Act - Business Activity Tax Simplification Act of 2006 - Amends federal law concerning the power of a state to impose a net income tax on income derived from interstate commerce to extend the exemption from such tax with respect to solicitations for, and sales of, tangible personal property shipped from outside the state to all other forms of property, services, and other transactions fulfilled from a point outside the state. Makes such net income tax prohibitions applicable to other business activity taxes specified by this Act. Prohibits imposing a net income tax or other business activity tax on a person's activities in interstate commerce unless such person has a physical presence in the state during the taxable period with respect to which the tax is imposed. Lawsuit Abuse Reduction Act of 2006- Amends Rule 11 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure (Signing of Pleadings, Motions, and Other Papers; Representations to Court; Sanctions) with respect to mandatory court sanctions for frivolous lawsuits and award of attorney's fees to parties prevailing on Rule 11 motions. Applies Rule 11 to state civil actions that substantially affect interstate commerce. Requires personal injury claims filed in state or federal court to be filed in the county or federal district meeting specified requirements. Requires a federal district court to suspend from the practice of law for one year (or longer, at the court's discretion) an attorney found to have violated Rule 11 three or more times. Establishes a rebuttable presumption that an attempt to litigate a claim or defense involving the same plaintiff and defendant that has been litigated and lost on three consecutive prior occasions is a Rule 11 violation. Imposes additional sanctions for the willful and intentional destruction of documents highly relevant to a federal court proceeding. Requires public disclosure of the record of a Rule 11 proceeding, except in specified circumstances. Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to replace the Robert C. Byrd Honors Scholarship program with an Innovation Scholarship program. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to: (1) award funds to a private nonprofit organization to administer, through a public-private partnership, a Mathematics and Science Honors Scholarships program for postsecondary and graduate students who commit to five consecutive years of service in a science, engineering, or mathematics field; (2) cover the student loan interest obligations of mathematics, science, or engineering professionals and elementary and secondary school teachers who commit to five consecutive years of service in such positions; and (3) award grants to states to establish, expand, or reform state mathematics and science education coordinating councils where education, business, and community leaders collaborate to improve teacher recruitment and training and student performance in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics. Investment in America Act of 2006 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) make permanent the tax credit for increasing research activities; (2) increase the rates of the alternative incremental tax credit for research activities; and (3) allow a taxpayer to elect an alternative simplified tax credit for certain research expenses. Health Care Choice Act of 2006 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to apply the laws of the primary state (as designated by the health insurance issuer) to individual health insurance coverage offered by that issuer in both the primary state and any secondary state if the coverage and issuer meet certain requirements. Health Information Technology Promotion Act of 2006 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology to oversee the nationwide implementation of interoperable health information technology. Amends title XI of the Social Security Act to provide for establishment of uniform confidentiality and security standards with respect to individually identifiable patient health information. Prohibits the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) from taking any action to impede the development of seamless mobility (the ability of a user and a user's connecting devices to move easily among Internet-protocol enabled technology platforms, facilities, and networks).</summary>
</bill>
