<bill session="112" type="h" number="2363" updated="2013-07-20T01:30:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care OverUse Reform Today Act (HealthCOURT Act) of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish performance-based quality measures, to establish limitations on recovery in health care lawsuits based on compliance with best practice guidelines, and to provide grants to States for administrative health care tribunals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400626"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2011-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2011--Introduced.
Health Care OverUse Reform Today Act (HealthCOURT Act) of 2011 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to provide for the selection and issuance of best practice guidelines for treatment of medical conditions. Requires the Secretary to contract with a qualified physician consensus-building organization to develop guidelines and issue a rule that provides for the establishment of such guidelines. Prohibits the Secretary from making a rule that includes guidelines other than those submitted by such organization. Requires the Secretary to routinely review guidelines and, as necessary, enter into additional contracts to issue guidelines. Prohibits a court from awarding noneconomic damages or punitive damages in any health care lawsuit with respect to treatment that is consistent with a guideline issued under this Act. Prohibits guidelines from being introduced as evidence of negligence or deviation in the standard of care in any health care lawsuit unless such guidelines have previously been introduced by the defendant. Declares that there shall be no presumption of negligence if a health care provider provides treatment in a manner inconsistent with such guidelines. Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary to award grants to states for the development, implementation, and evaluation of administrative health care tribunals for the resolution of disputes concerning injuries allegedly caused by health care providers. Sets forth provisions governing the operation of such tribunals, including requiring a review of allegations by an expert panel to assess liability.</summary>
</bill>
