<bill session="112" type="h" number="6145" updated="2013-07-20T02:03:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">New Bedford Whaling National Historical Park Resources Assistance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide preservation and interpretation assistance for resources associated with the New Bedford Whaling National Historical Park in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2012-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2012--Introduced.
New Bedford Whaling National Historical Park Resources Assistance Act- Amends the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 to: (1) authorize the Secretary of the Interior to assist in the interpretation and preservation of the Lewis Temple House, the Nathan and Polly Johnson House, and the Baker-Robinson Whale Oil Refinery associated with the New Bedford Whaling National Historical Park in Massachusetts; and (2) require each dollar of federal funds used for funding cooperative agreements for the preservation of such park to be matched dollar for dollar with funds contributed by non-federal sources. Repeals provisions prohibiting more than specified amounts from being: (1) appropriated for construction, restoration, and rehabilitation of visitor and interpretive facilities, and directional and visitor orientation signage; or (2) used for interpretive and education programs for the National Historic Landmark Schooner Ernestina.</summary>
</bill>
