<bill session="111" type="h" number="835" updated="2013-07-19T23:19:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dollar Bill Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To stimulate the economy and provide for a sound United States dollar by defining a value for the dollar, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2009-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/2009--Introduced.
Dollar Bill Act of 2009 - Directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Board) to make and maintain the value of the U.S. dollar at a market value of 0.002 of a troy ounce of gold. Instructs the Board, in regulating such value, to: (1) conduct open market operations against an explicit target for the price of gold on the exchange operated by the Commodities Exchange, Inc. (COMEX) of the New York Mercantile Exchange, Inc; and (2) use its banking and bank regulatory powers to maintain and promote stable, effective financial markets during and after the transition to such defined value. Prohibits the Board from conducting open market operations indirectly, as in the current practice of targeting the Federal Funds rate.Declares that, effective January 1, 2009, entities that depreciate capital assets for tax purposes shall be entitled to 100% expensing of all capital investment for tax purposes in the year that the investment is made. Requires the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to calculate the impact on federal revenues of the tax changes under this Act on a present value basis in the manner that such calculations are done by the Social Security Trustees, taking into account that: (1) first year expensing of capital investment accelerates, but does not change, the total amount of the depreciation that taxpayers take based upon their investments; and (2) capital investments by businesses have historically earned much higher returns than the interest rate on government bonds.</summary>
</bill>
