<bill session="110" type="h" number="6302" updated="2013-07-19T21:58:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Energy Independence through Offshore Drilling Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To achieve greater national energy independence by terminating the effect of laws prohibiting the spending of appropriated funds and Presidential withdrawals and authorities to conduct oil and natural gas leasing and preleasing activities for any area of the Outer Continental Shelf.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2008--Introduced.
American Energy Independence through Offshore Drilling Act - Terminates all federal laws prohibiting the spending of appropriated funds to conduct oil and natural gas leasing and preleasing activities for any area of the Outer Continental Shelf. Revokes all withdrawals of federal submerged lands of the Outer Continental Shelf from leasing for the exploration for, and development and production of, oil and natural gas. Revokes all authorities given to the President with respect to the leasing of federal submerged lands of the Outer Continental Shelf, given under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, except in the interest of national security.</summary>
</bill>
