<bill session="110" type="h" number="5899" updated="2013-07-19T21:55:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Iraq Shared Investment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require funding under the Iraq Security Forces Fund to be provided in the form of loans and to require the Government of Iraq to provide matching funds under the Commanders' Emergency Response Program to be used for agreed-upon purposes which enable military commanders in Iraq to respond to urgent humanitarian relief and reconstruction requirements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400044"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2008-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412206" joined="2008-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2008-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2008-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400177" joined="2008-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2008-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2008-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-24">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-24">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2008--Introduced.
Iraq Shared Investment Act - Requires that amounts made available under the Iraq Security Forces Fund shall be provided as loans subject to full repayment to the U.S. government. Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006 to provide that: (1) for each of FY2008-FY2009, the Secretary of Defense shall withhold from obligation and expenditure not less than 20% of the amount made available for the Commanders' Emergency Response Program until the Secretary certifies to the congressional defense committees that the government of Iraq has agreed to provide an amount equal to 20% of the amount made available under the Commanders' Emergency Response Program from its own resources to be used to enable military commanders in Iraq to respond to urgent humanitarian relief and reconstruction requirements; and (2) if the Secretary is unable to make such certification the amount withheld from obligation and expenditure shall be available for national debt reduction.</summary>
</bill>
