<bill session="113" type="h" number="1936" updated="2013-11-02T06:35:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Honoring Our WWII Merchant Mariners Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish the Merchant Mariner Equity Compensation Fund to provide benefits to certain individuals who served in the United States merchant marine (including the Army Transport Service and the Naval Transport Service) during World War II.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412498"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2013-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E640"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2849"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2013--Introduced.
Honoring Our WWII Merchant Mariners Act of 2013 - Establishes in the Treasury the Merchant Mariner Equity Compensation Fund for payments by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) of a monthly benefit of $1,000 to each individual who, between December 7, 1941, and December 31, 1946, was a documented member of the U.S. merchant marine (including the Army Transport Service and the Naval Transport Service) serving as a crewmember of a vessel that was operated in U.S. waters by the War Shipping Administration or the Office of Defense Transportation and under contract to, or the property of, the United States. Requires such individuals to: (1) apply for such benefit within one year after the enactment of this Act, and (2) not have received benefits under the Servicemen's Readjustment Act of 1944. Requires the Secretary to include, in annual budget documents submitted to Congress, detailed information on the Fund's operation.</summary>
</bill>
