<bill session="109" type="s" number="1593" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Payment Adjustment To Community Health Centers (PATCH) Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to enhance the access of Medicare beneficiaries who live in medically underserved areas to critical primary and preventive health care benefits at Federally qualified health centers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9514-9515"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="1819"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Introduced.
Medicare Payment Adjustment To Community Health Centers (PATCH) Act of 2005 - Amends part E (Miscellaneous) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise the definition of federally qualified health center (FQHC) services to include certain services furnished by an FQHC for which payment may otherwise be made under Medicare if they were furnished by a health care provider or health care professional other than an FQHC. Repeals the limitation of such services to outpatients of an FQHC, extending them to all patients of an FQHC. Repeals the declaration that any reference to a rural health clinic is deemed a reference to an FQHC. Ensures FQHC reimbursement for patients of hospitals and critical access hospitals under the hospital prospective payment system.</summary>
</bill>
