<bill session="113" type="h" number="893" updated="2013-11-02T06:26:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran, North Korea, and Syria Nonproliferation Accountability Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the imposition of sanctions with respect to foreign persons who transfer to or acquire from Iran, North Korea, or Syria certain goods, services, or technology that contribute to the proliferation activities of Iran, North Korea, or Syria, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412567" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2013-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2013-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412466" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2013-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2013-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2013-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2013-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, the Judiciary, Science, Space, and Technology, Financial Services, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration And Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2013--Introduced.
Iran, North Korea, and Syria Nonproliferation Accountability Act of 2013 - Directs the President to impose sanctions for not less that two years on any foreign person who on or after September 1, 2007, transferred to or acquired from Iran, Syria, or North Korea: (1) certain listed nuclear, dual use, missile, chemical, biological, toxic, or nonlisted but otherwise prohibited goods, services, or technology; (2) acquired, mined, or otherwise extracted materials within the territory or control of Iran, North Korea, or Syria for purposes relating to such countries' nuclear, biological, or chemical weapons, or missile development programs; (3) transferred to Iran, Syria, or North Korea goods, services, or technology that could assist such countries' efforts to extract or mill uranium ore; or (4) provided a vessel, insurance, or any other shipping service for transporting goods to or from Iran, North Korea, or Syria for purposes relating to such countries' nuclear, biological, or chemical weapons, or missile development programs. Directs the President to impose sanctions for at least two years on any foreign person that knowingly participated in a uranium-related joint venture with Iran, North Korea, or Syria, or with persons acting on behalf of, or entities controlled by, such countries. Applies the following sanctions to such prohibited activities: (1) arms export prohibitions, (2) Executive Order 12938 prohibitions, (3) dual use export prohibitions, (4) investment prohibitions, (5) financing prohibitions, (6) financial assistance prohibitions, (7) exclusion of corporate officers from the United States, and (8) sanctions on principal executive officers. Prohibits U.S. nuclear cooperation agreements and related export licenses and transfers of materials, services and goods with a country that is assisting the nuclear program of Iran, North Korea, or Syria, or is transferring advanced conventional weapons to such countries. Directs the President to submit an annual report to Congress that identifies each country that allows foreign persons under its jurisdiction to engage in sanctionable activities. Directs the President to prohibit assistance (other than humanitarian assistance) under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 and not issue export licenses for defense articles or defense services under the Arms Export Control Act to a foreign country that is assisting Iran, North Korea, or Syria in the acquisition, development, or proliferation of weapons of mass destruction or ballistic missiles. Prohibits any U.S. government agency from making extraordinary payments in connection with the International Space Station to the Russian Aviation and Space Agency or any other organization of the government of the Russian Federation unless the President has reported to Congress that: (1) it is Russian policy to oppose the proliferation to or from Iran, North Korea, and Syria of weapons of mass destruction and missile delivery systems; (2) the government of the Russian Federation has demonstrated a commitment to prevent the transfer to or from Iran, North Korea, and Syria of goods, services, and technology that could make a material contribution to Iran's nuclear, biological, chemical weapons, or missile programs; and (3) the Russian Aviation and Space Agency has not, during the one-year period ending on the date of such presidential determination, made transfers that are reportable under this Act to or from Iran, North Korea, or Syria. Authorizes the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to make extraordinary payments in connection with the International Space Station to the Russian Aviation and Space Agency that would otherwise be prohibited under this Act: (1) if such payments are necessary for crew safety aboard the International Space Station; or (2) for the construction, testing, preparation, delivery, launch, or maintenance of the Service Module, and for the purchase of the pressure dome for the Interim Control Module and the Androgynous Peripheral Docking Adapter for the U.S. propulsion module under specified conditions. Directs the President to report to Congress identifying each Russian person or entity that the U.S. government has paid since November 22, 2005, for work to be performed or services to be rendered under the Agreement Concerning Cooperation on the Civil International Space Station or any related protocol, agreement, or contract. Directs the Secretary of State to deny a visa to, and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to exclude from the United States, an alien listed in a report identifying persons involved in specified weapons proliferation activities with Iran. Amends the Ports and Waterways Safety Act to require, before a vessel arrives at a U.S. port, the owner, charterer, operator, or master of the vessel to certify that the vessel did not enter a port in Iran, North Korea, or Syria during the 180-day period ending on the date of the vessel's U.S. port arrival. Prohibits from landing in a U.S. port for at least two years: (1) any vessel for which a false certification was made; and (2) any other vessel owned or operated by a parent corporation, partnership, association, or individual proprietorship of the vessel for which the false certification was made. Directs the Secretary (of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating) to: (1) identify foreign ports at which vessels have landed during the preceding 12-month period that have also landed at ports in Iran, North Korea, or Syria during such period; and (2) inspect vessels arriving in the United States from such foreign ports to establish whether a vessel was involved, during the 12-month period ending on the date of the vessel's U.S. arrival, in any activity that would be sanctionable under this Act. Directs the President to apply foreign exchange, banking, property and loan guarantee sanctions to any person who provides to or acquires from Iran, North Korea, or Syria goods or technology that is used, or is likely to be used, for military applications. Directs the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), before issuing an export license for nuclear cooperation or approving a loan guarantee or any other U.S. assistance with respect to a nuclear energy project, to certify to Congress that issuing the license or approving the loan guarantee will not permit the transfer of any goods or technology that may have military application to Iran, North Korea, or Syria. Prohibits any U.S. contribution to the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) from being used to support any assistance provided by the IAEA through its Technical Cooperation Program to Iran, North Korea, or Syria. Repeals the Iran, North Korea, and Syria Nonproliferation Act.</summary>
</bill>
