<bill session="111" type="h" number="2407" updated="2013-07-19T23:33:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Climate Service Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a National Climate Service at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400155"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 12.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science and Technology"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2009--Introduced.
National Climate Service Act of 2009 - Requires the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to establish the National Climate Service within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to: (1) analyze the effects of weather and climate on communities; (2) carry out observations, data collection, and monitoring of atmospheric and oceanic conditions; (3) provide information and technical support for government efforts to assess and respond to climate variability and change; (4) develop systems for the management and dissemination of data, information, and assessments; and (5) conduct research to improve forecasting, characterization, and understanding of weather and climate variability and change and its effects on communities. Requires the Under Secretary to: (1) establish a Climate Service Office; (2) operate the National Climate Service through a national center, the Climate Service Office, and a network of regional and local facilities; (3) maintain a network of six Regional Climate Centers; (4) maintain a network of offices as part of Integrated Sciences and Assessments Program; (4) establish a Climate Service Advisory Committee; (5) establish Regional Integrated Sciences and Assessments Teams to conduct applied regional climate research and projects to address the needs of local and regional decision makers for information and tools to develop adaptation and response plans to climate variability and change; and (6) report to Congress on climate products and services currently delivered by an NOAA office or partner organization to user groups and stakeholders and the new products and services needed. Repeals the National Climate Program Act.</summary>
</bill>
