<bill session="109" type="s" number="1406" updated="2013-07-19T20:25:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Respirator Access Assurance Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect American workers and responders by ensuring the continued commercial availability of respirators and to establish rules governing product liability actions against manufacturers and sellers of respirators.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2006-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8320-8321"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2357"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
    <term name="Respiratory diseases"/>
    <term name="Safety appliances"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Warning labels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2005--Introduced.
Respirator Access Assurance Act of 2005 - States that manufacturers or sellers of respirators shall not be subject to claims for defective design or warning, or any claims based on such allegations, if the respirator in question received National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH) approval and was manufactured in compliance with NIOSH-approved design and labeling in effect on the date of manufacture. Provides for withdrawal of a previous NIOSH approval of a respirator on grounds of misrepresentation of material information or bribery of a NIOSH officer or employee (thus subjecting the manufacturer or seller to liability for a claim). Preempts all state and local laws with regard to such claims. Makes this Act applicable to any civil action in federal or state court for harm allegedly caused by a respirator, respirator manufacturer, or respirator seller. Applies this Act to any action than has not proceeded to trial as of the date of enactment.</summary>
</bill>
