<bill session="109" type="h" number="5404" updated="2013-07-19T19:52:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Good Samaritan Clean Watershed Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to advance cooperative conservation efforts, to reduce barriers to the formation and use of partnerships to enable Federal environmental stewardship agencies to meet the conservation goals and obligations of the agencies, to promote remediation of inactive and abandoned mines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400116"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman .</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1848"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="2780"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Good samaritan laws"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mine wastes"/>
    <term name="Mine water"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2006--Introduced.
Good Samaritan Clean Watershed Act - Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) or a state or Indian tribe with an approved remediation program to issue a permit to a Good Samaritan to remediate inactive or abandoned mines. Defines "Good Samaritan" as a person that: (1) did not cause the historic mine residue at the inactive or abandoned mines; (2) is not liable or responsible under federal, state, or tribal law for remediation of such residue; and (3) does not have an ownership interest in such site during or since the creation of the residue. States that to be eligible for a remediation permit, projects: (1) shall have the purpose of mitigating the effects of historic mine residue to improve the environment; and (2) are not in mines that are included on the National Priorities List of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) or mines that are subject to enforcement or response actions. Provides conditions for permit issuance, including environmental improvement and financial resources requirements and consideration of objections by land management agencies and public trustees. Deems permit activities to be compliant with the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (Clean Water Act or CWA) and CERCLA. Precludes the imposition of costs or damages under CWA and CERCLA related to the permit activities, except where the permittee's actions exacerbate the pollution as a result of gross negligence or intentional misconduct. Provides for the transfer, modification, or termination of permits and the role of the permitting authority. Requires the permitting authority to provide notice of the application for remediation of a mine site to: (1) designated lead state or tribal agencies; (2) local governments within a 20-mile radius of the project site; (3) federal, state, and tribal agencies that may have an interest in the application; and (4) the public. Authorizes the Administrator to enforce this Act and prescribes civil monetary penalties.</summary>
</bill>
