<bill session="112" type="h" number="2463" updated="2013-07-20T01:31:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Border Security Technology Innovation Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the next generation of border and maritime security technologies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400165"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412422" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412398" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412430" joined="2011-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-08">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-08">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM08" subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2011--Introduced.
Border Security Technology Innovation Act of 2011 - Directs the Under Secretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to ensure that any federal government interagency or intra-agency agreement entered into by the Under Secretary to develop and transition new technology explicitly characterizes the requirements, expected use, and concept of operations for that technology. Changes the termination date for DHS's Homeland Security Science and Technology Advisory Committee to December 31, 2014.Directs the Comptroller General to assess the basic science research needs in the border and maritime security domain.Requires: (1) the Secretary of DHS and the Director of the Joint Planning and Development Office to continue to research and develop technologies to permit routine operation of unmanned aerial vehicles, including autonomously piloted drones, within the national airspace for border and maritime security missions without any degradation of existing levels of safety for all national airspace system users; (2) the Secretary to coordinate with the Director to enter into pilot projects in designated test ranges in sparsely populated, low-density air traffic airspace to conduct research, experiments, and data collection in order to accelerate the safe integration of unmanned aircraft systems into the national airspace system as part of that Office's research activities; (3) the Under Secretary to continue to research and develop technologies to permit detection of near surface voids, such as tunnels, with an emphasis on technologies with real time capability; and (4) the Secretary to coordinate with other federal agencies and ensure the integration of such activities with relevant efforts of such other agencies and DHS's Centers of Excellence Program.Directs the Under Secretary, in coordination with: (1) the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, to continue a joint research and development program on anti-counterfeit technologies and standards; and (2) the Commissioner of United States Customs and Border Protection (CBP), to continue research on the use of mobile biometric technology at the nation's borders between the ports of entry.</summary>
</bill>
