<bill session="112" type="sr" number="543" updated="2013-07-20T02:15:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-04">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution to express the sense of the Senate on international parental child abduction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2012-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2012-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2012-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5991-5992" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-09-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="528">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 528.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-12-04" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and an amended preamble by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7403-7404" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7403-7404" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2012--Passed Senate amended.
Condemns the international abduction of all children. Urges countries identified by the Department of State as noncompliant or demonstrating patterns of noncompliance with the Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction to fulfill their commitment to implement the Convention. Calls on all countries: (1) to become a party to the Convention and institute measures to address cases of international parental child abduction, and (2) that have not become a party to the Convention to develop a mechanism for the resolution of cases of international parental child abduction that occur prior to becoming a party to the Convention. Expresses the sense of the Senate that the United States should: (1) pursue the return of each child abducted by a parent from the United States to another country through all appropriate means, facilitate access by the left-behind parent if the child is not returned, and, where appropriate, seek the extradition of the abductor parent; (2) take all appropriate measures to ensure that a child abducted to a Convention country is returned to the child's country of habitual residence; (3) use diplomacy to encourage other countries to become a party to the Convention and to encourage countries that have not become a party to the Convention to develop a mechanism to resolve cases of international child abduction that occur prior to becoming a party to the Convention; and (4) review the advisory services made available to U.S. citizens by the Department of State, the Department of Justice (DOJ), and other U.S. government agencies to improve the prevention of such child abduction from the United States, and to ensure that effective assistance is provided to U.S. citizen parents of such abducted children.</summary>
</bill>
