<bill session="112" type="h" number="5341" updated="2013-07-20T01:56:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sentinel Assurance for Effective Devices Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve postmarket risk identification and analysis with respect to devices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2012--Introduced.
Sentinel Assurance for Effective Devices Act of 2012 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) amend the new drug approval application procedures to make the postmarket risk identification and analysis system applicable, with certain exceptions, to devices; (2) give priority to class II and class III devices; and (3) engage outside stakeholders in development of the system and gather information from them regarding the content of an effective sentinel program through measures involving the public. Exempts the collection of voluntary information from health care providers for purposes of postmarket risk identification for devices from application of provisions for the coordination of federal information policy. Requires the Secretary to issue final regulations concerning a unique device identification system no later than December 31, 2012, and to implement such system for class III devices no later than one year after the date of issuance of final regulations; for implantable, life-sustaining, and life-supporting devices no later than three years after such date; and for all other devices no later than five years after such date.</summary>
</bill>
