<bill session="112" type="h" number="6026" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">DREDGE Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dredging for Restoration and Economic Development for Global Exports Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the project for navigation, Mississippi River Ship Channel, Gulf of Mexico to Baton Rouge, Louisiana, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412432"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2012--Introduced.
Dredging for Restoration and Economic Development for Global Exports Act of 2012 or the DREDGE Act of 2012 - Modifies the project for navigation, Mississippi River Ship Channel, Gulf of Mexico to Baton Rouge, Louisiana, to direct the Secretary of the Army to: (1) achieve, operate, and maintain a navigation channel of 50 feet with respect to the portion of the project from Baton Rouge to the Southwest Pass sea buoy; (2) complete such work not later than the last day of the third fiscal year beginning after the enactment of this Act; (3) conduct a pilot disposal and sediment project in the Southwest Pass area to determine the cost-effectiveness of pump-out disposal operations for hopper dredges for environmental enhancement and dredged material disposal; and (4) consult with appropriate federal, state, and local agencies and stakeholders to determine the safe placement and timing of such pump-out disposal operations that protect, create, restore, and nourish coastal wetlands and aquatic habitat. Requires: (1) all costs of such work to be treated as operation and maintenance costs, including the first costs of achieving a navigation channel of 50 feet; (2) the federal cost share of such work to be 100%; and (3) the Secretary to pay 100% of the costs of such work out of amounts made available from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund for operation and maintenance expenses. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on: (1) the cost and the environmental, storm damage reduction, and social benefits of the pump-out disposal operation; and (2) the total quantity of dredge material produced during operation and maintenance activities in the New Orleans District and the quantity that is beneficially used.</summary>
</bill>
