<bill session="112" type="h" number="1938" updated="2013-07-20T01:27:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-26T18:44:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-26T18:44:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">North American-Made Energy Security Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">North American-Made Energy Security Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">North American-Made Energy Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the President to expedite the consideration and approval of the construction and operation of the Keystone XL oil pipeline, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400400"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412406" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412429" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412433" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400622" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2011-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400392" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2011-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 13.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-07-08T14:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 112-140, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-25T19:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 370 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1938 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without installowed. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. All points of order against the amendments printed in this report are waived. The waiver of all points of order is prophylactic.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged from further consideration.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T13:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 370 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T14:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 370.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5509-5539" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T14:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1938 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without is in order. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. All points of order against the amendments printed in this report are waived. The waiver of all points of order is prophylactic.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 370 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jo Ann Emerson to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T14:03:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1938.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T15:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Welch amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Welch amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Terry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rush amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rush amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rush demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T15:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Eshoo amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T15:46:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Eshoo amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Eshoo demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Christensen amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cohen amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:05:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cohen amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cohen demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Murphy (CT) amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Murphy (CT) amendment No. 6, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Terry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rush amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rush amendment No. 7, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rush demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hanabusa amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:36:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hanabusa amendment No. 8, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Terry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Johnson (GA) amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Johnson (Ga) amendment No. 9, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Johnson (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kucinich amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kucinich amendment No. 11, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Kucinich demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T17:04:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1938.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T18:07:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5537" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5518" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T18:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Sutton moved to recommit with instructions to Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5537" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5537" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sutton motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to require that the President take all necessary actions to ensure that the Keystone pipeline does not result in unfair increases in gas price and that eminent domain is not used to seize farmland to build the pipeline.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5538" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T18:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 181 - 248 (Roll no. 649).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-07-26T18:44:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="650" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 279 - 147, 1 Present (Roll no. 650).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T18:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-07-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="116">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 116.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="370"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3400"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h720"/>
    <amendment number="h721"/>
    <amendment number="h722"/>
    <amendment number="h723"/>
    <amendment number="h724"/>
    <amendment number="h725"/>
    <amendment number="h726"/>
    <amendment number="h727"/>
    <amendment number="h728"/>
    <amendment number="h729"/>
    <amendment number="h730"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/26/2011--Passed House amended.
North American-Made Energy Security Act - Directs the President, acting through the Secretary of Energy (DOE), to coordinate with each federal agency responsible for coordinating or considering an aspect of the President's National Interest Determination and Presidential Permit decision regarding construction and operation of the Keystone XL pipeline (from Hardisty, Alberta, to Steele City, Nebraska, and then on to the U.S. Gulf Coast through Cushing, Oklahoma) to ensure that all necessary actions are taken on an expedited schedule. Requires each such agency to comply with any deadline the Secretary establishes. Directs the President, within 30 days after the final environmental impact statement, but not later than November 1, 2011, to issue a final order granting or denying the Presidential Permit for the Keystone XL pipeline. States that no action by the Secretary pursuant to this Act shall affect any duty or responsibility to comply with any requirement to conduct environmental review. Declares the sense of Congress that: (1) the United States must decrease its dependence on oil from countries hostile to its interests, and (2) increased access to Canadian energy resources will create jobs in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
