<bill session="110" type="s" number="3274" updated="2013-07-19T22:50:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Nanotechnology Initiative Amendments Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the 21st Century Nanotechnology Research and Development Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2008-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5940"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronics"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial research"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Nanotechnology"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2008--Introduced.
National Nanotechnology Initiative Amendments Act of 2008 - Amends the 21st Century Nanotechology Research and Development Act to expand the scope of the National Nanotechnology Program (the Program), including directing the Program to utilize the perspectives of the industrial community to promote the rapid commercial development of nanoscale-enabled devices, systems, and technologies. Requires issuing guidance to agencies that describes a strategy for transitioning research into commercial products and technologies. Revises requirements regarding the Program's triennial strategic plans. Requires participating agencies to support the activities of the committees of standards setting bodies involved in the development of standards for nanotechnology. Requires the National Nanotechnology Coordination Office to be supported by funds from each participating agency. Makes the National Nanotechnology Advisory Panel a distinct entity. Instructs the Panel to establish a subpanel to enable it in assessing whether societal, ethical, legal, environmental, and workforce concerns are adequately addressed by the Program. Rewrites provisions for triennial external review of the Program. Designates a Coordinator for Societal Dimensions of Nanotechnology, who shall convene a panel to develop a research plan. Establishes an Education Working Group to coordinate, prioritize, and plan the educational activities supported under the Program. Provides for one or more grants to establish Nanotechnology Education Partnerships to recruit and help prepare secondary school students to pursue postsecondary level courses in nanotechnology. Requires agencies supporting nanotechnology research facilities to provide access to companies that are developing prototypes of nanoscale products, devices, or processes. Sets forth provisions concerning nanotechnology related projects under existing nanotechnology transfer programs. Makes it an objective of the Program to establish industry liaison groups. Requires coordination and leveraging of federal investments with nanotechnology research, development, and technology transition initiatives. Requires the Program to include support for nanotechnology research and development in areas of national importance. Requires the Program to support nanomanufacturing research, including in green nanomanufacturing, energy production, water purification, agriculture, and health care. Requires specified reviews by the Advisory Panel of certain program component areas and nanotechnology research facilities. Sets forth provisions regarding nanoscale characterization and metrology. Requires: (1) a Government Accountability Office (GAO) study of nanotechnology related codes, standards, and regulations; and (2) public outreach.</summary>
</bill>
