<bill session="111" type="hr" number="609" updated="2013-07-19T23:01:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-08T19:04:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-07-08T19:04:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2997) making appropriations for Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2010, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400263"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-07T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-191, by Mr. McGovern.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-07T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment, the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the House with such amendments as may have been adopted. In the case of sundry amendments reported from the Committee, the question of their adoption shall be put to the House en gros and without division of the question. During consideration of H.R. 2997, the Chair may reduce to two minutes the minimum time for electronic voting under clause 6 of rule XVIII and clauses 8 and 9 of rule XX.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-07-07T19:41:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="84">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 84.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER AGAINST CONSIDERATION - Mr. Flake stated that the provisions of H.Res. 609 violate section 426(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 by imposing an unfunded mandate and made a point of order against the consideration of the resolution. Subsequently, the Chair noted that the required threshold of identifying the specific language in question had been met, and the House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the question of consideration. At the conclusion of debate on the question of consideration, the Chair will put the question to wit: Will the House now consider the resolution?</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7783-7792, H7793-7795, H7796-7798" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to consider the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 244 - 185 (Roll no. 489).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7784-7786" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 609.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T18:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H. Res. 609.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T18:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 183 (Roll no. 491).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7794-7795, H7797" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T18:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica moved to reconsider the vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to reconsider the vote Failed by recorded vote: 175 - 251 (Roll no. 492).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-07-08T19:04:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="493" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 238 - 186 (Roll no. 493).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7783-7784" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T19:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica moved to reconsider the vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08T19:12:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to reconsider the vote Failed by recorded vote: 170 - 254 (Roll no. 494).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="2997"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2997) making appropriations for Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2010.</summary>
</bill>
