<bill session="110" type="sr" number="705" updated="2013-07-19T22:19:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-10-02">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on the commitment of the United States to the preservation of religious and cultural sites and condemning instances in which such sites are desecrated.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2008-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-10-02" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10423-10424" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10423-10424" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10490-10491" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hc" number="255"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Jews"/>
    <term name="Lithuania"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2008--Passed Senate without amendment.
Expresses strongly to the government of Lithuania that the cemetery located in the Snipiskes area of Vilnius, Lithuania, an important part of the cultural heritage of the Jewish people, should not be further desecrated. Urges Lithuania to take all necessary steps to immediately stop, and if necessary reverse, construction on that cemetery. Reaffirms that constructive bilateral relations between Lithuania and the United States are important to the governments and citizens of both countries. Expresses strong support for the work of the United States Commission for the Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad and for the European countries that continue to work to preserve sacred historical sites.</summary>
</bill>
