<bill session="112" type="s" number="2175" updated="2013-07-20T02:35:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Due Process and Military Detention Amendments Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 to provide for the trial of covered persons detained in the United States pursuant to the Authorization for Use of Military Force and to repeal the requirement for military custody.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2012-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4192"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5936"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2012--Introduced.
Due Process and Military Detention Amendments Act of 2012 - Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 to provide that, in the case of a person detained in the United States pursuant to the Authorization for Use of Military Force, disposition under the law of war shall only mean transfer for trial and proceedings by a court established under article III of the Constitution. Requires such trial and proceedings to have all due process provided under the Constitution. Repeals the requirement of detention in military custody pending disposition under the law of war for individuals determined to be a member or part of al Qaeda or an associated force who has participated in planning or carrying out an attack or attempted attack against the United States or its coalition partners.</summary>
</bill>
