<bill session="109" type="s" number="2618" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Access to Medical Treatment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to permit an individual to be treated by a health care practitioner with any method of medical treatment such individual requests, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2006-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3390"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2792"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alternative medicine"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drug interactions"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="New Zealand"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/2006--Introduced.
Access to Medical Treatment Act - Gives an individual the right to be treated by a health care practitioner with any medical treatment that the individual desires, including a treatment that is not approved, certified, or licensed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, if: (1) the practitioner has personally examined the individual and agrees to treat the individual; and (2) the administration of such treatment does not violate licensing laws and is within the scope of the practice of such practitioner. Authorizes health care practitioners to provide any method of treatment to such an individual if certain requirements are met, including that: (1) there is no reason to conclude that such treatment will cause danger to the individual; and (2) the patient is informed in writing that such treatment has not been approved, certified, or licensed by the Secretary. Requires a practitioner to report: (1) administering such treatment and discovering it to be a danger to an individual; and (2) the positive effects of an unconventional medical treatment for a life-threatening medical condition. Allows an individual to introduce or deliver into interstate commerce, or to produce, transport, receive, or hold, a food, drug, device, or equipment solely for use in accordance with this Act if there have been no advertising claims made by the manufacturer, distributor, or seller with respect to a medical treatment. Requires notification to the Secretary if: (1) an individual imports a shipment of a food, drug, device, or any other equipment; or (2) a manufacturer intends to deliver an unapproved drug, device, or other equipment into interstate commerce. States that nothing in this Act shall in any way adversely affect the distribution or sale of dietary supplements.</summary>
</bill>
