<bill session="112" type="h" number="1828" updated="2013-07-20T01:26:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Feral Swine Eradication and Control Pilot Program Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide financial assistance to the State of Louisiana for a pilot program to develop measures to eradicate or control feral swine and to assess and restore wetlands damaged by feral swine.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400636"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2011-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="893"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2011--Introduced.
Feral Swine Eradication and Control Pilot Program Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to provide financial assistance to Louisiana to pay the federal share of the cost of a pilot program to: (1) study the damage to wetlands in Louisiana caused by feral swine, and (2) develop methods to eradicate or control feral swine and to restore damaged wetlands. Requires the Secretary to ensure that the pilot program uses the knowledge and expertise gained through activities carried out under the Coastal Wetlands Planning, Protection and Restoration Act and the Nutria Eradication and Control Act of 2003. Limits: (1) the federal share of total pilot program costs to 75%, and (2) the amount of the federal financial assistance that may for used for administrative expenses to 10%.</summary>
</bill>
