<bill session="112" type="s" number="253" updated="2013-07-20T02:18:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a commission to ensure a suitable observance of the centennial of World War I, and to designate memorials to the service of men and women of the United States in World War I.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2011-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2011-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S423-424"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social sciences and history"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2011--Introduced.
Establishes the World War I Centennial Commission to: (1) plan, develop, and execute programs, projects, and activities to commemorate the centennial of World War I; (2) encourage private organizations and state and local governments to organize and participate in such activities; (3) facilitate and coordinate such activities throughout the United States; (4) serve as a clearinghouse for the collection and dissemination of information about centennial events and plans; and (5) develop commemoration recommendations for Congress and the President. Designates: (1) the Liberty Memorial of Kansas City in Kansas City, Missouri, as the National World War I Museum and Memorial; and (2) the District of Columbia War Memorial in Washington, D.C., as the District of Columbia and National World War I Memorial (Memorial). Authorizes the World War I Memorial Foundation to establish a commemorative work at the Memorial Site.</summary>
</bill>
