<bill session="111" type="s" number="452" updated="2013-07-20T00:27:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Backcountry Landing Strip Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure public access to Federal land and to the airspace over Federal land.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300030"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2009-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2025"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2025"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/23/2009--Introduced.
Backcountry Landing Strip Access Act - Prohibits the Secretaries of the Interior or Agriculture from taking any action that would permanently close, restrict, or render or declare unserviceable any aircraft landing strip located on land under their jurisdiction unless: (1) the action has been approved by the head of the aviation department of the state in which the landing strip is located; (2) the Secretary publishes notice of the proposed action and provides for a 90-day public comment thereafter; and (3) the Secretary and appropriate state aviation department head have taken into consideration any comments received. Requires the Secretaries to: (1) establish a nationwide policy for governing backcountry aviation issues relating to the management of federal land under the jurisdiction of the Departments of the Interior and Agriculture; and (2) require officials with jurisdiction over such land to adhere to such policy. Requires private and publicly-owned aircraft land strips acquired by the government to be made available to the public for unrestricted use.</summary>
</bill>
