<bill session="109" type="s" number="3748" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of the Army to publish a supplement to the major rehabilitation report for the Herbert Hoover Dike system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2006-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Dikes (Engineering)"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Everglades"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2006--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Army, by May 31, 2007, to publish a supplement to the major rehabilitation report for the Herbert Hoover Dike system, approved by the Chief of Engineers in November 2000, which shall include: (1) an evaluation of existing conditions at the system; (2) an identification of additional risks associated with flood events at the system that are equal to or greater than the standard projected flood risks; (3) an evaluation of the potential to integrate Corps of Engineers projects into an enhanced flood protection system for Lake Okeechobee, including the potential for additional water storage north of Lake Okeechobee and an analysis of other project features included in the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan; and (4) a review of the report prepared for the south Florida water management district dated April 2006.</summary>
</bill>
