<bill session="110" type="s" number="967" updated="2013-07-19T22:28:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 41 of title 5, United States Code, to provide for the establishment and authorization of funding for certain training programs for supervisors of Federal employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3613-3614"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3614-3615" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-30">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-10-01">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-10-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1100">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1100.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-11-19">
      <text>By Senator Lieberman from Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs filed written report. Report No. 110-523.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Supervisors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2008--Reported to Senate amended.
Federal Supervisor Training Act of 2007 - Revises provisions relating to specific training programs for federal agency supervisors. Requires the head of each federal agency to establish: (1) a program to provide interactive instructor-based training to supervisors on developing and discussing relevant goals and objectives with the employee, communicating and discussing progress on performance goals and objectives and conducting performance appraisals, mentoring and motivating employees and improving employee performance and productivity, effectively managing employees with unacceptable performance, and addressing reports of a hostile work environment, reprisal, or harassment; (2) a program to provide training to supervisors on prohibited personnel practices and processes to enforce employee rights; and (3) a program under which experienced supervisors mentor new supervisors. Requires: (1) supervisors to complete such programs every three years; and (2) regulations prescribed by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to include measures by which to assess the effectiveness of agency supervisor training programs. Requires the Director to issue guidance to federal agencies on competencies supervisors are expected to meet in order to effectively manage, and be accountable for managing, the performance of employees. Requires each agency to: (1) develop competencies to assess the performance of each supervisor and, in developing such competencies, to consider such guidance developed by the Director and any other qualifications or factors determined by the agency; (2) assess the overall capacity of the supervisors in the agency to meet such guidance; (3) develop and implement a supervisor training program to strengthen issues identified during such assessment; and (4) measure the effectiveness of that program in improving supervisor competence. Instructs each agency, every year or on any basis requested by the Director, to submit a report to OPM on the progress of such agency in implementing the requirements specified above, including measures used to assess program effectiveness.</summary>
</bill>
