<bill session="109" type="h" number="6257" updated="2013-07-19T19:59:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Access to Life-Saving Medicine Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the licensing of comparable biological products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400425"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2006-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="4016"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Patent infringement"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Introduced.
Access to Life-Saving Medicine Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish a process for the approval of a comparable biological product based on its similarity to a previously licensed biological product (the reference product). Allows a person to file an abbreviated comparable product application with the Secretary of Health and Human Services that includes: (1) data demonstrating that the product is comparable to the reference product; (2) information to show that the conditions or conditions of use prescribed, recommended, or suggested in the labeling proposed for the comparable product have been previously approved for the reference product; and (3) information to show that the route of administration, the dosage form, and the strength of the comparable product are the same as those of the reference product. Sets forth conditions for approval of such an application by the Secretary. Allows an applicant to request that the Secretary make a determination as to the interchangeability of a comparable product and the reference product. Provides market exclusivity to such an interchangeable product. Requires the Secretary to establish requirements for the efficient review, approval, suspension, and revocation of comparable product applications. Sets forth provisions governing patent infringement claims against the license holder of a comparable product. Amends the Internal Review Code to allow a tax credit for qualified clinical testing expenses.</summary>
</bill>
