<bill session="110" type="h" number="5692" updated="2013-07-19T21:53:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Infant Crib Safety Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for infant crib safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400396"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2008-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2008-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H505-506"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative courts"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Furniture industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hotels, motels, etc."/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2008--Introduced.
Infant Crib Safety Act - Amends the Federal Hazardous Substances Act to make it unlawful for any commercial user to manufacture, sell, or otherwise place in the stream of commerce any full-size or nonfull-size crib which was made before 1999, does not conform to the standards of this Act, or has any missing, loose, or broken components. Makes it unlawful for any hotel, motel, or similar lodging facility to offer or provide such a crib. Considers to be a banned hazardous product under the Consumer Product Safety Act any crib which does not conform to specified regulations in the Code of Federal Regulations and standards of the American Society for Testing Materials, unless labeled as not intended to be used for, and dangerous to, an infant. Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to begin a rulemaking to include the requirements of the American Society for Testing Materials standards and to address any hazards due to crib and play yard durability. Requires the CPSC to promulgate a consumer product safety rule to require that cribs manufactured and introduced into interstate commerce contain a label warning consumers against the use of soft bedding. Includes in the definition of commercial user any person who manufactures or sells cribs or, by his or her occupation holds himself or herself out as having knowledge or skill peculiar to cribs, including child care facilities and family child care homes. Excludes from that definition an individual who sells a used crib at a one-time private sale.</summary>
</bill>
