<bill session="113" type="h" number="2385" updated="2013-11-05T04:46:27-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CFPB Pay Fairness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to set the rate of pay for employees of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection in accordance with the General Schedule.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412488"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412508" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412479" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412528" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412462" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412394" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412570" joined="2013-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2013-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-29">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3194"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/2013--Introduced.
CFPB Pay Fairness Act of 2013 - Amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, with respect to compensation of employees of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), to require the CFPB Director to set and adjust the rates of basic pay for CFPB employees in accordance with the General Schedule for federal employees. (Currently, the Director is merely authorized to do so.) Repeals the requirement that the Director at all times provide compensation (including benefits) to each class of employees at least comparable to the compensation and benefits then being provided by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System for the corresponding class of Federal Reserve employees. Repeals also the requirement that all such employees be compensated (including benefits) on terms and conditions consistent with specified terms and conditions of the Federal Reserve Act.</summary>
</bill>
