<bill session="109" type="h" number="3735" updated="2013-07-19T19:37:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Emergency Medicaid Relief Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent a reduction in the Medicaid Federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) determined for a State for fiscal year 2006.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2005-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2005--Introduced.
Emergency Medicaid Relief Act of 2005 - Prohibits the Federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) for a state for FY2006 from being less than the greater of: (1) the FMAP determined for the state for FY2005; or (2) the FMAP that would have been determined for the state for FY2006 if the per capita incomes for 2001 and 2002 that were used to determine the FMAP for the state for FY2005 were used. Provides that the FMAP applicable to a state for FY2006 after the application of this limitation on reduction shall apply only for purposes of titles XIX (Medicaid) and XXI (State Children's Health Insurance (SCHIP)) of the Social Security Act (SSA), as well as payments under such titles that are based on a certain enhanced FMAP, and shall not apply with respect to payments under SSA title IV (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF)). Repeals this Act effective October 1, 2006, and declares that it shall not apply to any fiscal year after FY2006.</summary>
</bill>
