<bill session="112" type="s" number="825" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Job Creation Through Innovation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permanently extend and modify the research tax credit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412390"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2514"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2514-2516" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="724"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="591"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2011--Introduced.
Job Creation Through Innovation Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase and make permanent the tax credit for increasing research activities, (2) allow an increased research tax credit for manufacturers whose domestic production gross receipts are more than 50% of their total receipts, (3) make the research tax credit refundable for businesses with an average number of employees of 500 or fewer, and (4) expand the qualifying advanced energy project credit by allocating in 2011 $5 billion of grants or tax credit amounts to manufacturers of goods and components (other than for assembly of components) in the United States that are used in alternative energy projects. Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Tax Act of 2009 to extend the grant program for investment in renewable energy property, including renewable resources used to produce electricity and fuel cell, solar, wind, geothermal, and microturbine property, in lieu of tax credits, by extending the placed-in-service deadline for such property through 2012. Extends through September 30, 2013, the deadline for submitting grant applications for such program.</summary>
</bill>
