<bill session="109" type="s" number="4041" updated="2013-07-19T20:48:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-11-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Child Medication Safety Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect children and their parents from being coerced into administering a controlled substance in order to attend school, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2006-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10745"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-30">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-11-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="662">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 662.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1790"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1790"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Attention deficit disorders"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hyperactive children"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Problem children"/>
    <term name="Psychotropic drugs"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Introduced.
Child Medication Safety Act of 2006 - Requires states, as a condition of receiving funds under any program or activity administered by the Secretary of Education, to develop and implement policies and procedures prohibiting school personnel from requiring a child, as a condition of attending school or receiving services, to obtain a prescription for any specified controlled substances listed under the Controlled Substances Act (CSA). Provides that nothing in such requirement shall be construed to create a federal prohibition against teachers and other school personnel consulting or sharing classroom-based observations with parents or guardians regarding a student's academic performance or behavior in the classroom or school, or regarding the need for evaluation for special education or related services under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA). Directs the Comptroller General to review and report on: (1) variation among state definitions of psychotropic medication in state jurisdiction over public education; (2) prescription rates of medications used in public schools to treat children diagnosed with attention deficit disorder, attention deficit hyperactivity disorder, and other disorders or illnesses; and (3) which of such medications are CSA-listed and which are not, including properties and effects of the latter and whether they have been considered for CSA-listing.</summary>
</bill>
