<bill session="111" type="h" number="4552" updated="2013-07-19T23:53:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Benefit Card Fairness Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to provide protection for consumers who have government benefit cards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400238"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2010-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2010-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/29/2010--Introduced.
Benefit Card Fairness Act of 2010 - Amends the Electronic Fund Transfer Act (EFTA) to extend its coverage to any account directly or indirectly established through a government agency to which electronic fund transfers (EFTs) are made by or on behalf of a government agency on a recurring basis (government payment account). Repeals the exemption from EFTA disclosure, protection, responsibility, and remedy requirements of electronic benefit transfer systems established by a federal, state, or local government agency for distributing needs-tested benefits, such as through automated teller machines (ATMs) or point-of-sale terminals. Requires a financial institution to offer a government payment account in compliance with this Act and with the requirements of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) for the provision of insurance to the consumer. Prescribes requirements for consumer choice in making an EFT to a government payment account, as well as for access to account balance and transaction history. Prohibits the assessment of specified fees on a government payment account, except certain transaction fees, a nominal fee of up to $1 for written periodic statements, and other permissible fees for specific services beyond ordinary use of the account. Requires a financial institution to make certain disclosures including: (1) the means to obtain account balance; (2) written account history; (3) fee information; and (4) error resolution.</summary>
</bill>
