<bill session="111" type="hr" number="932" updated="2013-07-19T23:04:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress that all State public health departments, local public health departments, hospitals, doctor offices, and other health care providers should adhere to guidelines issued from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention with regard to the H1N1 influenza virus.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2009-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2009-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412285" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2009-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Immunology"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2009--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) all public health departments, hospitals, and other health care providers should adhere to guidelines issued from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) regarding the H1N1 influenza virus; (2) the five target groups (pregnant women, people who live with or provide care for infants younger than six months, health care and emergency medical services personnel, people six months through 24 years of age, and people 25 years through 64 years of age who have certain medical conditions that put them at higher risk for influenza-related complications) should be encouraged to seek the vaccine and be the first priority for government responses; (3) the federal government should work closely with states, localities, and hospitals to ensure the vaccine is distributed quickly and efficiently; and (4) the federal government should study their response to the pandemic and work to improve the system and processes to enhance its response to future pandemics.</summary>
</bill>
