<bill session="109" type="s" number="1341" updated="2013-07-19T20:25:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Enhanced Transition Services Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to improve transitional assistance provided for members of the armed forces being discharged, released from active duty, or retired, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/1/2005 S7822-7825"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/1/2005 S7825-2827" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12596"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2005--Introduced.
Veterans' Enhanced Transition Services Act of 2005 - Requires the Secretary concerned to: (1) require preseparation counseling for members of reserve components who have been serving on active duty continuously for at least 180 days; and (2) ensure that commanders authorize such members to obtain counseling during duty time. Requires preseparation counseling on: (1) certification and licensure requirements for civilian occupations; and (2) civilian occupations that correspond to military occupational specialties. Requires such counseling to include additional information for veterans, including job training programs, small business ownership, veterans' preference, housing counseling, health care benefits, and disability compensation. Extends preseparation counseling to members of the National Guard being separated from long-term duty. Directs the Secretaries of Defense and Homeland Security to require participation in the Department of Labor transitional services program unless members previously participated in the program or are returning to previously held employment or educational pursuits. Requires the Secretary concerned to ensure that commanders authorize such members to obtain counseling during duty time. Directs the Secretaries of Defense, Homeland Security, and Veterans Affairs to jointly submit to Congress a plan to maximize access to benefits delivery at discharge programs for members of the Armed Forces. Directs the Secretary of Defense to prescribe minimum content and standards for required medical examinations, including screening for mental health disorders, and to provide follow-up services. Requires the Secretary of Defense to carry out a program to facilitate veteran-to-veteran preseparation counseling.</summary>
</bill>
