<bill session="109" type="s" number="1717" updated="2013-07-19T20:28:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Price Gouging bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oil and Gas Price Gouging Prevention Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prevent gas and oil gouging during natural disasters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2005--Introduced.
Oil and Gas Price Gouging Prevention Act of 2005 - States that it is unlawful during the period of a major disaster or emergency designated by the President to increase the price of any oil or gas product more than 15 percent above its price immediately prior to the declaration, unless such increase is attributable to additional costs incurred by either the seller or national or international market trends. Instructs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to establish procedures to report violations of this Act, including links on its Internet website and a toll-free telephone number. Subjects violations of this Act to maximum criminal penalties of $10 million if a corporation, or, if any other person, $350,000, or imprisonment, or both. Authorizes the FTC to impose a maximum civil penalty of $5,000 for each such violation. States that each day of violation shall constitute a separate offense. Authorizes state Attorneys General to bring a civil action for a violation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
