<bill session="109" type="s" number="1838" updated="2013-07-19T20:29:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal and District of Columbia Government Real Property Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the sale, acquisition, conveyance, and exchange of certain real property in the District of Columbia to facilitate the utilization, development, and redevelopment of such property, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2005-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/07/2005 S11228"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/7/2005 S11228-11230" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-27">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce,  and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-28">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-511.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Collins with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-08-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="581">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 581.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13">
      <text>By Senator Collins from Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs filed written report. Report No. 109-359.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="3699"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3699"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Convention facilities"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Mental care facilities"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports facilities"/>
    <term name="Streets"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Waterfronts"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2006--Reported to Senate amended.
Federal and District of Columbia Government Real Property Act of 2005 - (Sec. 2) Requires the Mayor of the District of Columbia, by January 31 of each year, to report to specified congressional committees on the use and development, during the previous year, of land transferred pursuant to this Act. Requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO), by January 31 of each even numbered year, to report to the same congressional committees on: (1) such use and development during the previous two years; and (2) how they comply with the Anacostia Waterfront Initiative Framework Plan. Title I: Real Property Conveyances Between the General Services Administration and the District of Columbia - (Sec. 101) Directs the General Services Administration (GSA) to convey to the District of Columbia U.S. Reservation 13, subject to specified conditions, and the Old Naval Hospital, on the day on which the District conveys to GSA certain real property on the West Campus of Saint Elizabeths Hospital. (Sec. 102) Terminates any pending District claim against the United States for failure to perform or to reimburse the District for the cost of performing specified services concerning Saint Elizabeths Hospital and the District of Columbia Mental Health Services. Title II: Streamlining Management of Properties Located in the District of Columbia - (Sec. 201) Transfers administrative jurisdiction over certain U.S.-owned properties from the District to the Secretary of the Interior for administration by the Director of the National Park Service (NPS). Transfers administrative jurisdiction over other specified properties from the United States to the District. Requires certain properties transferred to the Secretary to be used as the site for establishment of a memorial to honor disabled veterans of the U.S. Armed Forces. (Sec. 202) Requires conveyance of specified properties by the District to the Secretary, to be administered by NPS for the closure of a one-block long roadway adjacent to Montrose Park, and for the closing of the rights-of-way now occupied by the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal. Directs the Secretary to convey certain other properties to the District. (Sec. 203) Requires the Secretary to convey U.S. Reservation 174 to the District upon the District's enactment of a final plan that meets specified requirements for the development of the former Convention Center Site. Title III: Poplar Point - (Sec. 301) Requires NPS, upon certification by the Secretary (acting through NPS), to convey Poplar Point to the District after the District adopts a land-use plan for it meeting specified requirements. Requires the deed for the conveyance of Poplar Point to include a restriction requiring that 70 acres, including wetlands, be maintained for park purposes in perpetuity, as identified in the land use plan. Grants any person (including an individual or public entity) standing to enforce the requirements. (Sec. 303) Provides for conveyance: (1) from the District to NPS, at no cost, of certain replacement facilities and properties to which NPS is to be relocated; and (2) from NPS to the District of certain other properties withheld from the conveyance of Poplar Point. Title IV: General Provisions - (Sec. 402) Declares that the United States shall not be responsible for paying costs and expenses, other than those related to or associated with environmental liabilities or cleanup actions provided under law, incurred by the District or any other parties in connection with effecting the provisions of this Act or amendments made by it. (Sec. 403) Authorizes a federal or District officer or employee to contract for payment of costs or expenses related to any properties conveyed under quitclaim deed under this Act or any amendment made by this Act. (Sec. 405) Requires the Mayor of the District, the Administrator of GSA, or the Secretary (as the case may be) to execute and deliver a quitclaim deed or prepare and record a transfer plat, as appropriate, within six months after the property is conveyed.</summary>
</bill>
