<bill session="109" type="s" number="2164" updated="2013-07-19T20:32:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health and Welfare Relief Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend titles IV, XVIII, and XIX of the Social Security Act to improve the provision of care under the programs under such titles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2005-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2005--Introduced.
Health and Welfare Relief Act of 2005 - Amends title XVIII of the Social Security Act (SSA) with respect to: (1) the 2006 update to the single conversion factor for physician's services; (2) a three-year transition of hold harmless payments for small rural hospitals under the prospective payment system for hospital outpatient department services; (3) the composite rate component of the basic case-mix adjusted system for dialysis services; and (4) other related matters. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop a strategic and implementing plan to address issues regarding physician investment in specialty hospitals. Extends through calendar 2006 the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families program under SSA title IV part A, the national random sample study of child welfare and child welfare waiver authority, and transitional medical assistance and abstinence education programs. Provides for emergency health care, including disaster relief Medicaid under SSA title XIX, and other relief for survivors of Hurricane Katrina. Amends the TANF Emergency Response and Recovery Act of 2005 with respect to: (1) reimbursement of states for TANF benefits to assist families affected by Hurricane Katrina; (2) an increase in additional TANF funds available for hurricane-damaged states; and (3) rules for receipt of Hurricane Katrina emergency TANF benefits and their application to the child support requirement. Specifies requirements related to disclosure based on valid authorization and emergency procurement authority in support of Hurricane Katrina rescue and relief efforts.</summary>
</bill>
