<bill session="111" type="sr" number="161" updated="2013-07-20T00:17:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution recognizing June 2009 as the first National Hereditary Hemorrhagic Telangiecstasia (HHT) month, established to increase awareness of HHT, which is a complex genetic blood vessel disorder that affects approximately 70,000 people in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2009-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-05-21" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5885" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5885" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5877" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="536"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="sr" number="141"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="sr" number="508"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Blood and blood diseases"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Passed Senate without amendment.
Expresses support for the designation of June 2009 as National Hereditary Hemorrhagic Telangiecstasia (HHT) month. Recognizes: (1) the need to pursue research to find better treatments and a cure for HHT; (2) the HHT Foundation International as the only U.S. advocacy organization working to find a cure for HHT while saving the lives and improving the well-being of individuals and families affected; (3) the importance of comprehensive care centers in providing complete care and treatment for HHT patients; (4) that stroke, lung, and brain hemorrhages can be prevented through early diagnosis, screening, and treatment of HHT; (5) that severe hemorrhages in the nose and gastrointestinal tract can be controlled through intervention and that heart failure can be managed through proper diagnosis and treatments of HHT; and (6) that a leading medical and academic institution estimated that $6.6 billion of one-time health care costs can be saved through aggressive management of HHT in the at-risk population. Acknowledges the need to identify the approximately 90% of the HHT population that has not yet been diagnosed and that is at risk for death or disability due to sudden rupture of the blood vessels in major organs in the body.</summary>
</bill>
