<bill session="110" type="s" number="1143" updated="2013-07-19T22:30:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-01-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to designate the Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse and the surrounding Federal land in the State of Florida as an Outstanding Natural Area and as a unit of the National Landscape System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2007-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4682"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4682-4683" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-216.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-01-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 110-288.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="640">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 640.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="1922"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1922"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1922"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Lighthouses and lightships"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/2007--Introduced.
Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2007 - Establishes the Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse Outstanding Natural Area to protect, conserve, and enhance the unique and nationally important historic, natural, cultural, scientific, educational, scenic, and recreational values of the federal land surrounding the Lighthouse for the benefit of generations of people in the United States while: (1) allowing certain recreational and research activities to continue in the Area; and (2) ensuring that Coast Guard operations and activities are unimpeded within the boundaries of the Area. Directs the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Commandant of the Coast Guard, to develop a comprehensive management plan to provide long-term management guidance for the public land in the Area. Requires the Secretary to manage the Area as part of the National Landscape Conservation System. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into cooperative agreements with federal, state, county, other local government agencies, and other partners (including the Loxahatchee River Historical Society) for the long-term management of the Area; and (2) acquire for inclusion in the Area any state or private land or any interest in state or private land that is adjacent to the Area and identified in the management plan as appropriate for acquisition.</summary>
</bill>
