<bill session="110" type="h" number="3980" updated="2013-07-19T21:38:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Families First Immigration Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for safe and humane policies and procedures pertaining to the arrest, detention, and processing of aliens in immigration enforcement operations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2007-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2008-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2008-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2008-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="2074"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Bail"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/25/2007--Introduced.
Families First Immigration Enforcement Act - Requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), in a workplace enforcement operation that is calculated to apprehend or does apprehend at least 50 aliens, to do the following: (1) give state agencies sufficient notice to arrange for representatives who speak the detainees' language and to provide for any special needs; (2) afford access to state social service agencies to screen and interview detainees to determine if medical risks or risks to relatives exist; (3) consider, upon recommendation, the release of detainees on age, medical, or family related humanitarian grounds; and (4) provide a toll-free number for families of detainees to report their relationship to DHS or state social services. Requires that such aliens have access to legal orientation presentations through the Executive Office for Immigration Review's legal orientation program. States that detainees should be held within the jurisdiction of the local United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) field office to the extent that space allows. Requires a detainee's release within 72 hours of apprehension if such alien is not subject to mandatory detention, does not pose a flight risk, or is subject to humanitarian release. States that such alien shall be released: (1) on his or her own recognizance; (2) by posting a minimum bond; (3) on parole under the Immigration and Nationality Act; or (4) through the intensive supervision appearance or similar program.</summary>
</bill>
