<bill session="110" type="sc" number="30" updated="2013-07-19T22:19:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A concurrent resolution urging all sides to the current political crisis in Ukraine to act responsibly and use dialogue to resolve the crisis and ensure a free and transparent democratic system in Ukraine based on the rule of law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5510" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="hc" number="115"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/2007--Introduced.
Welcomes the strong relationship formed between the United States and Ukraine since the restoration of Ukraine's independence in 1991. Urges all sides to the current political crisis in Ukraine to act responsibly and use dialogue to resolve the crisis. Expresses support for the efforts of the Ukrainian people to establish a full democracy, the rule of law, and respect for human rights. Pledges continued assistance to the strengthening of a democratic system in Ukraine and to the continued development of a free market economy. Reaffirms the Senate's commitment to Ukraine's independence, sovereignty and territorial integrity, and assumption of Ukraine's place as a full member of the international community of democracies.</summary>
</bill>
