<bill session="110" type="h" number="2757" updated="2013-07-19T21:27:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Acts popularly known as the Duck Stamp Act and the Wetland Loan Act to reauthorize appropriations to promote the conservation of migratory waterfowl and to offset or prevent the serious loss of important wetlands and other waterfowl habitat essential to the preservation of such waterfowl, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400403"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2007-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2007-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="272"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Postage stamps"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2007--Introduced.
Amends the Wetland Loan Act to extend funding for conservation of migratory waterfowl and habitat.Amends the Duck Stamp Act to increase the price of federal migratory-bird hunting and conservation stamps.Makes amounts appropriated under the Wetlands Loan Act or from the migratory bird conservation fund available to acquire land only if the Migratory Bird Conservation Commission recommends it. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, to designate the priority general public uses that will be authorized on such land and the first date on which each designated use will be allowed. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the funds provided pursuant to this Act should be used for preserving and increasing waterfowl populations in accordance with the goals and objectives of the North American Waterfowl Management Plan and should supplement and not replace current conservation funding; and (2) this Act should be implemented in a manner that helps private landowners achieve their long-term land use objectives in ways that enhance the conservation of wetlands and wildlife habitat.</summary>
</bill>
