<bill session="112" type="s" number="513" updated="2013-07-20T02:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Saving Kids From Dangerous Drugs Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to provide enhanced penalties for marketing controlled substances to minors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1410-1411"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1411" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2011--Introduced.
Saving Kids from Dangerous Drugs Act of 2011 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to make it unlawful for any adult (at least 18 years of age) to knowingly or intentionally manufacture or create, with intent to manufacture, create, distribute, or dispense, a Schedule I or II controlled substance that is: (1) combined with a beverage or candy product; (2) marketed or packaged to appear similar to a beverage or candy product; or (3) modified by flavoring or coloring with the intent to distribute, dispense, or sell it to a person under 18 years of age. Imposes enhanced criminal penalties for violations (not to exceed 10 years for a first offense or 20 years for a subsequent offense, involving the same controlled substance and schedule). Exempts any controlled substance that has been approved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) under the drug approval process or that has been altered at the direction of a medical practitioner for a legitimate medical purpose.Directs the United States Sentencing Commission to review its guidelines and policy statements to reflect the enhanced penalties provided by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
