<bill session="111" type="s" number="763" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mortgage and Rental Disaster Relief Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, to authorize temporary mortgage and rental payments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4175-4177"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/2009--Introduced.
Mortgage and Rental Disaster Relief Act of 2009 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to provide temporary assistance in the form of mortgage or rental payments to or on behalf of individuals and households who, as a result of financial hardship caused by a major disaster, have received written notice of dispossession or eviction from a residence because of a foreclosure of mortgage or lien, cancellation of sales contract, or lease termination, entered into before such disaster. Defines such a "financial hardship" to include: (1) the loss of employment or significant income because a job, a business, or a business interest was located in a disaster area; or (2) suffering financially because of travel restrictions or station or road closures affecting residents of such area.Restricts eligibility for such assistance to individuals or households who have an adjusted gross income of not more than $75,000 ($100,000 for individuals or households who resided in an area with a high cost of living). Directs the President to adjust the limits annually to reflect inflation. Allows assistance to be provided for the duration of the period of financial hardship caused by the disaster, not to exceed 18 months. Requires recipients determined to be ineligible to return the full amount of assistance to the government.Makes this Act applicable to any major disaster declared on or after October 21, 2007.</summary>
</bill>
