<bill session="112" type="h" number="3878" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chemawa Indian School Trust Transfer and Self-Determination Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to hold in trust for the benefit of the nine federally recognized Indian tribes in Oregon the Chemawa Indian School land and improvements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412315"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2012-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2012-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2012--Introduced.
Chemawa Indian School Trust Transfer and Self-Determination Act of 2012 - Directs the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) to transfer to the Secretary of the Interior administrative jurisdiction over federally owned property occupied by the Chemawa Indian School and Chemawa Cemetery in Salem, Oregon. Requires the Secretary to hold that property in trust for nine federally recognized Indian tribes in Oregon. Requires the tribes to agree to use the Chemawa Indian School property only for their educational or cultural benefit, or for other purposes that are authorized by the Chemawa Indian School Board of Trustees (Board) and approved by the Secretary. Prohibits gaming on such lands. Directs the Secretary to establish the Board, which is to be composed of nine trustees appointed by the tribes and two adjunct trustee advisors appointed by the Secretary. Authorizes the Board to assume operation of the Chemawa Indian School or use the trust land for purposes authorized by this Act if it enters into a self-determination or self-governance agreement with the Secretary regarding such assumption or use. Requires the Board to use land occupied by the Chemawa Indian School for the collective benefit of the Oregon tribes, if the Secretary certifies that it is no longer needed for Indian education.</summary>
</bill>
