<bill session="112" type="h" number="2314" updated="2013-07-20T01:30:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Interagency Personnel Rotation Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase the efficiency and effectiveness of the Government by providing for greater interagency experience among national security and homeland security personnel through the development of a national security and homeland security human capital strategy and interagency rotational service by employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400633"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2012-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2012-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2012-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2012-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2011-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, Homeland Security, Foreign Affairs, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight, Investigations, and Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM09" subcommittee="Oversight, Investigations, and Management" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="1268"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2011--Introduced.
Interagency Personnel Rotation Act of 2011 - Establishes a Committee on National Security Personnel (Committee) within the Executive Office of the President. Requires such Committee to issue a National Security Human Capital Strategy to develop the national security and homeland security personnel necessary to accomplish national security and homeland security objectives that require integration of personnel and activities from multiple executive branch agencies to maximize mission success and minimize cost. Requires the Committee to identify a National Security Interagency Community of Interest (ICI) for purposes of carrying out this Act and to provide for employees serving in an ICI position to be assigned on a rotational basis to another ICI position that is within a related agency or within an interagency body. Defines "ICI position" as a position whose duties primarily relate to national security or homeland security policy formulation or execution. Provides for a system of interagency rotational service by which employees with national security and homeland security expertise serve for a period of time in other agencies with a national security mission. Makes such interagency rotational service a requirement for selection to the Senior Executive Service. Requires employees serving in an ICI position to participate in orientation training and education on national security and homeland security strategy. Requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to establish a course for political appointees relating to the objectives, history, and functioning of the senior-level interagency process and strategies for ensuring maximum interagency cohesion and the accomplishment of national security and homeland security objectives in an efficient and effective manner.</summary>
</bill>
