<bill session="111" type="s" number="2872" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-12">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize appropriations for the National Historical Publications and Records Commission through fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2009-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13034-13035"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13035" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with amendments. With written report No. 111-213.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-06-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="438">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 438.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2010-07-12" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5750" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5750" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13T17:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1556"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5616"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Humanities programs funding"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2010--Passed Senate amended.
Authorizes appropriations for the National Historical Publications and Records Commission for FY2010-FY2014. Amends the Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000 with respect to the Federal National and Regional Records Center Revolving Fund. Increases from 4% to 10% the maximum amount of the Fund's total income that may be retained as an operating reserve or for the replacement or acquisition of capital equipment and other support systems of the National Archives and Records Administration. Increases from 4% to 10% the threshold amount in excess of which any amounts remaining in the Fund at the close of each fiscal year that must be returned to the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts. Amends the Presidential Historical Records Preservation Act of 2008 to shift from the Commission to the Archivist the authority to make grants for establishment of state and local databases for records of servitude, emancipation, and post-civil war reconstruction. Requires the Archivist to consider Commission advice and recommendations before making such a grant.</summary>
</bill>
