<bill session="111" type="s" number="3924" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Accountability in Health Care Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote transparency and accountability concerning the implementation of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2010-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Public Accountability in Health Care Implementation Act - Sets forth procedures for rules implementing the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA). Requires a federal official responsible for issuance of a rule under PPACA to promulgate the final rule not later than: (1) 60 days after the termination of any specified comment period for the interim final rule, taking into account any comments received during such period; or (2) 90 days after such an interim final rule is issued if the federal official responsible fails to provide for such comment period, taking into account comments received during a subsequent comment period. Applies this Act to any interim final rule issued under PPACA prior to, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act. Requires the 60-day and the 90-day periods for any interim final rules issued prior to enactment of this Act to commence upon enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
