<bill session="111" type="h" number="1918" updated="2013-07-19T23:29:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Western Hemisphere Energy Security Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit United States companies to participate in the exploration for and the extraction of hydrocarbon resources from any portion of a foreign maritime exclusive economic zone that is contiguous to the exclusive economic zone of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2009-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
Western Hemisphere Energy Security Act of 2009 - Permits U.S. persons (including agents and affiliates) to: (1) engage in any transaction necessary for exploration and extraction of hydrocarbon resources from any portion of a foreign exclusive economic zone that is contiguous to the exclusive economic zone of the United States; (2) export without license authority all equipment necessary for such exploration or extraction; and (3) import into the United States the hydrocarbon resources and products that are extracted under this Act. Amends the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 to instruct the Secretary of the Treasury to authorize under a general license certain travel-related transactions for travel to, from, or within Cuba in connection with exploration and extraction of hydrocarbon resources in any part of a foreign maritime exclusive economic zone that is contiguous to the United States exclusive economic zone.Includes among persons authorized to travel to Cuba under this Act full-time employees, executives, agents, and consultants of oil and gas producers, distributors, and shippers.</summary>
</bill>
