<bill session="111" type="h" number="1401" updated="2013-07-19T23:24:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">VET Corps Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create a service corps of veterans called Veterans Engaged for Tomorrow (VET) Corps focused on promoting and improving the service opportunities for veterans and retired members of the military by engaging such veterans and retired members in projects designed to meet identifiable public needs with a specific emphasis on projects to support veterans, including disabled and older veterans and retired members of the military.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412212"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412224" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400281" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412192" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2009-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2009--Introduced.
VET Corps Act of 2009 - Amends the National and Community Service Act of 1990 to direct the Corporation for National and Community Service to establish the Veterans Engaged for Tomorrow Corps (VET Corps), composed of veterans, retired military personnel, and their family members to: (1) help veterans, retired military personnel, and their family members obtain training, certification, or access to education or employers and otherwise to serve their communities through national and community service programs; (2) support existing outreach efforts to inform veterans about available services and benefits; (3) act as a clearinghouse for persons desiring to serve the veteran population; (4) coordinate with other departments and agencies to identify and address existing and future needs and challenges of veterans; and (5) provide veterans with opportunities to adjust to civilian life. Allows individuals to serve as VET Corps members for up to 24 months. Outlines VET Corps membership requirements and authorized benefits while performing or participating in VET Corps projects. Directs the Corporation to make grants to veteran service organizations, nonprofit organizations, federal agencies, state or local governments, or institutions of higher education for establishing, operating, and supporting VET Corps projects.</summary>
</bill>
