<bill session="113" type="h" number="2168" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Heroes Vote Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to promote the efficient delivery and receipt of absentee ballots and other voting materials to absent uniformed services voters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412584"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="123"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Helping Heroes Vote Act of 2013 - Amends the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (the Act) to direct the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to notify the appropriate election official of the state in which a servicemember is registered to vote of any change in the servicemember's current mailing address due to being deployed on active duty for more than 30 days away from his or her permanent duty station or being redeployed without first returning to such duty station. Repeals a state's authority to waive ballot transmission requirements with respect to absentee military voters and overseas citizens who request such ballots within 45 days of a federal election. Requires the use of express delivery in the case of a failure to meet such requirement. Requires each state to establish alternative procedures to accept and process absentee ballots of military voters and overseas citizens in the event of a major disaster in that state. Prohibits a state from refusing to accept voter registration and absentee ballot applications from overseas voters (under current law, only from absent servicemember voters) on the grounds of early submission. Authorizes additional funding to carry out the Act.</summary>
</bill>
