<bill session="109" type="h" number="6094" updated="2013-07-19T19:58:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-21T14:01:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-21T14:01:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Protection Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Community Protection Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restore the Secretary of Homeland Security's authority to detain dangerous aliens, to ensure the removal of deportable criminal aliens, and combat alien gang crime.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400633" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400658" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400287" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2006-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20T19:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1018 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4830, H.R. 6094 and H.R. 6095. In each case, the bill shall be considered as read; no amendments shall be in order; and the previous question shall be considered as ordered to final passage, without intervening motion, except one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1018.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6869-6879" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4830, H.R. 6094 and H.R. 6095. In each case, the bill shall be considered as read; no amendments shall be in order; and the previous question shall be considered as ordered to final passage, without intervening motion, except one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21T12:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 6094.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6876" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21T13:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gutierrez moved to recommit with instructions to Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6876" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6876" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21T13:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gutierrez motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment inserting a new section entitled Provision of Additional Resources to Apprehend Criminal Aliens.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21T13:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Sensenbrenner stated that the provisions of the instructions were not germane to the bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21T13:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21T13:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gutierrez appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21T13:52:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 225 - 195 (Roll no. 464).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-09-21T14:01:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="465" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 328 - 95 (Roll no. 465).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6869-6872" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21T14:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="1018"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="1018"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="6089"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="6090"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Automobile theft"/>
    <term name="Burglary"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Right of asylum"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2006--Passed House without amendment.
Community Protection Act of 2006 - Title I: Dangerous Alien Detention Act of 2006 - (Sec. 101) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to permit indefinite detention of specified dangerous aliens under orders of removal who cannot be removed, subject to review every six months. States that habeas corpus review of such provisions shall be available only in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia after exhaustion of administrative remedies. Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) detain an alien subject to an administrative final order of removal who has been granted a stay of removal during the pendency of such stay; and (2) parole an alien ordered removed and provide that such alien not be detained unless removal becomes foreseeable or the alien violates parole conditions. Requires that a detention review process be established for aliens under order of removal who have effected an entry and are cooperating with removal. (Sec. 102) Authorizes indefinite detention of an inadmissible alien until such alien is subject to an administrative final order of removal. States that habeas corpus review of such provision shall be available only in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia after exhaustion of administrative remedies. Title II: Criminal Alien Removal Act - (Sec. 201) Provides for expedited removal of aliens removable on criminal grounds. Title III: Alien Gang Removal Act of 2006 - (Sec. 301) Makes an alien inadmissible for U.S. entry if: (1) such alien has been deported for criminal street gang participation; or (2) the consular officer or the Secretary knows or has reasonable grounds to believe that such alien is a member of a criminal street gang seeking U.S. entry in furtherance of gang-related crimes or activities or is a member of a designated criminal street gang. Defines: (1) criminal street gang; and (2) gang crime. Makes an alien deportable who: (1) is a street gang member convicted of committing or attempting to commit a gang crime; or (2) is determined by the Secretary to be a member of a designated criminal street gang. Authorizes the Attorney General to designate a group or association as a criminal street gang. Requires the Attorney General to provide specified congressional leaders with prior notice of, and the factual basis for, such designation. Provides for revocation of such designation by: (1) an Act of Congress; (2) the Attorney General's review based upon changed circumstances or national security; or (3) judicial appeal or petition to the Attorney General by a gang or association so designated. (Sec. 302) Requires mandatory detention of aliens subject to removal based upon criminal street gang membership. (Sec. 303) Makes such aliens ineligible for asylum and protection from removal to certain countries.</summary>
</bill>
