<bill session="112" type="h" number="685" updated="2013-07-20T01:16:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Checkpoint Images Protection Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to criminalize the unauthorized recording and distribution of security screening images of individuals created by advanced imaging technology utilized by the Transportation Security Administration or other Federal authority, require the Transportation Security Administration to disable image retention capabilities of advanced imaging technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2011-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2011-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2011-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2011-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2011-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM" subcommittee="Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2011--Introduced.
Checkpoint Images Protection Act of 2011 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose a fine and/or prison term of up to one year on any individual who knowingly: (1) photographs or otherwise records an image produced using advanced imaging technology during the screening of an individual at an airport or upon entry into any building owned or operated by the federal government without express authorization pursuant to a federal law or regulation, or (2) distributes such image to any individual who is not authorized pursuant to a federal law or regulation to receive it.&#160; Exempts individuals who, within the scope of their employment, record or distribute an image solely to be used in a criminal investigation or prosecution or in an investigation relating to foreign intelligence or a threat to the national security. Directs the Assistant Secretary, Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to certify that, in order to improve airport security screening processes while ensuring passenger privacy protection, the image retention capabilities of all advanced imaging technology utilized by TSA to screen passengers at checkpoints in our nation's airports have been disabled.</summary>
</bill>
