<bill session="111" type="s" number="659" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving the Teaching and Learning of American History and Civics Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Improving the Teaching and Learning of American History and Civics Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the teaching and learning of American history and civics.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300002"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2009-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2009-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3567-3571"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Economic theory"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2009--Introduced.
Improving the Teaching and Learning of American History and Civics Act of 2009 - Creates a new part E (American History and Civics Education) under title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA), under which are placed the existing Teaching of Traditional American History, Civic Education (containing the We the People and Cooperative Civic Education and Economic Education Exchange programs), and Close Up Fellowship programs. Establishes, under part E of title II of the ESEA, programs requiring the Secretary to award competitive matching grants to IHEs, museums, libraries, research centers, or certain other educational institutions to establish Presidential Academies for Teaching of American History and Civics and Congressional Academies for Students of American History and Civics which offer seminars or institutes for teachers and outstanding students of such subjects, respectively. Creates, under part E, a program authorizing the Secretary to provide grants or contracts to National History Day, Inc. for specified activities promoting and improving the study of history. Repeals the American History and Civics Education Act of 2004, which contained a version of the Presidential Academies, Congressional Academies, and National History Day programs. Reauthorizes part E programs through FY2015. Amends the ESEA to require states to: (1) establish challenging academic content and student achievement standards in U.S. history, beginning in the 2011-2012 school year; and (2) measure the achievement of students against such standards at least one time during grades 3 through 5, grades 6 through 9, and grades 10 through 12, beginning in the 2012-2013 school year. Improving the Teaching and Learning of American History and Civics Act of 2009 - Amends the National Assessment of Educational Progress Authorization Act to direct the Commissioner for Education Statistics to: (1) give priority to conducting national assessments of student achievement in history at least once every four years in grades 4, 8, and 12; and (2) conduct trial state academic assessments of student achievement in U.S. history and civics in grades 8 and 12.</summary>
</bill>
