<bill session="110" type="h" number="5705" updated="2013-07-19T21:53:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Energy Partnership with India Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a commission to study methods for improving and promoting bilateral renewable energy cooperation between the United States and India, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2008-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2008--Introduced.
Clean Energy Partnership with India Act of 2008 - Establishes in the legislative branch the Congressional Commission on Renewable Power Technology Commerce with India to: (1) study methods for improvement and promotion of bilateral renewable energy cooperation between the United States and India; and (2) recommend to Congress and the President methods and strategies to develop joint energy policy between the United States and India for reliable energy throughout India using renewable, environmentally-friendly means of production. Requires the Secretary of State to report to Congress on: (1) the extent to which energy is reliably available in India and what portion of it is produced through renewable means; (2) estimated investment, export, and job creation potential if U.S. industry plays a central role in the production and distribution of renewable energy in India; (3) estimated economic benefits and poverty reduction that would result if India's energy needs were met through renewable energy; (4) the estimated level of greenhouse gasses that India would produce in the coming years if it did not pursue renewable means of energy production; and (5) recommendations for the federal government and the private sector regarding technical assistance with the investment, production, and distribution of renewable energy in India. Directs the President to seek to establish a permanent joint renewable energy council between the United States and India to advise the President of the United States and the Prime Minister of India on promotion of environmentally sustainable economic growth in India and the United States through public policy regarding investment, production, and distribution of renewable energy in India.</summary>
</bill>
