<bill session="109" type="hr" number="571" updated="2013-07-19T18:59:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18T23:31:00-05:00">FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-11-18T23:31:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the deployment of United States forces in Iraq be terminated immediately.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18T20:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 572 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 571 and H. Con. Res. 308 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Sec. 2. Upon adoption of this resolution, House Concurrent Resolution is hereby adopted. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18T21:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 572.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11005-11025" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11005" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18T21:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 571 and H. Con. Res. 308 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Sec. 2. Upon adoption of this resolution, House Concurrent Resolution 308 is adopted. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18T21:50:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 571.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18T23:05:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11025" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE" datetime="2005-11-18T23:31:00-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="608" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Failed by recorded vote: 3 - 403, 6 Present (Roll no. 608).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18T23:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="572"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="572"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military withdrawal"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2005--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the deployment of U.S. forces in Iraq be terminated immediately.</summary>
</bill>
