<bill session="112" type="s" number="2139" updated="2013-07-20T02:35:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Contingency Contracting Reform Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance security, increase accountability, and improve the contracting of the Federal Government for overseas contingency operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2012-02-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-17">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Subcommittee on Contracting Oversight. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-659.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSGA13" subcommittee="Contracting Oversight (Ad Hoc)" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4259"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2234"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3286"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/29/2012--Introduced.
Comprehensive Contingency Contracting Reform Act of 2012 - Requires the President, in making any request for financing an overseas contingency operation (OCO), to include in such request a specific statement of the requested funds and a specific proposal to finance the amount requested. Designates the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) as the principal advisor to the President on financial matters in connection with OCOs. Sets forth the responsibilities of specified Inspectors General for OCOs and requires the appointment of a designated lead Inspector General for any OCO that exceeds 30 days. Expands the responsibilities of the Chief Acquisition Officers in federal agencies to include oversight of contracts and contracting activities for OCOs. Includes contracts for support of OCOs in the management structure of the Department of Defense (DOD), Department of State, and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID). Requires the designation of at least one suspension and debarment official for each federal agency. Expands the bases for the suspension of contractors from contracting with the federal government. Requires the DOD Secretary to prescribe in regulations the chain of authority and responsibility for policy, planning, and execution of contract support for OCOs. Requires the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to provide quarterly assessments of the capability of OCOs to support current and anticipated wartime missions and to recommend resources required to improve and enhance support and planning for such operational contract support. Requires the inclusion of matters relating to OCOs in joint professional military education. Establishes: (1) within the Department of State the Office of Acquisition and Logistics to oversee acquisition, procurement, and logistics management activities in the Department of State; and (2) within USAID the Office of Acquisition and Assistance to direct, manage, and oversee USAID acquisition and procurement activities. Requires the Secretary of State to: (1) conduct a quadrennial diplomacy and development review of U.S. diplomatic and overseas development strategy, with a view toward determining such U.S. strategy for the next 20 years; and (2) develop and administer a course for Department of State personnel on acquisition for Department of State support and participation in OCOs. Limits periods for OCO contracts to three years for competitively bid contracts and one year for non-competitively bid contracts. Limits service contracts to a single tier of subcontractors. Requires: (1) a review, risk analysis, and report on the performance of security functions of OCOs; (2) a justification and approval for sole-source OCO contracts; and (3) the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish and maintain a separate uniform contract writing system for all executive agencies, except for DOD, which shall establish and maintain its own system. Requires the Administrator of Federal Procurement Policy to establish and maintain a database of prices of items and services charged the federal government under government contracts to assist federal acquisition officials in monitoring developments in such prices and conducting pricing or cost analyses. Requires contractors and related entities to consent to personal jurisdiction for civil actions on overseas contracts valued at more than $5 million. Amends the federal criminal code to impose a fine and/or prison term of up to five years on any individual who knowingly and with intent to defraud recruits, solicits, or hires a person outside the United States to work on on a government contract performed on government facilities outside the United States by means of materially false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises regarding such employment. Authorizes the termination of a contract if a contractor or subcontractor engages in severe forms of human trafficking. Requires the DOD Secretary to certify to Congress that a country in which a capital project for an OCO (i.e., a project with an estimated cost in excess of $1 million) is being carried out has the capability to maintain and utilize such project.</summary>
</bill>
