<bill session="112" type="s" number="602" updated="2013-07-20T02:21:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clearing Unnecessary Regulatory Burdens Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">CURB Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require regulatory reform.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2011-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2011-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1757"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-220.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-20">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-220.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1960"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2011--Introduced.
Clearing Unnecessary Regulatory Burdens Act or the CURB Act - Requires each federal agency to: (1) report to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs on the costs and benefits of each significant regulatory action and of identified alternatives; (2) develop or have written procedures for the approval of significant guidance documents; (3) maintain on its website a list of such documents in effect; (4) establish and advertise on its website a means for the public to electronically submit comments on such documents and a request for issuance, reconsideration, modification, or rescission of such documents; and (5) publish a notice in the Federal Register announcing that a draft of an economically significant guidance document is available, make such document publicly available, invite comment on such draft, and respond to such comments. Defines a "significant regulatory action" as any regulatory action that is likely to result in a regulation that may: (1) have an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more or adversely affect in a material way the economy, a sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, or state, local, or tribal governments or communities; (2) create a serious inconsistency or otherwise interfere with an action taken or planned by another agency; (3) materially alter the budgetary impact of entitlements, grants, user fees, or loan programs or the rights and obligations of recipients thereof; or (4) raise novel legal or policy issues arising out of legal mandates and the priorities, principles, and provisions of this Act. Authorizes an agency head, in consultation with such Office, to identify a particular document or category of such documents for which the procedures of this Act are not feasible or appropriate. Requires agencies to notify the Administrator &#160;in emergency situations or when they are&#160;obligated by law to act more quickly than normal review procedures allow. Allows a reduction or waiver of civil penalties on small entities for failure to comply with regulatory requirements.</summary>
</bill>
