<bill session="112" type="hr" number="174" updated="2013-07-20T01:04:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-17T10:57:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-03-17T10:57:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1076) to prohibit Federal funding of National Public Radio and the use of Federal funds to acquire radio content.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-16T18:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-35, by Mr. Nugent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-16T18:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. Although the rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill, the Committee is not aware of any points of order. The waiver is prophylactic in nature. Although the rule waives all points of order against provisions in the bill, the Committee is not aware of any points of order against any of the provisions in the bill. The waiver of all points of order against provisions in the bill is prophylactic in nature.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-03-16T18:57:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="19">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 19.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17T09:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1911-1920" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17T09:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 174.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17T10:46:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 233 - 179 (Roll no. 189).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1919" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17T10:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Point of order raised by Mr. Weiner on the content of the measure. Mr. Weiner stated that the underlying bill made in order by H. Res. 174 had not been posted online for 72 hours, and as such, was in violation of the rules of the House. Point of order overruled by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-03-17T10:57:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="190" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 236 - 181 (Roll no. 190).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1911" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17T10:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="1076"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2011--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1076) to prohibit Federal funding of National Public Radio and the use of Federal funds to acquire radio content.</summary>
</bill>
