<bill session="109" type="h" number="619" updated="2013-07-19T19:09:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Denver Federal Center Redevelopment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 40, United States Code, to authorize the Administrator of General Services to lease and redevelop certain Federal property on the Denver Federal Center in Lakewood, Colorado.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400020"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="1611"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2005--Introduced.
Denver Federal Center Redevelopment Act - Authorizes the Administrator of General Services to enter into leases of Federal real property, including improvements thereon, with totally nonfederal entities to provide for the construction, rehabilitation, operation, maintenance, or use of all, or portions of, the Denver Federal Center. Lists terms and conditions for such a lease (master lease), including that it: (1) have as its primary purpose enhancing the value of the Center; (2) be negotiated pursuant to such procedures as the Administrator considers necessary to ensure the integrity of the selection process and to protect U.S. interests; (3) be for a term not to exceed 50 years; and (4) provide that all development risk remain with the nonfederal entity. Directs that a master lease be for fair consideration. Requires that net proceeds from a master lease be deposited into, administered, and expended, subject to appropriations Acts, as part of the Federal Building Fund. Authorizes the Administrator to retain from the proceeds of a master lease amounts necessary to recover the expenses incurred by the Administrator with respect to such lease.</summary>
</bill>
