<bill session="110" type="h" number="5939" updated="2013-07-19T21:55:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Montgomery GI Bill Degree Extension Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to extend the time limitation for the use of entitlement to educational assistance under the Montgomery GI Bill for certain persons actively pursuing a qualifying educational degree or certificate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412258"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-01">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-01">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3082"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2008--Introduced.
Montgomery GI Bill Degree Extension Act of 2008 - Extends the time limitation (generally ten years from the original eligibility date) for the use of educational assistance under the Montgomery GI Bill all-volunteer force educational assistance program, in the case of an individual who has completed at least 50% of the credit or time requirements leading to a degree or certificate before the last day of the ten-year period, to the earlier of: (1) the date on which the individual completes such requirements; or (2) two years after the last day of the ten-year period.</summary>
</bill>
