<bill session="109" type="s" number="1721" updated="2013-07-19T20:28:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Heritage Area Extension Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Mississippi River National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 to extend the authorization for certain national heritage areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2005-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2005-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2005-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2005-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2005-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2005-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2005-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2006-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-663.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2005--Introduced.
National Heritage Area Extension Act of 2005 - Amends the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 to: (1) extend to September 30, 2027, the authorization for making grants or providing assistance with respect to the National Coal Heritage Area, Tennessee Civil War Heritage Area, Augusta Canal National Heritage Area, Steel Industry American Heritage Area, Essex National Heritage Area, South Carolina National Heritage Corridor, America's Agricultural Partnership, Ohio &amp; Erie Canal National Heritage Corridor (redesignated by this Act as the Ohio &amp; Erie National Heritage Canalway), and Hudson River Valley National Heritage Area; and (2) increase the amount authorized to be appropriated for such areas. Adds Lincoln County, West Virginia, and Paint Creek and Cabin Creek in Kanawha County, West Virginia, to the National Coal Heritage Area. Requires, with respect to such Area, the Secretary of the Interior to continue a certain contractual agreement with the National Coal Heritage Area Authority rather than the Governor of West Virginia. Adds Berkeley County, South Carolina, to the South Carolina Heritage Area. Reauthorizes appropriations for the New Jersey Coastal Heritage Trail Route. Directs the Secretary to prepare a strategic plan for the Route. Adds six members to the John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Commission. Requires the Commission to update the Corridor plan. Mississippi River National Heritage Area Act - Establishes the Mississippi River National Heritage Area. Provides authorities and duties of the management entity for such Area, including development of an Area management plan.</summary>
</bill>
