<bill session="109" type="s" number="3042" updated="2013-07-19T20:40:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">All-Hazards Public Health Emergency and Bioterrorism Preparedness and Response Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve preparedness for and response to bioterrorism and other public health emergencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300006"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2006-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public health administration"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2006--Introduced.
All-Hazards Public Health Emergency and Bioterrorism Preparedness and Response Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) establish guidelines for preparedness grantees to conduct assessments of public health capacities; (2) dispense only 50% of a preparedness grant unless the entity has an approved preparedness and response plan; (3) establish measurable performance standards with respect to basic preparedness for identified public health threats; and (4) study the size and scope of the health care and public health workforces necessary to respond to common public health issues and emergencies. Establishes within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Public Health to carry out the public health preparedness functions of HHS. Conditions the receipt of grant funds on an entity having a plan for operational continuity in the event of bioterrorism or another public health emergency. Establishes a fund to provide short-term assistance to health care providers and members of the public health workforce in the event of bioterrorism or another public health emergency. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish the Public Health Workforce Scholarship Program to offer scholarships in return for working at federal, state, local, and tribal public health agencies; (2) establish the Public Health Workforce Loan Repayment Program to provide for the repayment of loans in exchange for working at such agencies; and (3) award grants to public health agencies for workforce loan repayment programs.</summary>
</bill>
