<bill session="110" type="h" number="774" updated="2013-07-19T21:10:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rape Prevention and Education Grant Program Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to extend the program of grants for rape prevention education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400260"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2007--Introduced.
Rape Prevention and Education Grant Program Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations for FY2008-FY2012 for grants to states for rape prevention and education programs conducted by rape crisis centers, state sexual assault coalitions, and other public and private nonprofit entities. Earmarks a portion of such funds for the provision of resource information, policy, training, and technical assistance to federal, state, local, and Indian tribal agencies, state sexual assault coalitions, local sexual assault programs, and other professionals and interested parties on issues relating to sexual assault, including maintenance of a central resource library to collect, prepare, analyze, and disseminate information, statistics, and analyses relating to the incidence and prevention of sexual assault.</summary>
</bill>
