<bill session="111" type="s" number="555" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District Land Exchange Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District Land Exchange Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the exchange of certain land located in the Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forests in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2009-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2966"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-223.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-131.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="281">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 281.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="3923"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3923"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District Land Exchange Act of 2009 - Requires the Secretary of Agriculture, if the Sugar Loaf Fire Protection District of Boulder, Colorado, offers to convey specified non-federal land in unincorporated Boulder County and the offer is acceptable to the Secretary, to accept the offer and, on receipt of acceptable title in and to the non-federal land, to convey federal land in the Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forests in Colorado. Makes provisions relating to the exchange of public lands and interests within the National Forest System under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 applicable to the land exchange authorized by this Act, except that: (1) the Secretary may accept a cash equalization payment in excess of 25% of value of the federal land; and (2) as a condition of the exchange, the District shall pay costs related to land surveys and appraisals of the federal and non-federal land and enter into an agreement with the Secretary that allocates any other administrative costs between the Secretary and the District. Expresses the intent of Congress that the land exchange be completed within one year after enactment of this Act. Allows the Secretary to offer to sell the federal land to the District if the exchange is not completed by that deadline. Permits the Secretary to offer the federal land for sale to the District for its fair market value. Requires amounts received as a result of any cash equalization payment and any sale of the federal land carried out pursuant to this Act to be available for the acquisition of land or interests in the Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forests. Requires the acquired non-federal land to become part of the Arapaho-Roosevelt National Forests. Revokes any public orders withdrawing the federal land from entry and appropriation under the public land laws to the extent necessary to permit conveyance of the federal land to the District. Withdraws the federal land, unless it is already withdrawn or segregated from entry and appropriation under such laws, including the mining and mineral leasing laws and the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970, until it is conveyed to the District.</summary>
</bill>
