<bill session="111" type="h" number="6189" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">EEOICPA Amendment Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to establish the Advisory Board on Toxic Substances and Worker Health for the contractor employee compensation program under subtitle E of such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400431"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2010-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2010--Introduced.
EEOICPA Amendment Act of 2010 - Amends the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to require the President to establish an Advisory Board on Toxic Substances and Worker Health. Requires the Board to advise the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Energy (DOE), and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) on the review and approval of the site exposure matrix (SEM) used to determine the eligibility of DOE contractor employee claims for compensation for illnesses resulting from exposure to toxic substances. (The SEM is a Department of Labor database on the presence of toxic substances at DOE and Radiation Exposure Compensation Act [RECA] facilities, as well as of information on scientifically established links between toxic substances and illnesses.)</summary>
</bill>
