<bill session="111" type="s" number="944" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wounded Warrior Transition Assistance Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to require the Secretaries of the military departments to give wounded members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces the option of remaining on active duty during the transition process in order to continue to receive military pay and allowances, to authorize members to reside at their permanent places of residence during the process, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2009-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4968-4969"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2009--Introduced.
Wounded Warrior Transition Assistance Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of each military department to provide each reserve member of that department who is being evaluated for separation or retirement for disability, or for placement on the temporary disability retired list or inactive status list, the option to remain on active duty during such evaluation in order to continue to receive military pay and allowances, until the member is: (1) cleared to return to duty; or (2) separated, retired, or placed on the temporary disability retired or inactive status list. Requires each Secretary to retain on active duty (for pay and allowances purposes) a reserve member who incurs an injury or illness while on active duty, is being discharged or separated from the Armed Forces, or is being released from active duty, and is not being evaluated in connection with such discharge, separation, or release, until the member is: (1) retired or placed on the temporary disability retired or inactive status list; or (2) determined ineligible for such care or benefits based solely upon the injury or illness. Requires military human resources commands to return to active duty during their evaluation period reserve members who request such option. Encourages the use of local residences by reserve members during such transition periods. Authorizes the use of Defense Health Program funds for reserve members who become ill or injured while on active duty and separate as a result of such illness or injury. Provides for the assignment of Judge Advocate General personnel to assist members of the Armed Forces (members) in connection with the medical discharge process and disability evaluations. Expresses support for access of veterans service organizations to military facilities to provide counseling and services to members.</summary>
</bill>
