<bill session="113" type="s" number="344" updated="2013-11-02T06:55:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from approving the introduction into commerce of gasoline that contains greater than 10-volume-percent ethanol, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2013-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1462"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1469"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2013--Introduced.
Prohibits the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) from authorizing or otherwise allowing the introduction into commerce of gasoline that contains greater than 10-volume-percent ethanol, including by granting a waiver for new fuels and fuel additives from the Clean Air Act's fuel standards. Nullifies any waiver granted under such Act before this Act's enactment that allows for the introduction into commerce of gasoline containing greater than 10-volume-percent ethanol for use in motor vehicles, including the waivers entitled: (1) "Partial Grant and Partial Denial of Clean Air Act Waiver Application Submitted by Growth Energy To Increase the Allowable Ethanol Content of Gasoline to 15 Percent; Decision of the Administrator" (published on November 4, 2010), and (2) "Partial Grant of Clean Air Act Waiver Application Submitted by Growth Energy To Increase the Allowable Ethanol Content of Gasoline to 15 Percent; Decision of the Administrator" (published on January 26, 2011). Nullifies, 60 days after this Act's enactment, the portions of the rule entitled "Regulation to Mitigate the Misfueling of Vehicles and Engines with Gasoline Containing Greater Than Ten Volume Percent Ethanol and Modifications to the Reformulated and Conventional Gasoline Programs" (published on July 25, 2011) to mitigate misfueling.</summary>
</bill>
