<bill session="113" type="h" number="3056" updated="2013-11-02T06:44:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Warriors' Peer-Outreach Pilot Program Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program on the provision of outreach and support services to veterans pursuing higher education under the Post 9/11 Educational Assistance Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412520"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412516" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
Warriors' Peer-Outreach Pilot Program Act - Directs the Secretary of Veteran Affairs to carry out a three-year pilot program to provide outreach and support services to veterans at institutions of higher learning that enable them to make more successful use of their entitlement to educational assistance. Requires the Secretary to select one four-year public university, one community college, and one private nonprofit college at which to conduct the pilot program. Requires the pilot program to provide peer-outreach and peer-support services to students at such institutions who are veterans of Operation Enduring Freedom, Operation Iraqi Freedom, and Operation New Dawn by employing veterans who: (1) are using, or have successfully used, their entitlement to educational assistance; and (2) have served on active duty in a theater of combat operations. Directs the Secretary to provide training to the veterans employed by the pilot program and to develop requirements and measures for assessing the effectiveness of program services.</summary>
</bill>
