<bill session="109" type="s" number="56" updated="2013-07-19T20:13:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-10-12">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rio Grande Natural Area Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Rio Grande Natural Area Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Rio Grande Natural Area Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Rio Grande Natural Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Rio Grande Natural Area in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300003"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2005-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-02-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-03-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici under authority of the order of the Senate of 3-17-2005 without amendment. With written report No. 109-45.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-03-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="64">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 64.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2005-07-26" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9018-9052" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9045-9046" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-01">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gohmert moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7657-7659" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 56.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2006-09-27T23:22:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7657-7658" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2006-10-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-10-12">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2006-10-12" type="public" number="109-337">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-337.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/2006--Public Law.
Rio Grande Natural Area Act - (Sec. 3) Establishes the Rio Grande Natural Area in Colorado (which shall include the Rio Grande River from the southern boundary of the Alamosa National Wildlife Refuge to the New Mexico State border, extending 1/4 mile on either side of the bank of the River) to conserve, restore, and protect the natural, historic, cultural, scientific, scenic, wildlife, and recreational resources of the Area. (Sec. 4) Establishes the Rio Grande Natural Area Commission to: (1) advise the Secretary of the Interior with respect to the Area; and (2) prepare a management plan relating to nonfederal land in the Area. (Sec. 5) Sets forth provisions governing the powers of the Commission, including authorizing the Commission to enter into cooperative agreements for purposes of carrying out such management plan on nonfederal land in the Area. Prohibits the Commission from acquiring any real property or interest in real property. Directs the Commission to assist the Secretary in implementing such management plan by carrying out authorized activities to preserve and interpret the Area's natural, historic, cultural, scientific, scenic, wildlife, and recreational resources. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to prepare a management plan for Federal land in the Area. Requires the Commission to submit its management plan for the management of the nonfederal land in the Area to the Secretary for approval or disapproval. (Sec. 7) Requires the Secretary to administer the Federal land in the Area in accordance with the laws applicable to public land and the management plan in a manner that provides for: (1) education, scientific study, and limited public recreation; (2) the protection of the wildlife habitat; (3) a prohibition on the construction of water storage facilities; and (4) the reduction in the use or removal of roads in the Area. Encourages the Secretary to negotiate with the State, the Rio Grande Water Conservation District, and affected water users concerning changes in the streamflow. Applies the management plan for the nonfederal land to private land in the Area only if the private landowner agrees to be bound by such plan. Permits the Secretary to acquire land or an interest in land within the Area from willing sellers. Makes inapplicable Wild and Scenic Rivers Act requirements that Federal agencies consider potential national wild, scenic, and recreational river areas in water and land use planning. (Sec. 8) Prohibits anything in this Act from: (1) modifying the Rio Grande Compact; (2) regulating private land; (3) imposing any mandatory streamflow requirements; (4) creating an express or implied Federal reserved water right; (5) imposing more restrictive Federal water quality standards; or (6) preventing State acquisition of an instream flow to assist in protecting the natural environment. (Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 10) Terminates the Commission ten years after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
