<bill session="112" type="s" number="1581" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FAIR Enforcement Against Duty Evasion Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fighting for American Industry's Right to Enforcement Against Duty Evasion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the importer of record program and the collection of fees and duties in connection with the importation of merchandise into the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6642"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6656"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2011--Introduced.
Fighting for American Industry's Right to Enforcement Against Duty Evasion Act or FAIR Enforcement Against Duty Evasion Act of 2011 - Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to eliminate the option of an importer to post a bond or security in lieu of a cash deposit for each entry of merchandise exported into the United States by a new exporter (shipper) and producer that is the subject of a review by the administering authority as to whether antidumping or countervailing duties shall be imposed on such merchandise. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe minimum standards to require customs brokers to implement, and customers (importers) to comply with, reasonable procedures for collecting information to identify U.S. and non-U.S. customers seeking to import merchandise into the United States. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress recommendations for: (1) determining the most effective way to require foreign nationals to provide customs brokers and federal agencies with accurate information, comparable to that required of U.S. nationals, on the identity of foreign nationals seeking to import merchandise into the United States; and (2) establishing a system for such brokers and agencies to review information maintained by relevant federal agencies to verify the identity of foreign nationals and U.S. nationals who seek to import merchandise into the United States. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to implement certain modifications to the importer of record database.</summary>
</bill>
