<bill session="110" type="s" number="37" updated="2013-07-19T22:20:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Waste Access to Yucca Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance the management and disposal of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste, to assure protection of public health safety, to ensure the territorial integrity and security of the repository at Yucca Mountain, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300036"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2008-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300035" joined="2007-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300097" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2007-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6551-6553"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Mountains"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2007--Introduced.
Nuclear Waste Access to Yucca Act - Withdraws specified lands in Nye County, Nevada, permanently from any form of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws, including: (1) the mineral leasing laws; (2) the geothermal leasing laws; (3) materials sales laws; and (4) the mining laws. Transfers jurisdiction over such lands to the Secretary of Energy. Reserves use of such lands for certain activities associated with the disposal of high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel under the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982. Requires the Secretary to manage the lands so withdrawn, and submit to Congress and the state of Nevada a management plan for their use. Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to direct the Secretary to apply to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) for a license to construct and operate facilities to receive and store spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste at the Yucca Mountain site. Authorizes the Secretary to begin construction of connected infrastructure facilities after completion of a final environmental impact statement evaluating the activities involved. Requires the Secretary to acquire rights-of-way for construction and operation of railroad facilities to transport spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste from existing rail systems to the site of surface facilities within the geologic repository operations area for the receipt, handling, packaging, and storage of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste prior to emplacement. Revises requirements for new plant contracts.</summary>
</bill>
