<bill session="111" type="h" number="6297" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Biosecurity Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the international strategy of the United States for monitoring, reducing, and responding to biological risks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400371"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
International Biosecurity Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of State to establish the International Biosecurity Initiative which shall: (1) pursue efforts to establish international standards for pathogen and laboratory safety; (2) pursue efforts to ensure a strong global legal regime for biosecurity; (3) pursue strategies to strengthen the Convention on the Prohibition of the Development, Production and Stockpiling of Bacteriological (Biological) and Toxin Weapons and on their Destruction; (4) engage in cooperative efforts to improve national, regional, and multinational surveillance and response capabilities with respect to infectious disease outbreaks; (5) support international mechanisms that enhance biosecurity policy coordination; (6) facilitate the alignment of foreign assistance for biosecurity with the public health needs of recipient countries; (7) engage in multilateral and bilateral discussions of biodefense programs and control of sensitive biotechnologies to ensure that they are limited to peaceful purposes; and (8) develop an assessment of the potential security threats and societal and ethical impacts posed by emerging and future biotechnology developments. Directs the Secretary to: (1) convene an International Biosecurity Task Force of experts to serve as a nongovernmental consultative body for the International Biosecurity Initiative; (2) establish the Nonproliferation and Counterterrorism Fellowship Program to provide eligible students and recent graduates educational fellowships for obtaining a deeper understanding of federal efforts to counter terrorist activities and to promote nonproliferation; (3) submit to Congress an assessment of the limits and capabilities of technologies that could be used for investigating biological incidents and allegations of illegal biological weapons activities; (4) submit to Congress an assessment of the global legal regime for biosecurity; and (5) report to Congress following any incident in which a foreign country fails to share information about the outbreak of a previously unknown infectious disease or about an outbreak for which the country is otherwise required to share information.</summary>
</bill>
