<bill session="113" type="h" number="2295" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Basel III CASE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Basel III Commonsense Approach for Small Entities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency to conduct an empirical impact study on proposed rules relating to the International Basel III agreement on general risk-based capital requirements, as they apply to smaller financial institutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412527"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2013-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2547"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2767"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="731"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/2013--Introduced.
Basel III Commonsense Approach for Small Entities Act or Basel III CASE Act - Directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC), and the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, before issuing any final rule in relation to proposals they have issued for the International Basel III agreement on general risk-based capital requirements, to conduct an empirical study that includes: (1) a quantitative analysis of the rule's impact on the U.S. financial services sector, specifically community, mid-size, and regional financial institutions; and (2) a determination of the long-term impact of the rule, including changes to the current risk weight framework. Permits a financial institution to provide information voluntarily for the study upon agency request, but prohibits agencies from requiring such information. Requires the study to be made available to the public for notice and comment.</summary>
</bill>
