<bill session="112" type="h" number="853" updated="2013-07-20T01:17:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transition-to-Success Mentoring Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to award grants to eligible entities to establish, expand, or support school-based mentoring programs to assist at-risk middle school students with the transition from middle school to high school.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412258"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2011-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2011-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2011-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2011-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2011--Introduced.
Transition-to-Success Mentoring Act - Amends title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to reauthorize appropriations under part H (School Dropout Prevention). Establishes a transition-to-success mentoring program under part H of the ESEA requiring the Secretary of Education to award five-year grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) or partnerships between LEAs and community-based nonprofit organizations to establish, expand, or support school-based mentoring programs to assist at-risk students in transitioning from middle to high school. Requires grantees to assign to each at-risk student in his or her middle school a success coach who: (1) creates a plan of success for the student; (2) enters into an agreement with the student's parents regarding their role in implementing such plan; (3) meets with the student at least once a month to assess and assist the student's progress; (4) meets at least quarterly with the student and the student's parents, teachers, or counselors to evaluate the student's progress and revise or establish new goals for the next academic year; and (5) serves as the student's advocate between the student's parents and teachers. Authorizes the use of grant funds to train success coaches and cover the cost of any materials they use under the mentoring program.</summary>
</bill>
