<bill session="111" type="h" number="2290" updated="2013-07-19T23:32:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Uranium Extraction and Milling Control Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the application of measures to foreign persons who transfer to Iran, Syria, or North Korea certain goods, services, or technology that could assist Iran, Syria, or North Korea to extract or mill their domestic sources of uranium ore.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400371"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2009-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6296"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2009--Introduced.
International Uranium Extraction and Milling Control Act of 2009 - States that it shall be U.S. policy to: (1) oppose the transfer to Iran, North Korea, and Syria of goods, services, or technology relevant to their capability to extract or mill uranium ore; and (2) work with like-minded countries to impose international restrictions on such transfers. Amends the Iran, North Korea, and Syria Nonproliferation Act to include in the President's proliferation report to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations identification of every foreign person who on or after January 1, 2009, transferred to Iran, Syria, or North Korea goods, services, or technology that could assist efforts to extract or mill uranium ore within the territory or control of Iran, North Korea, or Syria.</summary>
</bill>
