<bill session="111" type="s" number="893" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Imported and Domestic Product Safety Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Office of Imported and Domestic Product Safety in the Department of Commerce and the Product Safety Coordinating Council to improve the management, coordination, promotion, and oversight of food and product safety responsibilities, to improve consumer and business access to food and product safety information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/2009--Introduced.
Imported and Domestic Product Safety Act of 2009 - Establishes in the Department of Commerce an Office of Imported and Domestic Product Safety to carry out specified duties, including: (1) coordinating all departments and agencies that have product safety responsibilities in a way that protects the health and safety of U.S. consumers and provides consumers and businesses with access to product safety information; (2) improving the www.Recalls.gov website; and (3) developing a publicly accessible database with information about all mandatory and voluntary product safety actions taken by businesses, departments, and agencies. Establishes a Product Safety Coordinating Council to assist the Office's director.</summary>
</bill>
