<bill session="110" type="h" number="62" updated="2013-07-19T21:04:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006 to extend the deadline for the submission of the final report of the Commission on the Implementation of the New Strategic Posture of the United States, to provide for the appointment of additional members for the Commission, to ensure the availability of funds for the Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400017"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Military posture"/>
    <term name="Strategic forces"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006 to: (1) make the chairman of the Commission on the Implementation of the New Strategic Posture of the United States responsible for all Commission financial and administrative matters; (2) extend until 18 months after its first meeting the deadline for the Commission's final report to the congressional defense committees; (3) provide guaranteed Commission funding for FY2008; and (4) terminate the Commission 30 days after the date of its final report. Authorizes the chairmen of the defense committees to jointly appoint up to three additional Commission members.</summary>
</bill>
