<bill session="111" type="s" number="487" updated="2013-07-20T00:27:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stem Cell Research Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for human embryonic stem cell research.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2009-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2009-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2009-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2009-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2562"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2562-2563" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="873"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4808"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cell biology and embryology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/2009--Introduced.
Stem Cell Research Enhancement Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct and support research that utilizes human embryonic stem cells, regardless of the date on which the stem cells were derived from a human embryo. Limits such research to stem cells that meet the following requirements: (1) the stem cells were derived from human embryos donated from in vitro fertilization clinics, were created for the purposes of fertility treatment, and were in excess of the needs of the individuals seeking such treatment; (2) prior to donation, it was determined that the embryos would never be implanted in a woman and would otherwise be discarded; and (3) the individuals seeking fertility treatment donated the embryos with written informed consent and received no financial or other inducements. Requires the Secretary to develop techniques for the isolation, derivation, production, or testing of stem cells that are capable of producing all or almost all of the cell types of the developing body and may result in improved understanding of treatments for diseases and other adverse health conditions, but that are not derived from a human embryo. Requires the Secretary to: (1) provide guidance concerning the next steps required for additional research; (2) prioritize research with the greatest potential for near-term clinical benefit; and (3) take into account techniques outlined by the President's Council on Bioethics and any other appropriate techniques and research.</summary>
</bill>
