<bill session="109" type="s" number="91" updated="2013-07-19T20:14:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthen Social Work Training Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title VII of the Public Health Service Act to ensure that social work students or social work schools are eligible for support under certain programs to assist individuals in pursuing health careers and programs of grants for training projects in geriatrics, and to establish a social work training program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S258"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S259" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="College teachers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Psychologists"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2005--Introduced.
Strengthen Social Work Training Act of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to include clinical psychology and social work programs among eligible health education programs for purposes of receiving grants to: (1) support programs for underrepresented minorities; (2) provide scholarships to disadvantaged students; and (3) offer faculty positions to disadvantaged students. Allows the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to, and enter into contracts with: (1) schools offering degrees in social work to provide support for geriatric training projects; (2) hospitals, schools, or other entities to plan or operate an approved social work training program and to provide financial assistance to program participants that are planning to specialize, work, or teach in the field of social work; and (3) schools offering social work programs to establish, maintain, or improve academic administrative units to provide clinical instruction in social work. Authorizes health maintenance organizations (HMOs) to offer health services through a clinical social worker as provided for under State law.</summary>
</bill>
