<bill session="111" type="h" number="3479" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Scrapping Unsustainable Redundant Programs Leaves Us Solvent Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SURPLUS Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To eliminate duplicative Government programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400155"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO24" subcommittee="Government Management, Organization, and Procurement" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2009--Introduced.
Scrapping Unsustainable Redundant Programs Leaves Us Solvent Act of 2009 or the SURPLUS Act - Requires the Secretaries of Agriculture, Commerce, Defense, Education, Energy, Health and Human Services (HHS), Homeland Security (DHS), Housing and Urban Development (HUD), the Interior, Labor, State, Transportation (DOT), Treasury, and Veterans Affairs (VA), the Attorney General, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) determine if any federal programs within his or her agency are duplicative; (2) submit to Congress, and make available to the public, a report on the results; and (3) terminate or consolidate programs performing similar functions, except for any program that is required or authorized by statute. Considers to be duplicative: (1) a grant program the purpose of which the Secretary determines to be to benefit a specific group that is identical or substantially similar to a group that is eligible for another grant program; and (2) any other program the Secretary determines to be performing the same essential function as another program.</summary>
</bill>
