<bill session="112" type="h" number="3567" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-01T19:19:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-02-01T19:19:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Welfare Integrity Now for Children and Families Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">WIN for Children and Families Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Welfare Integrity Now for Children and Families Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">WIN for Children and Families Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title IV of the Social Security Act to require States to implement policies to prevent assistance under the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) program from being used in strip clubs, casinos, and liquor stores.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400636"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2012-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-01T13:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Boustany moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-01T13:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H315-322" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-01T13:39:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3567.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-01T14:23:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-01T19:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H355-356" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-02-01T19:19:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="20" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 395 - 27 (Roll no. 20).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H315" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-02-01T19:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3630"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3659"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="943"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2012--Passed House amended.
Welfare Integrity Now for Children and Families Act of 2012 or WIN for Children and Families Act - Amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require a state to which a state family assistance grant is made to maintain policies and practices necessary to prevent the use of state TANF assistance in any electronic benefit transfer transaction in a liquor store, casino or gambling establishment, or strip club. Defines "electronic benefit transfer transaction" as the use of a credit or debit card service, automated teller machine (ATM), point-of-sale terminal, or access to an online system for the withdrawal of funds or the processing of a payment for merchandise or a service. Establishes administrative penalties for states which have not reported on their implementation of or enforced such policies and practices.</summary>
</bill>
