<bill session="109" type="h" number="1481" updated="2013-07-19T19:17:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Interstate Transmission Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure reliability of electric service to provide for expansion of electricity transmission networks in order to support competitive electricity markets to modernize regulation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400438"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2005-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-05">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public interest"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/5/2005--Introduced.
Interstate Transmission Act - Amends the Federal Power Act to direct the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to establish, by rule, incentive-based, performance-based, participant-funded, and cost-based rate treatments for the transmission of electric energy in interstate commerce by public utilities. Grants FERC jurisdiction over an Electric Reliability Organization (ERO) certified by FERC, regional entities, and all users, owners, and operators of the bulk-power system, for purposes of approving reliability standards and enforcing compliance with this Act. Prescribes guidelines for ERO certification and reliability standards. Urges the President to negotiate international agreements with the governments of Canada and Mexico to provide for: (1) effective compliance with reliability standards; and (2) the effectiveness of the ERO in the United States and Canada or Mexico. Instructs FERC to establish a regional advisory body on the petition of at least two-thirds of the States within a region that have more than one-half of their electric load served within the region. Exempts Hawaii and Alaska from application of electric reliability standards under this Act. Repeals the requirement for FERC prior authorization of the disposition of public utility facilities. Prescribes FERC preferences for the formation of a transmission organization. Prescribes guidelines for the designation as a national interest electric transmission corridor of any geographic area experiencing or likely to experience electric energy transmission capacity constraints or congestion that adversely affects consumers. Grants FERC permitting authority for the construction or modification of electric transmission facilities in a national interest electric transmission corridor. Grants the consent of Congress to three or more contiguous States to enter into an interstate compact establishing regional transmission siting agencies to facilitate siting of future electric energy transmission facilities within such States and to carry out the electric energy transmission siting responsibilities of such States. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to treat electric transmission property as 15-year property for depreciation income tax deduction purposes under the accelerated cost recovery system.</summary>
</bill>
