<bill session="113" type="h" number="2964" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Savings for Working Families Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish and provide for the treatment of Individual Development Accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400320"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
Savings for Working Families Act of 2013 - Allows certain low-income individuals between age 18 and 61 to establish tax-exempt individual development accounts (IDAs) to pay for certain qualified expenses, including education expenses, first-time homebuyer costs, and business capitalization or expansion costs. Sets forth rules for the establishment, maintenance, and termination of IDAs. Permits tax-free withdrawals from IDAs for qualified expenses, but requires IDA beneficiaries to complete one or more financial education courses prior to making an IDA withdrawal.Allows certain financial institutions, tax-exempt organizations, and Indian tribes to sponsor and administer IDAs. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow such entities a business-related tax credit for the cost of administering IDAs and for making matching contributions to IDAs in parallel accounts. Provides that IDA amounts shall be disregarded for purposes of determining eligibility for assistance under certain means-tested federal programs.</summary>
</bill>
