<bill session="112" type="h" number="4360" updated="2013-07-20T01:47:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate certain segments of the Farmington River and Salmon Brook in the State of Connecticut as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2012-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="2286"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/16/2012--Introduced.
Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic River Act - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate specified segments of the Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook in Connecticut as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to manage: (1) the river segments in accordance with the Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Management Plan, dated June 2011; and (2) coordinate the management responsibilities of the Secretary under this Act relating to such segments with the Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic Committee. Makes the provisions of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act prohibiting federal acquisition of lands by condemnation applicable to the designated segments. Limits the authority of the Secretary to acquire lands for the purposes of such segments to acquisition by donation or with the owner's consent and subject to additional management plan criteria. Prohibits the designation made by this Act from being construed as: (1) prohibiting the potential future licensing or re-licensing of the Rainbow Dam and Reservoir (including associated transmission lines and other project works) by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) as a federally licensed hydroelectric generation project, or (2) affecting the operations of a hydroelectric facility at the Dam and Reservoir. Bars the Lower Farmington River from being administered as part of the National Park System or being subject to System regulations. Revises the description of a specified designated segment of the Farmington River in Connecticut.</summary>
</bill>
