<bill session="109" type="h" number="6079" updated="2013-07-19T19:58:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-27T19:41:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-27T19:41:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hedge Fund Study Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Hedge Fund Study Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the President's Working Group on Financial Markets to conduct a study on the hedge fund industry.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="2006-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T19:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller, Gary moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T19:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7596-7598" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T19:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6079.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-09-27T19:41:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7596" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2006--Passed House amended.
Hedge Fund Study Act - Instructs the President's Working Group on Financial Markets to study and report to certain congressional committees on the hedge fund industry. (Sec. 2) Requires the study to analyze: (1) the changing nature of hedge funds and what characteristics define a hedge fund; (2) the growth of hedge funds within financial markets; (3) the growth of pension funds investing in hedge funds; (4) whether hedge fund investors are able to protect themselves adequately from the risk associated with their investments; (5) whether hedge fund leverage is effectively constrained; (6) the potential risks hedge funds pose to financial markets or to investors; (7) various international approaches to hedge fund regulation; and (8) benefits of the hedge fund industry to the economy and the markets. Requires the recommendations to include: (1) any proposed legislation relating to appropriate disclosure requirements for hedge funds; (2) the type of information hedge funds should disclose to regulators and to the public; (3) any efforts the hedge fund industry or regulators of financial institutions should undertake to improve practices or provide examples of successful industry initiatives; and (4) any oversight responsibilities that members of the President's Working Group should have over the hedge fund industry, and the degree and scope of such oversight.</summary>
</bill>
