<bill session="112" type="h" number="4079" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Housing for Homeless Veterans Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require recipients of grants and other assistance from the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for the provision of housing and other services for homeless veterans to comply with codes relevant to operations and level of care provided, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412487"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2012-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2012--Introduced.
Safe Housing for Homeless Veterans Act - Prohibits the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) from making a grant or providing other assistance to any entity for the provision of housing or housing services to homeless veterans unless such entity submits to the Secretary a certification that the building proposed for such housing or services is in compliance with all local codes relevant to operations and level of care provided, as well as any other local requirements regarding the condition of the structure and the operation of the supportive housing or service center. Directs the Secretary, in awarding such grants, to give priority to entities seeking a grant or assistance for a project that includes making improvements to a building to ensure that the building meets such codes and other requirements. Requires entities receiving grants or assistance for the fiscal year during which this Act is enacted to submit such a certification within two years after enactment.</summary>
</bill>
