<bill session="111" type="h" number="2936" updated="2013-07-19T23:38:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bill to Underwrite Increased Lending to Domestic (BUILD) Manufacturing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">BUILD Manufacturing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create a program to guarantee loans made to manufacturing companies in order to promote increased domestic lending to the United States manufacturing industry.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400630"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412266" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412234" joined="2009-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2009-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412273" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2009-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2009-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2009-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2009-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2009-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2009-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2009-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2009-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412304" joined="2009-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2009-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412313" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412229" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2009-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2009--Introduced.
Bill to Underwrite Increased Lending to Domestic (BUILD) Manufacturing Act or BUILD Manufacturing Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should use all available powers to encourage financial institutions that are in receipt of federal financial support to immediately increase lending to the domestic manufacturing sector. Establishes within the Treasury the Manufacturing Loan Guarantee Program, headed by the Administrator of the Term Asset-Backed Securities Loan Facility (established by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System), to guarantee loans made by depository institutions to U.S. manufacturing companies. Prohibits any such loan from equaling or exceeding 1.5 times the gross net worth of the company receiving the loan. Allows a company to have more than one guaranteed loan, within aggregate dollar limits. Authorizes the Administrator to adjust Program loan guarantee percentages in order to maximize lending and to minimize default rates of participating manufacturers. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Administrator should encourage participating depository institutions to focus on lending to small- and medium-sized manufacturers.</summary>
</bill>
