<bill session="113" type="h" number="1760" updated="2013-11-02T06:33:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration and Naturalization Investment Ventures for Engineering, Science, and Technology in America Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INVEST in America Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an entrepreneur-based immigrant category for alien entrepreneurs who have completed or are in the process of completing a degree in Science, Engineering, Math or a technology-related field.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400361"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2013--Introduced.
Immigration and Naturalization Investment Ventures for Engineering, Science, and Technology in America Act of 2013 or INVEST in America Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide conditional permanent resident status for an alien entrepreneur (and spouse and children) who: (1) is in the process of completing, or has completed, a graduate level degree in science, technology, engineering, math or a related academic discipline from an accredited U.S. institute of higher education; (2) establishes a new commercial enterprise related to such study that meets specified employment and wage requirements; and (3) is admissible as an immigrant. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to terminate such alien's status for fraud or failure to meet status requirements during the 60-month period after obtaining such status. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Education to submit a recruitment, retainment, and investment strategic plan to Congress to attract skilled and talented foreign nationals to immigrate to the United States to create jobs and grow the economy.</summary>
</bill>
