<bill session="111" type="s" number="2835" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Climate Change Investment Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reduce global warming pollution through international climate finance, investment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2010-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2009--Introduced.
International Climate Change Investment Act of 2009 - Requires the President to establish the Strategic Interagency Board on International Climate Investment to assess, monitor, evaluate, and report on the progress and contributions of departments and agencies in supporting funding for international climate change activities and the goals and objectives of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change and the Bali Action Plan. Requires the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to establish a program to provide assistance to reduce greenhouse gas emissions (GHGs) from deforestation in developing countries. Establishes program objectives, including achieving emissions reductions of at least 720 million tons of carbon dioxide equivalent in 2020, a cumulative amount of at least 6 billion tons of carbon dioxide equivalent by December 31, 2025, and additional emissions reductions in subsequent years. Requires the Administrator to establish a publicly accessible registry of the emissions reductions achieved with such assistance. Requires the Administrator to develop and implement a program that addresses noncompletion or reversal with respect to any GHG emissions that were not, or are no longer, sequestered in the international deforestation reduction program. Requires: (1) the Secretary of State to establish the International Clean Energy Deployment Program to provide assistance to qualifying entities to implement clean technology activities that will contribute to reductions, sequestration, or avoidance of GHG emissions in eligible countries; and (2) the President to establish an interagency group to administer such program. Establishes an expert panel to provide guidance on technology deployment and programs to such group. Requires the Secretary to establish an International Climate Change Adaptation and Global Security Program to provide assistance to the most vulnerable developing countries for adapting and promoting resilience to climate change and its impacts. Requires the Secretary, working with the Board, to report biannually on climate change and energy policy for the five highest GHG emitting countries that are not members of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development.</summary>
</bill>
