<bill session="109" type="s" number="1532" updated="2013-07-19T20:26:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Agroterrorism Prevention Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 18 of the United States Code to criminalize acts of agroterrorism, and to enhance the protection of the United States agricultural industry and food security through the increased prevention, detection, response and recovery planning.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2005-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9296-9297"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural estimating and reporting"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Farms"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Germplasm resources"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Plant diseases"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Produce trade"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seeds"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
    <term name="Virus diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2005--Introduced.
Agroterrorism Prevention Act of 2005 - Amends federal criminal law to criminalize acts of agroterrorism (as defined by this Act). Provides for related monitoring and intelligence enhancements. Directs the Secretaries of Agriculture, Health and Human Services, and Homeland Security to expand and continue vulnerability assessments of the agriculture and food sectors. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) assist states and counties develop and implement plans for agricultural disease prevention and recovery (such plans to be modeled after the state animal response team); (2) assist states develop related regional and national response plans; (3) establish a public awareness campaign for agricultural producers that emphasizes heightened biosecurity and agricultural disease anomaly reporting; (4) develop guidelines to improve the monitoring of human traffic, vehicles, and materials entering or leaving farm or ranch operations, and disseminate such guidelines to agricultural producers; (5) develop a National Veterinary Stockpile; and (6) develop a National Plant Disease Recovery System. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to report respecting: (1) the need to modernize or replace federal animal and plant disease laboratories: and (2) state capability as first responders to animal diseases that threaten U.S. agriculture. States that if a livestock or poultry contract provides for arbitration, arbitration may be used to settle a controversy only if, after the controversy arises, both parties consent in writing to use arbitration to settle the controversy.</summary>
</bill>
