<bill session="110" type="s" number="2870" updated="2013-07-19T22:46:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Disability Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out quality assurance activities with respect to the administration of disability compensation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="5709"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/16/2008--Introduced.
Veterans Disability Fairness Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in order to carry out the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) quality assurance program with respect to the administration of veterans' disability compensation, to ensure the accuracy and consistency across VA offices of the treatment of claims for disability compensation, including disability rating determinations and whether a disability is service-connected. Requires the Secretary to conduct reviews and audits, at least annually, to identify and correct any inaccuracies or inconsistencies in disability ratings and the adjudication of disability compensation claims by VA regional offices and employees responsible for such ratings or adjudications.</summary>
</bill>
