<bill session="110" type="s" number="1563" updated="2013-07-19T22:33:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sudan Disclosure and Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the disclosure of certain activities relating to the petroleum industry of Sudan, to increase the penalties for violations of sanctions provisions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7337-7338"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7338-7340" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2007--Introduced.
Sudan Disclosure and Enforcement Act of 2007 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should bring before the U.N. Security Council a resolution requiring multilateral sanctions against the government of Sudan in response to its acts of genocide against the people of Darfur and its continued refusal to allow the implementation of a peacekeeping force. Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require specified securities issuers who are involved in the petroleum industry in Sudan to disclose to the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC): (1) such activities if they result in annual gross receipts of $1 million or more; and (2) the geographic area within Sudan where such activities occurred, and specifically if such activities took place solely within Southern Sudan and designated areas. Authorizes a national security waiver. Terminates disclosure requirements if the Secretary of State: (1) determines that Sudan no longer supports acts of international terrorism; and (2) certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that Sudan has demonstrated significant improvement in protecting Darfur's civilian population. Amends the International Emergency Economic Powers Act to increase civil penalties and establish criminal penalties for violations of such Act. Authorizes additional appropriations for the Office of Foreign Assets Control to support intelligence gathering, licensing, compliance, and administrative activities associated with sanctions against Sudan and persons operating in Sudan. Requires the President to publish notice in the Federal Register if specified sanctions have been terminated. Amends the U.S. Troop Readiness, Veterans' Care, Katrina Recovery, and Iraq Accountability Appropriations Act, 2007 to repeal specified reporting requirements respecting companies performing natural resource extraction activities, including oil-related activities and mining of minerals, in Sudan.</summary>
</bill>
