<bill session="113" type="s" number="897" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bank on Students Loan Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent the doubling of the interest rate for Federal subsidized student loans for the 2013-2014 academic year by providing funds for such loans through the Federal Reserve System, to ensure that such loans are available at interest rates that are equivalent to the interest rates at which the Federal Government provides loans to banks through the discount window operated by the Federal Reserve System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412542"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2013-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3260"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="1979"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2013--Introduced.
Bank on Students Loan Fairness Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to provide the Secretary of Education, from the combined earnings of the Federal Reserve System, with the amount the Secretary determines to be reasonably necessary to award Direct Stafford Loans during the award year beginning July 1, 2013, to all eligible students attending participating institutions of higher education selected by the Secretary. Prohibits appropriated funds from being used for Direct Stafford Loans made during that period. Sets the interest rate on Direct Stafford Loans first disbursed on or after July 1, 2013, and before July 1, 2014, at the primary credit rate charged by the Federal Reserve banks on July 1, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
