<bill session="111" type="h" number="6077" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to clarify policies regarding ownership of pore space.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400431"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1856"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to define "pore space" as a subsurface space of any size that can be used as storage space for carbon dioxide or other substances injected into the space for storage. Vests ownership in the federal government of any subsurface pore space located below a federal surface estate. Requires inclusion within a conveyance of the surface ownership of federal land the conveyance of the federal pore space in all strata below the surface of such land (other than previously reserved mineral rights) unless the ownership interest in the pore space has previously been severed from the surface ownership. Prohibits: (1) any agreement conveying federal interests underlying the surface of the land from also conveying ownership of federal pore space in the stratum unless the agreement explicitly conveys the interest in pore space; and (2) the holder of any pore space right from using the surface estate (except for the uses described in a properly recorded instrument). States that the mineral estate is dominant for purposes of determining the priority of subsurface uses between a mineral estate and pore space.</summary>
</bill>
