<bill session="111" type="h" number="2874" updated="2013-07-19T23:37:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Helping Active Duty Deployed Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to improve the equitable relief available for servicemembers called to active duty, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412301" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412304" joined="2009-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR  E1428"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-28">
      <text>Provisions of measure incorporated into H.R. 3949.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2009--Introduced.
Helping Active Duty Deployed Act of 2009 - Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to prohibit a cell phone company from charging an early termination penalty for a cellular telephone contract entered into on behalf of a service member who has received orders for foreign deployment or for permanent change of station within the United States. (Current law provides such protection for a contract entered into by the service member.) Revises provisions concerning arrearages and other obligations to prohibit a lessor from charging an early termination charge with respect to a residential, professional, business, or agricultural rental lease or a motor vehicle lease entered into by a person who subsequently enters military service, or for a service member who has received orders for permanent change of station or for deployment in support of a military operation. States that: (1) lease amounts for a period preceding the lease termination shall be paid on a prorated basis; and (2) other unpaid lease charges shall be paid by the lessee. Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require an institution of higher education to refund the tuition and fees paid by a student whose absence is due to military service for the payment period or period of enrollment for which such student did not receive academic credit as a result of such absence.</summary>
</bill>
