<bill session="112" type="s" number="2885" updated="2013-07-20T02:41:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for the award of the Purple Heart to members of the Armed Forces who are killed or wounded in a terrorist attack perpetrated within the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2012-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2012-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5144"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2012--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense (DOD), and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) with respect to the Coast Guard, should duly honor those members of the Armed Forces who are killed or wounded in the United States in terrorist attacks that are inspired by the ideology that gives rise to terrorism, as defined by the Final Report of the National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States. Provides that, for purposes of awarding the Purple Heart, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall treat a member of the Armed Forces who is killed or wounded in a terrorist attack within the United States in the same manner as a member killed or wounded in action due to an act of an enemy of the United States. Makes this Act effective as of January 1, 2009. Directs the Secretaries concerned to: (1) review each death or wounding of a member within the United States between January 1, 2009, and the date of enactment of this Act to determine whether such death or wounding qualifies as a death or wounding resulting from a terrorist attack for purposes of this Act; and (2) upon a positive determination, take appropriate action.</summary>
</bill>
