<bill session="109" type="s" number="4072" updated="2013-07-19T20:48:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gulf Coast Back to Business and Homes Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to address ongoing small business and homeowner needs in the Gulf Coast States impacted by Hurricane Katrina and Hurricane Rita.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-11-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11073-11074"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-11-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11074" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/2006--Introduced.
Gulf Coast Back to Business and Homes Act of 2006 - Authorizes appropriations for the Economic Development Administration of the Department of Commerce to make grants to appropriate state government agencies in Louisiana, Alabama, Mississippi, and Texas for assistance to small businesses located in a disaster area that was negatively affected by Hurricanes Katrina or Rita in 2005. Amends the Small Business Act to require the deferment of payments of principal and interest on loans made by the Small Business Administration (SBA) before December 31, 2006, to a small business located in a disaster area negatively affected by such hurricanes. Amends the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Hurricane Recovery, 2006 to authorize the SBA Administrator to waive the duplication of certain benefits with respect to hurricane recovery loans made to affected small businesses in Louisiana.</summary>
</bill>
