<bill session="111" type="h" number="195" updated="2013-07-19T23:13:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Informed Choice Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to nonprofit tax-exempt organizations for the purchase of ultrasound equipment to provide free examinations to pregnant women needing such services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400388"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/2009--Introduced.
Informed Choice Act - Allows the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to nonprofit community based pregnancy help medical clinics for the purchase of ultrasound equipment. Requires each grantee to: (1) provide free ultrasound examinations to pregnant women; (2) show the visual image of the fetus from the ultrasound examination to each pregnant woman with a general anatomical and physiological description of the fetus; (3) give each pregnant woman the approximate age of the embryo or fetus; (4) provide information on abortion and alternatives to abortion, such as childbirth and adoption, and information concerning public and private agencies that will assist in those alternatives; and (5) obtain medical malpractice insurance. Limits each grant to the lesser of 50% of the purchase price of the ultrasound machine involved or $20,000.</summary>
</bill>
