<bill session="112" type="s" number="2129" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reforming and Consolidating Government Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for reforming and consolidating agencies of the Federal Government to improve efficiency and effectiveness.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2012-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-21">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-531.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4409"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2012--Introduced.
Reforming and Consolidating Government Act of 2012 - Defines "efficiency-enhancing plan," for purposes of executive authority to reorganize federal agencies, as a reorganization plan that the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) determines will or is likely to result in a decrease in the number of agencies or cost savings in performing the functions that are the subject of the plan. Expands executive authority to reorganize federal agencies by allowing: (1) the creation of a new executive department or the abolition or renaming of an existing department, (2) the consolidation of two or more departments, and (3) the creation of a new agency that is not a component or part of an existing executive department. Allows a provision in a reorganization plan to take effect only if such plan is transmitted to Congress within two years of the enactment of this Act and is an efficiency-enhancing plan.</summary>
</bill>
