<bill session="112" type="h" number="2692" updated="2013-07-20T01:33:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Access to Postal Services Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 39, United States Code, to modify the procedures governing the closure or consolidation of postal facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412186"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2011-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Postal Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2011--Introduced.
Access to Postal Services Act - Modifies the procedures the U.S. Postal Service must follow in connection with the closing or consolidation of any postal facility, including: (1) requiring an assessment of the need for the closure or consolidation, (2) eliminating a requirement to consider the resulting Postal Service economic savings, (3) requiring posted notice in each affected postal facility and notice by mail to all persons served by such postal facility at least 90 days before the final decision is made, and (4) requiring (under current law, allowing) suspension of the determination pending an appeal to the Postal Regulatory Commission. Exempts emergency suspensions (as defined under Postal Service regulations) or lease termination or cancellation by a party other than the Postal Service. Requires such posted notice to include the cost savings the Postal Service estimates it will realize from the closing or consolidation, in the first year following the date of such closing or consolidation, with an explanation of the estimate assumptions and methodologies. Directs the Inspector General of the Postal Service, within two years after the closing or consolidation of any postal facility after enactment of this Act, to submit to the Postmaster General and Congress its findings with respect to the actual cost savings realized by the Postal Service in the first year following such closing or consolidation. Defines "postal facility," for the provisions amended by this Act, to include an office, branch, station, or other facility operated by the Postal Service providing services to postal patrons served by the facility.</summary>
</bill>
