<bill session="111" type="h" number="2650" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coast Guard Modernization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Coast Guard Modernization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 14, United States Code, to modernize the leadership of the Coast Guard, to modernize the administration of marine safety by the Coast Guard, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2009-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-10-23">
      <text>Provisions of measure incorporated in to Title VII of H.R. 3619.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03T14:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 111-352.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-12-03T14:09:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="203">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 203.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3619"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3619"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2009--Reported to House without amendment.
Coast Guard Modernization Act of 2009 - Title I: Coast Guard Leadership - (Sec. 101) Revises provisions concerning the leadership of the Coast Guard, including: (1) allowing more than one admiral; (2) requiring that the Coast Guard Vice Commandant, while so serving, have the rank of admiral; and (3) replacing the current area commanders with vice admirals and revising their responsibilities. Title II: Marine Safety Administration - (Sec. 201) Requires the Commandant to promote maritime safety according to specified priorities. (Sec. 202) Requires the Commandant to: (1) designate Coast Guard positions constituting the marine safety workforce; (2) report annually on the adequacy of the current marine safety workforce to meet the anticipated workload; and (3) establish a management information system for that workforce. Requires there to be a chief of marine safety in each Coast Guard sector. Authorizes the Commandant to establish and operate one or more Centers of Expertise for Marine Safety. Requires the Commandant, by policy, to establish a program under which a Coast Guard officer, member, or employee may be assigned to a private entity to further Coast Guard interests regarding marine safety, including to train the person. Requires a related annual report. (Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to develop a long-term strategy for improving vessel safety and the safety of individuals on vessels, including annual issuance of a plan and schedule for achieving specified goals. (Sec. 204) Provides for a principal advisor to the Commandant regarding marine safety. (Sec. 205) Requires, except for the Commandant, that any individual adjudicating an appeal or waiver of a marine safety decision either have certain training, experience, and qualifications or be advised by a senior staff member who meets those requirements and concurs in the decision on appeal. (Sec. 206) Requires a marine safety curriculum at the Coast Guard Academy and during other officer accession programs. (Sec. 207) Requires the Commandant to report on the Coast Guard's efforts to recruit and retain civilian marine inspectors and investigators and the impact of such recruitment and retention efforts on Coast Guard organizational performance.</summary>
</bill>
