<bill session="111" type="h" number="2489" updated="2013-07-19T23:34:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-27T16:20:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-10-27T16:20:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">AmericaView Geospatial Imagery Mapping Program Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Land Remote Sensing Outreach Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Land Remote Sensing Outreach Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize a comprehensive national cooperative geospatial imagery mapping program through the United States Geological Survey, to promote use of the program for education, workforce training and development, and applied research, and to support Federal, State, tribal, and local government programs.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To authorize a national cooperative geospatial imagery program through the United States Geological Survey to promote use of remote sensing data.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400443"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2009-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1207"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-09-30">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-10-21T14:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-309.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-10-21T14:29:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="175">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 175.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-10-26T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-26T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11742-11744" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-26T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2489.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-26T14:11:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-27T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11824-11825" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-10-27T16:20:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="817" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 379 - 33 (Roll no. 817).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/26/2009 H11742-11743" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-10-27T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-27T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1078"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/27/2009--Passed House amended.
National Land Remote Sensing Outreach Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish and maintain a national land remote sensing outreach program within the United States Geological Survey (USGS) to advance the availability, timely distribution, and widespread use of geospatial imagery for education, research, assessment, and monitoring purposes in each state and on the lands of an Indian tribe. Requires the Secretary, under such program, to: (1) support geospatial imagery sharing, applied research, and educational programs of each participating state and Indian tribe; (2) identify new geospatial imagery needs and infrastructure; (3) share and cooperate in the development of geospatial imagery applications, education, and training infrastructure in each participating area; (4) cooperate with participating states and tribes to encourage the expansion of geospatial imagery mapping courses taught at educational institutions; (5) encourage expansion of geospatial imagery research at such institutions; (6) encourage expansion of the knowledge and use of geospatial imagery products in the workforce through outreach programs, workshops, and other training opportunities; (7) encourage participating states and tribes to build partnerships with local governments to identify unique research and development needs and geospatial imagery application pilot programs; (8) promote cooperation and sharing of expertise regarding geospatial imagery applications among participating states and tribes; and (9) provide a mechanism to enable the states and tribes to transfer geospatial imagery and applications to USGS. Authorizes the Secretary to provide grants to qualified educational institutions, to state, local, and tribal governments, or to consortia of these entities on a competitive basis to: (1) advance the interest of the federal government in promoting the use of imagery by educational institutions, states, localities, and tribes; and (2) achieve specified program purposes. Limits the federal share to 75% of the cost of each program for which a grant is made. Directs the Secretary to establish and maintain a committee to advise the Director of USGS regarding the program.</summary>
</bill>
