<bill session="111" type="s" number="2865" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-07">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Award Program Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Congressional Award Program Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Congressional Award Program Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Congressional Award Program Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Congressional Award Program Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the Congressional Award Act (2 U.S.C. 801 et seq.), and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-15">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman without amendment. With written report No. 111-163.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="317">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 317.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2010-03-17" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1680" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1680" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18T10:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23T11:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Payne moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23T11:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4690-4692" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23T11:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2865.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-06-23T11:22:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4690-4691" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23T11:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-06-25">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-07-07">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-07-07" type="public" number="111-200">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-200.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/2010--Public Law.
Congressional Award Program Reauthorization Act of 2009 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Congressional Award Act to revise requirements for appointment and reappointment of members of the Congressional Award Board, especially the limitation of service on the Board to two consecutive terms. Exempts a member from the two-term limit during a period of service as Board Chairman. Permits reappointment of such individual to an additional full term after termination of such Chairmanship. Requires a Board member's term to begin on October 1 of the even numbered year, with one-half of the Board positions having terms which begin in each even numbered year. Changes from calendar to fiscal year the annual period for which the Director is required to ensure that the Board's liabilities do not exceed its assets. Requires the Board, if the Comptroller General finds that the Director has not substantially complied with such duty, to: (1) instruct the Director to take such necessary actions to correct any deficiencies (as under current law); and (2) remove and replace the Director if they are not promptly corrected. Repeals the requirement that, upon a Director's failure to correct such deficiencies, the Board take necessary action to prepare for the orderly cessation of Board activities. Allows the Board to accept funds to carry out its functions and make expenditures that are awarded in any grant program administered by a federal agency. (Currently the Board is prohibited from using federal resources.) Repeals the limitation on contributions to Statewide Congressional Award Councils to public monetary and in-kind contributions for Program purposes (thus allowing private contributions as well). Allows the donation of funds or other resources to restrict their use to scholarships. Names the nonprofit corporation the Board is required to establish to assist it in carrying out the Program the Congressional Award Foundation. Repeals the requirement that the corporation be private. Treats the Foundation together with any subsidiary nonprofit corporations as the collective Corporation to which appropriate duties shall be delegated, including the employment of personnel, expenditure of funds, and the incurrence of financial or other contractual obligations. Allows the Congressional Award Board (which as under current law shall be members of the Board of Directors of the Foundation) to appoint up to 24 additional voting members to the Foundation Board. Makes the Congressional Award Program Director serve as a nonvoting member of the Foundation Board. Extends the Congressional Award Board until October 1, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
