<bill session="110" type="s" number="2204" updated="2013-07-19T22:39:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Warming Wildlife Survival Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Global Warming and Acidification Coastal and Ocean Resiliency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to assist wildlife populations and wildlife habitats in adapting to and surviving the effects of global warming, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13091-13092"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13092-13097" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2338"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2211"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Freshwater resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sea level"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/18/2007--Introduced.
Global Warming Wildlife Survival Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to establish: (1) a national strategy for assisting wildlife populations and habitats in adapting to the impact of global warming; (2) an advisory board on such impact; (3) the National Global Warming and Wildlife Science Center within the United States Geological Survey (USGS); and (4) a State and Tribal Wildlife Grants Program.Global Warming and Acidification Coastal and Ocean Resiliency Act - Requires the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) establish a national strategy to protect, maintain, and restore coastal and marine ecosystems so that they are more resilient and better able to withstand the additional stresses associated with global warming, including relative sea level rise, and ocean acidification; (2) establish an advisory board on the impact of global warming on the ocean and coastal communities; (3) make grants for protecting, maintaining, or restoring the resilience and health of coastal, ocean, and Great Lakes ecosystems and resources; and (4) arrange with the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) for a report to Congress on such impact.Amends the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to require the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) establish a coastal climate change resiliency planning and response program; and (2) issue guidelines for the implementation of climate change resiliency planning grants to states.Requires the Director of USGS to convene regional scientific symposia to examine the ecological impact of global warming on each imperiled species in each U.S. ecosystem. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to arrange with NAS to convene a panel to report on: (1) such impact; (2) different ecological scenarios that may result from different intensities, rates, and other critical manifestations of global warming; and (3) assisting such species.</summary>
</bill>
