<bill session="112" type="h" number="1573" updated="2013-07-20T01:23:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate implementation of title VII of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, promote regulatory coordination, and avoid market disruption.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2011-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412400" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412463" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412453" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412422" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400207" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412010" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412417" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412430" joined="2011-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-15">
      <text>Hearings Held Prior to Introduction.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 30 - 24.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16T15:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 112-109, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16T16:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Agriculture. H. Rept. 112-109, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-06-16T16:20:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="63">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 63.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2011--Reported to House amended, Part II.
(Sec. 1) Amends the Wall Street Transparency and Accountability Act of 2010, Title VII of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, to delay until December 31, 2012, or 90 days after publication of the relevant final rule or regulation (unless the rule or regulation specifies a later date), or the otherwise applicable effective date, whichever is the latest, the effective date for implementation of certain parts of Title VII, including the promulgation of regulations, the conduct of studies and preparation of reports, and the registration of persons, as well as the exemption of persons, agreements, contracts, or transactions from coverage by Title VII. Exempts from such delay, however, the authority of the Commodity Futures Trading (CFTC) and the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to issue final definitions pertaining to swap transactions, swap participants, and eligible contract participants. Requires the CFTC and the SEC to further define swaps and related terms subject to their joint rulemaking. States that the effective date for CFTC reporting of swap-data and SEC reporting of security-based swap data is 90 days after publication of the final rule in the Federal Register, or the effective date otherwise applicable to such reporting, whichever is later. Grants the CFTC and the SEC interim authority to permit the reporting of swap data and security-based swap data to certain persons who have: (1) provided notice of their intention to register as a swap data repository or as a security-based swap data repository, and (2) made appropriate undertakings to the respective Commission as the latter determines to be in the public interest. (Sec. 2) Requires the two Commissions, before prescribing final rules and regulations under Title VII, to conduct additional public hearings and roundtables on specified issues, solicit public comment, and take into account the testimony of interested parties when performing mandatory cost-benefit analyses and when determining the effective date of final rules and regulations. (Sec. 3) Amends the Commodity Exchange Act (CEA) and the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to authorize the CFTC and the SEC, respectively, to exempt a person from the registration and related regulatory requirements of such Acts if: (1) the person is subject to comparable supervision and regulation under a regulatory scheme administered by another regulatory authority or the appropriate government authorities in the person's home country that is comparable to the requirements of Title VII, (2) adequate information-sharing arrangements are in effect between the agencies and the foreign regulator, and (3) the exemption is consistent with the public interest .</summary>
</bill>
