<bill session="109" type="s" number="2489" updated="2013-07-19T20:35:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">U.S. Additional Protocol Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">U.S. Additional Protocol Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">An original bill to implement the obligations of the United States under the Protocol Additional to the Agreement between the United States of America and the International Atomic Energy Agency for the Application of Safeguards in the United States of America, signed by the United States on June 12, 1998.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-03">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Lugar. With written report No. 109-226.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-04-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="385">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 385.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2006--Reported to Senate without amendment.
U.S. Additional Protocol Implementation Act - Title I: General Provisions - (Sec. 101) Authorizes the President to: (1) implement this Act and the Protocol Additional to the Agreement between the United States of America and the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) for the Application of Safeguards in the United States of America, with Annexes, which was signed by both parties in Vienna on June 12, 1998 (Additional Protocol); and (2) designate which federal agencies shall issue or amend and enforce regulations to implement this Act and the provisions of the Additional Protocol. Title II: Complementary Access - (Sec. 201) Prohibits complementary access to any location in the United States pursuant to the Additional Protocol without the authorization of the U.S. Government. Authorizes complementary IAEA access in accordance with this Act to any location in the United States subject to access under the Additional Protocol. States that, in the event of complementary access to a privately owned or operated location, no employee of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Mine Safety and Health Administration, or the Occupational Safety and Health Administration of the Department of Labor may participate in the access. (Sec. 202) Prescribes complementary access procedures, including consents, administrative search warrants, and warrantless complementary access. States it is unlawful for any person willfully to fail, refuse to permit, or otherwise impede complementary access authorized by this Act, or an entry in connection with such access. Title III: Confidentiality of Information - (Sec. 301) Exempts information acquired by the U.S. Government under this Act or under the Additional Protocol from certain statutory disclosure requirements. Title IV: Enforcement - (Sec. 401) Prescribes recordkeeping procedures. Sets forth civil and criminal penalties for: (1) recordkeeping violations; and (2) impeding authorized complementary access. Requires a violations hearing to be conducted before an administrative judge. Grants federal district courts jurisdiction over civil actions brought by the head of certain designated executive agencies. Title V: Environmental Sampling - (Sec. 501) Requires the President to notify certain congressional committees of IAEA Board approval of wide-area environmental sampling for use as a safeguards verification tool. (Sec. 502) Prohibits the United States from permitting either wide-area or location-specific environmental sampling proposed by the IAEA in the United States unless the President has made and reported specified determinations to certain congressional committees. Title VI: Authorization of Appropriations - (Sec. 601) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
