<bill session="113" type="h" number="3030" updated="2013-11-02T06:44:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Tax and Investment Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to treat Indian tribal governments in the same manner as State governments for certain Federal tax purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400218"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
Tribal Tax and Investment Reform Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to include Indian tribal governments in an annual allocation of a national tax-exempt bond volume cap. Repeals the condition limiting an Indian tribal government's eligibility to issue tax-exempt bonds or to be exempt from specified excise taxes to the connection of those bonds and excise taxes to an essential government function. Amends the IRC and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to treat employee benefit plans maintained by Indian tribes and domestic relations orders issued pursuant to tribal law in the same manner as plans maintained by states and domestic relations orders issued pursuant to state law. Treats tribal charities and foundations in the same manner as charities and foundations funded and controlled by other governmental entities for purposes of the tax-exempt status of, and deduction for contributions to, such organizations. Amends the Social Security Act to give Indian tribes or tribal organizations access to the Federal Parent Locator Service if they are eligible for a grant to operate a child support enforcement program. Makes those tribes and tribal organizations eligible to participate in the program that collects past-due support from the federal tax refunds individuals are due. Amends the IRC to establish a clean renewable energy bond limitation for Indian tribal governments for each of calendar years 2014, 2015, and 2016. Prohibits the Secretary of the Treasury from allocating more than 20% of the national clean renewable energy bond limitation to finance any one project.</summary>
</bill>
