<bill session="111" type="h" number="2642" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Missing in America Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to assist in the identification of unclaimed and abandoned human remains to determine if any such remains are eligible for burial in a national cemetery, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400406"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412265" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2009-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2009-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2009-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Veterans Missing in America Act of 2009 - Recognizes the tireless work and dedication of the Missing in America Project, in conjunction with numerous veterans service organizations, in identifying unclaimed remains of veterans. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to cooperate with such organizations to assist entities in possession of unclaimed or abandoned human remains in determining if any such remains are the remains of veterans or other individuals eligible for burial in a national cemetery. Requires the Secretary, upon a positive determination with respect to any such remains, to provide for and cover the cost of the burial and funeral expenses if the Secretary determines that: (1) there is no next of kin or other person claiming the remains; and (2) there are no other sufficient resources to cover such expenses. Directs the Secretary to establish a publicly accessible database of the names of any veteran or other individual so identified.</summary>
</bill>
