<bill session="109" type="s" number="728" updated="2013-07-19T20:19:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Water Resources Development Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Water Resources Development Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Rio Grande Environmental Management Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the consideration and development of water and related resources, to authorize the Secretary of the Army to construct various projects for improvements to rivers and harbors of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2006-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2006-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="2005-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3300-3302"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3349-3350"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-04-13">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-04-26">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe with amendments. With written report No. 109-61. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-04-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="93">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 93.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-18">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7694-7739" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7694-7725" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-18">
      <text>The committee amendments were withdrawn in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7813-7858" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 2864 as an amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 2864 in lieu of this measure by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Returned to the Calendar. Calendar No. 93.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>See also H.R. 2864.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2864"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="2864"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="109" type="h" number="2864"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2864"/>
    <bill relation="includes" session="109" type="h" number="2864"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Aquifers"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Beaches"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Chesapeake Bay"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Everglades"/>
    <term name="Exotic animals"/>
    <term name="Exotic plants"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fish culture"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Freshwater resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Long Island Sound"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Multipurpose projects"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Salvage"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sediment control"/>
    <term name="Selenium"/>
    <term name="Shellfish"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Stream conservation"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Susquehanna River Basin Commission"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Waterfronts"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Waterways"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4676"/>
    <amendment number="s4677"/>
    <amendment number="s4678"/>
    <amendment number="s4679"/>
    <amendment number="s4680"/>
    <amendment number="s4681"/>
    <amendment number="s4682"/>
    <amendment number="s4683"/>
    <amendment number="s4684"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/26/2005--Reported to Senate amended.
Water Resources Development Act of 2005 - Reauthorizes the Water Resources Development Act. Title I: Water Resources Projects - (Sec. 1001) Authorizes specified projects for navigation, ecosystem restoration, flood or storm damage reduction, and related purposes in Alaska, Arizona, California, Colorado, Florida, Illinois, Louisiana, Maryland, Missouri, New Jersey, New Mexico, Texas, Virginia, and Washington. Authorizes specified projects, subject to a favorable final report of the Chief of Engineers (Chief) by December 31, 2005, in Florida, Iowa, Louisiana, New York, New Jersey, and Ohio. (Sec. 1002) Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to: (1) modify the operation of the Upper Mississippi River and Illinois Waterway System to address cumulative environmental impacts; and (2) carry out a program to restore the ecosystem of the Louisiana Coastal Area. Establishes the Coastal Louisiana Ecosystem Protection and Restoration Task Force. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop a plan for modifying the Mississippi River Gulf Outlet; (2) establish a coastal Louisiana ecosystem science and technology program; (3) enter into a contract with the National Academy of Sciences to identify the cause of degradation of the Louisiana Coastal Area; and (4) study financing alternatives and potential reductions in the expenditure of federal funds in emergency responses that would occur as a result of ecosystem restoration in that Area. (Sec. 1004) Directs the Secretary to study and, if feasible, carry out a flood damage reduction project at Cache River Basin, Grubbs, Arkansas. (Sec. 1005) Directs the Secretary to study and, if feasible, carry out specified navigation projects in , Arkansas, Michigan, Wisconsin, and Ohio. (Sec. 1006) Directs the Secretary to study and, if appropriate, carry out specified aquatic ecosystem restoration projects in California and Rhode Island. Title II: General Provisions - Subtitle A: Provisions - (Sec. 2001) - Amends the Flood Control Act of 1970 to require: (1) written agreements for water resources projects; and (2) the Secretary to credit toward the non-federal share of the cost of a water resources project the value of in-kind contributions made by the non-federal interest. (Sec. 2003) Authorizes the Secretary to include individuals from the non-federal interest, including the private sector, in Corps of Engineers' training classes. (Sec. 2004) Replaces a prohibition against user fees with a requirement that the Secretary carry out a recreational user fee program to recover from users of recreation areas and project sites under the Corps' jurisdiction the portion of costs associated with operating and maintaining them. Requires any fee collected to be deposited into a Treasury account for the Corps, with not more than 80 percent of the fee made available to pay the costs of a project under the Corps' jurisdiction located at that area or site. (Sec. 2005) Directs the Chief to submit a report to specified committees on expenditures for the preceding fiscal year and estimated expenditures for the current fiscal year. (Sec. 2006) Amends the Water Resources Development Act (WRDA) of 1986 to require the Secretary, for all feasibility reports completed after December 31, 2005, to assess whether: (1) the project and each element is cost-effective; and (2) the project complies with federal, state, and local laws (including regulations) and public policies. Requires: (1) the recommendation of a feasibility study to be based on a cost-benefit analysis; and (2) the Chief, within two years, to complete the study and sign the Chief's report for the project, with an authorized extension for a complex or controversial study. (Sec. 2007) Mandates peer review of major engineering, scientific, and technical work products by the Corps. (Sec. 2008) Lists mitigation plan requirements under WRDA. (Sec. 2009) Authorizes the Secretary, at the request of a governmental agency or non-federal interest, to provide technical assistance in managing water resources. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to list in the annual civil works budget submitted to Congress the individual activities proposed for funding. (Sec. 2010) Directs the Secretary, acting through the Corps, to provide public access to water resource and related water quality data in the Corps' custody. (Sec. 2011) Requires budget priority for construction of flood control projects by non-federal interests to be proportionate to the percentage of project completion; and (2) a completed project to have the same priority as a project with a contractor on site. Directs the Secretary to enter into agreements for development of specified flood control or damage reduction projects in Illinois, Minnesota and Texas. (Sec. 2012) Amends the WRDA of 1992 to direct the Secretary, acting through the Chief, to develop Regional Sediment Management plans and carry out projects at identified locations for use in construction, repair, modification, or rehabilitation associated with federal water resources projects (activities) for: (1) the protection of property; (2) the protection, restoration, and creation of aquatic and ecologically related habitats, including wetlands; and (3) the transport and placement of suitable sediment. Directs the Secretary to develop plans and projects for regional management of sediment obtained in conjunction with such activities. Limits total federal costs associated with construction of a project to $5 million without congressional approval. Directs the Secretary to give priority to specified regional sediment management projects in New York, California, New Jersey and Pennsylvania, and Ohio. Repeals provisions of the WRDA of 1976 regarding the placement on state beaches of sand dredged in constructing and maintaining navigation inlets and channels adjacent to such beaches. (Sec. 2013) Authorizes the Secretary to carry out construction of small shore and beach restoration and protection projects not specifically authorized by Congress that otherwise comply with this Act, if advisable. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Chief, to conduct a national shoreline erosion control development and demonstration program. (Sec. 2014) Declares it to be U.S. policy to promote shore protection projects and related research that encourage the protection, restoration, and enhancement of sandy beaches on a comprehensive and coordinated basis by the federal government, states, localities, and private enterprises. (Sec. 2015) Directs that costs incurred for monitoring for an ecosystem restoration project be cost-shared in accordance with the formula relating to the original construction project for a maximum period of ten years. (Sec. 2016) Directs the Corps to include ecosystem restoration benefits in the calculation of benefits for specified projects in California. (Sec. 2018) Directs the Secretary to: (1) implement a program to allow electronic submission of permit applications for permits under the Corps' jurisdiction; and (2) carry out specified measures, including conducting a study to identify unused, underused, or additional water storage capacity at reservoirs, to support the water resource needs of project sponsors and any affected state, local, or tribal government for authorized project purposes. (Sec. 2020) Authorizes the Administrators of the Southeastern, Southwestern, and Western Area, Power Administrations to credit the Secretary receipts from the sale of power and related services. (Sec. 2021) Removes certain restrictions on the federal hopper dredges Essayons and Yaquina. Subtitle B: Continuing Authorities Projects - (Sec. 2031) Amends the River and Harbor Act of 1960 to increase the limitation on allotments for the construction of a small river and harbor improvement project at any single locality which will result in substantial benefits to navigation. (Sec. 2032) Amends the Flood Control Act of 1946 to increase the cap for funding for the protection of highways, bridge approaches, public works, and nonprofit public services. (Sec. 2033) Amends the WRDA of: (1) 1996 to increase appropriations for an aquatic restoration and protection project and make it a freshwater project; and (2) 1986 to increase appropriations for environmental modification of projects. (Sec. 2035) Directs the Secretary to carry out an estuary habitat restoration project upon determining that the project will improve the elements and features of an estuary, is in the public interest, and is cost-effective. (Sec. 2036) Amends the WRDA of 1999 regarding abandoned mine restoration to require the non-federal share of the costs of operation and maintenance for a project to be 100 percent. Increases authorized appropriations. (Sec. 2037) Authorizes the Secretary to carry out a small dam removal or rehabilitation project if it will improve the quality of the environment or is in the public interest. (Sec. 2038) Directs the Secretary to develop eligibility criteria for federal participation in navigation projects located in economically disadvantaged communities that are dependent on water transportation for subsistence in remote areas, American Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, or the U.S. Virgin Islands. (Sec. 2039) Amends the Flood Control Act of 1970 to direct that if the Secretary determines that a project needs to be continued for public health and safety purposes, the non-federal interest shall pay the increased costs up to 20 percent of the original estimated project costs and in accordance with the statutorily-determined cost share and the Secretary shall pay all increased costs remaining. Title III: Project-Related Provisions - (Sec. 3001) Directs the Secretary to carry out necessary removal of rubble, sediment, and rock impeding the entrance to the St. Herman and St. Paul Harbors, Kodiak, Alaska. (Sec. 3002) Directs the Secretary to: (1) correct design deficiencies in the Thompson Harbor, Sitka, Alaska, element of the navigation project, Southeast Alaska Harbors of Refuge; and (2) construct a new project management office in Tuscaloosa, Alabama. (Sec. 3004) Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) carry out rehabilitation of authorized and completed levees on the White River between Augusta and Clarendon, Arkansas; and (2) undertake channel stabilization and sediment removal measures for the flood control project at St. Francis Basin, Arkansas and Missouri. (Sec. 3007) Amends the Flood Control Act of 1950 to authorize the comprehensive flood-control project for the Ouachita River and tributaries. (Sec. 3008) Directs the Secretary to continue construction of the McClellan-Kerr Arkansas River Navigation System, Arkansas and Oklahoma, to operate and maintain the navigation channel to the authorized depth. (Sec. 3009) Directs the Secretary to mitigate the impacts of the new south levee of the settling basin of the flood control project at Cache Creek Basin, California, on the storm drainage system of the city of Woodland. Modifies the environmental restoration project at Hamilton Airfield, California, to include the diked bayland parcel known as Bel Marin Keys Unit V. (Sec. 3011) Amends the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 to provide that beginning January 1, 2007 (currently, 2003), no permit for dumping or authorization for dumping shall be issued for the site located off the coast of Newport Beach, California, known as "LA-3", unless such site has received a final designation or an alternative site has been selected. (Sec. 3012) Modifies: (1) the project for navigation at Larkspur Ferry Channel, Larkspur, California, to direct the Secretary to prepare a limited reevaluation report to determine whether maintenance of the project is feasible; (2) the project for flood damage reduction at Llagas Creek, California, to authorize the Secretary to complete the project in accordance with specified local cooperation requirements, at a specified cost; and (3) the project at Magpie Creek, California, to direct the Secretary to apply the cost-sharing requirements applicable to nonstructural flood control under the WRDA of 1986 for the portion of the project consisting of land acquisition to preserve and enhance existing floodwater storage. (Sec. 3016) Directs the Secretary to participate with state and local agencies in the implementation of a cooperative program to improve and manage fisheries and aquatic habitat conditions in Pine Flat Reservoir and in the 14-mile reach of the Kings River immediately below Pine Flat Dam, California. (Sec. 3017) Authorizes the Secretary to dredge the Redwood City Navigation Channel, California annually to maintain the authorized depth. (Sec. 3018) Directs the Secretary to credit a specified amount toward that portion of the non-federal share of the costs of any flood damage reduction project authorized before this Act's enactment that is to be paid by the Sacramento Area Flood Control Agency. (Sec. 3019) Directs that if the Secretary determines that projects proposed to be carried out by non-federal entities within specified portions of the San Francisco, California, waterfront are not in the public interest, those portions shall be declared not to be navigable water of the United States. (Sec. 3020) Directs the Secretary to enter into an agreement with the Salton Sea Authority and carry out the pilot projects for improvement of the environment of the Salton Sea if the projects are economically justified, technically sound, environmentally acceptable, and meet the objectives of the Salton Sea Reclamation Act. (Sec. 3021) Authorizes the Secretary to construct the projects for: (1) flood damage reduction and recreation, Upper Guadalupe River, California, in accordance with the Upper Guadalupe River Flood Damage Reduction, San Jose, California, Limited Reevaluation Report, dated March, 2004; and (2) flood damage reduction, Yuba River Basin, California. (Sec. 3023) Designates the western breakwater for the navigation project, New Haven Harbor, Connecticut, as the Charles Hervey Townshend Breakwater. (Sec. 3024) Redesignates a portion of the navigation project, New London Harbor, Connecticut, as an anchorage area. (Sec. 3025) Deauthorizes portions of a 10-foot channel of the navigation project, Norwalk Harbor, Connecticut. (Sec. 3026) Amends the WRDA of 1990 to bar the Secretary from carrying out any action to close or remove the St. George's Bridge, Delaware, without specific congressional authorization. (Sec. 3027) Directs the Secretary to remove the shipwrecked vessel, "the State of Pennsylvania," from the Christina River, Wilmington, Delaware. (Sec. 3028) Amends the WRDA of: (1) 2000 to make a provision of the WRDA of 1986 applicable to individual project funding limits and aggregate cost limits for Everglades restoration, Florida; and (2) 1996 to increase the federal share of the cost of carrying out the Seminole Water Conservation Plan. (Sec. 3030) Modifies the navigation project, Jacksonville Harbor, Florida, to authorize the Secretary to extend the navigation features at a specified total cost. (Sec. 3031) Amends the WRDA of 2000 to direct that the pilot projects for aquifer storage and recovery, Hillsboro and Okeechobee Aquifer, Florida be treated as being in the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan but with costs of operation and maintenance remaining 100 percent non-federal. (Sec. 3032) Directs the Secretary to carry out the hurricane and storm damage reduction project at Lido Key, Sarasota County, Florida. (Sec. 3033) Modifies the navigation project, Tampa Harbor, Florida, to authorize the Secretary to construct passing lanes in an area centered on Tampa Bay Cut B if necessary for navigational safety. (Sec. 3034) Authorizes the Secretary to exchange land at Allatoona Lake, Georgia. (Sec. 3035) Directs the Secretary to carry out additional general construction measures to allow for operation at lower pool levels to satisfy the recreation mission at Dworshak Dam, Idaho. (Sec. 3036) Directs the Secretary to rehabilitate the Gooding Channel Project, Idaho, if the rehabilitation and ecosystem restoration are feasible. (Sec. 3037) Extinguishes reversionary interests and use restrictions relating to industrial use purposes, Port of Lewiston, Idaho. (Sec. 3038) Modifies the Cache River Levee, Illinois, to add environmental restoration as a project purpose. (Sec. 3039) Amends the WRDA of 2000 to include Lake Michigan in a study along with the Chicago River. (Sec. 3040) Redefines the federal navigation channel for the North Branch Channel portion of the Chicago River to be no wider than 66 feet. (Sec. 3041) Authorizes the Secretary to participate in the reconstruction of flood control projects within Missouri and Illinois as a pilot program if such reconstruction is not required as a result of improper operation and maintenance by the non-federal interest. Directs the Secretary to give priority to specified projects in Illinois and Missouri. (Sec. 3042) Authorizes ecosystem restoration as a purpose of the project for flood control, Illinois and Des Plaines River Basin (Spunky Bottom). (Sec. 3043) Directs the Secretary, acting through the Tulsa District of the Corps of Engineers, to transfer land to Pleasant Township, Coffey County, Kansas, for use as the New Strawn Cemetery. (Sec. 3044) Directs the Secretary to convey to Geary County Fire Department, Milford, Kansas, all U.S. right to specified land for a fire station. (Sec. 3045) Amends the WRDA of 2000 to modify the project for ecosystem restoration, Ohio River, Kentucky, Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, Pennsylvania, and West Virginia, to authorize the Secretary to cost share projects with the consent of the affected local government, prepare an implementation plan, and initiate a pilot program in the Lower Scioto Basin, Ohio. (Sec. 3046) Modifies: (1) the public access feature of the Atchafalaya Basin Floodway System, Louisiana project, to authorize the Secretary to acquire from willing sellers the fee interest of an additional 20,000 acres in the Lower Atchafalaya Basin Floodway; and (2) the project for the Calcasieu River and Pass, Louisiana to authorize specified funds for rock bank protection. (Sec. 3048) Directs the Secretary, for the hurricane protection project, Larose to Golden Meadow, Louisiana, to make a determination regarding the technical feasibility, environmental acceptability, and economical justification of converting the Golden Meadow floodgate into a navigation lock. (Sec. 3049) Modifies: (1) the flood damage reduction and recreation project, East Baton Rouge Parish, Louisiana, to authorize the Secretary to carry out the project in accordance with specified reports at a specified cost; and (2) the project for mitigation of fish and wildlife losses, Red River Waterway, Louisiana, to carry out the project at a specified costs, to permit the purchase of marginal farmland for reforestation, and to incorporate certain wildlife and forestry management practices to improve species diversity. (Sec. 3051) Limits federal expenditures for a project at Camp Ellis, Saco, Maine. (Sec. 3052) Modifies the navigation project at Union River, Maine, to redesignate as an anchorage area a specified portion of the project. (Sec. 3053) Amends the WRDA of: (1) 1996 to increase the funding limit for the Chesapeake Bay environmental restoration and protection program, Maryland, Pennsylvania, and Virginia; and (2) 1999 to increase the total authorized cost for a project at Cumberland, Maryland. (Sec. 3055) Allows the navigation project at Fall River Harbor, Massachusetts and Rhode Island, to remain authorized, but limits the authorized depth of a portion of the project. (Sec. 3056) Directs the Secretary to establish and lead a partnership of appropriate federal agencies and the State of Michigan to: (1) promote cooperation among governments and other involved parties in the management of the St. Clair River and Lake St. Clair watersheds; and (2) develop and implement projects consistent with the management plan. (Sec. 3057) Directs the Secretary to carry out the navigation project at Duluth Harbor, Minnesota. (Sec. 3058) Provides for a land exchange between S.S.S., Inc., and the Corps of Engineers, at Pike County, Missouri. (Sec. 3059) Directs the Secretary to offer to convey to Missouri land purchased for the Union Lake Project that was deauthorized. (Sec. 3060) Amends the WRDA of 2000 to increase the amount authorized for appropriation for the Fort Peck Fish Hatchery, Montana. (Sec. 3061) Directs the Secretary to carry out restoration projects in the watershed of the Yellowstone River and tributaries, Montana and North Dakota, to produce ecosystem restoration and recreation benefits. (Sec. 3062) Limits federal expenditures for the environmental restoration project at McCarran Ranch, Nevada. (Sec. 3063) Directs the Secretary to: (1) carry out restoration projects in the Middle Rio Grande from Cochiti Dam to the headwaters of Elephant Butte Reservoir, New Mexico; and (2) plan, design, and construct projects to increase aquatic habitats within Long Island Sound and adjacent waters, New York and Connecticut. (Sec. 3065) Amends the WRDA of 1996 to: (1) increase the maximum total federal cost of the project at Orchard Beach, Bronx, New York; and (2) authorize the Secretary to enter into cost-sharing agreements with non-federal public interests for the acquisition, design, construction, management, or operation of a dredged material processing, treatment, contaminant reduction, or disposal facility using government funds. (Sec. 3067) Amends the WRDA of: (1) 1999 to increase the authorized cost for the ecosystem restoration project at Onondaga Lake, New York; (2) extend the authorization of appropriations for Missouri River restoration, North Dakota; and (3) increase the authorization for repair and rehabilitation of the Lower Girard Lake Dam, Ohio. (Sec. 3070) Requires increased operation and maintenance activities for the Toussaint River Federal Navigation Project, Carroll Township, Ohio, relating directly to the presence of unexploded ordnance to be carried out at full federal expense. (Sec. 3071) Declares that payments made by the city of Edmond, Oklahoma, to the Secretary in October 1999 of all costs associated with water storage costs at Arcadia Lake, Oklahoma, under a specified contract shall satisfy the city's obligations. (Sec. 3072) Terminates each reversionary interest and use restriction relating to public parks and recreation on land conveyed by the Secretary to Oklahoma at Lake Texoma under a specified statute. (Sec. 3073) Sets the remaining obligation of the Waurika Project Master Conservancy District payable to the government at the amounts, rates of interest, and payment schedules that existed on June 3, 1986. (Sec. 3074) Directs the Secretary to: (1) convey to Lowell, Oregon, all U.S. rights to a parcel of land located in Lane County, Oregon; (2) conduct studies and ecosystem restoration projects for the upper Willamette River watershed from Albany, Oregon, to the headwaters of the Willamette River and tributaries; (3) convey to Tioga Township, Pennsylvania, all rights to a specified portion of the Tioga-Hammond Lakes Floods Control Project, Tioga County, Pennsylvania, for use as the site of the administrative offices and road maintenance complex. (Sec. 3077) Amends the WRDA of 1996 to authorize the Secretary, with respect to the ecosystem restoration project for the Upper Susquehanna River Basin, Pennsylvania and New York, to provide assistance for implementation of wetland restoration projects and soil and water conservation measures. (Sec. 3078) Authorizes the Secretary to carry out all planning, design, and construction for: (1) the demolition and removal of the Grace and Pearman Bridges over the Copper River, South Carolina; and (2) the development of an aquatic reef off the South Carolina shore, using the remnants from that demolition and removal. (Sec. 3079) Directs the Secretary to convey to South Carolina all U.S. rights to land managed by the South Carolina Department of Commerce for public recreation purposes for the Richard B. Russell Dam and Lake, South Carolina, project. (Sec. 3080) Amends the WRDA of: (1) 2000 to extend the authorization of appropriations for Missouri River restoration, South Dakota; and (2) 1999 to extend the authorization of appropriations through FY 2015. (Sec. 3082) Authorizes the Secretary to carry out a flood damage reduction project at Anderson Creek, Jackson and Madison Counties, Tennessee, if the Secretary determines that the project is technically sound, environmentally acceptable, and economically justified. (Sec. 3083) Allows the flood control project, Harris Fork Creek, Tennessee and Kentucky to remain authorized for seven years. (Sec. 3084) Authorizes the Secretary to reconstruct, repair, and maintain the weir originally constructed in the vicinity of the mouth of Nonconnah Creek, Tennessee and Mississippi. (Sec. 3085) Extinguishes the reversionary interests and use restrictions relating to recreation and camping for land conveyed by the Secretary to the Tennessee Society of Crippled Children and Adults, Inc. (Easter Seals Tennessee). (Sec. 3086) Authorizes the Secretary to carry out a flood damage reduction project at Sandy Creek, Jackson County, Tennessee, if the Secretary determines that the project is technically sound, environmentally acceptable, and economically justified. (Sec. 3087) Amends the WRDA of 2000 to authorize construction of a navigation channel ten feet wide by 100 feet instead of 12 feet by 125 feet. (Sec. 3088) Provides that: (1) all costs of the navigation project, Freeport Harbor, Texas, incurred as a result of the discovery of the sunken vessel Comstock of the Corps of Engineers are a federal responsibility; and (2) the Secretary shall not seek further obligation or responsibility for that vessel's removal or costs associated with a delay due to its discovery. (Sec. 3089) Amends the WRDA of: (1) 1996 to bar the Secretary from considering flood control works constructed by non-federal interests within the drainage area in the determination of conditions existing prior to construction of the Upper White Oak Bayou, Texas, project; and (2) 2000 to authorize the Secretary to carry out measures to restore, protect, and preserve an ecosystem affected by a dam, and to include nine specified dams to be evaluated, under a dam remediation project in Vermont. (Sec. 3091) Directs the Secretary to: (1) revise the existing General Design Memorandum to permit the use of chemical means of control of Eurasian milfoil, water chestnutes, and other non-native plants in the Lake Champlain basin, Vermont; (2) carry out a study and develop a strategy for the use of wetland restoration, soil and water conservation practices, and nonstructural measures to reduce flood damage, improve water quality, and create wildlife habitat in the Upper Connecticut River watershed; and (3) conduct a study and develop a general management plan for restoration of the Upper Connecticut River ecosystem. (Sec. 3094) Amends the WRDA of: (1) 2000 to include among critical restoration projects for Lake Champlain watershed, Vermont and New York, river corridor assessment, protection, management, and restoration for ecosystem restoration purposes, and geographic mapping to produce a high-resolution, multispectral satellite imagery-based land use and cover data set; and (2) 1986 to authorize the restoration and rehabilitation of habitat for fish, including native oysters, in the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries in Virginia and Maryland and to increase the project cost for the Tangier Island Seawall, Virginia. (Sec. 3097) Directs the Secretary to provide a one-time placement of dredged material along portions of the Columbia River shoreline of Puget Island, Washington, for erosion control for the Lower Columbia River levees and bank protection works with regard to the Wahkiakum County diking districts No. 1 and 3. (Sec. 3098) Extinguishes the reversionary interests and use restrictions relating to port or industrial purposes for the Lower Granite Pool, Washington. (Sec. 3099) Transfers to the Secretary of the Interior administrative jurisdiction over the land acquired for the McNary Lock and Dam Project, Washington and Idaho, to be managed as part of the McNary National Wildlife Refuge. Directs the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to obtain prior approval of the Washington State Department of Fish and Wildlife for any change to the previously approved site development plan for the Cummins property. (Sec. 3100) Amends the Fish and Wildlife Compensation Plan for the Lower Snake River, Washington, and Idaho, to authorize the Secretary to conduct studies and implement aquatic and riparian ecosystem restorations and improvements specifically for fisheries and wildlife. (Sec. 3101) Amends the WRDA of 1996 to increase authorized project costs for the Marmet Lock, Kanawha River, West Virginia, project. (Sec. 3102) Authorizes the Secretary to construct the flood control project at Lower Mud River, Milton, West Virginia, substantially in accordance with the May 2004 draft report of the Corps of Engineers. (Sec. 3103) Authorizes a width of 75 feet and a depth of six feet for the portion of the inner harbor of the federal navigation channel of the Green Bay Harbor project, Wisconsin. (Sec. 3104) Amends the WRDA of: (1) 1999 to direct the Secretary to undertake specified flood mitigation and riverine restoration activities at the Underwood Creek Diversion Facility Project, Milwaukee County, Wisconsin; (2) 1988 to allow the Secretary to operate headwaters reservoirs outside specified minimum or maximum water levels after consultation with the Governor of Minnesota, affected tribal governments, and other specified parties; and (3) 1992 to allow the purchase of riverfront property for the Lower Mississippi River Museum and Riverfront Interpretive Site. (Sec. 3107) Directs the Secretary to carry out a pilot program to restore and protect fish and wildlife habitat in the middle Mississippi River. (Sec. 3108) Allows a nongovernmental organization to be considered a non-federal interest with the consent of the affected local government. (Sec. 3109) Amends the WRDA of 2000 to direct the Secretary to carry out a reconnaissance study to identify methods of restoring the fishery, ecosystem, and beneficial uses of the Great Lakes. (Sec. 3110) Extends the authorization for programs for: (1) Great Lakes remedial action plans and sediment remediation; and (2) Great Lakes tributary models. Title IV: Studies - (Sec. 4001) Directs the Secretary to carry out studies: (1) to develop national protocols for the use of the Euhrychiopsis lecontei weevil for biological control of Eurasian milfoil in the lakes of Vermont and other northern tier States; (2) of the ability of coastal or deepwater port infrastructure to meet national economic needs; (3) to address selenium concentrations in Colorado; and (4) for bank stabilization and shore protection for Nicholas Canyon, Los Angeles, California. Requires the Secretary to convene a panel of experts in wildlife biology and genetics to review the genetic variation of sturgeon species in the McClellan-Kerr Arkansas River Navigation Channel. (Sec. 4006) Amends the WRDA of 2000 to increase by 12 months an extension for completing the Oceanside, California, Shoreline Special Study. (Sec. 4007) Directs the Secretary to: (1) review the flood control and environmental restoration project at St. Helena, California; (2) use specified planning and design documents as the basis for recommendations to Congress for authorization of a project to provide flood protection for the South San Francisco Bay shoreline and restoration of the South San Francisco Bay salt ponds; and (3) complete work on the San Pablo watershed, California, to determine the feasibility of opportunities for restoring, preserving, and protecting the San Pablo Bay Watershed. Directs the Secretary to conduct feasibility studies for: (1) a project to use Sherman Island, California, as a dredged material rehandling facility to enhance the environment and meet other water resource needs on the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta, California; (2) carrying out ecosystem restoration and related activity along the South Fork of the South Branch of the Chicago River, Illinois (Bubbly Creek); (3) modifying the project for enlargement of the navigation channels in the Grand and Tiger Passes and Baptiste Collette Bayou, Louisiana; (4) storm damage reduction and beach erosion protection along Lake Erie at Luna Pier, Michigan; and (5) a project for navigation improvements and shoreline protection for Middle Bass Island State Park, Middle Bass Island, Ohio. (Sec. 4015) Authorizes the Secretary to determine the feasibility of: (1) providing improvements to the Savannah River for navigation and related purposes necessary to support the location of container cargo and other port facilities to be located in Jasper County, South Carolina; and (2) a dispersal barrier project at the Lake Champlain Canal. Title V: Miscellaneous Provisions - (Sec. 5001) Amends the WRDA of 1986 to provide for the removal of silt and related measures for sites (besides the Great Lakes) in Illinois, North Dakota, Vermont, and North Carolina. (Sec. 5002) Adds to the purposes of the Estuary Restoration Act of 2000 the implementation of a coordinated federal approach to estuary habitat restoration activities. Allows the Secretary, at the recommendation of the Estuary Habitat Restoration Council (established by this section), to delegate the implementation of projects costing less than $1 million to the Secretary of the Interior, the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere of the Department of Commerce, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, or the Secretary of Agriculture. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 5003) Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance to the Secretary of Agriculture for use in carrying out the Conservation Corridor Demonstration Program. (Sec. 5004) Designates the Division Engineer, North Atlantic Division, Corps of Engineers, as the ex officio U.S. member under the Susquehanna River Basin Compact, the Delaware River Basin Compact, and the Potomac River Basin Compact. Directs the Secretary to enter into agreements with the Susquehanna, Delaware, and Potomac River Basin Commissions to provide temporary water supply and conservation storage during any period in which such Commissions have determined that a drought warning or drought emergency exists. (Sec. 5005) Directs the Secretary to upgrade and make permanent the existing Chicago Sanitary and Ship Canal Dispersal Barrier, Chicago, Illinois. (Sec. 5006) Rio Grande Environmental Management Act of 2004 [sic] - Directs the Secretary to carry out in the Rio Grande system : (1) a program for the planning, construction, and evaluation of measures for fish and wildlife habitat rehabilitation and enhancement; and (2) implementation of a long-term monitoring, computerized data inventory and analysis, applied research, and adaptive management program. (Sec. 5007) Amends the WRDA of 1999 to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to make funds available to the State of South Dakota Terrestrial Wildlife Habitat Restoration Trust Fund. (Sec. 5008) Directs the Secretary to evaluate, design, and construct structural modifications to the Union Village, North Hartland, North Springfield, Ball Mountain, and Townshend Dams in Vermont to regulate flow and temperature to mitigate downstream impacts on aquatic habitat and fisheries. Title VI: Project Deauthorizations - (Sec. 6001) Deauthorizes specified flood damage reduction, flood control, navigation, environmental infrastructure, bridge construction, water supply, recreation, erosion protection, bulkhead construction and repair, jetty construction, cropland irrigation, and soil conservation projects in Alabama, California, Connecticut, Delaware and Maryland, Florida, Indiana, Iowa, Kentucky and Tennessee, Louisiana, Maine, Michigan, Mississippi, Nebraska, New Hampshire, New York, North Carolina and South Carolina, Ohio, Oregon, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Texas, Washington, and West Virginia.</summary>
</bill>
