<bill session="109" type="s" number="3724" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">EPSCoR Research and Competitiveness Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance scientific research and competitiveness through the Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2006-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2006-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2006-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2006-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2006-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2006-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2006-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2006-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8201"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="High technology"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scientific instruments and apparatus"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2006--Introduced.
EPSCoR Research and Competitiveness Act of 2006 - Authorizes appropriations for FY2007-FY2011 to the National Science Foundation (NSF) for the Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research (EPSCoR). Requires the Director of the NSF: (1) in the administration of the NSF's research infrastructure improvement grant program, to authorize states participating in the grant program to include partnership with out-of-state research institutions if the amount of funding transferred to another state does not exceed 5% of the amount of the grant in any fiscal year; and (2) from the amounts appropriated pursuant to this Act, to make available specified amounts for FY2007-FY2011 to such grant program. Requires the Director to obligate and spend not less than 20% of the amount available for EPSCoR on co-funding projects that are ranked by a peer-review process in the top 20% of all proposals submitted in response to an announced competition. Requires the submission of annual reports providing information concerning: (1) co-funded projects on a state-by-state basis; and (2) the amount and use of co-funding by each of the NSF's directorates. Requires the Director: (1) through the Office of Cyber Infrastructure, to develop and publish a plan enabling states participating in EPSCoR to develop partnerships and participate fully in the NSF's Cyber Infrastructure Initiative; and (2) through the Office of Major Research Instrumentation, to develop and publish a plan enabling states participating in EPSCoR to develop partnerships and participate fully in the NSF's major research instrumentation program.</summary>
</bill>
