<bill session="112" type="h" number="3120" updated="2013-07-20T01:37:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-01T20:47:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-08-01T20:47:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Student Visa Reform Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Student Visa Reform Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Student Visa Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to require accreditation of certain educational institutions for purposes of a nonimmigrant student visa, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400245"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-26">
      <text>Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-06-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-12T14:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 112-595.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-07-12T14:10:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="430">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 430.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T19:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T19:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5504-5506" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T19:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3120.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31T19:47:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Smith (TX) objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01T20:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5619" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-08-01T20:47:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/31/2012 H5504-5505" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01T20:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration Policy and Enforcement" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2012--Passed House amended.
Student Visa Reform Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require that a person coming to study at a college, university, or language training program in the United States under a nonimmigrant student F-visa must attend an institution that is accredited by an accrediting agency recognized by the Secretary of Education. Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to require academic institutions (exempts seminaries or other religious institutions) to be similarly accredited for F-visa purposes if: (1) the institution is not already required to be accredited, (2) an accrediting agency recognized by the Secretary of Education is able to provide such accreditation, and (3) 25 or more F-visa foreign students are or will be pursuing a course of study at the institution. Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to waive the accreditation requirement for an established college, university, or language training program that is otherwise in compliance with F-visa provisions and is making a good faith effort to satisfy the accreditation requirement. Prohibits a person convicted of certain felony offenses, including human trafficking or visa fraud relating to an academic institution's participation in the Student and Exchange Visitor Program (SEVP), from having subsequent ownership or substantial authority at an academic institution participating in SEVP. Provides a three-year exemption for students coming to study at a college or university that has been certified by the Secretary of Homeland Security but not yet accredited or denied accreditation by an accrediting agency.</summary>
</bill>
