<bill session="109" type="s" number="2378" updated="2013-07-19T20:34:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Broadband Data and E-rate Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to ensure that tribal libraries that receive assistance under the Library Services and Technology Act are eligible for E-rate assistance to the same extent as other libraries receiving such assistance and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300015" joined="2006-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2006-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2006-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2006-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/2006--Introduced.
Broadband Data and E-rate Improvement Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to make ineligible for preferential rates (E-rate assistance) or treatment with respect to universal telecommunications service any library or library consortium (tribal library) ineligible for assistance funded by a grant under the Library Services and Technology Act (LSTA) from an Indian tribe or other organization. (Thus makes LSTA grant-eligible tribal libraries also eligible for E-rate assistance to the same extent as other libraries receiving such assistance.) Directs the Secretary of Commerce to expand the American Community Survey conducted by the Bureau of the Census to elicit information for residential households, including those located on native lands, as to what technology such households use to access the Internet from home.</summary>
</bill>
