<bill session="112" type="h" number="3174" updated="2013-07-20T01:37:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Postal Service Pension Obligation Recalculation and Restoration Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the provisions of title 5, United States Code, relating to the methodology for calculating the amount of any Postal surplus or supplemental liability under the Civil Service Retirement System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400402"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy     .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1351"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="1649"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1688"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/2011--Introduced.
United States Postal Service Pension Obligation Recalculation and Restoration Act of 2011 - Prescribes the "average pay" to be used in determining annuities for civilian employment with the United States Postal Service (USPS) for purposes of provisions relating to future benefits attributable to such employment in order to calculate the amount of any USPS surplus or supplemental liability under the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS). Requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM): (1) within six months after enactment of this Act, to determine (or, if applicable, redetermine) the amount of such surplus or liability as of the close of the most recently ending fiscal year using the methodology required under this Act; and (2) if the result is a surplus, to transfer the surplus amount to the Postal Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund within 15 days after the determination of a surplus. Provides for an alternate determination of a USPS surplus or supplemental liability for FY2016-FY2020. Requires transfer of certain surplus postal retirement contributions in FY2011 to the Postal&#160;Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund or the Employees' Compensation Fund under the Federal Employees' Compensation Act. Prohibits USPS from closing any post office which is located more than 10 miles from any other post office. Expresses the intent of Congress that this Act shall apply to allocations of past, present, and future benefit liabilities between the USPS and the Treasury.</summary>
</bill>
