<bill session="113" type="s" number="884" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deter Cyber Theft Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Director of National Intelligence to develop a watch list and a priority watch list of foreign countries that engage in economic or industrial espionage in cyberspace with respect to United States trade secrets or proprietary information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2013-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3165-3166"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3166-3167" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2013--Introduced.
Deter Cyber Theft Act - Requires the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) to annually report to specified congressional committees on foreign countries that engage in economic and industrial espionage in cyberspace with respect to U.S. trade secrets or proprietary information. Requires each report to identify countries that engage in such espionage as well as countries that engage in the most egregious forms of such espionage. Directs the President to exclude from entry into the United States any article produced or exported by an entity identified within any such report, as long as the President determines that such exclusion is warranted for the enforcement of intellectual property rights or to protect the integrity of the Department of Defense (DOD) supply chain.</summary>
</bill>
