<bill session="109" type="s" number="3628" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">EXTEND the Energy Efficiency Incentives Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve and extend certain energy-related tax provisions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2006-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2006-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2006-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6809-6810"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air conditioning"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Heat pumps"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2006--Introduced.
EXTEND the Energy Efficiency Incentives Act of 2006 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) to allow individual taxpayers a tax credit, through 2010, for residential energy efficiency expenditures certified to achieve certain levels of energy savings; (2) modify standards for nonbusiness energy property (i.e., air conditioners, heat pumps, water heaters, etc.) and extend the tax credit for such property through 2010; (3) revise the tax credit for solar electric and hot water property to include all technologies for solar-derived electricity; (4) extend through 2010 the tax credits for residential energy efficient property and new energy efficient homes; (5) extend through 2011 the tax deduction for energy efficient commercial buildings and increase the maximum amount of such deduction; (6) allow a tax deduction for energy efficient low-rise buildings (four stories or less); (7) extend through 2011 the investment tax credit for solar energy and fuel cell property; and (8) allow a business-related tax credit for qualified training and certification costs and equipment expenditures for certifying residential energy savings.</summary>
</bill>
