<bill session="109" type="h" number="2411" updated="2013-07-19T19:25:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Matthew Boisvert Help Extend Respect Owed to Every Soldier (HEROES) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide improved benefits and procedures for the transition of members of the Armed Forces from combat zones to noncombat zones and for the transition of veterans from service in the Armed Forces to civilian life.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400269"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Group counseling"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Poisons"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Psychiatrists"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Suicide"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Toxicology"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2005--Introduced.
Matthew Voisbert Help Extend Respect Owed to Every Soldier (HEROES) Act - Requires: (1) the Secretary of Defense to establish minimum uniform standards for postdeployment medical examinations; (2) that such examinations include screening for mental health and substance abuse disorders; and (3) follow-up services in appropriate cases. Directs the Secretary of Defense to foster the early identification and treatment of mental health and substance abuse disorders experienced by members of the Armed Forces, with special emphasis on members who have served in a theater of combat operations within the preceding 12 months. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to employ at least one psychiatrist and a complementary medical team at each Department of Veterans Affairs (Department) medical center to conduct a specialized program for the diagnosis and treatment of post-traumatic stress disorder, and to employ additional mental health services specialists at such center. Authorizes such Secretary to contract for mental health and substance abuse treatment services in non-Department facilities when such services are not available in Department facilities. Requires the Secretary of Defense to transmit to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs: (1) within seven days the medical records of all military personnel being discharged, released from active duty, or retired; and (2) a roster of all personnel who have served in the theater of operations during Operations Iraqi Freedom or Enduring Freedom. Directs the Secretary of Defense to assist eligible persons in obtaining employment in stable and permanent positions. Requires individualized transitional services to be provided to separating military personnel. Includes additional elements within a program under which the Secretary of Labor provides services and information to separating military personnel and their spouses. Requires the Secretaries of Defense and Homeland Security to: (1) ensure that transition programs are provided at each military installation, National Guard armory and military family support center, and inpatient medical care facility; (2) ensure that military and veterans' service organizations and representatives are permitted to participate in such transition programs; and (3) facilitate the access of such State organizations and representatives to provide preseparation counseling and services to separating members. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to facilitate the access of such organizations and representatives to provide member information on the care and services available. Requires the Secretaries of Defense and Veterans Affairs to facilitate the sharing between their respective departments of information concerning member duties and assignments, exposures to toxic or hazardous substances, and illnesses or injuries incurred or aggravated in the course of such duties and assignments. Rescinds a Department Memorandum entitled "Status of VHA Enrollment and Associated Issues." Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to provide mortgage assistance to members who are seriously injured during military service. Repeals the $1,200 reduction in basic pay currently required for participation in the Montgomery GI Bill educational assistance program.</summary>
</bill>
