<bill session="113" type="h" number="2700" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Waiver Fairness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to provide for a process for waiver of requirements of that title where the requirement is asserted to otherwise result in a significant decrease in access to coverage or significant increase in premiums or other costs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400342"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2013-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2013--Introduced.
Health Care Waiver Fairness Act of 2013 - Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of Treasury to establish waiver processes under which the administrator of a health plan, an employer, an individual, or other entity may seek to waive the application of a health insurance coverage requirement under PPACA. Sets forth PPACA requirements that may be waived, including those related to minimum essential coverage and employers offering health care coverage to employees. Establishes requirements for the waiver process, including requiring submission of a statement describing how the imposition of the PPACA requirement would result in a significant decrease in access to coverage or a significant increase in premiums or other costs for such plan, employer, individual, or entity. Deems to be approved any waiver including such a statement. Requires the Secretary of HHS to conduct a public awareness campaign of the waiver process with funds made available for the Prevention and Public Health Fund.</summary>
</bill>
