<bill session="110" type="h" number="4019" updated="2013-07-19T21:39:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mortgage Disclosure Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to enhance disclosure of the terms of home mortgage loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2153"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2636"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mortgage interest rates"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/31/2007--Introduced.
Mortgage Disclosure Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to require a creditor to disclose to a consumer with respect to an extension of credit secured by the consumer's dwelling that the consumer is not required to complete the credit agreement merely because the consumer has received required disclosures or signed a loan application. Requires such disclosure to be furnished to the borrower not later than seven business days before the consummation of the transaction, as well as at the time of consummation. Requires additional disclosures in such a circumstance regarding any variable rates or payment schedules. Increases the actual damages for which a creditor is liable for noncompliance with such Act in the case of an individual action relating to a credit transaction not under an open end credit plan that is secured by real property or a dwelling. Replaces the current range of damages from $200 to $2,000 with a flat damages amount of $5,000, adjusted annually for inflation.</summary>
</bill>
