<bill session="109" type="h" number="5471" updated="2013-07-19T19:52:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Soledad Canyon Mine Leases Adjustment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide to the Bureau of Land Management a mechanism to cancel certain mining leases for lands in the leases CA-20139 and CA-22901 and provide new leasing opportunities in the Soledad Canyon adjacent to the City of Santa Clarita, California, that reflect the historical mining levels, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2006-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-01">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Mining engineering"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Sand and gravel industry"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2006--Introduced.
Soledad Canyon Mine Leases Adjustment Act - Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to cancel Bureau of Land Management leases CA-20139 and CA-22901 on lands subject to a federal mineral estate, which are located in Soledad Canyon adjacent to Santa Clarita, California. Directs the Secretary to provide to the Transit Mixed Concrete Corporation (TMC) other financial and mineral production opportunities in exchange for the economic value invested in trying to bring leases CA-20139 and CA-22901 into commercial production. Requires TMC to submit to the Secretary an itemized list with supporting documentation so the Secretary can determine that expenses associated with the leases are reasonable. Prohibits the Secretary from issuing leases for mining sand and gravel in the Soledad Canyon area of California that in the aggregate authorize mining exceeding historical production levels. Requires the Secretary, before issuing any lease authorizing the mining of sand or gravel in such area, to: (1) consult with the city of Santa Clarita, California, Los Angeles County, California, and the surface owners in the area; and (2) take into consideration the environmental and transportation concerns of such mining on the area.</summary>
</bill>
