<bill session="112" type="h" number="1604" updated="2013-07-20T01:24:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To facilitate certain activities, alleviate the extra regulatory burdens, and reduce costs related to carrying out projects of the Central Valley Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412403"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412190" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400297" joined="2011-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2011--Introduced.
Deems the submission of a Notice of Determination for a CVP project or issuance of a permit related to such project in accordance with the California Environmental Quality Act to meet environmental impact statement requirements of the National Environmental Protection Act of 1969 for that project or permit. Declares that the Bureau of Reclamation shall not be required to cease activity on such a project pending completion of a review or legal challenge of such a Notice or issuance of such a permit. Defines "CVP" to mean Central Valley Project and "project" to mean activity that: (1) is undertaken or funded by, or that requires an issuance of a permit by, a public agency; (2) has a potential to result in physical change to the environment; (3) may be subject to several discretionary approvals by governmental agencies; and (4) may include construction activities, clearing or grading of land, improvements to existing structures, and activities or equipment involving the issuance of a permit. Subjects an authorized CVP project to judicial review only in the U.S. district court for a district in which the authorized project is located. Limits the length of preliminary injunctive relief and stays pending appeal covering an authorized CVP project to 60 days, subject to renewals. Directs the court, in considering an injunction to an agency action under an authorized project, to balance the impact to the ecosystem likely affected by the project of the short- and long-term effects of undertaking the action against those of not undertaking the action.</summary>
</bill>
