<bill session="110" type="h" number="1504" updated="2013-07-19T21:16:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Beaches Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure the continuation and improvement of coastal restoration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2007-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Beaches"/>
    <term name="Civil engineering"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Quality of life"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sediment control"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2007--Introduced.
Community Beaches Protection Act - Rewrites provisions regarding the federal shore protection program to: (1) provide for the protection and restoration of beaches and other coastal infrastructure, as well as shore protection; and (2) include the purpose of promoting healthful recreation. Includes among areas to be given preference: (1) areas where regional sediment management plans have been adopted; and (2) areas that promote human health and safety and the quality of life. Directs the Secretary of the Army to pay the federal share of the cost of carrying out shore protection projects and research that encourages the protection, restoration, and enhancement of shores, sandy beaches, and other coastal infrastructure. Sets forth revised provisions regarding the federal share of the cost, which shall be equal for beach erosion control projects for purposes of recreation or for storm damage protection or environmental restoration. Directs the Secretary, at the request of a nonfederal interest and with congressional approval, to extend the period of federal participation in certain shore protection projects. Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 to prohibit the Secretary from: (1) soliciting contributions, in excess of the nonfederal share assigned to specified project purposes, from nonfederal interests for costs of constructing authorized projects; or (2) conditioning federal participation on the receipt of such contributions. Makes permanent the national shoreline erosion control development and demonstration program. Requires the program to include provisions for technology transfers to educational institutions. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cost-sharing agreements with nonfederal interests, and to modify existing shoreline protection projects, under specified circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
