<bill session="109" type="s" number="1223" updated="2013-07-19T20:24:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Information Technology for Health Care Quality Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve the quality and efficiency of health care delivery through improvements in health care information technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="2005-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6333-6334"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6334-6337" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Hospital personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Human engineering"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public health administration"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2005--Introduced.
Information Technology for Health Care Quality Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the Office of Health Information Technology to: (1) improve the quality and efficiency of health care delivery through the use of health information technology; (2) provide national leadership relating to such technology; (3) direct all federal health information technology activities; (4) facilitate the interaction between the federal government and the private sector relating to the development and use of such technology; and (5) develop a national strategy for improving the quality and enhancing the efficiency of health care through the use of such technology and the creation of a National Health Information Infrastructure. Requires the Director of the Office to approve or disapprove the policies of federal departments or agencies that would significantly affect the use of such technology, and provide for the adoption and dissemination of government standards that promote the efficient exchange of data between health information technology systems. Prohibits the Secretary of Health and Human Services from purchasing any health care information technology system that is not in compliance with such standards. Requires the Director to guarantee payment of the principal and interest on loans made to eligible entities, and award competitive matching grants, to: (1) implement local health information infrastructure to facilitate the development of interoperability across health care settings; or (2) facilitate the purchase and adoption of health information technology. Requires the Secretary, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish uniform health care quality measures and public reporting requirements across all federally supported health delivery programs.</summary>
</bill>
