<bill session="109" type="s" number="2400" updated="2013-07-19T20:34:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to transfer authority to review certain mergers, acquisitions, and takeovers of United States entities by foreign entities to a designee established within the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2006-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2006-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2006-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2006-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2006-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="2006-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1927"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2028-2030"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2030-2031" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Business intelligence"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Dubai Ports World aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2006--Introduced.
Amends the Defense Production Act of 1950 to repeal provisions concerning presidential authority to review certain proposed mergers, acquisitions, or takeovers (transactions) of U.S. entities by foreign entities. Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the President (or his designee) to undertake an investigation to determine the effects on national or homeland security of transactions which could result in foreign control of persons engaged in interstate commerce in the United States. Requires the President to first conduct a review of the proposed transaction to determine whether an investigation is warranted. Requires, with respect to any investigation conducted, the Director of National Intelligence to create a report consolidating the intelligence findings, assessments, and concerns of each of the relevant members of the intelligence community. Requires the President to conduct a mandatory investigation in any instance in which an entity controlled by or acting on behalf of a foreign government seeks to engage in any transaction which would result in control of a person engaged in interstate commerce in the United States. Establishes the Committee for Secure Commerce to act as the President's designee in the conduct of such investigations. Authorizes the President to suspend or prohibit a transaction if he finds that: (1) there is credible evidence to believe that the foreign interest exercising control might take action that threatens the national or homeland security; and (2) provisions of law other than the Homeland Security Act of 2002 and the International Emergency Economic Powers Act do not provide adequate and appropriate authority to protect the national or homeland security. States that the President's actions and findings shall not be subject to judicial review. Requires reports from the President to Congress: (1) each time an investigation is completed; and (2) quarterly on each transaction being reviewed.</summary>
</bill>
