<bill session="111" type="s" number="3724" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of Education to pay to Fort Lewis College in the State of Colorado an amount equal to the tuition charges for Indian students who are not residents of the State of Colorado.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2010-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5974"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of Education, beginning in FY2011, to pay to Fort Lewis College in Colorado an amount equal to the charges for tuition for Indian students who are not residents of Colorado and who are enrolled in the College. Limits the amount paid to Fort Lewis College per fiscal year to an amount equal to the charges for tuition for Indian students who were Colorado non-residents and who were enrolled for the academic year 2009-2010. Treats amounts received under this Act as a reimbursement from Colorado to Fort Lewis College for complying with federal law requiring the admission of Indian students at the College free of charge of tuition. Prohibits anything in this Act from being construed as relieving Colorado from reimbursing Fort Lewis College for each academic year: (1) with respect to Indian students who are not Colorado residents and who are enrolled in Fort Lewis College, any amount of the charges for tuition for such enrolled Indian students which exceeds the amount received under this Act; and (2) with respect to Indian students who are Colorado residents and who are enrolled in Fort Lewis College, an amount equal to the charges for tuition for such enrolled Indian students.</summary>
</bill>
