<bill session="112" type="h" number="4109" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Los Padres Conservation and Recreation Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Los Padres National Forest Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate additional National Forest System land in the Los Padres National Forest in the State of California as wilderness, to make certain wild and scenic river designations in that National Forest, to designate the Condor Ridge Scenic Area, to address off highway vehicle use in that National Forest, to facilitate a land exchange with the United Water Conservation District of California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/29/2012--Introduced.
Los Padres Conservation and Recreation Act of 2012 - Designates specified National Forest System lands in California that are administered as part of the Los Padres National Forest as wilderness and as additions to existing components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate specified creek segments in California as wild, scenic, or recreational rivers. Establishes the Condor Ridge Scenic Area within the National Forest. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to develop a comprehensive management plan for such area. Designates within the National Forest: (1) specified roads and trails for certain off-highway vehicle use, and (2) specified areas as off-highway vehicle areas. Directs the Secretary to study and report on the feasibility of and the public interest in the construction of specified new trails respecting the National Forest. Los Padres National Forest Land Exchange Act - Directs the Secretary to convey specified National Forest System lands to the United Water Conservation District of California in exchange for the conveyance of specified non-federal lands to the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to reserve easements for all trails and roads considered necessary for administrative purposes and to ensure public access.</summary>
</bill>
