<bill session="112" type="s" number="3657" updated="2013-07-20T02:48:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">LINE Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lines Interfere with National Elections Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to ensure that voters in elections for Federal office do not wait in long lines in order to vote.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6632"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2012--Introduced.
Lines Interfere with National Elections Act of 2012 or LINE Act of 2012 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require each state to provide for the minimum required number of voting systems, poll workers, and other election resources (including all other physical resources) for each voting site on the day of any federal election and on any days during which the state allows early voting for a federal election in accordance with standards established under this Act. Directs the Attorney General, to the maximum extent practicable in coordination with the Election Assistance Commission, to issue standards for a uniform and non-discriminatory distribution of such systems, workers, and other resources, taking into account with respect to any voting site, among other factors, the voting age population, the needs and numbers of disabled voters, and voters with limited English proficiency. Requires the standards, to the extent possible, to provide for a distribution of voting systems, poll workers, and other election resources with the goal of: (1) ensuring an equal waiting time for all voters in the state, and (2) preventing a waiting time of over one hour at any polling place. Requires each jurisdiction where a substantial number of voters waited more than 90 minutes to cast a vote in the federal election held on November 6, 2012, or any federal election held after that date, to comply with a state remedial plan to minimize voter waiting times.</summary>
</bill>
