<bill session="110" type="h" number="3922" updated="2013-07-19T21:38:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gang Reduction, Investment, and Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand and improve Federal gang prevention programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400212" joined="2007-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1582"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3547"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="456"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Homicide"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/22/2007--Introduced.
Gang Reduction, Investment, and Prevention Act - Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) designate and provide assistance to high-intensity gang activity areas in specified states and localities; (2) make grants to develop community-based programs for gang members and high-risk youth; (3) expand the Project Safe Neighborhoods program; (4) expand the Safe Streets Program of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to support criminal street gang enforcement teams; and (5) make grants for demonstration projects to carry out innovative approaches to combat gang activity.Directs the Attorney General to establish a National Gang Activity Database to provide information to law enforcement agencies about criminal street gangs.Directs the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice (DOJ) to establish a National Gang Research, Evaluation, and Policy Institute to implement programs to combat gang violence, including conducting a national conference to teach and promote gang violence prevention, intervention, and reentry strategies and establishing one or more gang intervention academies to promote effective gang intervention and policing.Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to authorize grants to assist prosecutors and law enforcement officers in investigating and prosecuting gang members and violent offenders.Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to expand the number of sites receiving juvenile delinquency reduction grants from 4 to 12. Extends funding for the Mentoring Initiative for System Involved Youth Program through FY2013.Establishes in the U.S. Marshals Service a Short-Term State Witness Protection Section to provide protection for witnesses in state and local trials involving homicide or other major violent crimes. Authorizes the Attorney General to make grants to prosecutor's offices to identify witnesses in need of protection.</summary>
</bill>
