<bill session="111" type="h" number="5218" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Great Teachers for Great Schools Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide for school improvement and professional development for teachers, principals, instructional staff, and other school leaders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2010-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2010-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2010--Introduced.
Great Teachers for Great Schools Act of 2010 - Amends title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to create a new part E (Building School Capacity for Effective Teaching). Directs the Secretary of Education to allot funds to states for subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to implement professional development systems that represent comprehensive, sustained, and intensive approaches to improving teachers' and principals' effectiveness that: (1) foster collective responsibility for improved student performance; (2) constitute professional learning that primarily occurs several times each week among established teams of teachers, principals, and other instructional staff; and (3) may be supported by activities such as courses, workshops, institutes, networks, and conferences. Requires states to first award subgrants to LEAs: (1) that demonstrate the greatest need for such funds; (2) in which the average graduation rates are less than 65%, if applicable; and (3) in which children who are eligible for free and reduced price meals under the school lunch program constitute at least 40% of the population of children aged 5 to 17 they serve. Allows LEA subgrantees to use school improvement funds received under title I of the ESEA to supplement professional development activities under this Act, which are to be integrated and aligned with their state's school improvement efforts under title I. Requires the professional development programs to include a system of formal evaluations conducted by states, LEAs, institutions of higher education, or external agencies experienced in conducting qualitative research.</summary>
</bill>
