<bill session="113" type="h" number="1509" updated="2013-11-02T06:31:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Autism Understanding and Training in School Methodologies for Educators Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a 5-year demonstration program to provide skills to classroom teachers and staff who work with children with autism spectrum disorders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2013-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2013--Introduced.
Autism Understanding and Training in School Methodologies for Educators Act of 2013 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to carry out a demonstration program to award 5-year grants to eligible local education agencies for the following purposes in schools for children in grades pre-kindergarten through 12: providing training to teachers, paraprofessionals, and other staff on effective ways to teach, communicate, recognize, support, and interact with children with autism spectrum disorders in the classroom; providing technical assistance consisting of consultation on the type of training needed, hands-on opportunities to practice and perform newly acquired skills and methodologies, and post-training support to ensure accuracy of implementation in the classroom; executing strategies for recruiting and retaining skilled personnel participating in the education of children with such disorders; and implementing a program of parental support and involvement in the education of students with such disorders.</summary>
</bill>
