<bill session="112" type="h" number="3490" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">21st Century Green High-Performing Public School Facilities Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Education to make grants to State educational agencies for the modernization, renovation, or repair of public school facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400442"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2012-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2012-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2914"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2011--Introduced.
21st Century Green High-Performing Public School Facilities Act - Requires the Secretary of Education to make grants to states for the modernization, renovation, or repair of public schools, including early learning facilities and charter schools, to make them safe, healthy, high-performing, and technologically up-to-date. Allocates grants among states in proportion to each state's share of school improvement funds under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Reserves 2% of the grant funds for assistance to outlying areas and Indian schools. Reserves 5% of the grant funds for LEAs serving geographic areas with significant economic distress and those serving geographic areas recovering from a natural disaster. Requires states to reallocate such grant funds to LEAs on the basis of each LEA's share of school improvement funds. Allows LEAs to give priority to projects involving the abatement, removal, or interim control of asbestos, polychlorinated biphenyls, mold, mildew, lead-based hazards, or a proven carcinogen. Directs LEA grantees to use a percentage of their grant, rising in 10% increments from 50% in FY2012 to 100% in FY2017, for public school modernization, renovation, repairs, or construction that meet Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED) green building rating standards, Energy Star standards, Collaborative for High Performance Schools (CHPS) criteria, Green Building Initiative environmental design and rating standards (Green Globes), or equivalent standards adopted by the entities that have jurisdiction over such LEAs. Requires the Secretary to provide outreach and technical assistance to states and LEAs concerning the best practices in school modernization, renovation, repair, and construction. Requires the Department of Education to evaluate the effect this Act's projects have on student academic achievement. Directs the Secretary to establish an Advisory Council on Green, High-Performing Schools to provide the Secretary with advice on the academic, health, energy, and environmental impact of such schools and assistance in facilitating their creation. Requires the Secretary to work with grant recipients to promote appropriate opportunities for individuals enrolled in a YouthBuild, Job Corps, or community or junior college program to gain employment experience on projects funded under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
