<bill session="113" type="s" number="1184" updated="2013-11-02T07:02:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Treat and Reduce Obesity Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to include information on the coverage of intensive behavioral therapy for obesity in the Medicare and You Handbook and to provide for the coordination of programs to prevent and treat obesity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2013-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2415"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug and radiation therapy"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2013--Introduced.
Treat and Reduce Obesity Act of 2013 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to include information on the coverage of intensive behavioral therapy for obesity in the "Medicare and You Handbook." Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop and implement a plan to coordinate the efforts of all HHS officers and agencies to treat, reduce, and prevent obesity and overweight in the adult population. Authorizes the Secretary, in addition to qualified primary care physicians and other primary care practitioners, to cover intensive behavioral therapy for obesity furnished by: (1) a physician who is not a qualified primary care physician; (2) an evidence-based, community-based HHS-certified lifestyle counseling program; or (3) any other appropriate health care provider (including a physician assistant, nurse practitioner, clinical nurse specialist, a clinical psychologist, and a registered dietitian or nutrition professional) upon referral from, and in coordination with, a physician or primary care practitioner in an office setting, a hospital outpatient department, or another HHS-specified setting. Authorizes the Secretary to cover under Medicare part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) medication for treatment of obesity or for being overweight for individuals with one or more comorbidities.</summary>
</bill>
