<bill session="110" type="s" number="2451" updated="2013-07-19T22:42:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">First Step Forward Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance public safety by improving the reintegration of youth offenders into the families and communities to which they are returning.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5178"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Community service (Punishment)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational vouchers"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2007--Introduced.
First Step Forward Act of 2007 - Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to: (1) require information on the number of juveniles (under age 21) released from prison and their living arrangements upon release in the annual report of the Administrator of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Office; (2) require states seeking juvenile justice grants to adopt procedures to assure the availability of post-release programs and services for juvenile offenders; and (3) require research and evaluation on outcomes for juvenile offenders who have been released from custody and reintegrated into communities. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) award grants to states to establish programs to identify juveniles likely to be released before attaining age 21 and to help such juveniles attain self-sufficiency; (2) develop outcome measures to assess the performance of states in operating juvenile offender reentry programs and track services provided to such offenders; and (3) conduct evaluations of state juvenile offender reentry programs. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to continue health care benefits for juvenile offenders after release from incarceration.</summary>
</bill>
