<bill session="110" type="s" number="1807" updated="2013-07-19T22:36:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Weather Mitigation Research and Development Policy Authorization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Weather Mitigation Advisory and Research Board, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300054"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3445"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Weather"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2007--Introduced.
Weather Mitigation Research and Development Policy Authorization Act of 2007 - Establishes in the National Science Foundation (NSF) the Weather Mitigation Advisory and Research Board to establish and coordinate the national research and development program on weather mitigation described in this Act. Requires the Executive Director of the Board to submit a plan for the establishment and coordination of the Program. Requires the Board to promote and fund research and development (R&amp;D), studies, and investigations with respect to: (1) improved forecast and decisionmaking technologies for weather mitigation operations, including tailored computer workstations and software and new observation systems with remote sensors; and (2) assessments and evaluations of the efficacy of weather mitigation. Authorizes the Board to establish a grant program for the awarding of grants to eligible entities (state agencies, institutions of higher education, and nonprofits that have expertise in the field of weather mitigation and experience working with state agencies) for R&amp;D projects that pertain to weather mitigation. Permits a grant recipient to only use the grant for a R&amp;D project that: (1) pertains to weather mitigation; and (2) was in operation on the day before the grant was awarded. Requires the submission of annual reports to the President and Congress on the activities conducted pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
