<bill session="112" type="h" number="4135" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Western Hemisphere Energy Security Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit United States companies to participate in the exploration for and the extraction of hydrocarbon resources from any portion of a foreign maritime exclusive economic zone that is contiguous to the exclusive economic zone of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2012-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA18" subcommittee="Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2012--Introduced.
Western Hemisphere Energy Security Act of 2012 - Permits U.S. persons (including agents and affiliates) to: (1) engage in any transaction necessary for either exploration and extraction of hydrocarbon resources or for oil spill prevention and clean-up activities from any portion of a foreign exclusive economic zone contiguous to the U.S. exclusive economic zone; (2) export without license authority all equipment necessary for such exploration, extraction, or oil spill prevention and clean-up activities; and (3) import into the United States the hydrocarbon resources and products that are extracted under this Act. Amends the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 to instruct the Secretary of the Treasury to authorize under a general license certain travel-related transactions for travel to, from, or within Cuba in connection with either exploration and extraction of hydrocarbon resources or oil spill prevention and clean-up activities in any such part of a foreign maritime exclusive economic zone contiguous to the U.S. exclusive economic zone. Includes among persons authorized to travel to Cuba under this Act full-time employees, executives, agents, and consultants of oil and gas producers, distributors, shippers, and persons who engage in oil spill prevention and clean-up activities.</summary>
</bill>
