<bill session="111" type="h" number="3330" updated="2013-07-19T23:42:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-29T10:50:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-07-29T10:50:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improved Oversight by Financial Inspectors General Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Improved Oversight by Financial Inspectors General Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act and the Federal Credit Union Act to provide more effective reviews of losses in the Deposit Insurance Fund and the Share Insurance Fund by the Inspectors General of the several Federal banking agencies and the National Credit Union Administration Board, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412274"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412291" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2009-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29T10:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Moore (KS) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29T10:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8967-8970" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29T10:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3330.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-07-29T10:50:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8967-8968" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29T10:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2009--Passed House without amendment.
Improved Oversight by Financial Inspectors General Act of 2009 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (FDIA) to revise the meaning of material loss to repeal its definition as an amount exceeding the greater of $25 million or 2% of the institution's total assets at the time the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) initiated assistance or was appointed receiver. Counts as a material loss any estimated loss in excess of $200 million occurring after March 31, 2009. Requires the Inspector General (IG) of each federal banking agency to report semiannually to the appropriate federal agency and to Congress regarding: (1) losses estimated to be incurred by the Deposit Insurance Fund (DIF) with respect to insured depository institutions the agency supervises; (2) each loss that is not a material loss, the grounds for appointing the FDIC as receiver, and whether any unusual circumstances exist that might warrant an in-depth review of the loss; and (3) the results of the IG's determinations. (Sec. 3) Amends the Federal Credit Union Act (FCUA) to require the IG of the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA) to report to the NCUA Board about any material loss to the National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund (NCUSIF) with respect to an insured credit union regarding: (1) why the credit union's problems resulted in a material loss to the NCUSIF; and (2) how such loss may be prevented in the future. Revises the definition of material loss to the NCUSIF, currently an amount exceeding the sum of $10 million and 10% of the credit union's total assets at the time the NCUA Board initiated assistance or was appointed liquidating agent. Increases the $10 million to $25 million. Requires the IG of the NCUA Board to report semiannually to the Board and Congress regarding: (1) losses estimated to be incurred by the NCUSIF with respect to insured credit unions; (2) each loss that is not a material loss, the grounds for appointing the NCUA Board as liquidating agent for any federal or state credit union, and whether any unusual circumstances exist that might warrant an in-depth review of the loss; and (3) the results of the IG's determinations. Instructs the Comptroller General to: (1) review reports regarding material losses to the NCUSIF, and (2) make recommendations for improvements in the supervision of insured credit unions.</summary>
</bill>
