<bill session="113" type="s" number="653" updated="2013-11-07T04:46:28-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Near East and South Central Asia Religious Freedom Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the establishment of the Special Envoy to Promote Religious Freedom of Religious Minorities in the Near East and South Central Asia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2013-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2013-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2013-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2013-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2013-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2013-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="301"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2013--Introduced.
Near East and South Central Asia Religious Freedom Act of 2013 - Authorizes the President to appoint a Special Envoy to Promote Religious Freedom of Religious Minorities in the Near East and South Central Asia within the Department of State. Requires the Special Envoy to: (1) promote the right of religious freedom of religious minorities in the countries of the Near East and South Central Asia, denounce the violation of such right, and recommend appropriate U.S government responses to such violations; (2) monitor and combat acts of religious intolerance and incitement targeted against such religious minorities; (3) ensure that the needs of such religious minority communities are addressed, including economic and security needs directly tied to religious-based discrimination and persecution; (4) work with foreign governments of such countries to address inherently discriminatory laws; and (5) coordinate and assist in the preparation of specified reports required by the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 and the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998. Authorizes the Special Envoy, subject to direction by the President and the Secretary of State, to represent the United States in matters and cases relevant to religious freedom in: (1) contacts with foreign governments, intergovernmental organizations, and specialized agencies of the United Nations (U.N.), the Organization of Security and Cooperation in Europe, and other international organizations; and (2) multilateral conferences and meetings relevant to religious freedom.</summary>
</bill>
