<bill session="110" type="h" number="7321" updated="2013-07-19T22:07:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-12-10T20:50:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-12-10T20:50:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Auto Industry Financing and Restructuring Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Auto Industry Financing and Restructuring Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize financial assistance to eligible automobile manufacturers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Ways and Means, the Judiciary, Transportation and Infrastructure, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T15:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1534 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 7321 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T18:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1534 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T18:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1534.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10908-10935" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H10908-10912" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T18:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 7321 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T18:17:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 7321.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T19:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed with debate on H.R. 7321.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T19:54:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1534, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the LaTourette amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-12-10T20:50:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="690" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 237 - 170, 1 Present (Roll no. 690).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T20:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="1534"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Corporate governance"/>
    <term name="Corporate management"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Economic stabilization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Golden parachutes"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government ownership"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Light rail transit"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Private aviation"/>
    <term name="Product development"/>
    <term name="Railroad equipment"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court justices"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1194"/>
    <amendment number="s5702"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/10/2008--Passed House amended.
Auto Industry Financing and Restructuring Act - (Sec. 3) Directs the President to designate one or more executive branch officers (designee) to carry out the purposes of this Act. Requires such designee to have appropriate expertise to facilitate the restructuring necessary to achieve the long-term financial viability of domestic automobile manufacturers. (Sec. 4) Requires the designee to authorize and direct the disbursement of bridge loans or to enter into commitments for lines of credit to each automobile manufacturer that submitted to Congress a plan on December 2, 2008, and request for such loan or commitment ("automaker," for purposes of this Act). Establishes as the amount of such assistance the amount intended to facilitate continued operations of the automaker and prevent its failure.(Sec. 5) Directs the designee to: (1) determine measures to assess the progress of each automaker for transforming the plan submitted into a restructuring plan; (2) evaluate progress toward developing a restructuring plan after a 45-day period beginning when the assessment measures were established; and (3) facilitate agreement on a restructuring plan to achieve and sustain the long-term viability, international competitiveness, and energy efficiency of an automaker.(Sec. 6) Requires each automaker to submit a restructuring plan to the designee no later than March 31, 2009. Directs the designee to approve such plan if it meets specified requirements, including that it will result in: (1) the repayment of all government-provided financing, under specified terms; (2) the domestic manufacturing of advanced technology vehicles, as described under the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007; (3) efforts to rationalize costs, capitalization, and capacity; and (4) proposals to restructure existing debt.(Sec. 7) Authorizes the designee, upon plan approval, to provide financial assistance to an automaker to implement the plan. Requires a loan to be called upon restructuring plan disapproval.(Sec. 9) Directs the designee to prioritize the loan assistance to automakers, based on: (1) its necessity for continued operations; (2) potential impacts of the automaker's failure on the U.S. economy; and (3) the ability to use the assistance to satisfy operational and long-term restructuring requirements.(Sec. 10) Makes appropriations to provide loan funds under this Act in an amount up to $14 billion. Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of Energy to replenish funds made available. Provides loan terms and conditions.(Sec. 11) Requires each recipient, during the loan period, to inform the designee of: (1) any proposed automaker transaction in excess of $100 million; and (2) any other material change in financial condition. Authorizes the designee to review and approve or disapprove such a transaction. Outlines provisions concerning an automaker's failure to comply with loan requirements.(Sec. 12) Requires the designee to receive warrants for up to 20% of the common or preferred stock of each automaker as a loan condition. Subjects each automaker, during the loan period, to specified executive compensation and corporate governance standards. Limits an automaker's owning or leasing of corporate passenger aircraft, and prohibits an automaker's payment of dividends, during such period. Subordinates to the federal loan any other automaker obligations.Prohibits a title 11 bankruptcy discharge from discharging an automaker or its successor in interest from any debt for assistance received under this Act.(Sec. 13) Directs the Comptroller General (CG) to conduct ongoing oversight of the designee's activities and performance and to report at least every 60 days to Congress. Adds to duties of the Special Inspector General established by the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 the duty to coordinate audits and investigations of the designee.(Sec. 14) Requires: (1) each loan recipient to analyze potential uses of excess production capacity to make vehicles for sale to public transit agencies; and (2) the CG to review such analyses and report thereon to Congress and the designee. (Sec. 15) Requires reports from the designee to Congress on: (1) bridge loans made under this Act; (2) the restructuring progress assessment measures established under section 5; (3) actions taken against an automaker for failure to comply with this Act's requirements; (4) any additional powers and authorities necessary to facilitate completion of a negotiated restructuring plan; (5) progress of automakers to continue operations and proceed with restructuring processes that restore financial viability and promote environmental sustainability; and (6) a plan on achieving the long-term viability, international competitiveness, and energy efficiency of each automaker.(Sec. 18) Directs the designee to serve as a guarantor of leases of qualified transportation property (domestic property subject to a lease approved by the Federal Transit Administration prior to January 1, 2006). Requires designee recoupment of payments of claims in excess of collateral held with respect to such guarantees.(Sec. 19) Authorizes a salary adjustment during FY2009 for justices and judges of the United States.Sets forth guidelines for application of the antitrust laws and antitrust agency participation in proceedings of the automakers.(Sec. 20) Makes inapplicable to ownership changes resulting from this Act certain Internal Revenue Code provisions limiting the carryover of net operating losses and certain built-in losses. (Sec. 21) Designates amounts provided under this Act as an emergency requirement under the FY2008 concurrent budget resolution. (Sec. XX [sic]) Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to require each financial condition report from insured depository institutions that received an investment or other assistance under the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) established by the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 or under the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to contain information on any increase in new lending during the report period that is attributable to such investment or assistance. Allows an alternative report on the total amount of increased new lending if the institution cannot accurately quantify the effect that an investment or other assistance under TARP has had on any new lending.</summary>
</bill>
