<bill session="113" type="h" number="2882" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Opportunities for Service-Disabled Veteran-Owned Small Businesses Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act and title 38, United States Code to provide for a consolidated definition of a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2013--Introduced.
Improving Opportunities for Service-Disabled Veteran-Owned Small Businesses Act of 2013 - Amends the Small Business Act to provide that if the death of a service-disabled veteran causes a small business concern to be less than 51% owned by one or more such veterans, the surviving spouse of such veteran who acquires ownership rights in such small business concern shall be treated as if the surviving spouse were that veteran for the purpose of maintaining the business's status as a small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans until the earlier of: (1) the date on which the surviving spouse either remarries or relinquishes the ownership interest, or (2) 10 years after the veteran's death. Repeals a provision providing for such treatment of the surviving spouse of a veteran-owned and controlled small business after the death of a veteran-owner. Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) that transfers from the Secretary to the Administrator control and administration of a required database of veteran-owned businesses.</summary>
</bill>
