<bill session="109" type="s" number="1568" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Communities First Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Banks Serving Their Communities First Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance the ability of community banks to foster economic growth and serve their communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2006-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2005-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2005-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2061"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Bank employees"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Bank holding companies"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Bank management"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Executives"/>
    <term name="Farms"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Mortgage banks"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Introduced.
Community Banks Serving Their Communities First Act, or the Communities First Act - Sets forth regulatory relief measures for community banks, including amendments to: (1) the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act to increase from $10 million to $250 million the asset levels of depository institution and home mortgage lenders that are exempt from disclosure requirements; (2) the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to permit certain insured depository institutions to submit a short form report of condition; and (3) the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 to exempt certain small-sized depository institutions from management assessment of internal controls requirements. Directs the Federal Reserve Board to publish proposed revisions to the Small Bank Holding Company Policy Statement on Assessment of Financial and Managerial Factors that provide that: (1) the policy shall apply to a bank holding company with pro forma consolidated assets of less than $1 billion that meets specified criteria; and (2) the debt-to-equity ratio allowable for a small bank holding company to remain eligible to pay a corporate dividend and for expedited processing procedures would increase from 1:1 to 3:1. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to increase from $250 million to $1 billion the asset size of institutions eligible for Federal banking examinations conducted at intervals subject to discretion of the appropriate Federal banking agency. Amends the Federal Reserve Act to increase from $1 million to $1 billion of total assets the size of small banks exempt from the limitation placed on extensions of credit to executive officers, director and principal shareholders. Amends the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to increase from $250 million to $1 billion the size of financial institutions eligible for a less frequent examination schedule. Amends the Truth in Lending Act to direct the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to prescribe regulations authorizing a consumer to waive the statutory three-day right of rescission in connection with a consumer credit transaction when the creditor is an insured depository institution. Amends the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act to exempt from its recordkeeping and public disclosure requirements a depository institution that makes fewer than 100 reportable loans annually. Amends the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act to exempt specified financial institutions from the requisite annual disclosure of privacy policy. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to direct the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation to review reports of condition periodically and reduce filings of related information or schedules pursuant to specified determinations. Amends the Federal Reserve Act to prohibit the aggregate amount of credit extensions that a member bank may make to an executive officer of the bank from exceeding $250,000. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) provide reduced tax rates and deferral of income recognition on long-term certificates of deposit; (2) exclude from gross income interest received by a qualified lender on any qualified real estate loan; (3) increase from $10 million to $30 million the cap on qualified small issue bonds; (4) provide limited liability company tax treatment for FDIC-insured limited liability companies; (5) provide a tax reduction on a C corporation which is a community bank; and (6) exempt community banks from the alternative minimum tax.</summary>
</bill>
