<bill session="113" type="h" number="2631" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Visa Overstay Enforcement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to criminalize unlawful presence.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412469"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4219"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-09">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-09">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2013--Introduced.
Visa Overstay Enforcement Act of 2013 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to make it a felony for any alien to be unlawfully present in the United States for a period of 30 consecutive days, except because of illness or any other extenuating circumstance. Requires such an alien to be punished: (1) in the case of a first offense, with a fine of not more than $10,000 or by imprisonment for not more than one year, or both; and (2) in the case of a subsequent offense, with a fine of not more than $15,000 or by imprisonment for not more than five years, or both. Declares that an alien convicted: (1) of a first offense may not be admitted to the United States for 5 years, and may not be granted a visa for 10 years; and (2) of a subsequent offense may not be admitted to the United States, and may not be granted a visa. Directs the the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) submit to Congress within 90 days a plan to implement a biometric exit capability using a person's fingerprints at all land, sea, and air ports of entry under the US-VISIT program; and (2) establish the biometric entry and exit data system required by the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 within one year at each airport that is a U.S. port of entry, and within two years at all U.S. ports of entry.</summary>
</bill>
