<bill session="110" type="h" number="6659" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Equal Treatment of Covered Bonds Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to provide the same treatment for covered bonds as for other qualified financial contracts to which a depository institution is a party when such institution is in receivership or conservatorship, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2008-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2008-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="2008-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2008--Introduced.
Equal Treatment of Covered Bonds Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to include a covered bond as a qualified financial contract with an insured depository institution, if it was entered into before appointment of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) as receiver for the institution, where a person has the right to cause the contract's termination, liquidation, or acceleration upon such an appointment. Defines such a bond as a nondeposit recourse debt obligation of an insured depository institution, with a term to maturity of at least one year, which is secured by specifically identified assets which are performing in accordance with the terms of the contracts which created the assets. Declares federal banking agency regulations inapplicable to any covered bond unless they are prescribed jointly by the Secretary of the Treasury, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, and the Board of Directors of the FDIC.</summary>
</bill>
