<bill session="110" type="s" number="354" updated="2013-07-19T22:23:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Campus Fire Safety Right-to-Know Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for disclosure of fire safety standards and measures with respect to campus buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hr" number="725"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="592"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="College teachers"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Electric appliances"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Fraternal organizations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Smoke detectors"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Student housing"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/2007--Introduced.
Campus Fire Safety Right-to-Know Act of 2007 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require each institution participating in any program under the Act to provide to all current students and employees, and to any applicant for enrollment or employment upon request, an annual fire safety report containing specified information about the campus fire safety practices and standards of that institution. Requires such institutions to: (1) record all on-campus fires, including the nature, date, time, and general location of each fire and all unwanted and false fire alarms; and (2) open such information to public inspection. Requires the institutions to report on such information annually to the campus community in a manner that will aid the prevention of similar occurrences. Directs each institution to require the national organizing bodies of the fraternities, sororities, and other student groups they recognize to collect specified fire safety information for each student housing facility they own, control, or occupy and report such information to the Secretary of Education, all current members, and to any interested party upon request. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on fire safety systems and standards in institution and student housing facilities, and on exemplary fire safety education and training programs at such institutions.</summary>
</bill>
