<bill session="112" type="s" number="1979" updated="2013-07-20T02:33:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Conrad State 30 Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide incentives to physicians to practice in rural and medically underserved communities and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2012-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2011-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2012-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2012-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2011--Introduced.
Conrad State 30 Improvement Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Technical Corrections Act of 1994 to make the J-1 visa waiver (Conrad state 30/medical services in underserved areas) program permanent. Includes in the priority worker preference allocation for employment-based immigrants alien physicians who have completed service requirements of a state waiver or exemption, plus an additional two years at the waiver-identified location or in a health care shortage area (including alien physicians who completed such service prior to enactment of this Act). Exempts H-1B nonimmigrant aliens seeking to enter the United States to pursue graduate medical education or training from specified entry limitations (including permitting extension of the six-year authorized period of admission under specified circumstances). Increases the number of alien physicians that a state may be allocated from 30 to 35 per fiscal year under specified circumstances. Permits an alien physician, after fulfilling a three-year service period with a health care employer, to apply for employment with a new health care employer in a health care shortage area.</summary>
</bill>
