<bill session="111" type="s" number="3975" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tax Relief Certainty Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to permanently extend the 2001 and 2003 tax relief provisions, and to permanently repeal the estate tax, and to provide permanent alternative minimum tax relief, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-11-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="651">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 651.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="6415"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2010--Introduced.
Tax Relief Certainty Act - Eliminates the terminating date of the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001, thus making the provisions of such Act permanent. Terminates after December 31, 2011, provisions of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act increasing tax benefits for adoption. Eliminates the terminating date of the Jobs and Growth Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2003 applicable to provisions reducing tax rates on dividends and capital gains. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) phase-in between 2010 through 2020 increases in the exemption amount for the alternative minimum tax (AMT); and (2) make permanent offsets against the AMT for certain nonrefundable tax credits.</summary>
</bill>
