<bill session="113" type="h" number="1108" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cross-Border Trade Enhancement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for alternative financing arrangements for the provision of certain services and the construction and maintenance of infrastructure at land border ports of entry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400657"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412482" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412577" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="408211" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412575" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412580" joined="2013-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration And Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="178"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2013--Introduced.
Cross-Border Trade Enhancement Act of 2013 - Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to enter into agreements with persons for the U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to provide customs and immigration services at a land border port of entry, subject to payment of a fee to reimburse the CBP for providing such services. Declares that nothing in this grant of authority shall be construed to reduce the responsibilities or duties of the CBP to provide services at land border ports of entry that have been authorized by law and federally-funded. Directs the Administrator of General Services to establish procedures for evaluating proposals submitted by persons to: (1) enter into cost-sharing or reimbursement agreements with the General Services Administration (GSA) for the construction or maintenance of infrastructure at a land border port of entry, and (2) provide GSA an unconditional gift of property for use in the construction or maintenance of such infrastructure. Prescribes minimum requirements for such procedures.</summary>
</bill>
