<bill session="110" type="h" number="6565" updated="2013-07-19T22:01:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FDIC Flexibility Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide additional authority to the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation in resolving problem financial institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1525"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2008--Introduced.
FDIC Flexibility Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to repeal: (1) requirements for least-cost resolution of troubled insured depository institutions; (2) requirements for consideration of direct financial assistance to a depository institution before appointment of a conservator or receiver; (3) certain Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) procedures for extension of time and mailed notification regarding determination of claims; and (4) specified FDIC authority relating to determination of claims. Amends the Federal Reserve Act to repeal limitations on advances to member banks by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act of 1991 to repeal provisions regarding early resolution of troubled insured depository institutions by federal banking agencies.</summary>
</bill>
