<bill session="111" type="h" number="2420" updated="2013-07-19T23:33:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Environmental Design of Electrical Equipment Act (EDEE) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act of 1976 to ensure a uniform Federal scheme of regulation of restrictions in the use of certain substances in electrical products and equipment in interstate and foreign commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2009-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2009--Introduced.
Environmental Design of Electrical Equipment Act (EDEE) Act - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act of 1976 to establish uniform national standards for the use of lead, mercury, hexavalent chromium, cadmium, polybrominated biphenyls, and polybrominated diphenyl ethers in electroindustry products manufactured after July 1, 2010. Defines "electroindustry product" as any product or equipment that is used to facilitate the transmission, distribution, or control of electricity, or that uses electricity for arc welding, lighting, signaling protection and communication, medical imaging, or electrical motors and generators.</summary>
</bill>
