<bill session="109" type="s" number="3884" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Darfur Peace and Accountability Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to impose sanctions against individuals responsible for genocide, war crimes, and crimes against humanity, to support measures for the protection of civilians and humanitarian operations, and to support peace efforts in the Darfur region of Sudan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2006-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2006-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2006-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9309-9310"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-09-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="604">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 604.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3127"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1462"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Air warfare"/>
    <term name="Alien property"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Arabs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armistices"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Bombardment"/>
    <term name="Chad"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Cults"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International courts"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Logistics"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Military communications"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="Military intelligence"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Military transportation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Tankers"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Uganda"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations membership"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2006--Introduced.
Darfur Peace and Accountability Act of 2006 - Sets forth the sense of Congress with respect to the situation in Darfur, Sudan, including the sense of Congress that the atrocities unfolding in Darfur are genocide, and the need for U.S. and international involvement in Darfur. Amends the Comprehensive Peace in Sudan Act of 2004 to direct the President, with waiver authority upon congressional notification, to block the assets and deny visas and entry to any individual complicit in or responsible for acts of genocide, war crimes, or crimes against humanity in Darfur, including certain family members or associates of such individual. Authorizes the President to provide assistance to reinforce an expanded African Union Mission in Sudan (AMIS). States that the President should take steps to deny the government of Sudan access to oil revenues, including prohibiting U.S. port entry to cargo ships or oil tankers engaged in trade activities in Sudan's oil sector or involved in the shipment of goods for the Armed Forces of Sudan until the government of Sudan has honored its commitments to cease attacks on civilians, demobilize and demilitarize the Janjaweed and associated militias, grant access for humanitarian assistance, and allow for the safe and voluntary return of refugees and internally displaced persons. Exempts from such prohibition cargo ships or oil tankers involved in: (1) an internationally recognized demobilization program or the shipment of economic assistance; or (2) the shipment of certain military assistance. Prohibits, with national interest waiver authority, U.S. assistance to a country in violation of U.N. Security Council Resolutions 1556 and 1591 (embargo on military assistance to Sudan). States that certain restrictions against the government of Sudan shall remain in place until the President makes specified certifications to the appropriate congressional committees regarding the government of Sudan. Amends the Assistance for International Malaria Control Act to repeal provisions authorizing the President to provide additional assistance to, and exempting prohibitions on exports from, areas outside the control of the government of Sudan. Amends the Comprehensive Peace in Sudan Act of 2004 to repeal the provision authorizing the President to provide additional nonmilitary assistance to areas outside the control of the government of Sudan. Authorizes the President, subject to congressional notification by the Secretary of State, to provide economic assistance for Southern Sudan, Southern Kordofan/Nuba Mountains State, Blue Nile State, and Abyei. Authorizes the President to provide specified military assistance to the government of Sudan. Waives prohibitions concerning Sudan in Executive Order No. 13067 regarding activities with respect to Southern Sudan, Southern Kordofan/Nuba Mountains State, Blue Nile State, and Abyei.</summary>
</bill>
