<bill session="111" type="s" number="507" updated="2013-07-20T00:27:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Non-Foreign AREA Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Non-Foreign Area Retirement Equity Assurance Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Non-Foreign AREA Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Non-Foreign Area Retirement Equity Assurance Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for retirement equity for Federal employees in nonforeign areas outside the 48 contiguous States and the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2009-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2638"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2638-2641" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-20">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-10-14">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with amendments. With written report No. 111-88.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-10-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="179">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 179.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1266"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/14/2009--Reported to Senate amended.
Non-Foreign Area Retirement Equity Assurance Act of 2009 or the Non-Foreign AREA Act of 2009 - Revises federal employee locality-based comparability payments provisions to include U.S. territories and possessions, including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, within a pay locality. Sets forth maximum rates of pay for Senior Executive Service (SES) and other senior level personnel in such areas. Revises the calculation of allowances based on living costs and conditions of environment for pay of employees stationed outside the continental United States or in Alaska to apply it only to areas designated as of December 31, 2009. Provides a formula for adjustment of such rate using a transition schedule for calendar years 2010-2012. Requires adjustment of special rates of pay determined to be necessary to obtain or retain the services of persons specified by statute in such a cost-of-living area in accordance with regulations to be prescribed by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) under this Act. Allows a temporarily raised limitation on the amount of special rates during the transition period of January 1, 2010, to January 1, 2012. Expresses the sense of the Congress with respect to pay disparities and locality areas for federal positions located in Alaska, Hawaii, or a U.S. territory. Defines "covered employees" for purposes of this Act, including employees who were eligible, before enactment, to be paid a cost-of-living allowance (COLA) but not a locality-based comparability payment. Describes application of this Act to postal employees. Allows an employee subject to this Act's transition schedule who retires from service during the period from January 1, 2010, through December 31, 2012, to elect to have any COLA paid during that period considered as basic pay for purposes of annuity computation. Directs the administrator of a pay system not administered by OPM, with the concurrence of the Director of OPM, to prescribe regulations to carry out this Act with respect to employees in such pay system. Requires such regulations to be consistent with the regulations prescribed by OPM to carry out this Act and to provide, with respect to employees not entitled to locality-based comparability payments, for special payments or adjustments for employees who were eligible to receive a COLA under other pay systems prior to this Act's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
