<bill session="112" type="h" number="63" updated="2013-07-20T01:10:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Long-Term Care Insurance Reform Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and title XIX of the Social Security Act to reform the provision of long-term care insurance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2011-01-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="159"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
Long-Term Care Insurance Reform Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to request the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC) to: (1) conduct reviews every five years of the national and state-specific markets for long-term care (LTC) insurance policies; (2) issue a white paper on disclosure requirements for LTC insurance policies, standardized definitions for LTC services, and issues related to the development of a proposed form for marketing LTC insurance policies; (3) establish a Working Group to develop a model disclosure form for marketing LTC insurance policies; and (4) incorporate such form into the Model Act and regulation. Sets forth requirements related to the use of the proposed model disclosure form for marketing LTC insurance policies, including requiring states to require issuers to use such forms. Amends the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 to require the National Clearinghouse for Long-Term Care Information to establish an Internet directory of information regarding LTC insurance ("to be known as LTC Insurance Compare). Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require a state Medicaid plan to provide for the annual submission of data relating to functional criteria for the receipt of nursing facility services under the plan. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to apply Medicaid partnership required model provisions to all tax-qualified LTC insurance contracts. Outlines a process for secretarial review of model provisions adopted by NAIC with respect to their application to tax-qualified LTC policies and Medicaid partnership policies to determine if updating such provisions would improve consumer protections for insured individuals. Applies 2006 NAIC model regulations to Medicaid partnerships. (Currently, 2000 NAIC model regulations apply). Sets forth additional requirements applicable to such policies.</summary>
</bill>
