<bill session="111" type="h" number="1353" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac Full Disclosure Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend the registration and reporting requirements of the Federal securities laws to certain housing-related Government-sponsored enterprises, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400328"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2009-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2009--Introduced.
Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac Full Disclosure Act - Amends the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act to declare that stock, obligations, securities, participations, or other instruments issued by the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) shall not be exempt securities within the meaning of the laws administered by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) (thus subjecting such securities to SEC regulation). Amends the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act to declare that any securities issued or guaranteed by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) shall not be exempt securities within the meaning of SEC-administered laws (thus subjecting such securities also to SEC regulation). States that transactions involving the initial disposition by an approved seller of pooled certificates acquired by the seller from Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac upon the initial issuance of the pooled certificates shall be deemed to be transactions by a person other than as an issuer, underwriter, or dealer within the meaning of the laws administered by the SEC. Defines pooled certificates as single class mortgage-backed securities guaranteed by Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac that have been issued by Fannie or Freddie directly to the approved seller in exchange for the mortgage loans underlying such mortgage-backed securities. Amends the Securities Act of 1933 to exempt specified applicants filing a securities registration statement subject to a fee from being required to pay aggregate fees in excess of 5% of the target offsetting collection amount for the fiscal year. States that fees paid in connection with registration statements relating to business combinations shall not be included in calculating the total fees paid by any applicant.</summary>
</bill>
