<bill session="111" type="s" number="672" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Natural Gas and Electricity Review and Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Natural Gas Act, the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978, and the Federal Power Act to modify provisions relating to enforcement and judicial review and to modify the procedures for proposing changes in natural gas rates.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/2009--Introduced.
Natural Gas and Electricity Review and Enforcement Act - Amends the Natural Gas Act, the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978, and the Federal Power Act to authorize the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to issue a temporary cease and desist order if it: (1) determines that any entity may be violating, may have violated, or may be about to violate any provision of such Acts or a FERC directive; and (2) finds that an alleged, threatened, or continued violation is likely to result in significant harm to either natural gas consumers or to the public interest. Amends the Federal Power Act to grant FERC emergency authority to change or suspend temporarily the rates, terms, or conditions of service on file with it before providing public notice and an opportunity for comment. Limits such temporary change or suspension to a period of not more than 30 days unless certain conditions are met.</summary>
</bill>
