<bill session="111" type="s" number="1354" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improved Financial and Commodity Markets Oversight and Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to elevate the Inspector General of certain Federal entities to an Inspector General appointed pursuant to section 3 of the Inspector General Act of 1978.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="885"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2009--Introduced.
Improved Financial and Commodity Markets Oversight and Accountability Act - Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to include the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA), the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC), and the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) as establishments the Inspector Generals of which shall be appointed by the President. Applies existing pay requirements under the Inspector General Reform Act of 2008 to the Inspectors General of such entities. Permits such Inspectors General to select, appoint, and employ such officers and employees as necessary and to obtain services of experts or consultants. Authorizes such Inspectors General to subpoena records and testimony necessary in the performance of their assigned functions. Requires the heads of those entities to: (1) take action to address deficiencies identified by their Inspector General; or (2) certify to both houses of Congress that no action is necessary or appropriate.</summary>
</bill>
