<bill session="113" type="s" number="290" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Title X Amendments Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce housing-related health hazards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S709"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1282"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2013--Introduced.
Title X Amendments Act of 2013 - Amends the Residential Lead-Based Paint Hazard Reduction Act of 1992 to revise the purpose for grants for lead-based paint hazard reduction in target housing. Requires such grants to be made instead for reduction of lead-based paint hazards and correction of other housing-related hazards. Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish a process by which, in order to verify a family's income level, a grantee may first obtain and use income and program participation information from an entity administering: (1) the HOME Investment Partnerships program under the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act; (2) the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC) established under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966; (3) reduced price or free lunches under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act; (4) the weatherization assistance program for low-income persons established under the Energy Conservation and Production Act; (5) the temporary assistance for needy families (TANF) program under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA); (6) the supplemental security income (SSI) program under SSA title XVI; or (7) any other program consistent with the family income requirements of the Residential Lead-Based Paint Hazard Reduction Act of 1992. Makes eligible to apply for such a grant, in addition to certain state or local governments, for specified activities relating to lead-based paint hazards: (1) an Indian tribe, and (2) private nonprofit organization partnering with the state or unit of general local government in which the activities will be carried out. Makes a private nonprofit organization not partnering with a state or local government eligible all the same to apply for a grant to reduce housing-related health hazards, including any condition of residential real property that poses a risk of biological, physical, radiological, or chemical exposure that can adversely affect human health. Revises grantee selection criteria for a grant to carry out activities relating to lead-based paint hazards, and prescribes criteria for activities relating to housing-related hazards. Prescribes an allocation of funds for grants to assess and correct housing-related health hazards and evaluate the effectiveness of such assessments and corrections. Reauthorizes the Act for FY2014-FY2018.</summary>
</bill>
