<bill session="109" type="sr" number="575" updated="2013-07-19T20:11:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution supporting the efforts of the Independent National Electoral Commission of the Government of Nigeria, political parties, civil society, and religious organizations to facilitate the first democratic transition of Nigeria from 1 civilian government to another in the general elections to be held in April 2007.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2006-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9791" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="sr" number="611"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Bush (George W.) Administration"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nigeria"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Presidential term of office"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Right of assembly"/>
    <term name="Term limits"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2006--Introduced.
Recognizes Nigeria's importance as a strategic partner and long-time friend of the United States. Acknowledges Nigeria's rising prominence as a regional leader and role model. Commends the National Assembly of Nigeria's decision to reject a constitutional amendment that would have allowed for a third presidential term. Encourages the government of Nigeria and the Independent National Electoral Commission to demonstrate a commitment to democratic elections by: (1) developing a voter registration and education plan; (2) addressing corruption charges; and (3) conducting unbiased recruitment and training of election officials. Urges the government of Nigeria to respect the freedoms of association and assembly, including the right of candidates, members of political parties, and others to assemble and conduct public events free from intimidation. Urges a robust effort by Nigeria's law enforcement and judicial officials to enforce the rule of law, particularly by preventing and investigating politically-motivated violence and prosecuting those suspected of such acts. Expresses U.S. support for coordinated efforts by the government of Nigeria and the Independent National Electoral Commission to work with political parties, civil society, religious organizations, and other entities to organize a peaceful democratic transition based on free elections in April 2007.</summary>
</bill>
