<bill session="109" type="hr" number="612" updated="2013-07-19T18:59:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-16T14:40:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-16T14:40:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the commitment of the House of Representatives to achieving victory in Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400658" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2005-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T07:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 619 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 612 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. Sec. 2. On the first legislative day of the second session of the One Hundred Ninth Congress, the House shall not conduct organizational or legislative business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T12:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 619 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T12:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 619.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11905-11920" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T12:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 612 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. Sec. 2. On the first legislative day of the second session of the One Hundred Ninth Congress, the House shall not conduct organizational or legislative business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T12:52:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 612.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T13:13:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H. Res. 612.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T14:14:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11920" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-12-16T14:40:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="648" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 279 - 109, 34 Present (Roll no. 648).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11905" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T14:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="619"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military withdrawal"/>
    <term name="Parliamentary government"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2005--Passed House without amendment.
Declares that: (1) the House of Representatives is committed to achieving victory in Iraq; (2) the presence of the U.S. Armed Forces in Iraq will only be required until Iraqi forces can stand up on their own; and (3) an artificial timetable for terminating the deployment of U.S. Armed Forces in Iraq is inconsistent with achieving victory. Acknowledges the Iraqi December 15, 2005, election as a crucial victory for its new democracy. Encourages Americans to express solidarity with the Iraq people and their goal of a democratic society. Honors the sacrifices made by the U.S. Armed Forces, their families, and members of the Iraq and Coalition forces. Expresses confidence that the U.S. Armed Forces, along with Iraqi and Coalition forces, will achieve victory in Iraq.</summary>
</bill>
