<bill session="111" type="s" number="637" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the construction of the Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System in the State of Montana and a portion of McKenzie County, North Dakota, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-91.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4119"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Missouri River"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2009--Introduced.
Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a cooperative agreement to provide federal assistance for the planning, design, and construction of the Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System for specified counties in Montana and North Dakota. Lists agreement requirements. Limits the federal share of planning, design, and construction of the System to 75% of the total cost. Delineates the components of System facilities for which federal funds may be expended and the System's service area. Limits the obligation of funds for construction. Provides that any cost relating to the System's operation, maintenance, or replacement shall not be a federal responsibility and shall be paid by the System.Directs the Administrator of the Western Area Power Administration to make available to the System a quantity of power required to meet the System's pumping and incidental operation requirements from the water intake facilities and through the water treatment facilities and all first water distribution pumping facilities. Makes the System eligible to receive power only if it operates on a nonprofit basis and is constructed pursuant to the agreement. Directs the Authority to develop a water conservation plan containing a description of water conservation objectives and measures and a schedule for carrying out such measures. Requires the plan to be designed to ensure that users of water provided by the System will use the best practical technology and management techniques to conserve water.</summary>
</bill>
