<bill session="109" type="h" number="250" updated="2013-07-19T19:06:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-21T16:57:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-21T16:57:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Manufacturing Technology Competitiveness Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Manufacturing Technology Competitiveness Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Manufacturing Technology Competitiveness Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish an interagency committee to coordinate Federal manufacturing research and development efforts in manufacturing, strengthen existing programs to assist manufacturing innovation and education, and expand outreach programs for small and medium-sized manufacturers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400119"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="2005-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2005-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E32"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Technology, and Standards.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-05-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-05-23T14:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 109-92.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-05-23T14:15:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="49">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 49.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-09-20T19:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 451 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 250 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Science now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T13:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 451 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 451.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8182-8189, H8198-8216" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8204-8206" label="text of measure as report in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 250 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Science now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 451 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Shelley Moore Capito to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T14:13:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 250.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 451, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boehlert amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 451, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gordon amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 451, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T15:02:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson-Lee (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T15:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 451, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Larson (CT) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Larson (CT) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Boehlert demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T15:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 451, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Udall (CO) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T15:29:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Udall (CO) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Udall (CO) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 250.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8214" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Honda moved to recommit with instructions to Science, Space and Technology.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8214" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8214" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Honda motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment which authorizes $140 million for fiscal year 2006 for the Advanced Technology Program. Of that amount, $40 million shall be for new awards.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T16:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8215" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T16:44:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 196 - 226 (Roll no. 484).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-09-21T16:57:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="485" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 394 - 24 (Roll no. 485).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-21T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Environment, Technology, and Standards" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="451"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2134"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building materials"/>
    <term name="Chemical engineering"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economic research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electrical engineering"/>
    <term name="Electronics"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Industrial engineering"/>
    <term name="Industrial production"/>
    <term name="Industrial research"/>
    <term name="Industrial standards"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Nanotechnology"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Physics"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Quality control"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h558"/>
    <amendment number="h559"/>
    <amendment number="h560"/>
    <amendment number="h561"/>
    <amendment number="h562"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/21/2005--Passed House amended.
Manufacturing Technology Competitiveness Act of 2005 - (Sec. 2) Directs the President to establish or designate an Interagency Committee (IC) to plan and coordinate federal efforts in manufacturing research and development, with an Advisory Committee from the non-federal sector. Requires the IC to: (1) include representatives from the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), the Science and Technology Directorate of the Department of Homeland Security, the National Science Foundation, the Department of Energy, and any other agency that the President may designate; and (2) have its Chair designated by the Director of OSTP. (Sec. 3) Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to establish a pilot program of collaborative manufacturing research grants. (Sec. 4) Requires the NIST Director to establish a program of manufacturing sciences research fellowships at the postdoctoral and the senior, established researcher levels.(Sec. 5) Revises requirements for evaluation of Centers under the NIST Manufacturing Extension Partnership program. Allows acceptance of funds for such Centers from other federal agencies and the private sector, without such funds being considered part of the federal share. Requires the NIST Director to establish, within the Manufacturing Extension Partnership (MEP) program, a program of competitive grants to Centers, or consortia of Centers, to develop projects to solve new or emerging manufacturing problems. Requires a three-year programmatic and operational plan for the MEP program to be transmitted to specified congressional committees. (Sec. 6) Authorizes appropriations for FY2006-2008 to the Secretary of Commerce for the following NIST programs: (1) scientific and technical research and services laboratory activities; (2) the Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award (under the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980); and (3) construction and maintenance of facilities. Reserves specified amounts of such FY2006 funding for NIST laboratory activities for: (1) electronics and electrical engineering; (2) manufacturing engineering; (3) chemical science and technology; (4) physics; (5) material science and engineering; (6) building and fire research; (7) computer science and applied mathematics; (8) technical assistance; (9) research support activities; (10) the Center for Neutron Research; and (11) the National Nanomanufacturing and Nanometrology Facility. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on: (1) impacts of the possible elimination of the Advanced Technology Program on NIST laboratory programs; and (2) how the Department of Commerce plans to absorb the loss of Advanced Technology Program funds to NIST laboratory programs, or otherwise mitigate the effects of this loss on its programs and personnel. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary, as part of Teacher Science and Technology Enhancement Institute program, to carry out a program of standards education grants to develop higher education curricula on the role of standards in engineering, business, science, and economics. Authorizes appropriations for FY2006-2008 to the Secretary for the Teacher Science and Technology Enhancement Institute program of NIST. (Sec. 8) Authorizes appropriations for FY2006-2008 to the Secretary for the following NIST programs: (1) Manufacturing Extension Partnership (MEP, with specified maximum portions for the competitive grant program established under this Act, through the Secretary or other appropriate federal agencies); (2) Collaborative Manufacturing Research Pilot Grants; and (3) Manufacturing Fellowships.(Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations for FY2006-2008 to the Director of the National Science Foundation for the Advanced Technological Education program under the Scientific and Advanced Technology Act of 1992. (Sec. 10) Requires the NIST Director to establish, within the MEP program, a Katrina Assistance Program (KAP) to provide assistance to impacted small and medium-sized manufacturers in areas impacted by Hurricane Katrina. Requires KAP to provide such assistance, establish triage teams and virtual assistance data centers, and assess and make recommendations to minimize potential disruption on national manufacturing supply chains. Exempts KAP from matching fund requirements. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 11) Requires the NIST Director to carry out an engineering performance study of the effects of Hurricane Katrina in the major disaster areas of Louisiana, Alabama, and Mississippi. Requires the study to: (1) examine physical structures damaged due to excessive wind, storm surge, and flooding, including engineered and nonengineered buildings and key physical infrastructures; and (2) develop new knowledge concerning practices related to building standards and codes, and review the adequacy of current building codes and standards. Authorizes the NIST Director to convene public meetings and conferences to inform the public, government authorities, and relevant professional associations regarding the study's findings and recommendations. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
