<bill session="112" type="s" number="1613" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pediatric, Adolescent, and Young Adult Cancer Survivorship Research and Quality of Life Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve and enhance research and programs on childhood cancer survivorship, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2012-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2012-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2012-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-09-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5909"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5909-5910" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3015"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2011--Introduced.
Pediatric, Adolescent, and Young Adult Cancer Survivorship Research and Quality of Life Act of 2011 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to allow the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to eligible entities to establish pilot programs to develop, study, or evaluate model systems for monitoring and caring for childhood cancer survivors. Authorizes the Secretary to convene a Workforce Development Collaborative on Medical and Psychosocial Care for Pediatric Cancer to establish a plan to meet specified objectives relating to medical and psychosocial care workforce development, including: (1) disseminating to health care educators information relevant to providing medical and psychosocial services to individuals with pediatric cancers; (2) adapting curricula for continuing education of the existing workforce; and (3) strengthening the emphasis on psychosocial health care in educational accreditation standards and professional licensing and certification. Reauthorizes and expands the National Cancer Institute's pediatric cancer research and awareness program to include research onfollow-up care for pediatric cancer survivors. Authorizes the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to make grants for pediatric cancer research, including research related to: (1) pediatric cancer survivors within minority or other medically underserved populations, and (2) health disparities in pediatric cancer survivorship outcomes.</summary>
</bill>
