<bill session="111" type="h" number="5394" updated="2013-07-20T00:01:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Haiti Private Sector Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of an American Enterprise Fund for Haiti and to ensure effective oversight of United States Government earthquake recovery and redevelopment activities in Haiti.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2010-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2010--Introduced.
Haiti Private Sector Development Act - Authorizes the President, after congressional consultation, to designate one private, nonprofit organization as the American Enterprise Fund for Haiti to receive funds and support under this Act to promote: (1) Haitian private sector development, including microbusinesses and small businesses, the agriculture, finance, energy, construction, garment, and tourism industries, and U.S.-Haitian joint ventures; and (2) policies and practices conducive to Haitian private sector development through loans, equity investments, feasibility studies, grants, technical assistance, training, insurance, and guarantees. Authorizes the Fund to establish the America for Haitian Private Sector Development Foundation which shall develop programs to recruit qualified individuals from the United States, including the Haitian diaspora in the United States, to provide technical expertise to the Haitian government to support public functions and to fill capacity gaps in the Haitian government, especially at ministries that oversee the private sector and were disrupted by the January 12, 2010, earthquake. Requires the President to submit an annual report to Congress, through 2016, summarizing all reports available to the President that were prepared for the purpose of providing oversight and evaluation of earthquake recovery and redevelopment activities conducted by U.S. government agencies during the preceding year.</summary>
</bill>
