<bill session="109" type="s" number="3740" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Presidential Funding Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reform the system of public financing for Presidential elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8274-8275, S8278-8279"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S8275-8278" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5905"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Checkoff"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Political conventions"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Primaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2006--Introduced.
Presidential Funding Act of 2006 - Amends Internal Revenue Code provisions relating to public financing of presidential election campaigns to: (1) quadruple (1:1 to 4:1) the matching rate for contributions to primary election candidates; (2) lower from $250 to $200 the limit on individual campaign contributions; (3) increase the presidential primary qualifying threshold from $5,000 to $25,000 in 20 states; (4) require presidential candidates to participate in the primary payment system to be eligible for general election payments; (5) move the starting date for payments to primary candidates from January 1 to July 1 of the year immediately preceding the presidential election year; (6) allow additional payments and increased expenditure limits for candidates who face opponents who do not participate in public financing and who raise more than 20% of applicable spending limits; (7) designate the last Friday before the first Monday in September as the date for payments to eligible presidential candidates; and (8) increase from $3 to $10 the presidential campaign tax return check-off amount.Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to: (1) increase expenditure limits for presidential primary campaigns and eliminate state primary spending limits; (2) limit political party general election campaign expenditures to $25 million, with an additional $25 million allowance after the party's candidate is nominated; (3) prohibit political parties from spending unregulated funds (soft money) on their national conventions; and (4) require presidential campaign committees to disclose information about bundled contributions (series of contributions aggregating more than $10,000).Amends the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 to reduce funding for the market access program by $100 million in FY2007.</summary>
</bill>
