<bill session="111" type="h" number="6107" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Taxpayer and Western Area Power Administration Firm Power Customer Protection and Government Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 301(d) of the Hoover Power Plant Act of 1984 to provide for notice regarding certification of certain projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2010--Introduced.
American Taxpayer and Western Area Power Administration Firm Power Customer Protection and Government Accountability Act - Amends the Hoover Power Plant Act of 1984 regarding the borrowing authority of the Western Area Power Administration (WAPA). Revises requirements for the mandatory certification by the WAPA Administrator before committing funds for any project in which the WAPA participates. Requires the Administrator, in addition to other things, to certify that: (1) appropriate agreements have been executed to ensure that project beneficiaries shall be solely responsible for repaying all capital and operation, maintenance, and replacement costs of the project; and (2) no federal costs associated with construction, financing, facilitating, planning, operating, maintaining, or studying any project shall be allocated, assigned, or recovered from customers or rates of any other WAPA power and transmission facility.</summary>
</bill>
