<bill session="111" type="s" number="3186" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-26">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Satellite Television Extension Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Satellite Television Extension Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Satellite Television Extension Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the Satellite Home Viewer Extension and Reauthorization Act of 2004 through April 30, 2010, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2010-03-25" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2104" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2104" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25T21:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25T22:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Maffei asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25T22:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2449" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-03-25T22:22:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2449" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25T22:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-03-26">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-03-26">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-03-26" type="public" number="111-151">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-151.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2010--Public Law.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Extends through April 30, 2010, the adjustment of royalty fees for the secondary transmission of the primary analog transmissions of network stations and superstations. Extends through such date the moratorium on copyright liability for subscribers not receiving a signal of Grade A intensity of a local network television broadcast station and receiving signals of network stations affiliated with the same network, if such subscribers had satellite service of such network signal terminated between July 11, 1998, and October 31, 1999. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to extend through April 30, 2010, the exemption of a subscriber from the originating station consent requirement for retransmission of broadcasting station signals if the subscriber receives the retransmitted signals directly to a home satellite antenna, is located outside the station's local market, and resides in an unserved household. Extends through May 1, 2010, the requirement that certain Federal Communications Commission (FCC) regulations prohibit: (1) a television broadcast station that provides retransmission consent from engaging in exclusive contracts for carriage or failing to negotiate in good faith; and (2) a multichannel video programming distributor from failing to negotiate in good faith for retransmission consent.</summary>
</bill>
