<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1516" updated="2013-07-19T21:03:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-28T21:01:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-28T21:01:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7201) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for energy production and conservation, and for other purposes and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7202) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend certain expiring provisions, to provide individual income tax relief, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412224"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28T21:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-902, by Mr. Arcuri.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28T21:00:00-04:00">
      <text>It shall be in order to consider in the House the bills H.R. 7201 and H.R. 7202. All points of order against consideration of the bills are waived except those arising under clause 10 of rule XXI. The bills shall be considered as read. All points of order against the bills are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bills to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Ways and Means; and (2) one motion to recommit, on</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-09-28T21:01:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="285">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 285.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28T21:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10309-10316" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H10310" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28T21:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1516.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-28T22:07:00-04:00">
      <text>WITHDRAWAL OF RESOLUTION - Pursuant to the rule, Mr. Arcuri withdrew the resolution from consideration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10316" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-12-10T16:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1533, H. Res. 1516 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hr" number="1533"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="7201"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="110" type="h" number="7201"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="7202"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="110" type="h" number="7202"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2008--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7201) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for energy production and conservation, and for other purposes and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7202) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend certain expiring provisions, to provide individual income tax relief.</summary>
</bill>
