<bill session="113" type="h" number="2266" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Subsidy Reserve Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to require certain systemically important entities to account for the financial benefit they receive as a result of the expectations on the part of shareholders, creditors, and counterparties of such entities that the Government will shield them from losses in the event of failure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2013--Introduced.
Subsidy Reserve Act of 2013 - Amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (Dodd-Frank) to require a nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve (Board) and each bank holding company with total consolidated assets of $500 billion or more (companies) to establish and maintain a Subsidy Reserve. Instructs the Board to: establish a formula for determining the financial benefit received by such companies as a result of the expectations on the part of their shareholders, creditors, and counterparties that the government will shield them from losses in the event of their failure; require them to apply the formula annually to their annual financial statement; and maintain the resulting amount in their Subsidy Reserve, in addition to any such previous amounts. Prohibits a decrease in the amount of funds in the Subsidy Reserve unless a company makes a sale of assets, spins off a subsidiary, or makes a similar divestiture. Permits the decrease only in an amount that reflects the amount of such sale, spin off, or similar divestiture, either on a pro rata basis or according to the risk weighting of the property sold, spun off, or divested. Prohibits amounts in the Subsidy Reserve from being taken into account when determining the companies' capital for purposes of meeting any capital requirement.</summary>
</bill>
