<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1105" updated="2013-07-19T23:05:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-25T13:17:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-02-25T13:17:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2701) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2010 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes, waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules, and providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-02-24T20:07:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-419, by Mr. Hastings (FL).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-24T20:07:00-05:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence now printed in the bill. The Chair may entertain a motion tha the Committee rise only if offered by the chair of the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence or his designee. The Chair may not entertain a motion to strike out the enacting words of the bill. After passage of H.R. 2701, it shall be in order to consider in the House S. 1494. All points of order against the Senate bill and against its consideration are waived. If the motion is adopted and the Senate bill, as amended, is passed, then it shall be in order to move that the House insist on its amendment to S. 1494 and request a</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-02-24T20:07:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="163">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 163.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T10:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H838-845, H848-849" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T10:24:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1105.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T11:35:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H845" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T11:35:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1109, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Dreier demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-02-25T13:17:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="66" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 237 - 176 (Roll no. 66).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H838" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25T13:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2701"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="2701"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="s" number="1494"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/24/2010--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2701) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2010 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes, waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules, and providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules.</summary>
</bill>
