<bill session="111" type="h" number="4941" updated="2013-07-19T23:57:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Anti-Cash Smuggling Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 31, United States Code, to include means of access to funds or the value of funds in certain records and reports on monetary instrument transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412286"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2010-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2010-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412316" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2010-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2010--Introduced.
Anti-Cash Smuggling Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to require reports concerning means of access to funds or the value of funds belonging or credited to a person, including electronic means and prepaid or stored cards (but not debit or credit cards). Requires such reports to be filed when a person: (1) transports, is about to transport, or has transported a means of access to funds or the value of funds from a place in the United States to or through a place outside the United States, or to a place in the United States from or through a place outside the United States; or (2) receives a means of access to funds or the value of funds transported into the United States from or through a place outside the United States. Authorizes either the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to apply to a court for a search warrant upon a reasonable belief that: (1) a monetary instrument or a tangible mechanism that constitutes a means of access to funds or the value of funds is being transported; and (2) a required report has not been filed or contains a material omission or misstatement. Authorizes a customs officer to stop and search, at the border and without a search warrant, any vehicle, vessel, aircraft, or other conveyance, any envelope or other container, and any person entering or departing from the United States. Subjects violations of this Act to criminal and civil forfeiture. Revises penalties and procedures regarding smuggling of cash, monetary instruments, and means of access to funds or the value of funds into or out of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
