<bill session="110" type="s" number="2409" updated="2013-07-19T22:41:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Loyalty to Our Legacy Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Architect of the Capitol to ensure that the Pledge of Allegiance to the Flag and the national motto "In God We Trust" are each displayed prominently in the Capitol Visitor Center on a permanent basis and to prohibit the Architect from removing or refusing to include language or other content from exhibits and materials relating to the Capitol Visitor Center on the grounds that the language or content includes a religious reference or Judeo-Christian content.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2007-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2007-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3908"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Capitol (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Christianity"/>
    <term name="Church and state"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Emblems"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Flags"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Judaism"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2007--Introduced.
Loyalty to Our Legacy Act of 2007 - Requires the Architect of the Capitol (AOC) to ensure that the Pledge of Allegiance to the Flag and the national motto "In God We Trust" are each displayed prominently in the Capitol Visitor Center (CVC) on a permanent basis. Prohibits the AOC, in preparing and producing any exhibit or other material relating to the CVC, from removing or refusing to include any language, symbol, writing, document, or record on the grounds that they include a religious reference or Judeo-Christian content.</summary>
</bill>
