<bill session="110" type="h" number="7166" updated="2013-07-19T22:06:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Health Care Access Improvement, Portability, and Cost Reduction Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve access to health care and health insurance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412201"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2008--Introduced.
American Health Care Access Improvement, Portability, and Cost Reduction Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to allow qualified primary care physicians or qualified nurse practitioners a tax credit of $1,000 for each month such providers provide services in a health professional shortage area.Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to make changes to the conversion factor for FY2010 for physicians Medicare payments.Allows a refundable tax credit for qualified health insurance coverage. Provides for advance payment of such credit.Revises IRC provisions relating to health savings accounts (HSAs) to: (1) allow HSAs to incorporate flexible spending and health reimbursement arrangements; (2) increase the annual HSA contribution limitation; (3) permit the use of HSAs to purchase health insurance; (4) allow the payment of certain medical expenses incurred before the establishment of an HSA; (5) allow veterans eligible for service-connected disability benefits to establish an HSA; and (6) allow spouses to make increased catch-up contributions to a single HSA.Requires the inclusion of education information about advance directives in the annual notice of Medicare benefits sent to eligible individuals.Revises provisions concerning Medicare+Choice private fee-for-service plans related to access standards under the plans and utilization.</summary>
</bill>
