<bill session="110" type="h" number="7258" updated="2013-07-19T22:07:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-10-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-10-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Credit Safety Commission Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create a new Consumer Credit Safety Commission, to provide individual consumers of credit with better information and stronger protections, and to provide sellers of consumer credit with more regulatory certainty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400102"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3629"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2008--Introduced.
Consumer Credit Safety Commission Act of 2008 - Establishes the Consumer Credit Safety Commission to promulgate consumer credit safety rules that: (1) ban abusive, fraudulent, unfair, deceptive, predatory, anticompetitive, or otherwise anti-consumer practices or product features for creditors; (2) place restrictions on consumer credit practices or product features to reduce the likelihood that they may be provided in a manner inconsistent with this Act; and (3) establish requirements for clear and adequate information appropriate to advance the objectives of this Act. Directs the Commission to: (1) establish and maintain a best practices guide for providers of consumer credit; (2) conduct, or award grants or contracts for, continuing studies and investigations of consumer credit industry practices; (3) help consumer credit providers to develop consumer credit safety standards or guidelines; and (4) establish and operate a consumer credit customer hotline to register complaints and receive information on how to combat anti-consumer credit. Directs the Commission to establish a program to promote federal-state cooperation to implement this Act. Sets forth civil and criminal penalties for acts prohibited by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
