<bill session="112" type="sr" number="378" updated="2013-07-20T02:13:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-15">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that children should have a safe, loving, nurturing, and permanent family and that it is the policy of the United States that family reunification, kinship care, or domestic and intercountry adoption promotes permanency and stability to a greater degree than long-term institutionalization and long-term, continually disrupted foster care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2012-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-02-15" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S803" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S803" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S704" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2012--Passed Senate without amendment.
Affirms that all children in the world, including those with special needs, deserve a safe, loving, nurturing, and permanent family, connections with siblings and relatives, or a permanent relationship with a caring adult. Acknowledges that the United States can and should do more by working with the private sector, nonprofit organizations, and faith-based communities to implement cost effective strategies that connect children living outside of family care with a permanent, supportive family, or connections with siblings and relatives, or a permanent relationship with a caring adult. Encourages states, counties, cities, and to the extent appropriate, other governments to invest resources in family preservation, reunification services, services to help older youth transition out of care with a connection to siblings, relatives or a caring adult, kinship adoption, domestic adoption, and intercountry adoption and post adoption strategies to ensure that more children in the United States are provided with safe, loving, and permanent family placements or a permanent relationship with a caring adult. Recognizes the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and the Department of State for recent efforts to develop a strategy for meeting the unique needs of children living outside of family care. Expresses the sense of the Senate that children should have a safe, loving, nurturing, and permanent family. Declars that it is U.S. policy that family reunification, kinship care, or domestic and intercountry adoption promotes permanency and stability to a greater degree than long-term institutionalization and long-term, continually disrupted foster care.</summary>
</bill>
