<bill session="109" type="s" number="1680" updated="2013-07-19T20:28:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Security Letter Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reform the issuance of national security letters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9939-9940"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2005--Introduced.
National Security Letter Reform Act of 2005 - Establishes procedures for judicial review of national security letters (NSLs). Authorizes: (1) the recipient of a request for records or other information under federal criminal code provisions concerning counterintelligence access to telephone toll and electronic communication transactional records, the Fair Credit Reporting Act, the Right to Financial Privacy Act, or the National Security Act of 1947 to petition the U.S. district court for an order modifying or setting aside the request; and (2) the court to modify or set aside a request if compliance would be unreasonable or oppressive. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) challenges to NSL nondisclosure requirements; (2) compelling compliance; and (3) closed hearings, filings under seal, and court review of classified information. Prohibits a wire or electronic communications service provider from disclosing that the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) has sought or obtained access to information or records if the Director of the FBI certifies that such disclosure may result in a danger to national security, interference with a criminal counterterrorism or counterintelligence investigation, interference with diplomatic relations, or a danger to the life or physical safety of any person. Sets penalties for violations of NSL nondisclosure provisions where committed with intent to obstruct an investigation or judicial proceeding.</summary>
</bill>
