<bill session="111" type="s" number="1726" updated="2013-07-20T00:39:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">USA PATRIOT Reauthorization and Additional Weapons Against Terrorism Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Additional Government Weapons Against Terrorism Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Classified Information Procedures Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">USA PATRIOT Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the expiring intelligence tools of the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 and defend against terrorism through improved classified procedures and criminal law reforms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2009-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9933-9934"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9934-9936" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2009--Introduced.
USA PATRIOT Reauthorization and Additional Weapons Against Terrorism Act of 2009 - USA PATRIOT Reauthorization Act of 2009 - Makes permanent the provisions of the USA PATRIOT Act: (1) granting roving electronic surveillance authority and authorizing the production of tangible things (including books, records, papers, and documents) for foreign intelligence and international terrorism investigations; and (2) revising the definition of an "agent of a foreign power" to include any non-U.S. person who engages in international terrorism or preparatory activities ("lone wolf" provision). Classified Information Procedures Reform Act of 2009 - Amends the Classified Information Procedures Act (CIPA) to: (1) require courts to grant certain ex parte government requests for CIPA protective orders; (2) restrict access to classified information obtained from nondocumentary sources; and (3) allow interlocutory appeals from any order for access to classified information (currently, appeals lie only from orders entered under CIPA). Additional Government Weapons Against Terrorism Act of 2009 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) impose criminal penalties for providing material support or resources to a perpetrator of international terrorism, or to a family member of or other person associated with such perpetrator, with the intent to facilitate, reward, or encourage international terrorism; (2) prohibit attempts or conspiracies to provide material support or resources to terrorist organizations; (3) impose criminal penalties for the use of false travel documents; and (4) deny release to individuals detained pending sentencing or appeal who have been convicted of certain terrorism crimes or crimes against children.</summary>
</bill>
