<bill session="110" type="h" number="5241" updated="2013-07-19T21:49:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Colorado Forest Insect Emergency Response Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to take expedited action to reduce the increased risk of severe wildfires to Colorado communities, water supplies, and infrastructure in or near forested areas most severely affected by infestations of bark beetles and other insects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400620" joined="2008-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E126"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-06">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-06">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3072"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Insect control"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Tree diseases"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2008--Introduced.
Colorado Forest Insect Emergency Response Act of 2008 - Amends the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior to designate an area of federal land in Colorado as an insect-emergency area if the area is: (1) subject to a widespread infestation of bark beetles or other insects; (2) characterized by insect-induced tree mortality that has, or within one year of the determination will have, produced a condition such that an immediate reduction in hazardous fuels is required in order to reduce the risks to human life and property or to a municipal water supply from a severe wildfire; and (3) identified for hazardous fuel reduction treatment in a community wildfire protection plan.</summary>
</bill>
