<bill session="109" type="sc" number="66" updated="2013-07-19T20:12:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A concurrent resolution affirming that the intent of Congress in passing the National Wildlife Refuge System Improvement Act of 1997 was to allow hunting and fishing on public land within the National Wildlife Refuge System and declaring that the purpose of reserving certain land as public land is to make the land available to the public for reasonable uses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13185" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2005--Introduced.
States that: (1) in passing the National Wildlife Refuge System Improvement Act of 1997, Congress demonstrated its clear intent to allow hunting and fishing on public lands within the National Wildlife Refuge System (the System); (2) the intent of Congress has not changed in any way since the date of enactment of that Act, and any assumption to the contrary is misguided and misinterprets the clear intent of Congress; and (3) the general purpose of reserving certain land as public land, including the land within the System, is to make the land available to the public for reasonable uses, which include hunting, fishing, other wildlife-dependent sports, and other outdoor purposes.</summary>
</bill>
