<bill session="109" type="h" number="5790" updated="2013-07-19T19:55:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Colorectal Cancer Early Detection, Prevention, and Treatment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for demonstation projects to carry out preventive health measures with respect to colorectal cancer.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2006-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2006-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400642" joined="2006-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2006-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2006-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2006-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2006-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Colon cancer"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2006--Introduced.
Colorectal Cancer Early Detection, Prevention, and Treatment Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to allow the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to make grants to public and private entities for demonstrations projects to: (1) provide colorectal cancer screenings to individuals who are 50 years of age or older or at high risk for such cancer; (2) provide case management and referrals for medical treatment to individuals screened; (3) ensure the provision of cancer care to individuals screened; (4) improve the education, training, and skills of health professionals in the detection and control of colorectal cancer; (5) evaluate the projects through appropriate surveillance or program monitoring activities; (6) develop and disseminate&#160;findings derived through such evaluations and the collection of data on outcomes; and (7) promote the benefits of receiving screenings through the projects. Requires applicants to give priority to low-income individuals who lack colorectal cancer coverage under health insurance and health plans. Requires the Secretary to give special consideration to applicants currently receiving grants for preventive health programs for breast or cervical cancers or prostate cancer.</summary>
</bill>
