<bill session="111" type="h" number="6065" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Secret Service Retirement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that certain Secret Service employees may elect to transition to coverage under the District of Columbia Police and Fire Fighter Retirement and Disability System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400349"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2010-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1862"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
United States Secret Service Retirement Act of 2010 - Authorizes an individual who was hired as a member of the United States Secret Service Division or the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division from January 1, 1984, through December 31, 1986, who has actively performed duties other than clerical for 10 or more years directly related to the Secret Service's protection mission, who is serving as a member of the Secret Service Division or the Secret Service Uniformed Division and participating in the Federal Employees' Retirement System on the date of enactment of this Act, and who has an amount in his or her Thrift Savings Fund account that exceeds that individual's transition cost and that is available for withdrawal immediately before filing an election, to file an election to transition to the District of Columbia Police and Firefighters Retirement and Disability System (DCPFRDS). Directs the Secret Service to notify Secret Service employees regarding: (1) their eligibility to file such an election; (2) transition costs; and (3) requirements to complete withdrawal forms and to provide for the transfer of such costs from the employee's Thrift Savings Fund account. Requires the Office of Pay and Retirement Services of the District of Columbia to transmit to the Secret Service determinations regarding such transition costs. Requires: (1) the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to prescribe regulations to provide for transition of covered employees from the Federal Employees' Retirement System to the Civil Service Retirement System; and (2) the District of Columbia government to provide for coverage of such employees in the DCPFRDS. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) the transfer of Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund funds of a covered employee to the Contributions for Annuity Benefits, United States Secret Service appropriations account of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS); and (2) the forfeiture of of a covered employee's Social Security contributions upon conversion.</summary>
</bill>
