<bill session="109" type="s" number="1701" updated="2013-07-19T20:28:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Abandoned Mine Land Reclamation Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to improve the reclamation of abandoned mines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2005-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-256.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Mine wastes"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2005--Introduced.
Abandoned Mine Land Reclamation Reform Act of 2005 - Amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to repeal the authorized use of certain moneys in the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund (Fund): (1) by the Secretary of Agriculture for reclamation of rural lands; and (2) by the Department of the Interior for studies by contract with organizations for advice and research and development projects and technical assistance. Sets forth a sliding scale reduction for reclamation fees required to be paid by operators of coal mining operations for coal produced by surface coal mining, coal produced by underground mining, and lignite coal. Extends to September 30, 2016, the period for payment of reclamation fees according to the existing formula. Revises Fund allocation requirements governing: (1) reclamation fees; (2) use of funds for abatement of acid mine drainage; and (3) graduated payments to states and Indian tribes. Instructs the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) to use unexpended interest paid into the Fund to execute transfers into the United Mine Workers of America Combined Benefit Fund. Directs the Secretary, upon the request of a state Governor or governing Indian tribal body, to enter into an agreement authorizing such entity to collect reclamation fees. Revises Fund objectives to repeal the objective of general welfare. Revises the prohibition against filing a lien against any person who neither consented to, nor participated in, nor exercised control over a mining operation which necessitated reclamation. Repeals the limitation of such prohibition to persons who owned the surface before May 2, 1977. Authorizes the Secretary to use amounts in the Fund to provide incentives to promote remining of eligible land. Extends from 2004 to 2015 the exception to the prohibition against approval of a permit due to any uncorrected air or water environmental protection violations if such violations result from an unanticipated event or or condition at a surface coal mining operation on lands eligible for remining.</summary>
</bill>
