<bill session="111" type="s" number="979" updated="2013-07-20T00:32:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SHOP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Health Options Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a nationwide health insurance purchasing pool for small businesses and the self-employed that would offer a choice of private health plans and make health coverage more affordable, predictable, and accessible.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2009-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2009-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5133-5134"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5135-5142" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2360"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2009--Introduced.
Small Business Health Options Program Act of 2009 or the SHOP Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to designate an office within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to administer a health insurance program for small businesses and self-employed individuals to purchase health insurance coverage meeting certain requirements. Establishes a Small Business Health Board to monitor the implementation of the program and make recommendations for improvements. Requires the Administrator of the program to: (1) enter into contracts with health insurance issuers to provide health insurance coverage under this Act; and (2) enter into agreements with entities to serve as navigators to provide information about the program, provide referrals to applicable agencies for any grievance, complaint, or question, and assist in enrollment. Requires a participating employer to ensure that each eligible employee has an opportunity to enroll in a plan. Sets forth requirements for health plans offered under this Act. Requires the Administrator to contract with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners to study: (1) the rating requirements that apply to health insurance purchased in the small group markets in the states and to develop recommendations concerning rating requirements; and (2) the administrative procedures that apply to the program and to health insurance purchased in the small group markets in states. Sets forth premium-setting rules for plans under this Act.Allows a state to prohibit participation in this program if the state offers alternative health benefit plans.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for small employers for qualified employee health insurance expenses under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
