<bill session="112" type="s" number="3676" updated="2013-07-20T02:48:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reducing Duplication Overseas Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote high-quality, cost-efficient, and effective administrative support services to agencies overseas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-12-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7980-7981"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7981-7982" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2012--Introduced.
Reducing Duplication Overseas Act of 2012 - Requires a federal agency that performs any foreign affairs functions and operates overseas to participate in the International Cooperative Administrative Support Services system for purposes of obtaining household furniture, furnishings, and appliance pools services, motor pool services, and management services unless such agency provides a detailed explanation that describes: (1) how such agency will provide the service outside the system, (2) the cost of the service, and (3) how providing the service outside the system will not increase overall costs. Requires such an agency to provide a detailed explanation certifying that the mission of the agency cannot be achieved by participation in the system. Requires the International Cooperative Administrative Support Services Executive Board to allow an agency to act as an alternative provider for administrative services at an overseas post in place of the system if the agency: (1) demonstratives that it can provide the administrative service more efficiently, and (2) agrees to provide the administrative service to all other International Cooperative Administrative Support Services customer agencies at the overseas post. Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to submit a review of the system to specified congressional committees</summary>
</bill>
