<bill session="112" type="s" number="420" updated="2013-07-20T02:20:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foster Care Mentoring Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to support the establishment or expansion and operation of programs using a network of public and private community entities to provide mentoring for children in foster care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2011-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2012"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3297"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2011--Introduced.
Foster Care Mentoring Act of 2011 - Amends part B (Child-Welfare Services) of title IV of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to states to support the establishment or expansion and operation of programs using networks of public and private community entities to provide mentoring for children in foster care. Authorizes a grant award directly to a political subdivision if the subdivision serves a substantial number of foster care youth. Prescribes program implementation guidelines, including: (1) application requirements, (2) training, (3) screening, (4) educational requirements, (5) federal and nonfederal share of funds for the program, (6) considerations in awarding grants, and (7) use of funds. Sets forth a maximum grant amount to be awarded to a state or political subdivision. Authorizes the Secretary to award a competitive grant to an eligible entity to establish a National Hotline Service or website to provide information to individuals interested in becoming mentors to youth in foster care. Instructs the Secretary of Education to implement a program to provide for the discharge or cancellation of the federal student loan indebtedness of an eligible mentor.</summary>
</bill>
