<bill session="110" type="h" number="1191" updated="2013-07-19T21:14:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-17T13:29:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-04-17T13:29:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the National Park Service to pay for services rendered by subcontractors under a General Services Administration Indefinite Deliver/Indefinite Quantity Contract issued for work to be completed at the Grand Canyon National Park.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400336"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2007-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T13:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3416-3417" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1191.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-04-17T13:29:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3416" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-08">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-01-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-319.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="671">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 671.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2007--Passed House amended.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, subject to the appropriation of such funds as may be necessary, to pay the amount owed to the subcontractors of Pacific General, Inc.(PGI), for work performed at the Grand Canyon National Park between FY2002-FY2003 under a General Services Administration (GSA) indefinite deliver/indefinite quantity contract (IDIQ), provided that: (1) the primary contract between PGI and the National Park Service is terminated; (2) the amount owed to the subcontractors is verified; (3) all reasonable legal avenues or recourse have been exhausted by the subcontractors to recoup amounts owed directly from PGI; and (4) the subcontractors provide a written statement that payment of the amount verified represents payment in full by the United States for all work performed at the Park under the IDIQ with PGI between FY2002-FY2003.</summary>
</bill>
