<bill session="111" type="s" number="3538" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Cyber Infrastructure Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the cyber security of the United States and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2010-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5445-5447"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4695"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/24/2010--Introduced.
National Cyber Infrastructure Protection Act of 2010 - Establishes within the Department of Defense (DOD) a National Cyber Center, headed by a Director who shall report directly to the President. Includes among the Director's duties: (1) coordinating federal government defensive operations, intelligence collection and analysis, and activities to protect and defend government information networks; (2) acting as the principal adviser to the President, the National Security Council, and the heads of federal agencies on matters relating to the protection and defense of such networks; and (3) keeping appropriate congressional committees fully informed of the Center's activities. Grants the Director access to all intelligence relating to cyber security collected by any federal agency, with specified exceptions. Provides for annual submissions to the Director of cyber budget requests by the head of each federal agency with responsibilities for matters relating to the protection and defense of federal information networks. Establishes within the National Cyber Security Program Budget a National Cyber Defense Contingency Fund. Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to determine the appropriate location for, and to establish within a National Laboratory, a public and private partnership for sharing cyber threat information and exchanging technical assistance, advice, and support, to be known as the Cyber Defense Alliance. Sets forth guidelines regarding the uses of shared information. Requires the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) to: (1) facilitate certain information sharing and declassification activities; and (2) establish uniform procedures for the receipt, care, and storage by agencies of information that is voluntarily submitted to the government through the Alliance. Establishes penalties for federal officers or employees who knowingly disclose cyber threat information protected from disclosure by this Act. Authorizes the federal government to provide warnings regarding potential threats to information networks. Terminates the Alliance on December 31, 2020.</summary>
</bill>
