<bill session="111" type="h" number="5397" updated="2013-07-20T00:01:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">H-1B and L-1 Visa Reform Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to reform and reduce fraud and abuse in certain visa programs for aliens working temporarily in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2010-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="887"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2010--Introduced.
H-1B and L-1 Visa Reform Act of 2010 - Amends the the Immigration and Nationality Act to revise employer and government provisions regarding H-1B (specialty occupation) and L-1 (intracompany transfer) nonimmigrant aliens. Amends H-1B employer application requirements to: (1) revise wage determination requirements; (2) require Internet posting and description of employment positions; (3) lengthen U.S. worker displacement protection: (4) apply certain requirements to all H-1B employers rather than only to H-1B dependent employers; (5) prohibit employer advertising that makes a position available only to, or gives priority to, H-1B nonimmigrants; and (6) limit the number of H-1B and L-1 employees that an employer of 50 or more workers in the United States may hire. Revises application review provisions. Authorizes the Department of Labor (DOL) to: (1) investigate applications for fraud; and (2) conduct H-1B compliance audits. Directs DOL to conduct annual audits of companies with large numbers of H-1B workers. Authorizes DOL to initiate H-1B employer application investigations. Increases employer penalties. Revises provisions regarding initiation of employer violation investigations by DOL. Provides for information sharing between DOL and United States Citizenship and Immigration Services regarding employer noncompliance. Authorizes DOL to hire 200 additional employees to administer H-1B programs. Prohibits, with a specified waiver by the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), an employer from hiring an L-1 nonimmigrant for more than one year who will: (1) serve in a capacity involving specialized knowledge; and (2) be stationed primarily at the worksite of an employer other than the petitioning employer. Specifies L-1: (1) employer petition requirements for employment at a new office; (2) wage rates and working conditions; and (3) employer penalties. Authorizes the Secretary to initiate an L-1 employer investigation. Requires a report to Congress regarding the L-1 blanket petition process.</summary>
</bill>
