<bill session="111" type="s" number="3251" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy Use By Federal Agencies Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve energy efficiency and the use of renewable energy by Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300019"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2590-2591"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2592-2593" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Energy. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-699.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG01" subcommittee="Energy" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/2010--Introduced.
Improving Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy Use By Federal Agencies Act of 2010 - Authorizes the head of each executive agency to establish projects under which an agency head may offer to enter into cost-effective power purchase agreements, during a 10-year period beginning on the date of this Act's enactment, for the purchase of electricity from renewable energy sources from federal facilities that are owned or controlled by the agency. Limits the term of the agreements to 30 years. Authorizes agencies to enter into interagency agreements as part of power purchase agreements. Establishes in the Treasury the Federal Facility Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy Projects Fund from which the Secretary of Energy (DOE) shall provide assistance for energy efficiency and renewable energy projects carried out at federal facilities. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a federal facility energy efficiency and renewable energy projects fund program under which the Secretary shall make loans to assist agencies in reducing energy use; (2) promulgate regulations that enable agencies to retain the financial savings that result from entering into utility energy saving contracts; (3) promulgate regulations that establish appropriate methods and procedures for agencies to identify all potential locations at their facilities for renewable energy projects; (4) issue guidance for agencies to employ advanced tools allowing energy savings through the use of computer hardware, energy efficiency software, and power management tools; and (5) issue guidance on a federal energy management and data collection standard that includes a plan for the General Services Administration (GSA) to publish energy consumption data for individual facilities on a searchable website accessible by the public. Requires agencies to submit annual plans on metering their consumption of electricity. Requires the Secretary to develop and report on best practices for the use of advanced metering of energy use in federal facilities, buildings, and equipment by federal agencies. Authorizes the Administrator of GSA to use appropriated funds to update project designs to meet federal building energy efficiency standards. Requires the Administrator and the Secretary to incorporate commissioning and recommissioning standards for all real property that: (1) is more than $10 million in value; (2) has more than 50,000 square feet; or (3) has energy intensity of more than $2 per square foot. Requires a contribution by the Secretary of Defense to a state for facilities for reserve components of the Armed Forces that is made at an armory or readiness center for an energy efficiency upgrade to cover 100% of the costs of architectural, engineering, and design services and the cost of the construction related to the upgrade.</summary>
</bill>
