<bill session="111" type="h" number="1316" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Flood Elevation Notification Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for appropriate notification of communities and homeowners of establishment of flood elevations for purposes of the National Flood Insurance Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400297" joined="2009-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2009--Introduced.
Flood Elevation Notification Act of 2009 - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to require the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), when establishing projected flood elevations for land use purposes, to first propose such determinations by: (1) providing the chief executive officer of each affected community notice of the elevations, including a copy of the pertinent maps and an explanation of the process to appeal for changes in the elevations; (2) causing notice of the elevations to be published in the Federal Register; (3) publishing the elevations in a prominent local newspaper, as well as a description of the flood determination appeals process, and contact information related to initiating an appeal; and (4) providing specified written notification, by first class mail, to each owner of real property affected by the proposed elevations.</summary>
</bill>
