<bill session="110" type="h" number="6475" updated="2013-07-19T22:00:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-11T14:52:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-11T14:52:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Daniel Webster Congressional Clerkship Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Daniel Webster Congressional Clerkship Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Daniel Webster Congressional Clerkship Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Daniel Webster Congressional Clerkship Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400245"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412188" joined="2008-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-08T18:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 110-831.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-08T18:38:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="533">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 533.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-09T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Brady (PA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-09T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7899-7903" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-09T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6475.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-09T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Ehlers objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-11T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Lewis of Georgia asked unanimous consent that the motion to suspend the rules relating to H.R. 6475 be considered as adopted in the form considered by the House on Tuesday, September 9, 2008.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8038-8039" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-09-11T14:52:00-04:00" how="without objection" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 09/09/2008 H7899-7900" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-11T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3533"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2008--Passed House without amendment.
Daniel Webster Congressional Clerkship Act of 2008 - Establishes the Daniel Webster Congressional Clerkship Program for the appointment of individuals who are graduates of accredited law schools to serve as Congressional Clerks in the Senate or House of Representatives. Requires the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration and the House Committee on House Administration to each select at least six individuals for a one-year term to serve as employees in their respective chambers. Specifies eligibility criteria for a Congressional Clerk, including that the selected candidate be a graduate of such a law school as of the starting date of his or her clerkship. Requires the committees to ensure that Congressional Clerks selected under this Act are apportioned equally between majority and minority party offices. Entitles each clerk selected to the same compensation as, and comparable benefits to, an individual who holds the position of a judicial clerkship for the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia within three months of graduating from law school. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
