<bill session="110" type="h" number="5671" updated="2013-07-19T21:53:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the laws establishing the Whiskeytown-Shasta-Trinity National Recreation Area and the Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area, units of the National Forest System derived from the public domain, to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to retain and utilize special use permit fees collected by the Secretary in connection with the operation of marinas in the recreation area and the operation of the Multnomah Falls Lodge in the scenic area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Hotels, motels, etc."/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="National scenic areas"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/2008--Introduced.
Amends Public Law 89-336 (relating to the establishment of the Whiskeytown-Shasta Trinity National Recreation Area in California) to set forth a special rule for the retention and use of amounts collected in connection with the issuance of a special use permit for the establishment or operation of a marina in such Area. Amends Public Law 99-663 (relating to the establishment of the Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area in Oregon and Washington) to set forth a special rule for the retention and use of amounts collected in connection with the issuance of a special use permit for the operation of the Multnomah Falls Lodge in such Area.</summary>
</bill>
