<bill session="112" type="h" number="5732" updated="2013-07-20T01:59:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Schools of the Future Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize a competitive grant program to implement and evaluate digital learning in rural locales.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412209"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2012--Introduced.
Schools of the Future Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive three- to five-year grants to eligible partnerships to implement and evaluate the results of technology-based learning practices, strategies, tools, or courses at rural schools. Defines "eligible partnerships" as those composed of a school partner, a digital learning partner, and an evaluation partner. Describes a "school partner" as a local educational agency, charter school network, consortium of elementary or secondary schools, regional educational service provider, or consortium of such entities. Includes among the grant-funded technology-based learning practices, strategies, tools, or courses, those that: (1) personalize the learning experience, (2) aid and inform instruction, (3) meet the needs of students with specific educational needs, (4) help students develop 21st century skills, and (5) give students access to courses that would otherwise be unavailable to them. Requires each partnership's evaluation partner, after the third year of the grant, to evaluate the effect of the technology-based learning practices, strategies, tools, or courses on student achievement.</summary>
</bill>
