<bill session="113" type="h" number="476" updated="2013-11-02T06:22:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GAAP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Generally Accepted Accounting Principles Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to require the President to submit with the budget an estimate of the deficit using generally accepted accounting principles, and to amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the Congressional Budget Office to submit the same with its report to the Committees on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400151"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2013-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2013--Introduced.
Generally Accepted Accounting Principles Act or GAAP Act - Requires the President's budget submission to include an estimate of the deficit or surplus for the fiscal year concerned, prepared using generally accepted accounting principles. Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the alternative levels of total revenues, total new budget authority, and total outlays (including related surpluses and deficits) covered by the annual Congressional Budget Office (CBO) fiscal policy report to the congressional budget committees on the upcoming fiscal year to be prepared using both cash basis accounting and generally accepted accounting principles.</summary>
</bill>
