<bill session="113" type="s" number="1367" updated="2013-11-02T07:03:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Heroes Fly Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to direct the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) to provide expedited air passenger screening to severely injured or disabled members of the Armed Forces and severely injured or disabled veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2013-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1344"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1403"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2013--Introduced.
Helping Heroes Fly Act - Directs the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration [TSA]) to develop and implement a process to ease travel and to the extent possible provide expedited passenger screening services for severely injured or disabled Armed Forces members and veterans, and their accompanying family members or nonmedical attendants. Requires the Assistant Secretary also to maintain an operations center to provide for the movement of such members and veterans through screening before boarding a domestic or foreign passenger aircraft. Directs the Assistant Secretary to establish and publish certain protocols for severely injured or disabled Armed Forces members and veterans or their family members and others to contact the operations center to request expedited screening services for the member or veteran.</summary>
</bill>
