<bill session="111" type="s" number="1096" updated="2013-07-20T00:33:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish an EnergyGrant Competitive Education Program to competitively award grants to consortia of institutions of higher education in regions to conduct research, extension, and education programs relating to the energy needs of the region.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5704-5706"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5713-5714" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2009--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Energy to award competitive matching grants to consortia of institutions of higher education (IHEs) located in at least six regions covering all the states to conduct research, extension, and education programs relating to the energy needs of such regions. Includes among such needs: (1) the promotion of low-carbon clean and green energy and related jobs; (2) the development of low-carbon green fuels to reduce dependency on oil; (3) the development of energy storage and energy management innovations for intermittent renewable technologies; and (4) the accelerated deployment of efficient-energy technologies in buildings and manufacturing facilities. Allows federally funded research and development centers to be members of such consortia. Requires each grantee to maintain an Energy Analysis Center to provide the IHEs in the region with analysis and data management support. Authorizes appropriations for this Act's grant program and the Department of Energy's Sun Grant program, which supports research involving bioenergy and biofuels production.</summary>
</bill>
