<bill session="109" type="h" number="3121" updated="2013-07-19T19:31:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 39, United States Code, to prevent certain types of mail matter from being sent by a Member of the House of Representatives as part of a mass mailing.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400228"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2005-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Congressional publicity"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Constituent relations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal mandates"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Press and politics"/>
    <term name="Public opinion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2005--Introduced.
Amends Federal postal law to prohibit a Member of the House of Representatives from sending as part of a mass mailing: (1) the usual and customary congressional newsletter or press release which may deal with such matters as the impact of laws and decisions on State and local governments and individual citizens, reports on public and official actions taken by Members of Congress, and discussions of proposed or pending legislation or governmental actions and the positions of the Members of Congress on, and arguments for or against, such matters; (2) the usual and customary congressional questionnaire seeking public opinion on any law, pending or proposed legislation, public issue, or subject; or (3) mail matter expressing congratulations to a person who has achieved some public distinction.</summary>
</bill>
