<bill session="111" type="h" number="5208" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Student Visa Security Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to strengthen student visa background checks and improve the monitoring of foreign students in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412234" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2010-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2010-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E751"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2010--Introduced.
Student Visa Security Improvement Act - Amends the the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) require DHS employees to conduct in-person interviews and conduct on-site reviews of applications and supporting documentation with respect to student and exchange program visa applicants prior to final visa adjudication, with emphasis on determining whether an applicant is inadmissible for terrorist-related activities; (2) require an institution or exchange visitor program participating in the Student and Exchange Visitor Program to ensure that each covered student or exchange visitor is an active program participant, is observed, and is reported to DHS if he or she transfers institutions or academic majors; (3) provide Student and Exchange Visitor Information System (SEVIS) access to appropriate employees of a SEVIS program sponsor under specified circumstances; and (4) require a SEVIS upgrade to add data fields that include verification that students are meeting minimum academic standards.</summary>
</bill>
