<bill session="111" type="s" number="1216" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Residential Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Consumer Product Safety Act to require residential carbon monoxide detectors to meet the applicable ANSI/UL standard by treating that standard as a consumer product safety rule, to encourage States to require the installation of such detectors in homes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2010-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1796"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2009--Introduced.
Residential Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act - Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to require the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to publish the American National Standard for Single and Multiple Station Carbon Monoxide Alarms (American National Standard ANSI/UL 2034-2005) as a mandatory consumer product safety standard. Makes it unlawful for any manufacturer or distributor to import or distribute any new assembled or unassembled residential carbon monoxide detector unless it complies with the standard. Requires the CPSC to issue a final rule in its proceeding titled Portable Generators, including a requirement that portable generators incorporate an automatic shutoff feature if compliance with such a requirement is technologically feasible. Requires the CPSC to establish a grant program to provide assistance to states to carry out a carbon monoxide alarm program.</summary>
</bill>
