<bill session="109" type="h" number="4880" updated="2013-07-19T19:47:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Maritime Terminal Security Enhancement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Maritime Terminal Security Enhancement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Commandant of the Coast Guard to require that a security plan for a maritime facility be resubmitted for approval upon transfer of ownership or operation of such facility, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400026" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400049" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2006-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400633" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400096" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2006-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400132" joined="2006-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400139" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400214" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400642" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="2006-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400637" joined="2006-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-06">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-06">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-04-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-04-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T21:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 109-709, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T21:47:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Homeland Security Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 17, 2006.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-17T14:42:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Homeland Security Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Dec. 8, 2006.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4839"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4839"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4842"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4842"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2334"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2334"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dubai Ports World aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Maritime Terminal Security Enhancement Act of 2006 - (Sec. 2) Directs the Commandant of the Coast Guard to require the resubmission of a facility security plan for Coast Guard approval upon the transfer of ownership or operational control over a port terminal facility. (Sec. 3) Directs the Commandant to require that the individual designated as the Facility Security Officer under a facility security plan be a U.S. citizen. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating (Secretary) to issue regulations by July 1, 2006, that allow access to secure areas within ports and vessels only to maritime workers and merchant mariners who have been issued approved biometric transportation security cards. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary, through the Commandant, to reassess foreign port compliance with international port security requirements and the effectiveness of antiterrorism measures maintained at those ports not less than every five years. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary, by July 1, 2006, to require, and develop the necessary forms and process for, enhanced crewmember identification credentials for U.S. and foreign merchant mariners on vessels that call on U.S. ports. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to issue implementing regulations for a long range vessel tracking system by April 1, 2007. (Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary to establish a university-based Center for Excellence for Maritime Domain Awareness. (Sec. 9) States that a container shipped directly or via a foreign port may enter the United States only if it is: (1) scanned with specified equipment and a copy of the scan is provided to the Commandant; and (2) secured with a specified seal before being loaded on the vessel for shipment. Directs the Commandant to establish standards for seals and scanning equipment. Authorizes FY2007-FY2012 appropriations to carry out such container-related activities. (Sec. 10) Authorizes the Secretary to require the owner or operator of a facility that is required to have a security plan and that is a cargo terminal to submit information, including contracts or other agreements that govern operations of such facilities, to the Secretary to determine if there is any security risk involving such owner or operator. Directs the Secretary to annually report to Congress regarding contracts and agreements that govern operation of facilities required to have a security plan.</summary>
</bill>
