<bill session="110" type="h" number="6760" updated="2013-07-19T22:02:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Combat Bonus Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To pay a one-time bonus to members of the Armed Forces who serve in a combat zone designated for Operation Iraqi Freedom or Operation Enduring Freedom, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2008--Introduced.
Combat Bonus Act - Requires the payment of a one-time bonus of $1,500 to each active-duty and reserve member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Coast Guard, or Merchant Marines who: (1) serves for 90 days or more on or after October 7, 2001, in a combat zone designated in connection with Operations Iraqi Freedom or Enduring Freedom; and (2) if discharged or released, is done so under conditions other than dishonorable. Makes individuals eligible for such bonus for qualifying service of less than 90 days if the individual: (1) dies of injuries incurred in connection with such service; or (2) is evacuated from a theater of combat due to an injury incurred in connection with such service.</summary>
</bill>
