<bill session="112" type="h" number="3833" updated="2013-07-20T01:43:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">DRIVES Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Driving Research through Innovative Viable Economic Solutions Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize surface transportation research programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400165"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2012-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2012-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-27">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-27">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1813"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1813"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/27/2012--Introduced.
Driving Research through Innovative Viable Economic Solutions Act of 2012 or DRIVES Act of 2012 - Amends federal transportation law related to: (1) surface transportation research, (2) technology deployment, (3) transportation training and education, (4) intelligent transportation systems, (5) University Transportation Centers, and (6) the Bureau of Transportation Statistics. Reauthorizes appropriations out of the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) for up to 80% of the costs of those programs and entities for FY2013-FY2016. Allows the Secretary to carry out surface transportation research and development activities to: (1) improve highway safety; (2) improve infrastructure integrity; (3) reduce congestion, improve highway operations, and enhance freight productivity; and (4) assess policy and system financing alternatives. Eliminates the Long-Term Pavement Performance, Seismic Research, and Long-Term Bridge Performance programs. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) implement a competitive prize program to stimulate surface transportation innovations, and (2) establish up to four Centers for Surface Transportation Excellence to assist states in implementing surface transportation programs. Requires the Secretary to implement a technology deployment program relating to all aspects of highway transportation. Eliminates the Innovative Bridge Research and Construction, Innovative Pavement Research and Deployment, and Safety Innovation Deployment programs. Directs the Secretary to implement the recommendations of the Future Strategic Highway Research program administered by the National Academy of Sciences (NAS). Sets the federal share of the costs of local technical assistance center activities at 50%. Requires amounts provided to institutions of higher education (IHEs) under the Dwight David Eisenhower Transportation Fellowship program to be used for student expenses. Eliminates the authority of states to use for surface transportation workforce development, training, and education certain federal funds they received to maintain the Interstate Highway System or replace or rehabilitate highway bridges. Repeals the International Highway Transportation Outreach and Surface Transportation-Environmental Cooperative Research programs. Requires the Secretary to develop a strategic five-year plan to guide federal transportation research and development activities. Repeals the National Cooperative Freight Transportation Research and Future Strategic Highway Research programs. Requires the Secretary to develop a five-year National Intelligent Transportation System (ITS) program plan. Amends SAFETEA-LU to require the Secretary to ensure that ITS programs conform with regional ITS architecture and standards. Authorizes the Administrator of the Research and Innovative Technology Administration, with a 50% federal share, to carry out collaborative research and development with non-federal entities, federal laboratories, and other federal agencies. Revises the university transportation centers program to establish competitive grants to IHEs to establish and operate university transportation centers for 65% of the costs to: (1) improve highway safety; (2) improve infrastructure integrity; (3) reduce congestion, improve highway operations, and enhance freight productivity; and (4) assess policy and system financing alternatives.</summary>
</bill>
