<bill session="113" type="hr" number="329" updated="2013-11-02T06:18:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Calling for the support of the fundamental rights of all Egyptian citizens, equal access to justice and due process of law, and transparent and accountable governance in Egypt.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and North Africa.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA13" subcommittee="Middle East and North Africa" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
Supports economic and political reforms that uphold the fundamental rights of all Egyptian citizens, equal access to justice, due process, and transparent and accountable governance. Calls on interim Egyptian President Adly Mansour and the government of Egypt to restore the Egyptian Constitution and the rule of law. Urges: (1) the process of amending the Egyptian Constitution to be transparent and secure broad consensus; (2) the Egyptian Armed Forces and security services to respect the rights of all Egyptian citizens; and (3) full restoration of media and civil society freedoms, including protecting media and journalists and overturning the verdicts in which 43 U.S. citizens, Egyptians, and others were given harsh sentences for their work to support democracy. Calls on: (1) the government of Egypt to continue to meet its obligations under the 1979 Egypt-Israel Peace Treaty; and (2) interim President Mansour and the Egyptian Armed Forces to end the climate of impunity, end arbitrary arrests and politically motivated detentions, prosecute acts of violence, and make the protection of of all Egyptian citizens an urgent priority.</summary>
</bill>
