<bill session="109" type="h" number="1529" updated="2013-07-19T19:17:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Power Act to provide for Federal and State coordination of permitting for electric transmission facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400368"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2005--Introduced.
Designates the Department of Energy (DOE) as the lead agency for purposes of coordinating all applicable Federal authorization and related environmental review of a proposed electricity transmission or distribution facility upon request of a current or prospective applicant for Federal authorization related to such a facility. Instructs DOE to establish prompt and binding intermediate milestones and ultimate deadlines for the review of and Federal authorization decisions relating to the proposed facility. Sets a one-year deadline for completion of all permit decisions and related environmental reviews regarding an application. Requires the Secretary of Energy to consult regularly with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) and FERC-approved Regional Transmission Organizations and Independent System Operators on changes to the national grid that will improve reliability, relieve congestion, and enhance the capability of the grid to deliver electricity.</summary>
</bill>
