<bill session="109" type="h" number="5327" updated="2013-07-19T19:51:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Servicemembers Credit Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to protect the credit of servicemembers deployed to an overseas combat zone and to facilitate awareness of a servicemember's rights under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400633" joined="2006-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Eviction"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Life insurance"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2006--Introduced.
Servicemembers Credit Protection Act - Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to direct the Secretary of Defense, in case of the deployment of a servicemember away from their usual duty station to duty for which the servicemember is entitled to special pay, to notify each consumer reporting agency (agency): (1) of the deployment of such servicemember within 30 days after the deployment; and (2) within 30 days after the end of such deployment. Requires the Secretary, in providing such notice, to take measures to ensure agency compliance with provisions of the Fair Credit Reporting Act with respect to the servicemember. Increases penalties for consumer credit reporting violations involving servicemembers deployed to an overseas combat zone. Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require each agency that receives a combat zone duty alert from the Secretary with respect to a servicemember to: (1) include the alert in the file of that consumer and provide such alert along with any credit score, until notified by the Secretary that the consumer no longer qualifies for such alert; and (2) during the period of the alert, exclude the consumer from any list provided to a third party to offer credit or insurance to such consumer as part of a transaction not initiated by the consumer. Requires the combat zone duty alert included in any consumer's file to include a summary of the consumer's rights under the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act and the duties of creditors and other persons to the consumer.</summary>
</bill>
