<bill session="112" type="s" number="606" updated="2013-07-20T02:21:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Creating Hope Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to improve the priority review voucher incentive program relating to tropical and rare pediatric diseases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2012-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3059"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2011--Introduced.
Creating Hope Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to revise the priority review voucher program for tropical diseases to: (1) include rare pediatric diseases; (2) allow unlimited transfers of vouchers under the program; and (3) require a sponsor intending to use a voucher to notify the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) at least 90 days (currently, 365 days) before submission of the application. Revises provisions regarding the priority review user fee, including to make it payable upon notification of the Secretary of intent to use the voucher. Authorizes the Secretary, upon request of the manufacturer or sponsor of a new drug, to designate that a new drug is: (1) for a rare pediatric disease, and (2) an innovative treatment. Requires the Secretary to deem a rare pediatric disease product application to be incomplete if it does not contain a description of the sponsor's plan to market the product in the United States. Authorizes the Secretary to refuse to issue a priority review voucher upon the approval of a rare pediatric disease application if the Secretary finds that the sponsor lacks a good faith intention to market the product in the United States. Directs the Secretary to issue a guidance document setting forth the evidentiary support necessary to demonstrate such a good faith intention. Requires sponsors of applications under the priority review voucher program to report to the Secretary within five years after the approval of the application on the demand and distribution of the product within the United States.</summary>
</bill>
