<bill session="113" type="h" number="2310" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Guard Units And Reservists Deserve Remembrance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make available for purchase Department of Veterans Affairs memorial headstones and markers for members of reserve components who performed certain training.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412454"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412547" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412563" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2013-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412509" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2013-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412525" joined="2013-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2013--Introduced.
Guard Units and Reservists Deserve Remembrance Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to make available for purchase a memorial headstone or marker for the marked or unmarked grave of: (1) an individual who performed inactive duty training or active duty for training as a member of a National Guard or Reserve component for at least six years, but did not serve on active duty and is not otherwise ineligible for a memorial headstone or marker on account of the nature of the individual's separation from the Armed Forces or other cause; or (2) such an individual whose remains are unavailable. Permits such a headstone or marker to be purchased under this Act by: (1) the individual; (2) the surviving spouse, child, sibling, or parent of the individual; or (3) an individual other than the next of kin, as determined by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to: (1) ensure that the prices of such headstones and markers are sufficient to cover their production and delivery costs, and (2) coordinate with the Secretary of Defense (DOD) in establishing procedures to determine whether an individual qualifies for the purchase of a memorial headstone or marker under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
