<bill session="109" type="s" number="1515" updated="2013-07-19T20:26:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicaid Advanced Practice Nurses and Physician Assistants Access Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to improve access to advanced practice nurses and physician assistants under the Medicaid Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2005-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2006-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9186"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9186" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="2716"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Midwives"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Physicians' assistants"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2005--Introduced.
Medicaid Advanced Practice Nurses and Physician Assistants Access Act of 2005 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to eliminate the state option to include nurse practitioners, certified nurse-midwives, and physician assistants as primary care case managers. Specifies as primary care case managers any nurse practitioner, certified nurse-midwife, or physician assistant that provides primary care case management services under a primary care case management contract. Revises the coverage of certain nurse practitioner services under the Medicaid fee-for-service program to remove the specification of certified pediatric nurse practitioner and certified family nurse practitioner in order to extend such coverage to services furnished by a nurse practitioner or clinical nurse specialist. Includes nurse practitioners, clinical nurse specialists, physician assistants, certified nurse midwives, and certified registered nurse anesthetists in the mix of service providers which Medicaid managed care organizations are required to maintain.</summary>
</bill>
