<bill session="110" type="h" number="5683" updated="2013-07-19T21:32:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-22">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Government Accountability Office Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Government Accountability Office Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Government Accountability Office Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Government Accountability Office Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Government Accountability Office Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Government Accountability Office Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make certain reforms with respect to the Government Accountability Office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2008-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2008-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E477"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-05-01">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T21:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government. H. Rept. 110-671.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-05-22T21:07:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="422">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 422.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-09T17:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis (IL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-09T17:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5080-5084" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-09T17:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5683.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-06-09T17:38:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5080-5082" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-06-09T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-06-25">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-07-26">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-07-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="901">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 901.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8070-8073" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8071-8073" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>The committee amendments were withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2008-08-01" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-09T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis (IL) moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7881-7884" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-09T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 5683.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2008-09-09T14:00:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7881-7883" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-09T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2008-09-09">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2008-09-22">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2008-09-22" type="public" number="110-323">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 110-323.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3268"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2564"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Expense accounts"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Oaths"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Severance pay"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5264"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/22/2008--Public Law.
Government Accountability Office Act of 2008 - (Sec. 2) Requires: (1) the Comptroller General to provide for a pay increase to covered Government Accountability Office (GAO) officers and employees if the increase that would otherwise take effect would be less than the required minimum percentage (equal to the total annual pay adjustment for General Schedule positions within a pay locality); and (2) nonpermanent merit pay to a such an officer or employee to be decreased by an amount equal to the portion of such person's basic pay that is attributable to the increase provided by this Act.Defines a "covered officer or employee" to mean a Government Accountability Office (GAO) officer or employee whose performance is at least at a satisfactory level and who is not a member of the Senior Executive Service, a Federal Wage System employee, or an employee who is in GAO's entry-level developmental programs.(Sec. 3) Requires the Comptroller General, within six months, to pay to a GAO employee who did not receive a permanent base pay increase in 2006 and 2007 a lump sum payment. Requires the lump sum payment to be: (1) applied prospectively; and (2) treated as basic pay for purposes of any determination of the average pay.Requires the GAO to deduct and withhold from such lump-sum payments employee contributions to, and to pay the applicable agency contribution to, the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund.Provides for an exclusive remedy for individuals with claims that they are owed any money denied to them in the form of pay increases for 2006 or 2007.(Sec. 4) Requires the Comptroller General to pay each qualified individual a lump-sum payment equal to the amount of performance-based compensation such individual was denied for 2006. Defines "qualified individual" to mean an individual who is: (1) a GAO officer or employee, excluding members of the Senior Executive Service, Federal Wage System employees, and employees in GAO's entry-level developmental programs; and (2) a Band I staff member with a salary above the Band I cap, a Band IIA staff member with a salary above the Band IIA cap, or an administrative professional or support staff member with a salary above the cap for that individual's pay band.(Sec. 5) Establishes an Office of the Inspector General in GAO to: (1) conduct and supervise audits and investigations relating to GAO; (2) provide leadership and coordination and recommend policies to promote economy, efficiency, and effectiveness in GAO; and (3) keep the Comptroller General and Congress informed concerning fraud and other serious problems, abuses, and deficiencies relating to the administration of GAO programs and operations.Authorizes the Inspector General to receive and investigate complaints or information from GAO employees concerning the possible existence of an activity constituting a violation of law, mismanagement, or a gross waste of funds. Requires the Inspector General to refer complaints or information concerning violations of personnel law to established investigative and adjudicative GAO entities.Prohibits the Inspector General from disclosing the identity of an employee who submitted a complaint or information without the employee's consent, unless such disclosure is unavoidable during the course of the investigation.Prohibits employees who have authority for personnel actions from taking or threatening action against employees as a reprisal for making a complaint or disclosing information, unless the complaint or disclosure was made with the knowledge that it was false or with willful disregard for its truth or falsity.Requires the Inspector General to report semiannually to the Comptroller General on the Office's activities. Requires the Comptroller General's annual report to Congress to assess the overall degree of federal agency cooperation with GAO audits.Prohibits the Comptroller General from preventing the Inspector General from carrying out any his or her responsibilities under this Act.(Sec. 6) Requires any executive agency that prepares an audited financial statement to reimburse GAO for the cost of any GAO audit of such statement if GAO audited the statement or schedule of such agency for fiscal year 2007. Requires the GAO to consult with the relevant executive agency and the Inspector General of such agency prior to the initiation of the audit on the scope, terms, and cost of such audit.(Sec. 7) Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to revise the coverage of certain GAO officers and employees under its financial disclosure requirements.(Sec. 8) Revises the highest basic pay rate for GAO personnel from GS-15 to Executive Level III.Increases from 15 to 20 the number of experts and consultants whose services the Comptroller General may procure for renewable three-year terms at rates up to level IV of the Executive Schedule.Makes funds appropriated to GAO for salaries and expenses also available for recruitment-related meals and entertainment.</summary>
</bill>
