<bill session="110" type="h" number="1573" updated="2013-07-19T21:17:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Japanese American Memorial Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the boundary of the Minidoka Internment National Monument, to establish the Minidoka National Historic Site, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain land and improvements of the Gooding Division of the Minidoka Project, Idaho, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400376"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2007-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1612"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="916"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Concentration camps"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Japanese Americans"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2007--Introduced.
Japanese American Memorial Act of 2007 - Adjusts the boundary of the Minidoka Internment National Monument located in Idaho to include the Nidoto Nai Yoni ("Let it not happen again") memorial that commemorates the Japanese Americans of Bainbridge Island, Washington, who were the first to be forcibly removed from their homes and relocated to internment camps during World War II. Authorizes the Secretary, for the purposes of defining the role of the National Park Service (NPS) in administering the Memorial owned by the City of Brainbridge Island to enter into agreements with the City of Bainbridge Island and specified entities. Authorizes the Secretary to operate and maintain a site in Seattle, Washington, for administrative and visitor use purposes associated with the Monument, using the facilities and other services of the Seattle unit of Klondike Gold Rush National Historical Park. Requires the Secretary to coordinate the development of interpretive and educational materials and programs for the Memorial and Monument site in Idaho with the Manzanar National Historic Site in California. American Falls Reservoir District Number 2 Conveyance Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to convey specified land to the: (1) American Falls Reservoir District No. 2 located in Jerome, Lincoln, and Gooding Counties, Idaho; (2) city of Gooding; and (3) Idaho Department of Fish and Game. Revokes the Department of Interior's previous orders that withdrew specified land from the Gooding Division of the Minidoka project.</summary>
</bill>
