<bill session="112" type="h" number="306" updated="2013-07-20T01:12:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-06T16:44:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-02-06T16:44:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Corolla Wild Horses Protection Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Corolla Wild Horses Protection Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Corolla Wild Horses Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement to provide for management of the free-roaming wild horses in and around the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400209"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2011-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2011-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2011-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2011-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2011-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2011-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-10-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-12-01T18:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-310.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-12-01T18:52:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="210">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 210.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-02-06T16:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-06T16:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H480-481" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-06T16:35:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 306.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-02-06T16:44:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H480" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-02-06T16:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-21">
      <text>Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3448"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Seashores and lakeshores"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2012--Passed House amended.
Corolla Wild Horses Protection Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the Corolla Wild Horse Fund, Currituck County, and the state of North Carolina to provide for the management of free-roaming wild horses in and around the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge. Requires that such agreement: (1) allow a herd of no more than 130 free-roaming wild horses in and around the Refuge; (2) provide for cost-effective management of such horses; and (3) provide for the introduction of a small number of free-roaming wild horses from the herd at Cape Lookout National Seashore as is necessary to maintain the genetic viability of the herd in and around the Refuge; and (4) specify that the Corolla Wild Horse Fund shall pay certain costs associated with the health, maintenance, removal, and placement of such horses. Bars the Secretary from excluding free-roaming wild horses from any part of the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge unless: (1) it is found that the presence of such horses on a part of the Refuge threatens the survival of an endangered species for which such land is designated as critical habitat, (2) such finding is based on a peer-reviewed scientific assessment, and (3) a period of public notice and comment is provided on such finding. Prohibits the removal of any horse from the Seashore for introduction at the Refuge, except with the approval of the Foundation for Shackleford Horses Inc. and consistent with the memorandum of understanding between the National Park Service (NPS) and the Foundation and the management plan for the Shackleford Banks Horse Herd. Prohibits anything in this Act from being construed as creating liability of the United States for any damages caused by the free-roaming wild horses to any person or property located inside or outside the boundaries of the Refuge.</summary>
</bill>
