<bill session="111" type="h" number="5349" updated="2013-07-20T00:00:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cambodian Trade Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that Cambodia's debt to the United States may not be reduced or forgiven, and textile and apparel articles that are the product of Cambodia and imported into the United States may not be extended duty free treatment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400102"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2010-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2010--Introduced.
Cambodian Trade Act of 2010 - Declares it is U.S. policy to: (1) support and encourage countries that comply with international agreements, respect human rights and the protection of refugee populations, and value and protect minority populations seeking asylum and protection from oppressive governments and regimes; and (2) assist refugees and minority populations seeking asylum and protection from oppressive governments and regimes. Prohibits the United States from reducing or forgiving a debt owed by Cambodia to the United States. Prohibits the extension of duty-free treatment to Cambodian textile or apparel articles imported into the United States.</summary>
</bill>
