<bill session="109" type="h" number="4367" updated="2013-07-19T19:42:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Domestic Violence Screening, Treatment, and Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the health care system's response to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking through the training and education of health care providers, developing comprehensive public health responses to violence.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2005-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2005-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2005-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elder abuse"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Forensic medicine"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="Stalking"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Wife abuse"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2005--Introduced.
Domestic Violence Screening, Treatment, and Prevention Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to award grants for the development of interdisciplinary training and education programs that provide health professions students with an understanding of, and clinical skills pertinent to, domestic violence, sexual assault, stalking, and dating violence. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to award grants to strengthen the response of state, tribal, territorial, or local health care systems to such violence. Amends title V (Maternal and Child Health Services) of the Social Security Act to give preference in awarding maternal and child health services grant funds to applicants that provide training for service providers in how to identify and treat the health effects of such violence. Requires states to set aside a reasonable portion of such funds to provide for such violence services. Directs the Secretary to allot additional funds to enable states to provide for identification and treatment of such violence. Allows the Secretary to awards grants to federally qualified health centers to improve the identification and treatment of such violence. Amends the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 to require the Secretary, acting through the Directors of CDC and the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ), to fund research on effective interventions in the health care setting that: (1) prevent domestic violence, dating violence, and sexual assault across the lifespan; (2) prevent the health effects of such violence; and (3) improve the safety and health of individuals who are currently being victimized.</summary>
</bill>
