<bill session="109" type="h" number="6168" updated="2013-07-19T19:58:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dietary Supplement and Nonprescription Drug Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to serious adverse event reporting for dietary supplements and nonprescription drugs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2006-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1826"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3546"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug adulteration"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Nonprescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2006--Introduced.
Dietary Supplement and Nonprescription Drug Consumer Protection Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require a manufacturer, packer, or distributor whose name appears on the label of a nonprescription drug or dietary supplement marketed in the United States to: (1) submit to the Secretary of Health and Human Services within 15 business days any report received of a serious adverse event associated with such drug or supplement when used in the United States; (2) submit within 15 business days any related medical information that is received within one year of the initial report; (3) maintain records related to each report for six years; and (4) permit inspection of such records. Requires the Secretary to develop systems to ensure that duplicate reports of a serious adverse event are consolidated into a single report. Allows the Secretary to establish an exemption from such reporting that would have no adverse effect on public health. Prohibits any state or local government from establishing or continuing any requirement related to a mandatory system for adverse event reports for nonprescription drugs or dietary supplements that is not identical to this Act. Prohibits the responsible person from: (1) refusing to permit access to any required record; or (2) failing to establish or maintain any record, or make any report, required under this Act. Deems a nonprescription drug or dietary supplement that is marketed in the United States to be misbranded, unless its label includes a domestic address or phone number for the reporting of a serious adverse event. Prohibits the importation of such a drug or supplement if the Secretary has credible evidence or information indicating that the responsible person has not complied with the requirements of this Act or has not allowed access to its records.</summary>
</bill>
