<bill session="109" type="s" number="2559" updated="2013-07-19T20:35:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Honest Services Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make it illegal for anyone to defraud and deprive the American people of the right to the honest services of a Member of Congress and to instill greater public confidence in the United States Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3216-3217"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3217" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional hearings"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2006--Introduced.
Honest Services Act of 2006 - Amends the federal criminal code to establish a fine or imprisonment for up to 20 years, or both, for anyone who knowingly and willfully attempts or executes a scheme or artifice to defraud and deprive the United States, Congress, or the constituents of a Member of Congress, of the right to the honest services of such Member. Covers both: (1) those who offer or provide a Member of Congress, or his or her employee, with anything of value with the intent to influence the performance of an official act; as well as (2) Members and staff who accept such things, or hold an undisclosed financial interest, with intent to be so influenced. Authorizes funds to the Department of Justice for additional personnel to investigate and prosecute honest services fraud, bribery, graft, and conflicts of interest offenses.</summary>
</bill>
