<bill session="113" type="s" number="310" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Startup Act 3.0</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to jump-start economic recovery through the formation and growth of new businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400284"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2013-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="633"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="714"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="193"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="293"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2013--Introduced.
Startup Act 3.0 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to adjust to conditional permanent resident status up to 50,000 aliens who have earned a master's or doctorate degree in a science, technology, engineering, or mathematics field (STEM field) and permit such an alien to remain in the United States: (1) for up to one year after the expiration of the alien's student visa, if the alien is searching for STEM field employment; and (2) indefinitely if the alien remains actively engaged in a STEM field. Removes a STEM alien's conditional status after five years of maintaining eligibility during the entire five-year period. Authorizes the Secretary to issue conditional immigrant visas to up to 75,000 qualified alien entrepreneurs. Removes such conditional basis after four years of maintaining qualified entrepreneur status. Eliminates the per-country numerical limitation for employment-based visas. Increases the per country numerical limitation for family based immigrants from 7% to 15% of the total number of family-sponsored visas. Amends the Chinese Student Protection Act of 1992 to eliminate the provision requiring the reduction of annual People's Republic of China immigrant visas to offset status adjustments under such Act. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) provide a permanent full tax exclusion on gain from the sale or exchange of qualified small business stock held for more than five years, (2) repeal the minimum tax preference and the 28% capital gains rate on such stock, and (3) provide a limited tax credit for certain startup small businesses. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to use certain federal agency extramural budget funds to award grants to institutions of higher education for initiatives to improve commercialization and transfer of technology. Requires the head of any federal or independent regulatory agency, before issuing a notice of rule making in connection with the issuance of a proposed major rule, to complete a review that, among other things, analyzes the problem that the rule intends to address, and identifies and analyzes the rule's expected impact on state, local, and tribal governments, as well as on the ability of new businesses to form and expand. Requires a cost-benefit analysis before rule issuance. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to regularly compile: (1) information from each of the states and the District of Columbia on laws that affect the formation and growth of new businesses, and (2) quantitative and qualitative information on U.S. businesses that are not more than one year old.</summary>
</bill>
