<bill session="112" type="s" number="1625" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Postal Reform Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Commission on Postal Reorganization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">CPR Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to restore the financial solvency of the United States Postal Service and to ensure the efficient and affordable nationwide delivery of mail.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2011-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-09-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5947"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2309"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2011--Introduced.
Postal Reform Act of 2011 - Amends provisions of federal law relating to the United States Postal Service (USPS) with respect to its reorganization, financial management, and workforce. Commission on Postal Reorganization Act or CPR Act - Establishes the Commission on Postal Reorganization. Requires USPS to develop and submit to the Commission a plan for the closure or consolidation of postal retail facilities, mail processing facilities, and USPS area and district offices. Requires the Commission to transmit such plan to Congress, publish it in the Federal Register, and hold public hearings. Requires USPS to implement the closure or consolidation of postal facilities and offices recommended by the Commission unless Congress enacts a joint resolution disapproving the recommendations of the Commission. Authorizes USPS to provide for five-day delivery of mail and make adjustments in the rural delivery of mail. Establishes the Postal Service Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority. Requires the USPS to submit to the Authority a financial plan and budget for each year that USPS is in a control period (a period which begins when the USPS has been in default with respect to any loans, bonds, notes, or other form of borrowing for at least 30 days). Grants certain powers to the Authority to act on behalf of USPS during a control period, including the power to renegotiate contracts and to submit recommendations to ensure compliance with USPS financial plans and budgets. Provides for the termination of a control period, subject to congressional approval. Revises provisions relating to the USPS workforce, including regarding: (1) redetermination of pay comparability, (2) limitations on contributions to life and health insurance plains, and (3) collective bargaining rights. Terminates the postal rate preference for national and state political committees. Reduces rate preferences for advertising by nonprofit organizations. Sets forth provisions for contracting of postal services, including the establishment of an advocate for competition. Requires the Postal Regulatory Commission and USPS to make noncompetitive purchase requests for any noncompetitive award of a postal contract publicly available on the Internet. Sets forth procedures for identifying and resolving ethical issues in the contracting process.</summary>
</bill>
