<bill session="111" type="h" number="1706" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Consumer Access to Generic Drugs Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit brand name drug companies from compensating generic drug companies to delay the entry of a generic drug into the market, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400350"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412285" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2009-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2009-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 16 - 10 .</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2009--Introduced.
Protecting Consumer Access to Generic Drugs Act of 2009 - Prohibits, as an unfair and deceptive act or practice and an unfair method of competition in or affecting interstate commerce, any person from being a party to any agreement resolving or settling a patent infringement claim in which: (1) an abbreviated new drug (generic) application filer receives anything of value; and (2) such filer agrees not to research, develop, manufacture, market or sell the generic drug. Excludes a resolution or settlement that includes no more than: (1) the right to market the generic drug before the expiration of the patent or other exclusivity period; or (2) the waiver of a patent infringement claim for damages. Authorizes the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to exempt agreements in furtherance of market competition and for the benefit of consumers. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide that a generic drug applicant forfeits market exclusivity for failing to market the drug 75 days after: (1) a court dismisses a declaratory judgment action for lack of subject matter jurisdiction; or (2) the applicant files with the Secretary of Health and Human Services a covenant that the patent owner will not sue the applicant for patent infringement. Deems an applicant to have forfeited market exclusivity if the applicant enters into an agreement that violates this Act. Amends the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 to revise reporting requirements related to agreements between a generic drug applicant and a brand name drug company to include: (1) a description of the subject matter of other agreements between the parties; and (2) a certification that the materials filed represent the complete, final, and exclusive agreement between the parties.</summary>
</bill>
