<bill session="113" type="s" number="274" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CHEW Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Children Eating Well Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen nutrition education for elementary school and secondary school students to promote healthy eating choices through developmentally appropriate lessons and activities integrated into the school day.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2013--Introduced.
Children Eating Well Act or the CHEW Act - Requires each local educational agency (LEA) participating in the school improvement program under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to: (1) develop and implement healthy eating and nutrition education programs in its schools, and (2) periodically monitor schools' efforts to improve students' healthy eating and nutritive knowledge. Requires LEAs to consult multiple viewpoints in developing and implementing the healthy eating and nutrition education programs. Includes professional development for teachers, school staff, and food service workers as part of those programs. Directs the Secretary of Education, Secretary of Agriculture, and Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish an inter-agency task force to review nutrition education curricula and recommend effective nutrition education programs for elementary and secondary schools.</summary>
</bill>
