<bill session="109" type="s" number="1170" updated="2013-07-19T20:23:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-16">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fort Stanton-Snowy River National Cave Conservation Area Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Fort Stanton-Snowy River National Cave Conservation Area Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Fort Stanton-Snowy River Cave National Conservation Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Fort Stanton-Snowy River National Cave Conservation Area.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An act to establish the Fort Stanton-Snowy River Cave National Conservation Area.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300036"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6106-6107"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6107" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-157.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-09-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-163.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-10-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="264">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 264.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13058-13059" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S13058-13059" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2005-11-16" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16T20:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Caves"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2593"/>
    <amendment number="s2594"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/16/2005--Passed Senate amended.
Fort Stanton-Snowy River National Cave Conservation Area Act - Establishes the Fort Stanton-Snowy River National Cave Conservation Area in Lincoln county, New Mexico, to protect, conserve, and enhance the unique and nationally important historic, cultural, scientific, archaeological, natural, and educational subterranean cave resources of the Fort Stanton-Snowy River cave system. Specifies that the Conservation Area include the area within the boundaries depicted on the map entitled "Fort Stanton-Snowy River Cave National Conservation Area" and dated November 2005. Instructs the Secretary to only allow uses of the Conservation Area that are consistent with the protection of the cave resources. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, in administering the Conservation Area, to include providing for management of the surface area of the Conservation Area in accordance with the Fort Stanton Area of Critical Environmental Concern Final Activity Plan dated March, 2001, or any amendments to such plan, consistent with this Act. Withdraws all federal surface and subsurface land within the Conservation Area and all lands and interests in the surface and subsurface land that are acquired by the United States for inclusion in the Conservation Area from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the general land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) operation under the mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws. Directs the Secretary to develop a plan for the long-term management of the Conservation Area. Requires that such plan provide for a cooperative agreement with Lincoln county to address the historical involvement of the local community in the interpretation and protection of the resources of such Area. Provides that the establishment of the Conservation Area shall not: (1) create a protective perimeter or buffer zone around the Conservation Area; or (2) preclude uses or activities outside the Conservation Area that are permitted under other applicable laws, even if the uses or activities are prohibited within such Area. Authorizes the Secretary to establish facilities for: (1) the conduct of scientific research; and (2) the interpretation of the historical, cultural, scientific, archaeological, natural, and educational resources of the Conservation Area. Prohibits anything in this Act from constituting an express or implied reservation of any water right. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
