<bill session="110" type="s" number="2568" updated="2013-07-19T22:43:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to prohibit preleasing, leasing, and related activities in the Chukchi and Beaufort Sea Planning Areas unless certain conditions are met.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2008-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-01-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5058"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5588"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6057"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Bears"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/29/2008--Introduced.
Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to prohibit the Secretary of the Interior from offering for leasing, preleasing, and specified related activity within the Chukchi or Beaufort Sea Planning Area until the following prerequisites have been met: (1) the Secretary enters into an agreement with the National Research Council to report to Congress upon specified missing information regarding the Chukchi and Beaufort Sea marine and coastal ecosystems, and the adequacy of environmental, public health and cultural studies; (2) the polar bear is listed as an endangered species or a threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973, and critical habitat is designated for it, or the Secretary publishes a determination that such a listing is not warranted; (3) the Secretary determines that specified deployable mechanical oil spill response technologies exist; and (4) the Secretary determines that oil and gas exploration and development can be conducted in the Planning Areas without risk of substantial adverse impact to wildlife or wildlife habitat and subsistence, and that risk avoidance measures are identified and their efficacy established.</summary>
</bill>
