<bill session="112" type="s" number="1559" updated="2013-07-20T02:29:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">San Juan Islands National Conservation Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the San Juan Islands National Conservation Area in the San Juan Islands, Washington, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2011-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-09-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5626"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5626-5627" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-642.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2912"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2011--Introduced.
San Juan Islands National Conservation Area Act - Establishes the San Juan Islands National Conservation Area in the state of Washington. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to develop a comprehensive plan for the long-term management of the Conservation Area. Requires the Secretary to manage the Conservation Area in a manner to conserve, protect, and enhance the resources of such area. Authorizes the Secretary to prescribe measures for the control of nonnative invasive plants and noxious weeds within the Conservation Area. Instructs the Secretary, in consultation with Indian tribes, to ensure the protection of religious and cultural sites within the Conservation Area and to provide access to them by tribal members for traditional cultural and customary uses. Directs the Secretary to establish the San Juan Islands National Conservation Area Advisory Council to advise the Secretary on the preparation and implementation of the management plan.</summary>
</bill>
