<bill session="111" type="hr" number="417" updated="2013-07-19T22:59:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that President Barack Obama should immediately work to reverse damaging and illegal actions taken by the Bush/Cheney Administration and collaborate with Congress to proactively prevent any further abuses of executive branch power.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400013"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, Foreign Affairs, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Presidential administrations"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2009--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that President Obama should : (1) reaffirm the nation's commitment to the rule of law, checks and balances, the legislative process, and the Bill of Rights; (2) support Congress's right of access to information to perform its legislative and oversight functions; (3) cooperate with congressional investigations into the lack of prosecutions under the War Crimes Act and the Federal Anti-Torture Act despite allegations of serious violations; (4) reaffirm U.S. treaty obligations under the Geneva Conventions and ensure that all individuals held by the United States have access to petition for a writ of habeas corpus; (5) ensure that all suspected terrorists at Guantanamo are immediately tried in fair judicial proceedings; (6) engage the international community to ensure the release of innocent detainees; (7) require independent judicial review of claims of state secrets privilege by executive branch officials; (8) reaffirm that the Office of the Vice President is part of the executive branch; (9) collaborate with Congress to investigate presidential pardons and articulate comprehensive standards to guide future pardons; and (10) commit to providing all signing statements for publication, affirm Congress' right to participate in court proceedings regarding the constitutionality of such statements, and ensure that Congress can obtain testimony from administration officials claiming executive privilege to justify such statements. Calls on the President to cooperate with congressional efforts to: (1) establish an independent investigation to hold all Bush Administration officials accountable for any crimes; (2) ensure that the disclosure of the identity of any U.S. intelligence agent could give rise to criminal liability; (3) restore faith in the American justice system by investigating and censuring officials for misconduct in office; (4) repeal the redefinition of grave abuses of Common Article 3 of the Geneva Conventions included in the Military Commissions Act of 2006; (5) tighten standards for when a declaration of war is required for military action; (6) strengthen federal perjury laws to prohibit the issuance of false statements, concealment, or false documentation in any matter related to a presidential request for a declaration of war; (7) codify strong anti-torture language and approve uniform standards for interrogation of individuals in U.S. custody; and (8) prohibit the transfer of persons by the U.S. for detention, interrogation, or trial to a country that supports torture, cruel, or degrading treatment in the detention or interrogation of individuals.</summary>
</bill>
