<bill session="113" type="s" number="317" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Inspector General of the Environmental Protection Agency to include certain assessments in reports.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412320"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412556" joined="2013-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S713-714"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2013--Introduced.
Requires the Inspector General of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), in reports required to be submitted not later than April 30 and October 31 of each calendar year, to include an assessment of the agency's compliance during the applicable period with the following: (1) portions of Executive Orders 12866 and 13563 concerning reporting of regulatory and deregulatory agendas, as well as successor Executive Orders establishing such requirements; (2) regulatory flexibility agenda requirements; (3) portions of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 that require agencies to publish statements describing and assessing state, local, and tribal compliance costs before promulgating any general notice of proposed rulemaking; and (4) requirements of Executive Order 13132 concerning certifications by agencies upon transmittals of draft final regulations of adherence to federalism principles.</summary>
</bill>
