<bill session="112" type="s" number="1273" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Direct Care Job Quality Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act with regard to certain exemptions under that Act for direct care workers and to improve the systems for the collection and reporting of data relating to the direct care workforce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2012-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2341"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2011--Introduced.
Direct Care Job Quality Improvement Act of 2011 - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 with respect to the exemption from minimum wage and maximum hour requirements of any employee employed on a casual basis in domestic service employment to provide companionship services for individuals who because of age or infirmity are unable to care for themselves. Extends the same exemption to a casual employee in domestic service employment to provide companionship services for disabled individuals unable to care for themselves. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop a direct care workforce monitoring program. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require a state Medicaid plan to require the state to report annually to the Secretary on the adequacy of its direct care workforce to provide long-term care (LTC) services. Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to require the National Health Care Workforce Commission, as a high priority, to review, analyze, and report annually to Congress and the Health Resources and Services Administration on the current and projected direct care workforce supply and demand. Directs the Secretary to award grants to states, Indian tribes, and tribal organizations to develop data collection and monitoring systems to assess the adequacy of a state's or tribe's direct care workforce to meet current and future demand for LTC services. Directs the Secretary to award competitive three-year grants to states and other eligible entities to improve the recruitment, retention, and education of direct care workers.</summary>
</bill>
