<bill session="109" type="s" number="3128" updated="2013-07-19T20:40:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Uniformity for Food Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for uniform food safety warning notification requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300004" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2006-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="2006-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2006-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2006-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2006-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300069" joined="2006-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2006-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2006-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2006-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-741.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4167"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2006--Introduced.
National Uniformity for Food Act of 2006 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FFDCA) to prohibit any state or political subdivision from establishing or continuing in effect for any food in interstate commerce any requirement that is not identical to specified FFDCA provisions (that would result in materially different requirements), including those related to adulterated foods, unsafe food additives, new animal drugs, and warnings concerning food safety. Allows state enforcement of identical provisions unless the Secretary of Health and Human Services has determined that such state provisions should not be enforced. Allows a state to petition for an exemption or to establish a national standard regarding any requirement under FFDCA or the Fair Packaging and Labeling Act relating to food regulation. Allows the Secretary to provide such an exemption if the requirement: (1) protects an important public interest that would otherwise be unprotected; (2) would not cause any food to be in violation of any federal law; and (3) would not unduly burden interstate commerce. Allows a state to establish a requirement that would otherwise violate FFDCA provisions relating to national uniform nutrition labeling or this Act if the requirement is needed to address an imminent hazard to health that is likely to result in serious adverse health consequences and if other requirements are met. Declares that this Act does not preempt certain state and local laws relating to labeling or a consumer advisory relating to food sanitation imposed on a food establishment or recommended by the Secretary. Declares that the Act takes effect only if the Secretary certifies to Congress that implementation will pose no additional risk to the public health or safety from terrorist acts relating to the food supply.</summary>
</bill>
