<bill session="111" type="h" number="5310" updated="2013-07-20T00:00:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Brownfields Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to reauthorize and improve the Brownfields revitalization program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2010-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2010--Introduced.
Brownfields Reauthorization Act of 2010 - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to: (1) include nonprofit organizations within the meaning of "eligible entity" for purposes of brownfields revitalization funding; (2) increase the limit on the maximum amount of a grant for brownfields remediation for each site; (3) authorize the President to transfer any duties under the brownfield remediation grant program to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA); (4) revise eligibility requirements for brownfields revitalization funding; (5) require the Administrator to establish a program to provide multi-purpose grants to inventory, characterize, assess, conduct planning related to, or remediate brownfield sites in an area; (6) require the Administrator to establish a program to make competitive grants to be used at brownfield sites for projects that reduce environmental impact, increase community livability, and encourage sustainability; (7) authorize the Administrator to assign EPA employees to entities servings small, disadvantaged, or rural communities to build local capacity for the remediation and revitalization of brownfield sites in such communities; (8) increase and extend funding for brownfields revitalization; (9) require at least 7.5% of such funding to be used to carry out projects that reduce environmental impact, increase community livability, and encourage sustainability; and (10) increase and extend funding for state response programs established under such Act.</summary>
</bill>
