<bill session="110" type="s" number="2112" updated="2013-07-19T22:38:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nurse-Managed Health Clinic Investment Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish the Nurse-Managed Health Clinic Investment program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2007-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2007--Introduced.
Nurse-Managed Health Clinic Investment Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants for the cost of operating nurse-managed health clinics that provide primary care for underserved or vulnerable populations and are associated with a school, college, or nursing department, federally qualified health center, or independent nonprofit health or social services agency.Requires a grant application to contain assurances that a clinic will: (1) provide all required comprehensive primary health services for a period of not to exceed two years (subject to a waiver); and (2) establish a community advisory committee to provide input into the clinic's decisionmaking process.Permits grant funds to be used for primary care and additional health services for the management of clinic programs, salaries, training, and the acquisition and leasing of buildings and equipment. Requires the amount of any grant to be determined by the Secretary considering the financial need of, and state, local, and other operational funding provided to, the clinic.Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a program through which the Secretary shall provide clinics technical and other assistance in meeting requirements of this Act; and (2) develop and implement a plan for evaluating clinics funded.</summary>
</bill>
