<bill session="112" type="h" number="6086" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HUNT Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hunt Unrestricted on National Treasures Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the heads of Federal public land management agencies to prepare reports on the availability of public access and egress to Federal public lands for hunting, fishing, and other recreational purposes, to amend the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to provide funding for recreational public access to Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412281"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2012-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2012-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-09">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-09">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2012--Introduced.
Hunt Unrestricted on National Treasures Act or the HUNT Act - Requires each head of a federal public land management agency (the National Park Service, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the U.S. Forest Service, and the Bureau of Land Management [BLM]), to annually make available to the public on its website a report that includes: (1) a list of the lands more than 640 acres in size under its jurisdiction on which the public is allowed to hunt, fish, or use such lands for other recreational purposes and to which there is no public access or egress or to which such access or egress to the lands' legal boundaries is significantly restricted; (2) a list of such lands that the agency head determines have significant potential for use for hunting, fishing, and other recreational purposes; and (3) a plan to provide such access and egress that is consistent with the travel management plan in effect. Requires each agency head to make available to the public on the agency's website, and thereafter revise, a list of roads or trails that provide the primary public access and egress to the legal boundaries of contiguous parcels of land equal to more than 640 acres in size under the agency's jurisdiction on which the public is allowed to hunt, fish, or use such lands for other recreational purposes. Amends the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to require allotment from the Land and Water Conservation Fund of an amount not less than 1.5 % of the moneys appropriated for projects that secure public access to federal land for hunting, fishing, and other recreational purposes through easements, rights-of-way, or fee title acquisitions from willing sellers.</summary>
</bill>
