<bill session="109" type="s" number="3820" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Broadband for Rural America Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to expand broadband access for rural Americans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8833-8836"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S8836-8839" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2006--Introduced.
Broadband for Rural America Act of 2006 - Establishes the Broadband Access Trust Fund. Establishes, in the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), the Office of Broadband Access to coordinate the use of all Fund resources as those resources relate to the expansion of broadband technology into rural or unserved areas. Deposits into the Fund appropriations and one percent of the proceeds of frequency band auctions. Amends provisions of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 relating to making or guaranteeing loans for broadband facilities and equipment in eligible rural communities to: (1) to extend the period for making or guaranteeing such loans; (2) modify the definition of "eligible rural community;" (3) remove provisions giving priority to communities in which residential broadband service is not available; and (4) modify loan eligibility criteria. Authorizes grants to provide broadband services. Requires the FCC to issue a final order in the matter of Unlicensed Operation in TV Broadcast Bands. Sets forth requirements for the order, including that it allow certified unlicensed devices to use certain non-licensed television broadcast channels in rural areas. Requires the FCC to initiate a proceeding to reconfigure its band plans: (1) for the upper 700 MHz band and the unauctioned portions of the lower 700 MHz band to designate up to 12 MHz of paired recovered analog spectrum; and (2) to include spectrum to be licensed for small geographic license areas. Establishes the Rural Broadband Access Task Force to study broadband deployment.</summary>
</bill>
