<bill session="112" type="h" number="3471" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Helping Individuals Return to Employment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HIRE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Labor to award grants for the employment of individuals in targeted communities to perform work for the benefit of such communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412254"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2011--Introduced.
Helping Individuals Return to Employment Act or HIRE Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to award competitive grants to eligible entities to hire unemployed individuals age 16 and older to perform a minimum of 20 hours per week of work to benefit certain communities, including activities such as public works, beautification, historic restoration, tutoring, and adult education. Restricts such grants to eligible entities located in or primarily serving in a community designated either as a renewal community, an empowerment zone, or a historically underutilized business zone (HUBZone), if the unemployment rate in the area is higher than 7% during the 3-month period preceding award of the grant. Requires that priority in the award of grants be given to individuals who have been unemployed for more than a year. Prescribes certain grant limitations.</summary>
</bill>
