<bill session="111" type="s" number="425" updated="2013-07-20T00:27:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Food Safety and Tracking Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for the establishment of a traceability system for food, to amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act, the Poultry Products Inspections Act, the Egg Products Inspection Act, and the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for improved public health and food safety through enhanced enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2236"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="815"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/2009--Introduced.
Food Safety and Tracking Improvement Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FFDCA) to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a traceability system for all stages of manufacturing, processing, packaging, and distribution of food through which the Secretary can retrieve the history, use, and location of each article of food shipped in interstate commerce. Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act, the Poultry Products Inspection Act, and the Egg Products Inspection Act to require a person (other than a household consumer) who has reason to believe that any meat, poultry, egg, or egg product handled by such person is adulterated or misbranded to notify the Secretary of Agriculture of the identity and location of the article. Directs the Secretary, upon finding that the article is adulterated or misbranded and there is a reasonable probability that human consumption would present a threat to public health, to: (1) provide all appropriate persons an opportunity to cease distribution of the article, make appropriate notifications, and recall the article; and (2) require an immediate cessation of distribution if voluntary action is not taken. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) refuse to provide, or to withdraw, inspections of an establishment for willful or repeated violations of the respective Act; (2) deny or suspend inspection in the public interest to protect the health or welfare of consumers or to ensure the effective performance of an official duty under the respective Act; and (3) assess civil penalties for violations. Amends the FFDCA to require a person (other than a household consumer or other individual who is an intended consumer) who has reason to believe that an article of food introduced into interstate commerce is adulterated or misbranded in a manner that, if consumed, may result in illness or injury to notify the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Directs the Secretary, upon finding that to be the case, to: (1) provide all appropriate persons an opportunity to cease distribution of such article, make appropriate notifications, and recall the article; and (2) require an immediate cessation of distribution if voluntary action is not taken. Allows the Secretary to assess penalties for prohibited acts.</summary>
</bill>
