<bill session="111" type="h" number="4516" updated="2013-07-19T23:53:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financial Services Industry Stability Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide stability in the financial services industry by promoting transparency, simplicity, fairness, accountability, and equal access in the market for consumer financial products or services and ensuring that no financial company becomes too big to fail, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H336"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2010--Introduced.
Financial Services Industry Stability Act of 2010 - Directs the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to review all programs administered by the Board and utilize them in furtherance of this Act. Directs each federal department, agency, and independent establishment in the executive branch to utilize its authority to: (1) implement programs to promote transparency, simplicity, fairness, accountability, and equal access in the market for consumer financial products or services; and (2) take necessary steps to ensure that no financial company is able to pose a systemic risk to the health of the U.S. economy by becoming too large to fail. Requires the Board Chairperson to define the terms "systemic risk" and "too large to fail" and enumerate procedures that specify when and how the Chairperson and the head of any other federal department, agency, or independent executive branch establishment shall: (1) cause financial companies that are determined to be too large to fail to restructure in size and scope of operations so as not to pose a systemic risk to the health of the U.S. economy; and (2) impose increased capital reserve requirements upon any financial company which has been ordered to restructure. Requires the Chairperson to: (1) define criteria for causing the restructuring of financial companies; and (2) establish a fund composed of annual levies on financial companies to finance restructurings.</summary>
</bill>
