<bill session="112" type="s" number="1875" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reform and Reauthorization Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412495"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2867"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2011--Introduced.
United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reform and Reauthorization Act of 2011 - Amends the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 to prohibit: (1) an individual from serving more than two consecutive terms as a member of the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom, (2) each member serving on the date of enactment of this Act from being reappointed to more than one additional consecutive term, (3) a member attending less than 75% of the meetings during one of such member's terms from being eligible for reappointment, and (4) a member from being eligible to be elected as Chair of the Commission for a second, consecutive term. Establishes staggered office terms by modifying certain terms of office conditions for members appointed to serve from May 15, 2012, through May 14, 2014. Requires, for purposes of providing remedies and procedures to address alleged violations of rights and protections that pertain to various specified antidiscrimination laws, that all employees of the Commission be treated as employees whose pay is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate or the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives and that the Commission be treated as an employing office of the Senate or House. Increases to $250,000 the maximum amount the Commission may expend in any fiscal year to procure temporary or intermittent services contracts for the conduct of certain activities necessary to Commission functions. Extends the Commission's termination date to September 30, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
