<bill session="112" type="h" number="4094" updated="2013-07-20T01:45:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preserving Access to Cape Hatteras National Seashore Recreational Area Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Preserving Access to Cape Hatteras National Seashore Recreational Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize pedestrian and motorized vehicular access in Cape Hatteras National Seashore Recreational Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400209"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2012-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2012-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412484" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2012-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-06-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 18.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-06-15T11:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-526, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-15T11:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-06-15T11:53:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="374">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 374.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2578"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2372"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Seashores and lakeshores"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2012--Reported to House without amendment, Part I.
Preserving Access to Cape Hatteras National Seashore Recreational Area Act - Requires the Cape Hatteras National Seashore in North Carolina to be managed in accordance with the Interim Protected Species Management Strategy/Environmental Assessment issued by the National Park Service (NPS) on June 13, 2007, for the Cape Hatteras National Seashore Recreational Area until the Secretary of the Interior issues a new final rule that meets the additional restrictions specified below. Bars the imposition of any additional restrictions on pedestrian or motorized vehicular access to any part of the Recreation Area for species protection beyond those in the Interim Management Strategy, other than as specifically authorized pursuant to this Act. Allows the Secretary if, based on peer-reviewed science and after public comment, it is determined that additional restrictions on access to a part of the Recreation Area are necessary to protect endangered species, to only restrict pedestrian and vehicular access for recreational activities for the shortest possible time and on the smallest possible portions of such area. Prohibits the final rule titled "Special Regulations, Areas of the National Park System, Cape Hatteras National Seashore--Off-Road Vehicle Management" from having any force or effect. Invalidates the April 30, 2008, consent decree filed in the United States District Court for the Eastern District of North Carolina regarding off-road vehicle use at the Seashore.</summary>
</bill>
