<bill session="111" type="s" number="2895" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oregon Eastside Forests Restoration, Old Growth Protection, and Jobs Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to restore forest landscapes, protect old growth forests, and manage national forests in the eastside forests of the State of Oregon, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13385-13386"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-565.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-04">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-682.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/17/2009--Introduced.
Oregon Eastside Forests Restoration, Old Growth Protection, and Jobs Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, through the Chief of the Forest Service, to manage certain forest, stream, grassland, wetland, alpine, and other land and water located in a covered area of Oregon to: (1) conserve and restore forest and watershed health; (2) reduce the risk of uncharacteristic natural disturbances from fire, insects, and disease; (3) allow for characteristic natural disturbances; and (4) increase the resistance and resiliency of the covered lands to uncharacteristic events. Requires the Secretary to implement ecological restoration projects in the covered area in order to achieve such goals. Requires the delineation of each riparian habitat conservation area in a watershed for all permanently flowing streams, lakes, wetlands, seeps, springs, and intermittent streams. Requires the conservation and restoration of aquatic and riparian resources within National Forest land in the covered area. Establishes the Eastside Forest Scientific and Technical Advisory Panel to periodically advise the Secretary, collaborative groups, and the public about the development and implementation of forest and watershed management goals, the Eastside Landscape Forest Restoration Assessment, and ecological restoration projects. Requires the Restoration Assessment to include a 10-year restoration plan for the comprehensive ecological restoration of forest and watershed health in the covered area. Subjects ecological restoration projects carried out under this Act to an environmental analysis. Provides for expedited judicial review of an action challenging a project developed under this Act. Provides for: (1) the establishment of regional biomass projects; (2) stewardship contracting projects to carry out ecological restoration projects; and (3) the selection of a Deputy Regional Forester to serve as the principal agency contact for implementation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
