<bill session="111" type="h" number="4481" updated="2013-07-19T23:52:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Deficit Reduction Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reduce the Federal budget deficit in a responsible manner.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412290"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-20">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-20">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1613"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/20/2010--Introduced.
Deficit Reduction Act of 2009 - Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) to redefine, for FY2011-FY2019, discretionary spending limits (spending caps) for new budget authority and outlays to mean the baseline, minus any emergency spending, for the preceding fiscal year as adjusted for inflation and (as under current law) as adjusted in strict conformance with such Act. Revises sequestration requirements for enforcement of discretionary spending limits. Requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to conduct such a sequestration to eliminate a budget year breach. Eliminates specific formula requirements for adjustments to discretionary spending limits for: (1) highways; (2) continuing disability reviews for the Social Security Administration (SSA); (3) allowances for the International Monetary Fund (IMF); (4) specified allowances for international arrearages; (5) the earned income tax credit (EITC) compliance initiative; (6) Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) adoption incentive payments; and (7) conservation. Prescribes an adjustment to discretionary spending limits for overseas contingency operations related to the global war on terrorism, including Iraq and Afghanistan. Redefines low-growth, for purposes of OMB's required low-growth notification to Congress, from less than zero to less than 1%. Extends Pay-As-You-Go requirements and enforcement mechanisms through FY2019. Establishes sequestration enforcement mechanisms to eliminate deficit limits for FY2012-FY2019. Specifies additional Social Security, veterans, Tier I Railroad Retirement benefits and other programs and activities exempt from a sequestration order as well as certain economic recovery programs. Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (CBA) to make it out of order in both chambers to consider any legislation causing the discretionary limits in the Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act to be exceeded.</summary>
</bill>
