<bill session="109" type="h" number="3283" updated="2013-07-19T19:33:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-27T16:45:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-07-27T16:45:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Trade Rights Enforcement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance resources to enforce United States trade rights.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400095" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400168" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400214" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400338" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400632" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2005-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6440-6452" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6440-6444" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3283.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26T11:29:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6464-6465" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="2005-07-26T13:33:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="421" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 240 - 186 (Roll no. 421).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26T13:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26T22:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 387 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3283 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution shall be considered as adopted. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 387 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 387.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6842-6858" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3283 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution shall be considered as adopted. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T14:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3283.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T16:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6855" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T16:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cardin moved to recommit with instructions to Ways and Means.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6855-6857" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6856" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T16:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cardin motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6855-6857" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T16:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 195 - 232 (Roll no. 436).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-07-27T16:45:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="437" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 255 - 168 (Roll no. 437).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6842-6848" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="387"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="387"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="1421"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1421"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Balance of payments"/>
    <term name="Biotechnology"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computer industry"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Corn"/>
    <term name="Cotton"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Currency devaluation"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy demand"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grain"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Patent infringement"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Product counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Rabbits"/>
    <term name="Raw materials"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Textile industry"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade fairs"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="U.S. International Trade Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h519"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/27/2005--Passed House without amendment.
United States Trade Rights Enforcement Act - (Sec. 2) Expresses the sense of Congress about making the countervailing duty law under the Tariff Act of 1930 applicable to actions by nonmarket economy countries, and the impact on the U.S. economy of the huge growth in trade with the People's Republic of China (PRC). (Sec. 3) Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to impose countervailing duties on certain merchandise from nonmarket economy countries. Revises the definition of countervailable subsidy regarding countervailing duty investigations to provide that with respect to the PRC, if the Secretary of Commerce encounters special difficulties in calculating the amount of subsidy benefits to be conferred, the Secretary may use methodologies for identifying and measuring such subsidy benefits which take into account the possibility that prevailing terms and conditions in China may not always be available as appropriate benchmarks. Requires the administering authority, when applying such methodologies, where practicable, to adjust such prevailing terms and conditions before considering the use of those prevailing outside China. Requires the Secretary of Commerce, in imposing countervailable duties and subsidies on a class or kind of merchandise of a nonmarket economy country, to ensure that: (1) no countervailable subsidy is double counted in an antidumping order on the same class or kind of merchandise of the country; and (2) the imposition of countervailable duties is consistent with U.S. international obligations. (Sec. 4) Suspends for three years the requirement that the administering authority direct the Customs Service to allow, at the option of the importer of such merchandise, the posting, until completion of the review, of a bond or security in lieu of a cash deposit for each entry of the subject merchandise (bonding privileges). Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to report to specified congressional committees: (1) recommendations on whether such suspension should be extended; and (2) assessments of the effectiveness of any administrative measures that have been implemented to address the difficulties giving rise to the suspension. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to report to specified congressional committees, with recommendations for additional action, on the major problems experienced in the collection of duties, including fraudulent activities intended to avoid their payment. (Sec. 5) Requires the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR) and, as appropriate, the Secretary of Commerce or the Secretary of Agriculture, to ensure that specified steps are taken by the PRC to ensure its compliance with its international trade obligations regarding: (1) intellectual property rights; (2) access for exports of U.S. goods, services, and agriculture; and (3) a required detailed accounting of its subsidies to the World Trade Organization (WTO) by the end of 2005. Requires the President to report biannually and, as appropriate, monthly to specified congressional committees a description of: (1) the specific steps taken by the PRC to meet such obligations; (2) an analysis of the extent to which PRC officials are attempting in good faith to meet them; and (3) the actions, if any, the President will take to obtain PRC compliance. Directs the President, if he determines that the PRC has not met each of its specified intellectual property obligations or made significant improvements in protection of intellectual property rights in accordance with its trade obligations, to assign resources necessary to collect evidence of such trade agreement violations for use in dispute settlement proceedings against the PRC in the WTO. (Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to report to specified congressional committees on: (1) the definition of currency manipulation; (2) actions of foreign countries that will be considered to be such; (3) how statutory provisions addressing it by U.S. trading partners contained in, and relating to, the Bretton Woods Agreements Act and the Exchange Rates and International Economic Policy Coordination Act of 1988 can be better clarified administratively to provide for improved and more predictable evaluation; and (4) the mechanism adopted by the PRC government to relate its currency to a basket of foreign currencies and the degree to which such application moves the currency closer to a market-based representation of its value. (Sec. 7) Authorizes appropriations for FY2006-FY2007 for the Office of the USTR. Expresses the sense of Congress that the enforcement of U.S. rights and of the obligations of U.S. trading partners under trade agreements has gained such significance that the Office of USTR should: (1) determine which of its current positions is most responsible for carrying out these important enforcement duties; and (2) assign that position, in addition to any other title, the title of Chief Enforcement Officer. (Sec. 8) Authorizes appropriations for FY2006-FY2007 for the U.S. International Trade Commission. Requires the Commission to study and report to specified congressional committees on trade and economic relations between the United States and the PRC, addressing the PRC's economic policies, including its exchange rate policy, the competitiveness of its industries, the composition and nature of its trade patterns, and other elements impacting U.S. trade account, industry, competitiveness, and employment. (Sec. 9) Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should: (1) strive to expand membership in the Agreement on Government Procurement of the WTO; (2) ensure that the PRC meets its WTO obligations; (3) seek a commitment from the PRC to maintain its suspension of the implementation of its law on government procurement, pending the conclusion of negotiations to accede to the Agreement; and (4) seek commitments from the PRC and other countries that are not yet members of the Agreement to implement the principles of openness, transparency, fair competition based on merit, nondiscrimination, and accountability in their government procurement as embodied in that Agreement. Urges the President to direct all appropriate U.S. officials to raise these concerns with appropriate PRC officials and other trading partners.</summary>
</bill>
