<bill session="113" type="h" number="2480" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nurse and Health Care Worker Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Labor to issue an occupational safety and health standard to reduce injuries to patients, nurses, and all other health care workers by establishing a safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention standard, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2013-10-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E963-964"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Musculoskeletal and skin diseases"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2013--Introduced.
Nurse and Health Care Worker Protection Act of 2013 - Requires the Secretary of Labor to promulgate an interim final standard on safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention to prevent musculoskeletal disorders for direct-care registered nurses and all other health care workers that requires the use of engineering and safety controls to handle patients through the use of mechanical technology and devices where feasible. Requires, however, the use of alternative controls and measures, including trained, designated lift teams, where such technology and devices are not feasible, in order to minimize the risk of injury to nurses and health care workers. Includes among the requirements of a final standard that health care employers: (1) develop and implement a safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention program; (2) train their workers on safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention; and (3) post a uniform notice that explains the standard, procedures to report patient handling-related injuries, and workers' rights under this Act. Requires the Secretary to conduct unscheduled inspections to ensure compliance with the standard. Amends title VXIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to apply the safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention standard to hospitals receiving Medicare funds.</summary>
</bill>
