<bill session="109" type="s" number="964" updated="2013-07-19T20:21:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Americans Outdoors Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide a conservation royalty from Outer Continental Shelf revenues to establish the Coastal Impact Assistance Program, to provide assistance to States under the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965, to ensure adequate funding for conserving and restoring wildlife, to assist local governments in improving local park and recreation systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300002"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2005-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4574-4579" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Demography"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2005--Introduced.
Americans Outdoors Act of 2005 - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) to require the transfer of qualified outer continental shelf revenues from the Treasury to specified programs. Rewrites coastal impact assistance program provisions to set forth new formulas for allocating amounts transferred for coastal impact assistance payments among producing States (coastal States within a specified distance from qualified Outer Continental Shelf oil and gas drilling leases) and among coastal political subdivisions. Amends the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 (LWCFA) to: (1) establish a new formula for apportioning outdoor conservation and recreation funds to the States (including U.S. territories and the District of Columbia); (2) make Indian tribes eligible for funds under a competitive grants program established by the Secretary of the Interior; and (3) require States to allocate a percentage of their annual apportionment to localities. Requires States seeking LWCFA funds to develop State action agendas. Amends the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act to establish a new formula for apportioning Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account funds to include apportionments to Indian tribes. Amends the Urban Park and Recreation Recovery Act of 1978 to: (1) include among that Act's purposes the development of new recreation areas and facilities; and (2) address the treatment of funds transferred under OCSLA.</summary>
</bill>
