<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1082" updated="2013-07-19T20:59:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-09T12:03:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-04-09T12:03:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing the plumbing industry and supporting the goals and ideals of "National Plumbing Industry Week".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2008-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T11:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Velazquez moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T11:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2092-2093" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T11:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1082.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-04-09T12:03:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2092" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Family enterprises"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Plumbing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Special weeks"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2008--Passed House without amendment.
Recognizes that small business plumbing contractors have benefited from the reduced regulatory burden provided as a result of passage of the Regulatory Flexibility Act of 1980 and the Small Business Regulatory Enforcement Fairness Act of 1996. Recognizes that the loan guarantee program under Section 7(a) of the Small Business Act administered by the Administrator of the Small Business Administration has provided access to capital for small business plumbing contractors. Recognizes that approximately 80% of plumbing contractors around the country are small, family owned and run companies. Recognizes these small firms account for a large percentage of our Nation's GDP, through sales, service, and repair. Recognizes how small businesses in the plumbing industry are the leader in developing, and utilizing new innovative technologies which help improve and maintain the infrastructure our Nation depends on. Supports the goals and ideals of National Plumbing Industry Week (April 27-May 3, 2008).</summary>
</bill>
