<bill session="113" type="h" number="776" updated="2013-11-02T06:25:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Security in Bonding Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to revise requirements related to assets pledged by a surety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412454"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412563" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412558" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412560" joined="2013-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-15">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2013--Introduced.
Security in Bonding Act of 2013 - Revises requirements related to assets pledged by a surety. Declares that if another applicable law or regulation permits the acceptance of a bond from a surety that is not subject to specified federal law, and is based on a pledge of assets by the surety, the assets pledged by such surety shall: (1) consist of eligible obligations given as security instead of surety bonds; and (2) be submitted to the government official required to approve or accept the bond, who shall deposit the assets with a depository (the Secretary of the Treasury, a federal reserve bank, or a depository designated by the Secretary). Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 with respect to any Small Business Administration (SBA) guarantee or agreement to indemnify a surety under the Small Business Investment Program against loss from a breach of the terms of a bid bond, payment bond, performance bond, or ancillary bonds, by a principal on any total work order or contract amount at the time of bond execution that does not exceed $ 6.5 million, as adjusted for inflation. Increases from 70% to 90% of the loss incurred and paid by a surety authorized to issue bonds subject to SBA guarantee the SBA's maximum obligation to pay the surety under the guarantee or agreement to indemnify.</summary>
</bill>
