<bill session="109" type="s" number="3708" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of Education Appropriations Act, 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of Health and Human Services Appropriations Act, 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Department of Labor Appropriations Act, 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Education Appropriations Act, 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Health and Human Services Appropriations Act, 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Department of Labor Appropriations Act, 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">An original bill making appropriations for the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2007, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-01">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-286, pt. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-03">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-286, pt. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-286, pt. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Specter. With written report No. 109-287.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-07-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="526">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 526.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSAP18" subcommittee="Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3010"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5647"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Alternative medicine"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arthritis"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Biomedical engineering"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Black lung"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular diseases"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Citizenship education"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Committee for Purchase from People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporation for National and Community Service"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Deaf"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Digestive diseases"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in education"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug interactions"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Eye diseases"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service"/>
    <term name="Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Hearing disorders"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Imaging systems in medicine"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Impact aid"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical libraries"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare Payment Advisory Commission"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Muscular diseases"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="National Commission on Libraries and Information Science"/>
    <term name="National Council on Disability"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board"/>
    <term name="National Mediation Board"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Nervous system diseases"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Old age assistance"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Pension trust guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Public broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Radiation victims"/>
    <term name="Railroad retirement plans"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Skin diseases"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Stroke"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student housing"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2006--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2007 - Makes appropriations for the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and related agencies for FY2007. Title I: Department of Labor - Department of Labor Appropriations Act, 2007 - Makes appropriations for FY2007 to the Department of Labor for: (1) the Employment and Training Administration, including training and employment services; (2) community service employment for older Americans; (3) federal unemployment benefits and allowances; (4) state unemployment insurance and employment service operations; (5) advances to the Unemployment Trust Fund and the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund; (6) employment and training program administration; (7) the Employee Benefits Security Administration; (8) the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation; (9) the Employment Standards Administration; (10) certain special benefits, including ones for disabled coal miners; (11) the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Fund; (12) the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund; (13) the Occupational Safety and Health Administration; (14) the Mine Safety and Health Administration; (15) the Bureau of Labor Statistics; (16) the Office of Disability Employment Policy; (17) departmental management; (18) the Office of Jobs Corps; (19) veterans employment and training; and (20) the Office of Inspector General. Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, funds and transfers of funds appropriated under this title. (Sec. 101) Prohibits use of Job Corps funds under this title to pay individual compensation at a rate in excess of Executive Level I. (Sec. 102) Allows not more than 1% of discretionary funds for the current fiscal year for the Department of Labor in this Act to be transferred between a program, project, or activity. Prohibits any increase of any such program, project, or activity by more than 3% by any such transfer. (Sec. 103) Prohibits funds under this Act from being obligated or expended to procure goods mined, produced, manufactured, or harvested or services rendered, in whole or in part, by forced or indentured child labor in industries and host countries already identified by the Department of Labor prior to enactment of this Act, in accordance with a specified executive order. (Sec. 104) Authorizes appropriations to the Denali Commission to conduct job training of the local workforce where Denali Commission projects will be constructed. (Sec. 105) Directs the Department of Labor to submit its FY2008 congressional budget to the Committees on Appropriations in the format and level of detail used by the Department of Education in its FY2007 congressional budget. (Sec. 106) Directs the Secretary of Labor to submit to the Committees on Appropriations not later than July 1, 2007, an operating plan that outlines the planned allocation by major project and activity of FY2007 funds made available for the provision of employment and training services. (Sec. 107) Directs the Secretary of Labor, after September 30, 2006, to issue a monthly transit subsidy to Department of Labor employees in the National Capital Region in an amount not to exceed $105. (Sec. 108) Prohibits recipients of employment and training funds from using such funds to pay the salary and bonuses of an individual at a rate in excess of Executive Level II, with an exception for specified vendors. Title II: Department of Health and Human Services - Department of Health and Human Services Appropriations Act, 2007 - Makes appropriations for FY2007 to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) for: (1) the Health Resources and Services Administration; (2) the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC); (3) the National Institutes of Health (NIH); (4) the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration; (5) the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality; (6) the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services; (7) the Administration for Children and Families; (8) the Administration on Aging; and (9) the Office of the Secretary. (Sec. 211) Prohibits the use of funds : (1) for voluntary family planning projects unless the applicant certifies that it encourages family participation in the decision of minors to seek family planning services and that it provides counseling to minors on how to resist attempts to coerce minors into engaging in sexual activities; and (2) to carry out the Medicare Advantage program if the Secretary of HHS denies participation in such program to an otherwise eligible entity because it will not provide, pay for, provide coverage of, or provide referrals for abortions. (Sec. 213) Prohibits any provider of voluntary planning services under the Public Health Service Act from being exempt from any state law requiring notifications or the reporting of child abuse, child molestation, sexual abuse, rape, or incest. (Sec. 214) Prohibits the use of funds to withhold substance abuse funding from a state that fails to enforce state laws prohibiting the sale of tobacco products to individuals under the age of 18 if such state certifies to the Secretary that it will commit additional funds to ensure compliance with such laws. Sets forth requirements for states that miss the retailer compliance rate goal established by the Secretary. (Sec. 215) Allows the Secretary to exercise certain authority in order to carry out international health activities during FY2007. (Sec. 223) Authorizes the Secretary to award a grant to the Delta Health Alliance to solicit and fund proposals from local governments, hospitals, health care clinics, academic institutions, and rural public health-related entities and organizations for research development, educational programs, health care services, job training, and planning, construction, and equipment of public health-related facilities in the Mississippi Delta region. (Sec. 224) Allows the Secretary to waive certain allocation and matching requirements for HIV health services for Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, and Texas and eligible metropolitan areas in those states. Title III: Department of Education - Department of Education Appropriations Act, 2007 - Makes appropriations for FY2007 to the Department of Education for: (1) education for the disadvantaged; (2) impact aid; (3) school improvement programs; (4) Indian education; (5) innovation and improvement activities; (6) safe schools and citizenship education; (7) English language acquisition and language enhancement; (8) special education; (9) rehabilitation services and disability research; (10) special institutions for persons with disabilities, including the American Printing House for the Blind, the National Technical Institute for the Deaf, the Kendall Demonstration Elementary School, the Model Secondary School for the Deaf, and Gallaudet University; (11) vocational and adult education; (12) certain student financial assistance programs, as well as federal administrative expenses for such programs (setting a maximum individual Pell Grant amount); (13) specified higher education programs; (14) Howard University; (15) the college housing and academic facilities loans program account; (16) the historically Black college and university capital financing program account; (17) the Institute of Education Sciences; (18) departmental management and program administration; (19) the Office for Civil Rights; and (20) the Office of the Inspector General. Sets the maximum individual Pell Grant amount at $4,050 during award year 2007-2008. Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, funds appropriated under this title. (Sec. 301) Prohibits the use of funds to transport teachers or students in order to: (1) overcome racial imbalance in any school; or (2) carry out a racial desegregation plan. (Sec. 302) Prohibits the use of funds to require, directly or indirectly, the transportation of any student to a school other than the school nearest the student's home, except, for a student requiring special education, to the school offering such special education, in order to comply with title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964. Declares that such a prohibited indirect requirement of student transportation includes the transportation of students to carry out a plan involving the reorganization of the grade structure of schools, the pairing of schools, or the clustering of schools, or any combination of grade restructuring, pairing or clustering. Exempts the establishment of magnet schools from such prohibition. (Sec. 303) Prohibits the use of funds to prevent the implementation of programs of voluntary prayer and meditation in public schools. (Sec. 304) Allows the transfer between appropriations of not more than 1% of discretionary funds for the current fiscal year for the Department of Education in this Act. Prohibits any increase of any such appropriation by more than 3% by any such transfer. (Sec. 305) Considers five specified Illinois school districts to be local educational agencies (LEAs) for purposes of the Impact Aid program, which compensates Leas for the financial burden of federal activities affecting their school districts. Considers federally connected students in such districts to be attending schools in one such district, North Chicago Community Unit School District 187, for the purpose of making that district eligible for Impact Aid. Conditions such treatment on the agreement of the five school districts to apportion such assistance equitably among all five of them, and to use it only for direct educational services. Title IV: Related Agencies - Makes appropriations for FY2007, including to: (1) the Committee for Purchase From People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled; (2) the Corporation for National and Community Service, for domestic volunteer service programs and operating expenses, administrative expenses and salaries, and the Office of Inspector General; (3) the Corporation for Public Broadcasting; (4) the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service; (5) the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission; (6) the Institute of Museum and Library Services; (7) the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission; (8) the National Commission on Libraries and Information Science; (9) the National Council on Disability; (10) the National Labor Relations Board; (11) the National Mediation Board; (12) the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission; (13) the Railroad Retirement Board for the dual benefits payments account, federal payments to the railroad retirement accounts, administration, and the Office of Inspector General; and (14) the Social Security Administration for payments to the Social Security trust funds, the Supplemental Security Income (SSI) Program, administrative expenses, and the Office of Inspector General. Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, funds appropriated under this title. Title V: General Provisions - (Sec. 505) Prohibits the use of funds to carry out any program of distributing sterile needles or syringes for the hypodermic injection of any illegal drug. (Sec. 507) Prohibits the use of funds for: (1) health benefit coverage that includes coverage of abortion unless the pregnancy is the result of an act of rape or incest or a woman suffers from a physical disorder, injury, or illness that would place her in danger of death unless an abortion is performed; (2) a federal agency or program or a state or local government that discriminates against a health care entity because it does not provide, pay for, provide coverage of, or refer for abortions; or (3) the creation of human embryos for research purposes or research in which human embryos are destroyed, discarded, or knowingly subjected to risk of injury or death greater than that allowed for research on fetuses in utero under federal law. (Sec. 510) Prohibits the use of funds: (1) for any activity that promotes the legalization of any schedule I controlled substance unless there is significant medical evidence of a therapeutic advantage to using such drug or substance or there are federally sponsored clinical trials being conducted to determine therapeutic advantage; (2) to promulgate or adopt any final standard providing for a unique health identifier for an individual until legislation is enacted specifically approving the standard; (3) to enter into an arrangement with a nongovernmental financial institution to serve as disbursing agent for benefits payable under the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974; or (4) to disseminate scientific information that is deliberately false or misleading.</summary>
</bill>
