<bill session="112" type="s" number="3357" updated="2013-07-20T02:45:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">San Juan County Federal Land Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal land in San Juan County, New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2012-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2012--Introduced.
San Juan County Federal Land Conveyance Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, on request of the plaintiffs in the case Blancett v. United States Department of the Interior, et al., in the U.S. District Court for the District of New Mexico, to convey to them by sale all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to any portion of approximately 19 acres of certain federal land in San Juan County, New Mexico (including any improvements or appurtenances). Requires deposit of the proceeds of any such conveyance in a special account, to be available for the acquisition of land from willing sellers in the state for resource protection that is consistent with the purposes for which the Bald Eagle Area of Critical Environmental Concern was established.</summary>
</bill>
