<bill session="113" type="h" number="2858" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildland Firefighters Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To implement reforms to the Federal land management agency fire programs in order to address the complexities of 21st century wildfires in a more cost-effective and efficient manner.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400101"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2013--Introduced.
Wildland Firefighters Protection Act -Requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), in cooperation with federal land management agencies, to develop a separate and district occupational series for firefighters who are engaged in the prevention, control, suppression, and management of wildfires (wildland firefighters) that more accurately reflects the variety of duties performed by such firefighters. Establishes a three-year compensation pilot program for full- and part-time wildland firefighters to provide such firefighters with enhanced compensation (portal-to-portal compensation) while assigned to an emergency incident. Provides for the treatment of differential pay for hazardous duty as part of the base pay of wildland firefighters for retirement purposes.</summary>
</bill>
