<bill session="113" type="h" number="2853" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hospital Price Transparency and Disclosure Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the public disclosure of charges for certain hospital and ambulatory surgical center treatment episodes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400630"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412568" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2013--Introduced.
Hospital Price Transparency and Disclosure Act of 2013 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require a hospital or ambulatory surgical center to report to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) regarding: (1) the frequency of occurrence of certain treatment episodes for the most frequently treated conditions or diseases in each setting, (2) the total number of treatment episodes for which care was furnished by the hospital or center, and (3) the insured and uninsured average charge by the hospital or center for such treatment episode.&#160; Requires the Secretary to post promptly on the HHS website: (1) such information in a manner that promotes charge comparisons among hospitals and among ambulatory surgical centers, and (2) an appropriate link to other consumer quality information maintained on such site or a site maintained by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services. Requires a hospital and an ambulatory surgical center to post prominently at each admission site a notice of the availability of such data. Authorizes civil penalties for violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
