<bill session="110" type="h" number="2766" updated="2013-07-19T21:28:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Dairy Equity Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish regional dairy marketing areas to stabilize the price of milk and support the income of dairy producers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2007-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG29" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices"/>
    <term name="Agricultural production"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Economic research"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Food consumption"/>
    <term name="Food prices"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Marketing orders"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Price regulation"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2007--Introduced.
National Dairy Equity Act of 2007 - Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to give producers in a state participating in the national dairy market loss payment program 60 days to decide whether to continue participating in such program or to participate in the program established under this Act. Establishes the following five regional dairy marketing areas: (1) Northeast region - Northeast Dairy Marketing Area (Connecticut, Delaware, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, and Vermont); (2) Southern region - Southern Dairy Marketing Area (Alabama, Arkansas, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, Louisiana, Mississippi, Missouri, North Carolina, Oklahoma, South Carolina, Texas, Tennessee, Virginia, and West Virginia); (3) Midwest region - Midwest Dairy Marketing Area (Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Michigan, Minnesota, Nebraska, North Dakota, Ohio, South Dakota, and Wisconsin); (4) Intermountain region - Intermountain Dairy Marketing Area (Arizona, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, New Mexico, Utah, and Wyoming) and (5) Pacific region - Pacific Dairy Marketing Area (Alaska, California, Hawaii, Oregon, and Washington). Administers each region by a Regional Dairy Board. Sets forth Board powers, including authority to establish: (1) over-order price (a price higher than the marketing order or non-marketing area price) for Class I milk; (2) equalization pools to equalize over-order prices to producers throughout a regulated area; and (3) processor administrative fees. Requires producer referendum to approve of a proposed over-order price establishment, amendment, or termination. States that each covered processor that purchases Class I milk during a month that will be sold in the regulated area of a Region shall pay to the Secretary an amount equal to the product of the over-order premium and the quantity of purchased Class I milk. Establishes in the Treasury the National Dairy Producers Fund. Directs the Secretary to make monthly payments from the Fund to the Boards which shall make payments to eligible producers of all milk classes. Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to extend the national dairy market loss payment program.</summary>
</bill>
