<bill session="111" type="h" number="5265" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Combat Illegal Immigration Through Employment Verification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To continue to prohibit the hiring, recruitment, or referral of unauthorized aliens, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400042"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2010--Introduced.
Combat Illegal Immigration Through Employment Verification Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to make employment of unauthorized aliens unlawful. Sets forth provisions respecting: (1) employer document verification requirements; and (2) employment authorization and/or identity documents. Sets forth employment eligibility verification system (EEVS) provisions. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) provide for the disclosure of certain taxpayer identity information to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to assist in immigration enforcement; and (2) increase specified penalties for employer failure to provide correct information returns. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish within the Criminal Investigation office of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) a unit to investigate tax-related violations related to the employment of unauthorized aliens. Sets forth IRS and Social Security Administration (SSA) immigration-related enforcement provisions. Provides for increases in worksite enforcement and immigration fraud detection personnel.</summary>
</bill>
