<bill session="113" type="h" number="2549" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BEST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Biliteracy Education Seal and Teaching Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To award grants to States to establish a Seal of Biliteracy program to recognize high-level student proficiency in speaking, reading, and writing in both English and a second language.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412516"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412517" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412530" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="408211" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Biliteracy Education Seal and Teaching Act or the BEST Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to award renewable two-year grants to states to establish or improve a Seal of Biliteracy program to recognize student proficiency in speaking, reading, and writing in both English and a second language. Requires students who wish to participate in such a program to submit an application to their state that includes assurances that they: (1) will receive a secondary school diploma or its equivalent in the year they apply; and (2) have met the state's criteria for demonstrating proficiency in speaking, reading, and writing in both English and a second language. Requires states to provide participating students who demonstrate that proficiency: (1) a permanent seal or other marker on their secondary school diploma or its equivalent, and (2) documentation of that proficiency on their official academic transcript. Allows students who gain proficiency in a second language outside of school to participate in such programs. Prohibits states from charging students an application fee.</summary>
</bill>
