<bill session="111" type="h" number="3824" updated="2013-07-19T23:46:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Expanded Health Insurance Options Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To allow States to establish interstate compacts for the purpose of expanding health insurance options.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400099"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2009-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2009-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/15/2009--Introduced.
Expanded Health Insurance Options Act of 2009 - Authorizes states to enter into arrangements to form interstate compacts under which health insurance issuers would offer coverage meeting the requirements of this Act under a unified regulatory structure governing the issuance, renewal, rating, mandated benefits, and similar items of coverage. Requires each compact to ensure that individuals who are insured in a participating state are able to access an independent external appeals process to review decisions made by health insurance issuers relating to coverage. Makes a participating state in which an insurance issuer is licensed responsible for the enforcement of applicable laws, regulations, agreements, and orders governing health insurance issuers and coverage. Authorizes a participating state in which a covered individual resides to require a health insurance issuer to pay premiums and taxes, submit to an examination of financial condition, and comply with state laws regarding fraud and abuse and unfair claims practices.</summary>
</bill>
