<bill session="112" type="s" number="1807" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Research and Development Coordination Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974 to provide for the prioritization, coordination, and streamlining of energy research, development, and demonstration programs to meet current and future energy needs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7136"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7136-7137" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-188.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/2011--Introduced.
Energy Research and Development Coordination Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974 to direct the Secretary of Energy to submit to Congress, along with the President's annual budget proposal, a comprehensive plan for federal energy research, development, and demonstration programs based on the most recent Quadrennial Energy Review. Requires the plan to be designed to solve problems in energy supply, transmission, and use (including associated environmental problems) in the immediate and short-term, medium-term, and long-term. Directs the Secretary to submit to Congress, along with the annual budget proposal of the Department of Energy (DOE), a detailed description of an energy research, development, and demonstration program to implement the aspects of the comprehensive plan appropriate to the DOE. Establishes a National Energy Research Coordination Council within the DOE to coordinate the development and funding of energy research, development, and demonstration activities for all energy program agencies. Requires the Chairpersons of the Council to establish a consolidated budget proposal each fiscal year to implement the comprehensive plan for federal energy research, development, and demonstration programs. Requires the physical location of the Council to be separate and distinct from DOE headquarters.</summary>
</bill>
