<bill session="110" type="s" number="896" updated="2013-07-19T22:28:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Physician Shortage Elimination Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act and the Social Security Act to increase the number of primary care physicians and medical residents serving health professional shortage areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3204-3206"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="410"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2007--Introduced.
Physician Shortage Elimination Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations for FY2008-FY2012 to: (1) carry out the National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program and Loan Repayment Program to assure an adequate supply of physicians and other health professionals to provide primary health services; (2) assist schools in supporting programs of excellence in health professionals education for underrepresented minority individuals; and (3) assist individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to undertake education to enter a health profession. Allows the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to community health centers to: (1) establish new or alternative-campus accredited medical residency training programs affiliated with a hospital or other health care facility; or (2) fund new residency positions within existing accredited medical residency training programs at the centers and their affiliated partners. Requires the Secretary to give preference to funding medical residency training programs focusing on primary health care. Allows the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to make grants to community health centers to: (1) increase the number of medical service providers associated with such centers; and (2) increase primary health care capabilities through the construction, expansion, or renovation of facilities. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to recipients of financial assistance for area health education center programs to improve the effectiveness of such programs. Amends title XVIII (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to make changes to the direct and indirect graduate medical education provisions regarding costs for the training program for purposes of counting the number of residents in a non-hospital setting. Sets forth requirements for a medical residency training program to be considered an accredited training program with an integrated rural track.</summary>
</bill>
