<bill session="110" type="s" number="2281" updated="2013-07-19T22:40:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Thunder Bay National Marine Sanctuary and Underwater Preserve Boundary Modification Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Thunder Bay National Marine Sanctuary and Underwater Preserve Boundary Modification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to expand the boundaries of the Thunder Bay National Marine Sanctuary and Underwater Preserve and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13686-13687"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-06">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation Senate Subcommittee on Oceans, Atmosphere, Fisheries, and Coast Guard. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-1164.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Inouye without amendment. With written report No. 110-511.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1094">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1094.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSCM22" subcommittee="Oceans, Atmosphere, Fisheries, and Coast Guard" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="6204"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Thunder Bay National Marine Sanctuary and Underwater Preserve Boundary Modification Act - Expands, notwithstanding any provision of law or regulation, the boundaries of the Thunder Bay National Marine Sanctuary and Underwater Preserve in Lake Huron, located off the northeast coast of Michigan's Lower Peninsula. Requires that the expanded area be managed as part of the National Marine Sanctuary System. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to certify that any license, permit, approval, other authorization, or right to conduct a prohibited activity (made pursuant to specified regulations) that exists on enactment of this Act shall apply to such an activity conducted within the area added by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
