<bill session="112" type="s" number="966" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bone Health Promotion and Research Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for osteoporosis and related bone disease education, research, and surveillance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Musculoskeletal and skin diseases"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2011--Introduced.
Bone Health Promotion and Research Act of 2011 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop and implement a National Bone Health Program under which: (1) the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) may conduct, support, and promote the coordination of research, investigations, demonstrations, training, and studies relating to the control, prevention, and surveillance of osteoporosis and related bone diseases; (2) the Secretary may coordinate and carry out national education and outreach activities to support, develop, and implement education initiatives and outreach strategies appropriate for osteoporosis and related bone diseases; and (3) the Secretary may award grants to states and Indian tribes for comprehensive osteoporosis and related bone disease control and prevention programs. Requires the Director of CDC to establish the Osteoporosis and Related Bone Disease Advisory Committee to advise the Secretary and the Assistant Secretary for Health on activities addressing such diseases. Directs the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to expand and intensify NIH research programs for osteoporosis and related bone diseases, including by awarding planning grants or contracts for the establishment or enhancement of research programs for such diseases. Authorizes the Director of CDC to award grants or enter into cooperative agreements for the collection, analysis, and reporting of data on such diseases.</summary>
</bill>
