<bill session="111" type="s" number="3181" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect the rights of consumers to diagnose, service, maintain, and repair their motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2010-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="S2127"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2057"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2010--Introduced.
Motor Vehicle Owners Right to Repair Act of 2010 - Requires the manufacturer of a motor vehicle sold, leased, or otherwise introduced into commerce in the United States to provide to the owner of the motor vehicle and the service provider of the motor vehicle, using reasonable business means and on a non-discriminatory basis, all information and tools needed to diagnose, service, maintain, or repair the motor vehicle. Provides for enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). Permits civil actions by: (1) states on behalf of the state's residents; and (2) consumers and service providers. Provides for the protection of trade secrets, except that no information may be withheld by a manufacturer on the ground that it is a trade secret if that information is provided (directly or indirectly) to authorized dealers or service providers.</summary>
</bill>
