<bill session="113" type="h" number="1487" updated="2013-11-02T06:31:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improved Health Care at Lower Cost Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles XVIII and XI of the Social Security Act to establish an exception from the physician self-referral prohibition and a safe harbor from Federal antikickback and other sanctions for incentive payments made by hospitals to physicians under certain incentive payment programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2013--Introduced.
Improved Health Care at Lower Cost Act of 2013 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) and XI of the Social Security Act with respect to the prohibition against certain (potential financial conflict-of-interest) physician referrals. Excepts from the physician self-referral prohibition any monetary incentive payments made by hospitals to physicians under certain incentive payment programs designed to align incentives among hospitals and physicians (through techniques such as product standardization, the substitution of lower cost products, and care coordination initiatives that encourage medically appropriate decreases in length of stay) to improve efficiency and decrease costs while maintaining or improving quality. Exempts such monetary incentive payments (creates a safe harbor for them) from federal criminal antikickback and other sanctions.</summary>
</bill>
