<bill session="110" type="s" number="2033" updated="2013-07-19T22:38:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cell Phone Consumer Empowerment Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for greater disclosure to, and empowerment of, consumers who have entered into a contract for cellular telephone service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412249" joined="2008-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-17">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 110-1175.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2007--Introduced.
Cell Phone Consumer Empowerment Act of 2007 - Requires that a wireless telephone service provider disclose, in a plain and conspicuous way, contract information regarding terms, charges, minutes, taxes and surcharges, and E-911 service in any publication of the contract, before a consumer enters into the contract, and in advertising. Requires wireless service bills to be clearly organized and use plain language, have taxes and fees in a separate section, and itemize roaming charges. Requires each provider to make available a map showing the wireless telephone service area of the provider and the wireless telephone service area of the provider in each state. Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to monitor the quality of wireless telephone service provided in the United States by requiring semiannual reports of wireless service providers. Requires that early termination fees be prorated over the term of a wireless subscriber's contract in a way that reasonably links the fee to recovery of the cost of the device or other legitimate business expenses. Regulates service contract extensions, cancellation penalties, and changes in rates, terms, or conditions. Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to allow a member of the uniformed services to terminate a cellular phone service contract in specified circumstances involving service of at least 90 days. Preempts inconsistent state laws.</summary>
</bill>
