<bill session="109" type="s" number="3870" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Iran Human Rights Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to hold the current regime in Iran accountable for its human rights record and to support a transition to democracy in Iran.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300013"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Opposition (Political science)"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations delegations"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2006--Introduced.
Iran Human Rights Act of 2006 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) there is a direct relationship between the state of freedom and democracy within Iran and the efforts of the Iranian regime to acquire nuclear weapons and the long-term success of the global war on terror; and (2) it is essential that the issue of human rights violations in Iran should remain a top U.S. foreign policy priority independent of efforts to address the nuclear threat in Iran. Directs the President to appoint a special envoy for human rights in Iran within the Department of State to coordinate efforts to improve respect for the fundamental human rights of the people of Iran and work with organizations committed to promoting democracy in Iran. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the U.S. government should explore the possibility of a regional human rights dialogue with Iran; (2) the United Nations has a significant role to play in improving human rights in Iran; and (3) the commitment to human rights and democracy of an Iranian national who has applied for a U.S. entry visa should be considered when determining visa eligibility. Authorizes the President to provide financial and political assistance to eligible foreign and domestic individuals, organizations, and entities that support human rights and the promotion of democracy in Iran and that are opposed to the non-democratic government of Iran. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) U.S. nonhumanitarian assistance to Iran should be contingent on substantial human rights progress and transition to democracy; and (2) U.S. humanitarian assistance to any department, agency, or entity of the government of Iran should be delivered, distributed, and monitored according to internationally recognized humanitarian standards, be provided on a needs basis, and beneficiaries should be informed of the assistance's source. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) communicating democratic ideals to the people of Iran is essential to fostering change in that country; and (2) U.S. public broadcasting into Iran has in the past been intentionally undermined by foreign governments. Sets forth new requirements for Radio Farda and Voice of American Persian Service, including prohibiting the employment of persons by such services who have worked within the previous ten years for the Iranian Information Ministry or any official news agency of the government of Iran, including the Islamic Republic News Agency. Authorizes the special envoy to award grants to eligible entities for broadcasting programs and activities to promote democratic transition in Iran. Authorizes the President to impose diplomatic and economic sanctions on foreign governments or entities that assist the government of Iran in blocking the free transmission of U.S. government radio and television broadcasts into Iran.</summary>
</bill>
