<bill session="109" type="s" number="1061" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pathways for All Students to Succeed Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for secondary school reform, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-05-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="108">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 108.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8371"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="921"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Paraprofessional school personnel"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/2005--Introduced.
Pathways for All Students to Succeed Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to establish a program that will provide grants to State educational agencies (SEAs), and direct grants or subgrants through SEAs to eligible local educational agencies (LEAs), to establish literacy and mathematics skills programs to improve overall reading, writing, and mathematics performance among students in middle school and secondary school. Requires LEAs receiving a literary or mathematics subgrant to hire literacy or mathematics coaches (at least one such coach for every 20 teachers) to work with classroom teachers to carry out specified related activities. Authorizes the Secretary to establish a program of grants to SEAs and, through them, subgrants to LEAs that: (1) enables a secondary school receiving assistance under title I of the Elementary and Secondary Act of 1965 (ESEA) to hire a sufficient number of academic counselors (at least one for 150 students) to develop personal six-year plans defining career and education goals for each student at the school, including those with limited English proficiency; (2) involves parents in the development and implementation of such plans; and (3) provides academic counselors and staff at the schools receiving grants under this Act the opportunity to coordinate with other programs and services, including those supported by Federal funds, to ensure that students have access to the resources and services necessary to fulfill their personal plans. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to SEAs and, through them, subgrants to LEAs to promote school improvement and student achievement, through certain programs and activities, in schools identified as needing improvement under specified provisions of ESEA as amended by the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001. Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive grants to SEAs to develop or increase the capacity of data systems for assessment and accountability purposes, including collection of graduation rates.</summary>
</bill>
