<bill session="111" type="h" number="4829" updated="2013-07-19T23:56:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Next Generation 9-1-1 Preservation Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to enhance and promote the Nation's public safety and citizen activated emergency response capabilities through the use of 9-1-1 services, to further upgrade public safety answering point capabilities and related functions in receiving 9-1-1 calls, and to support in the construction and operation of a ubiquitous and reliable citizen activated system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400124"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412298" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2010-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E362"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications, Technology, and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications, Technology, and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3115"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2010--Introduced.
Next Generation 9-1-1 Preservation Act of 2010 - Revises provisions of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to provide for matching grants (with a federal share of up to 80%) to eligible entities for: (1) the implementation and operation of E-911 services, migration to an IP-enabled emergency network, and adoption and operation of Next Generation 9-1-1 services and applications; (2) the implementation of IP-enabled emergency services and applications enabled by Next Generation 9-1-1 services, including the establishment of IP backbone networks and the application layer software infrastructure needed to interconnect the multitude of emergency response organizations; and (3) training in 9-1-1 services of public safety personnel, including call-takers, first responders, and other individuals and organizations who are part of the emergency response chain. Defines "9-1-1 services" as service including both E-911 services and Next Generation 9-1-1 services. Defines "Next Generation 9-1-1 services" to mean an IP-based system comprised of hardware, software, data, and operational policies and procedures that: (1) provides standardized interfaces from emergency call and message services to support emergency communications; (2) processes all types of emergency calls, including voice, data, and multimedia information; (3) acquires and integrates additional emergency call data useful to call routing and handling; (4) delivers the emergency calls, messages, and data to the appropriate public safety answering point and other appropriate emergency entities; (5) supports data or video communications needs for coordinated incident response and management; or (6) provides broadband service to public safety answering points or other first responder entities. Requires a report to Congress from: (1) the Administrator of General Services (GSA) identifying the 9-1-1 capabilities of the multi-line telephone system in use by all federal agencies in all federal buildings and properties; and (2) the Comptroller General (GAO) concerning state and local use of 9-1-1 service charges.</summary>
</bill>
