<bill session="112" type="sr" number="239" updated="2013-07-20T02:12:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution acknowledging the contributions and sacrifices of the young men who served as colonists on behalf of the United States in the Federal occupation of the islands of Howland, Baker, Jarvis, Canton, and Enderbury from 1935 through 1942, facilitating the United States claim of jurisdiction over such islands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2011-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4913-4914" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social sciences and history"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2011--Introduced.
Acknowledges: (1) the accomplishments and sacrifices of the Hui Panala 'au colonists on the islands of Howland, Baker, Jarvis, Canton, and Enderbury from 1935 through 1942; and (2) the local, national, and international significance of the seven-year colonization of such islands by the United States, which resulted in the United States extending sovereignty into the Equatorial Pacific. Recognizes and commends the accomplishments, sacrifices, and contributions of more than 130 young men, the majority of whom were Native Hawaiian, who participated in the Equatorial Pacific colonization project. Extends condolences to families on such islands&#160;who lost loved ones in the service of the United States and apologizes for the lack of compensation afforded to those families.</summary>
</bill>
