<bill session="109" type="s" number="2619" updated="2013-07-19T20:36:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hope Housing Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Federal Emergency Management Agency to provide relief to the victims of Hurricane Katrina and Hurricane Rita by placing manufactured homes in flood plains, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4874"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2343"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Floodplains"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Mobile homes"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/2006--Introduced.
Hope Housing Act of 2006 - Requires the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to place a manufactured home purchased by FEMA between August 1, 2005, and this Act's enactment date in a floodway or costal high hazard area or in a flood plain (without elevating such home up to the base flood level or without complying with specified decision-making processes and mitigation requirements) to house an individual displaced by Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita, upon request from or on behalf of such individual, provided the Director has received an evacuation plan from the state or local government officials for the area of placement. Bars civil actions against the federal government for damages related to the flooding of a home that is the subject of such placement. Requires the Director to provide any person provided such a home with written notice of the potential risks associated with such placement and such limitations on liability.</summary>
</bill>
