<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1608" updated="2013-07-19T23:10:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Condemning the detainment of a South Korea fishing ship by North Korea and the continued provocation by the North Korean military.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412387"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/10/2010--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that North Korea should: (1) release the 7-member crew of the Daesung 55; (2) stop any hostile rhetoric and activity towards the Republic of Korea and engage in mutual dialogue to enhance inter-Korean relations; (3) return to the Six-Party diplomatic process and commit to the complete dismantlement of its nuclear programs; and (4) comply with U.N. Security Council Resolutions 1718 and 1874. Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) the United States remains committed to the promotion of inter-Korean dialogue and cooperation; and (2) the strategic importance of the U.S-Republic of Korea alliance in promoting peace and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula and in Northeast Asia should be recognized. Condemns North Korea for the detainment of the Daesung 55 and hostile activity towards the Republic of Korea. Urges the international community to implement all Security Council resolutions pertaining to security on the Korean Peninsula.</summary>
</bill>
