<bill session="111" type="h" number="3950" updated="2013-07-19T23:47:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving Mathematics and Science Teacher Quality Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend provisions of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 relating to mathematics and science instruction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400119"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2009-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2009-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/2009--Introduced.
Improving Mathematics and Science Teacher Quality Act - Amends part B of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to authorize the inclusion of informal science education centers and business consortia as partners in the grant program to improve the quality of elementary and secondary school mathematics and science teachers. Requires the inclusion of teacher training departments of institutions of higher education in such partnerships, but removes state educational agencies as partnership participants. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award such grants to states for redistribution as competitive subgrants to eligible partnerships. (Currently, the Secretary awards grants directly to such partnerships if appropriations do not exceed a specified amount.) Requires that grant priority be given to eligible partnerships that carry out activities modeled after programs which are to be identified and disseminated by the Secretary, in consultation and coordination with the Director of the National Science Foundation, for replication on a more expansive basis. Removes the provision of financial incentives to recruit and retain teachers from authorized grant uses. Reauthorizes appropriations for the programs under parts A and B of title II of the ESEA through FY2015.</summary>
</bill>
