<bill session="110" type="s" number="2120" updated="2013-07-19T22:39:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Investment and Economic Development for the Americas Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Social Investment and Economic Development for the Americas Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the establishment of a Social Investment and Economic Development Fund for the Americas to provide assistance to reduce poverty, expand the middle class, and foster increased economic opportunity in the countries of the Western Hemisphere, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2007-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2008-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-06-24">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden without amendment. With written report No. 110-419.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-07-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="879">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 879.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3692"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Middle class"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Social Investment and Economic Development for the Americas Act of 2007 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to direct the President, through the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), to provide assistance to reduce poverty, expand the middle class, and foster increased economic opportunity in Western Hemisphere countries. Requires a 10% recipient country contribution. Establishes within USAID the Western Hemisphere Economic Investment and Development Advisory Committee which shall: (1) serve as a link among the U.S. government, nongovernmental organizations, the private sector, and other interested parties; and (2) review projects funded under this Act. Directs the President to report annually to Congress on programs and activities under this section. Authorizes FY2008-FY2017 appropriations. (Sec. 4) Amends the Inter-American Development Bank Act to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the United States Executive Director at the Bank to use U.S. influence to urge the Bank to establish a Social Investment and Economic Development Fund for the Americas to provide assistance to reduce poverty, expand the size of the middle class, and foster increased economic opportunity in Western Hemisphere countries. Authorizes FY2008-FY2017 appropriations for U.S. contributions to the Fund. (Sec. 5) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) amounts authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act should be used to help countries in Latin America and the Caribbean focus on improving indicators in the area of investing in people; (2) the Multilateral Investment Fund has been successful in promoting inclusive economic growth in Latin America and the Caribbean; (3) creating a public-private partnership working in coordination with the Fund will allow the Fund to expand economic opportunity to the people in the Western Hemisphere; and (4) amounts authorized to be appropriated pursuant to this Act for initiatives to reduce poverty, expand the middle class, and foster increased economic opportunity in the countries of the Western Hemisphere are in addition to amounts that would be allocated or projected in the President's budget request for Latin America and Caribbean. (Sec. 6) Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary for payment to the Inter-American Development Bank of arrears owed by the United States to the Fund.</summary>
</bill>
