<bill session="113" type="s" number="308" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting and Preserving Social Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title II of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make improvements in the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program, to provide for cash relief for years for which annual COLAs do not take effect under certain cash benefit programs, and to provide for Social Security benefit protection.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2013-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="649"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="567"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2013--Introduced.
Protecting and Preserving Social Security Act - Directs the Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) of the Department of Labor to prepare and publish for each calendar month a Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers (CPIEC) that indicates changes over time in consumption expenditures typical for individuals in the United States age 62 or older. Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to make the CPIEC the applicable Consumer Price Index (CPI) for computation of cost-of-lving increases in OASDI benefits for such individuals. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prescribe special rules for the determination of wages and self-employment income above the contribution and benefit base after 2013. Amends SSA title II to include surplus average indexed monthly earnings (AIME) in the determination of primary OASDI amounts.</summary>
</bill>
