<bill session="109" type="s" number="346" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Canadian Waste Import Ban Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit the importation of Canadian municipal solid waste without State consent.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1273-1274"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1274" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2109"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2005--Introduced.
Canadian Waste Import Ban Act of 2005 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit the importation into any State, and acceptance by a solid waste management facility, of Canadian municipal solid waste for disposal or incineration until the date on which the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) promulgates regulations to implement and enforce the Agreement Concerning the Transboundary Movement of Hazardous Waste between the United States and Canada. Authorizes State Governors to opt out of such prohibition pending promulgation of regulations if notice is submitted to the Administrator. Requires the Administrator to: (1) perform the functions of the Designated Authority of the United States described in the Agreement with respect to the importation and exportation of municipal solid waste; and (2) implement and enforce the Agreement. Directs the Administrator, when making importation decisions under the Agreement, to obtain the consent of each State and to consider the impact of importation on homeland security, public health, and the environment.</summary>
</bill>
