<bill session="109" type="s" number="1688" updated="2013-07-19T20:28:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hurricane Katrina Medicaid and SCHIP Relief Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide 100 percent Federal financial assistance under the Medicaid and State children's health insurance programs for States providing medical or child health assistance to survivors of Hurricane Katrina, to provide for an accommodation of the special needs of such survivors under the medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2005-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-12">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-09-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="210">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 210.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2005--Introduced.
Hurricane Katrina Medicaid and SCHIP Relief Act of 2005 - Provides that, during the Hurricane Katrina disaster period, any affected state may provide medical assistance, under a state Medicaid plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (SSA), without submitting a state plan amendment, to an adult Katrina Survivor, or to a child Katrina Survivor, under SSA title XXI (State Child Health Insurance Program) (SCHIP). Applies to the area of residence (or former residence) of a Katrina Survivor a federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) during the disaster period of 100% for Medicaid or SCHIP assistance provided, and costs directly attributable to all related administrative activities. Excludes the disaster relief period in computing the Medicare part B late enrollment penalty. Extends the initial enrollment period for prescription drug plans under Medicare part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) to at least May 15, 2007. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish premium and cost-sharing documentation rules for Katrina Survivors which take into account the loss and unavailability of documents due to Hurricane Katrina. Requires the Secretary to post on the Internet website for the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services a list of declared disaster areas, including parishes and counties, resulting from Hurricane Katrina. Designates the provisions of this Act as emergency requirements exempt from certain budget constraints under H.C. Res. 95 (109th Congress).</summary>
</bill>
