<bill session="109" type="hc" number="126" updated="2013-07-19T20:03:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-20T13:32:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-04-20T13:32:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the condolences and deepest sympathies of the Congress in the aftermath of the recent school shooting at Red Lake High School in Red Lake, Minnesota.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400316"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400214" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="2005-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-20T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Kline moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-20T11:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2167-2171" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-20T11:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 126.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-20T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-20T13:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2179" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-04-20T13:32:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="113" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 424 - 0 (Roll no. 113).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2167-2168" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-04-20T13:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Youth violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/20/2005--Passed House without amendment.
Declares that the House of Representatives condemns the tragic violence which occurred at Red Lake High School in Red Lake, Minnesota. Honors: (1) the heroism and memory of Derrick Brun, whose courageous actions and self-sacrifice no doubt saved the lives of others; (2) the heroism, courage, and memory of Daryl Lussier, Michelle Sigana, Neva Rogers, Dewayne Lewis, Chase Lussier, Alicia Spike, Thurlene Stillday, and Chanelle Rosebear, who lost their lives in this terrible tragedy; and (3) the heroism of Ryan Auginash, Steven Cobenais, Lance Crowe, Jeffrey May, and Cody Thunder, all of whom were wounded. Expresses hope for the rapid and complete recovery of these victims as well as support for their families, friends, and loved ones. Offers condolences to all of the families, friends, and loved ones of the victims. Applauds: (1) the Red Lake Band of Chippewa for their strength as a community in dealing with this tragedy; (2) the hard work, dedication, and professional conduct exhibited by local, State, and Federal law enforcement officials and the other community leaders and private citizens who offered their support and assistance; and (3) the hard work and dedication of the health care personnel. Commends them for providing tireless and sensitive care to the victims, the families, and the entire community. Encourages the American people to renew their commitment to and support for efforts to prevent school violence.</summary>
</bill>
