<bill session="113" type="h" number="1997" updated="2013-11-02T06:35:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Communities Achieving Sustainability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To allow investor participation in the loan rehabilitation program authorized under section 203(k) of the National Housing Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2013-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2013--Introduced.
Communities Achieving Sustainability Act - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), during a 2-year period, to insure and make commitments to insure rehabilitation loans (including advances during rehabilitation) made by financial institutions in order to assist in the rehabilitation of 1- to 4-family structures used primarily for residential purposes. Limits insurable rehabilitation loans to investors who do not intend to occupy the structure in question but obtain a rehabilitation loan for the purpose of appreciation or production of income with respect to the structure. Allows mortgage insurance for up to four such structures during a calendar year. Prohibits such mortgages from exceeding 90% of the appraised value of the structure in question. Requires the single premium payment due at the time of insurance to be increased by 10 basis points for any mortgage insured under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
