<bill session="113" type="s" number="1268" updated="2013-11-02T07:02:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to approve an agreement between the United States and the Republic of Palau.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5504-5505"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5505-5506" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Approves, with specified exceptions, the agreement and appendices signed by the United States and the Republic of Palau on September 3, 2010, in connection with the Compact of Free Association between the United States and Palau. Provides that, if Palau withdraws more than $5 million from the trust fund set up by the Compact in any of FY2011-FY2014, certain amounts will be withheld from Palau until it reimburses the fund for the total amounts withdrawn that exceeded $5 million in any of those fiscal years. Authorizes appropriations to: (1) subsidize postal services to Palau, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Federated States of Micronesia for FY2014-FY2024, and (2) carry out specified federal responsibilities under the Compact. Repeals specified offset requirements. Provides funding through FY2023 for: (1) the trust fund, and (2) economic assistance. Provides funding through FY2024 to create an Infrastructure Maintenance Fund for routine and periodic maintenance of major capital improvement projects. (Requires Palau to provide specified quarterly amounts for the Fund.) Provides funding through FY2016 for infrastructure projects. Revises passport requirements.</summary>
</bill>
