<bill session="109" type="s" number="2013" updated="2013-07-19T20:31:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-06">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States-Russia Polar Bear Conservation and Management Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">United States-Russia Polar Bear Conservation and Management Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">United States-Russia Polar Bear Conservation and Management Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to implement the Agreement on the Conservation and Management of the Alaska-Chukotka Polar Bear Population.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2005-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2005-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12851"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-02-27">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Stevens without amendment. With written report No. 109-217.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-02-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="365">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 365.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-06-06">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5511-5513" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-06-06" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5511-5513" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-06-06T20:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-06T20:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Bears"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Wild animal trade"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4190"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/6/2006--Passed Senate amended.
United States-Russia Polar Bear Conservation and Management Act of 2005 - Amends the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to make it unlawful for a person to take, import, export, possess, transport, or sell any polar bear or polar bear products in violation of the Agreement Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Russian Federation on the Conservation and Management of the Alaska-Chukotka Polar Bear Population (Agreement) or any annual taking limit or other restriction adopted by the U.S.-Russia Polar Bear Commission. Authorizes a government official to import a polar bear or a polar bear product for purposes of forensic testing or any other law enforcement purpose. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to administer and enforce the Agreement on behalf of the United States. Sets forth provisions: (1) requiring the seizure and forfeiture of polar bear and polar bear products that are, or are attempted to be, imported, exported, possessed, transported, or sold in violation of this Act; and (2) authorizing the detention and inspection of containers (including accompanying documents) for polar bear and polar bear products. Sets forth both civil and criminal penalties for violations of this Act. Considers violations under this Act to be transportation of wildlife for purposes of the prohibition on the import, export, or sale of fish, plants, and wildlife in violation of U.S., Indian, state, or foreign laws under the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981. Sets forth requirements for designation and appointment of U.S. members on the U.S.-Russia Polar Bear Commission. Requires the Secretary to take all appropriate actions to implement the decisions and determinations of the U.S.-Russia Polar Bear Commission. Authorizes the Secretary to share authority for the management of the taking of polar bears for subsistence purposes with the Alaska Nanuuq Commission. Authorizes appropriations for FY2006-FY2010 for the Secretary: (1) to carry out functions and responsibilities under this Act and the Agreement; (2) to carry out functions and responsibilities of the U.S. Section to the U.S.-Russia Polar Bear Commission; and (3) to carry out the Alaskan Cooperative Management Program.</summary>
</bill>
