<bill session="109" type="h" number="5632" updated="2013-07-19T19:54:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend Chapter 301 of title 49, United States Code, to establish a national tire fuel efficiency consumer information program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400373"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2006-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2006-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="2006-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2006-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-06-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-06-28T22:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 109-537.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-06-28T22:39:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="301">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 301.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Automobile tires"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2006--Reported to House amended.
Amends federal transportation law to direct the Secretary of Transportation to promulgate rules establishing a national motor vehicle tire fuel efficiency consumer information program to educate consumers about the effect of tires on automobile fuel efficiency. Requires information to be provided to consumers at the point of sale and other sites. Requires the Secretary to conduct periodic assessments of the rules to determine the utility of such rules to consumers, the level of cooperation by industry, and the contribution to national goals with respect to energy consumption. Prohibits the Secretary from requiring permanent labeling concerning tire fuel efficiency information on a tire. Permits a state to enforce a law or regulation on tire fuel efficiency consumer information in effect on January 1, 2006. Allows a state to adopt or enforce a tire fuel efficiency consumer information law or regulation that is enacted after January 1, 2006, only if it is identical to the federal requirement. Prohibits anything in this Act from being construed to preempt a state from regulating the fuel efficiency of tires not otherwise preempted under federal transportation law. Sets forth a civil penalty for persons who fail to comply with the consumer information program requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
