<bill session="111" type="s" number="3180" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit the use of funds for the termination of the Constellation Program of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2010-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="2010-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2010-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2010--Introduced.
Requires the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to comply with the provision under the heading Exploration in the Science Appropriations Act, 2010 (title III of division B of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010) relating to a prohibition on the use of funds for termination or elimination of any programs, projects, or activities of the architecture of NASA's Constellation Program. Bars use of the provisions of the Anti-Deficiency Act as a basis for terminating or eliminating any contracts, programs, projects, or activities of the Program. Requires the Comptroller General to submit a report on the Program to Congress. Requires such report to set forth a description and assessment of the contracts, programs, projects, and activities of the Program, if any, that are contrary to law or are experiencing waste, fraud, or abuse. Instructs the Administrator of NASA to ensure shuttle launch capability, including by not terminating any contractor support that will limit or impair the launching of, at a minimum, the payloads manifested for the shuttle.</summary>
</bill>
