<bill session="110" type="hc" number="184" updated="2013-07-19T22:10:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preserve our Salmon and Renewable Energy Resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress opposing removal of dams on the Columbia and Snake Rivers for fishery restoration purposes, supporting the renewable energy that the dams produce, and agreeing that their removal does not make sound environmental nor fiscal sense.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412201"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2007--Introduced.
Preserve our Salmon and Renewable Energy Resolution - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the dams on the Columbia and Snake Rivers are essential to commerce in the Pacific Northwest; (2) the survivability rate of salmon and steelhead has increased since the dams have been in place; (3) breaching the dams will not guarantee recovery of salmon and steelhead; (4) the environmental impact of removing the dams will be extremely damaging; (5) the dams on the Columbia and Snake Rivers provide renewable pollution free energy to the Pacific Northwest and helps backup California's power grid; and (6) two conclusive and exhaustive studies have already been completed which considered removing the dams or reservoir drawdown on the Snake River and concluded that we need to keep the dams.</summary>
</bill>
