<bill session="111" type="s" number="1142" updated="2013-07-20T00:33:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Informed Health Care Decision Making Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to inclusion of effectiveness information in drug and device labeling and advertising.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5848-5849"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5849-5850" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Informed Health Care Decision Making Act - Requires the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (FDA) to: (1) determine whether standardized, quantitative summaries of the benefits and risks of drugs in a tabular or drug facts box format would improve health care decisionmaking by clinicians, patients, and consumers; and (2) establish and update standards for comparative clinical effectiveness information in the labeling and advertising of drugs and devices under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act. Defines "comparative clinical effectiveness" as the clinical outcomes, effectiveness, safety, and clinical appropriateness of a drug or device in comparison to one or more drugs or devices approved to prevent, diagnose, or treat the same health condition in the same patient demographic subpopulation. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require information on comparative clinical effectiveness for drugs and devices in labeling and advertising.</summary>
</bill>
