<bill session="110" type="h" number="5146" updated="2013-07-19T21:48:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Invest in Energy Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to require the Secretary of Energy to acquire petroleum in quantities sufficient to fill the available capacity of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, subject to certain limitations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400229"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="2008-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-28">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Ocean energy resources"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/28/2008--Introduced.
Invest in Energy Security Act - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 governing petroleum acquisition for the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) to direct the Secretary of Energy to: (1) sell specified quantities of petroleum received under the royalty-in-kind program; and (2) suspend petroleum acquisition for the SPR under such program. Authorizes the Secretary to resume such acquisition upon notifying Congress that specified circumstances exist, and to suspend acquisition again if certain other circumstances arise. Establishes the Energy Independence and Security Fund to receive all proceeds from sales of SPR petroleum. Allocates amounts from such Fund for: (1) the Energy Transformation Acceleration Fund for university-based research projects and program direction expenses; (2) Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy account for rural wind energy systems; (3) solar energy technologies; (4) weatherization assistance for low-income housing; (5) ocean and wave energy, including hydrokinetic renewable energy; (6) technologies to improve the energy efficiency and reduce greenhouse gas emissions from industrial processes and from buildings; (7) improvements to the energy efficiency of transportation and electric power; (8) geothermal research and development managed by the National Renewable Energy Laboratory; (9) advanced geothermal drilling and resource characterization managed by National Energy Technology Laboratory; (10) carbon capture and storage; (11) Ultra-Deepwater and Unconventional Natural Gas and Other Petroleum Research Fund; (12) environmental research in support of small producers of domestic petroleum and natural gas, for regulatory analysis and for support for the stripper well consortium; and (13) the H-Prize Program of the Department of Energy.</summary>
</bill>
