<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1382" updated="2013-07-19T23:08:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-25T15:31:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-05-25T15:31:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing sympathy to the families of those killed by North Korea in the sinking of the Republic of Korea Ship Cheonan, and solidarity with the Republic of Korea in the aftermath of this tragic incident.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2010-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-24T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Faleomavaega moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-24T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3712-3714" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3712" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-24T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1382.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-24T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Faleomavaega objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-25T15:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3769-3770" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-05-25T15:31:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="296" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 411 - 3 (Roll no. 296).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/24/2010 H3712" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-05-25T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="sr" number="525"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2010--Passed House without amendment.
Expresses condolences to the families and loved ones of the sailors of the Republic of Korea Ship Cheonan who were killed in action on March 26, 2010. Stands in solidarity with the people and the government of the Republic of Korea in the aftermath of this incident. Reaffirms the commitment of the House of Representatives to the alliance between the Republic of Korea and the United States and to the Republic of Korea's security. Supports the findings and conclusions of the Republic of Korea's investigation report. Condemns North Korea for sinking the Cheonan. Calls for an apology by North Korea for its hostile acts and a commitment by North Korea never to violate the Korean War Armistice Agreement again. Urges the international community to: (1) support the Republic of Korea as it prepares to respond to the sinking of the Cheonan; and (2) implement all U.N. Security Council Resolutions pertaining to security on the Korean Peninsula, including Security Council Resolutions 1695, 1718, and 1874. Urges the United States, in coordination with its allies and partners, to take other appropriate actions in response to the sinking of the Cheonan and other hostile acts of North Korea.</summary>
</bill>
