<bill session="111" type="h" number="1385" updated="2013-07-19T23:24:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-03T14:16:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-06-03T14:16:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend Federal recognition to the Chickahominy Indian Tribe, the Chickahominy Indian Tribe-Eastern Division, the Upper Mattaponi Tribe, the Rappahannock Tribe, Inc., the Monacan Indian Nation, and the Nansemond Indian Tribe.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412304" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2009-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E594"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-18">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-05-12T16:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-104.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-05-12T16:36:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="50">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 50.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02T19:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 490 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 31 and H.R. 1385. General debate for both bills is limited to 1 hour equally divided and controlled. For H.R. 1385, specified amendments are in order. For each bill, the previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T13:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 490 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T13:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 490.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6101-6115" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T13:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 31 and H.R. 1385. General debate for both bills is limited to 1 hour equally divided and controlled. For H.R. 1385, specified amendments are in order. For each bill, the previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 490 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Tim Holden to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T13:12:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1385.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T13:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 490, an amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources, now printed in the bill, is considered as adopted as original text for the purpose of further amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T13:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 490, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Goodlatte #1 amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T14:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 490, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Goodlatte #2 amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T14:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1385.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T14:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6107-6113" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T14:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6115" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-06-03T14:16:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="111" type="hr" number="490"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1178"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1178"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h160"/>
    <amendment number="h161"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/3/2009--Passed House amended.
Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2009 - Extends federal recognition to the following Indian tribes (the tribes) in the Commonwealth of Virginia and establishes their relationship with the federal government as described below: (1) the Chickahominy Tribe; (2) the Chickahominy Indian Tribe--Eastern Division; (3) the Upper Mattaponi Tribe; (4) the Rappahannock Tribe, Inc.; (5) the Monacan Indian Nation; and (6) the Nansemond Indian Tribe. Makes the tribes and their members eligible for all services and benefits provided by the federal government to federally recognized Indian tribes. Establishes the service area of each tribe and requirements for each tribe regarding its membership roll, governing documents, and governing body. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, on request of any of the tribes, to take specified lands into trust for the benefit of that tribe, to be considered part of that tribe's reservation. Prohibits the tribes from conducting gaming activities. Prohibits this Act from affecting the hunting, fishing, trapping, gathering, and water rights of the tribes and their members. Requires Virginia to exercise jurisdiction over all criminal offenses committed, and all civil actions arising, on lands in Virginia owned by, or held in trust by the United States for, the tribes. Authorizes the Secretary to accept all or any portion of Virginia's jurisdiction over such offenses and actions on verification by the Secretary of a tribe's certification that the tribe possesses the capacity to reassume such jurisdiction. Prohibits the use of eminent domain to acquire lands in fee or in trust for an Indian tribe recognized under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
