<bill session="110" type="s" number="3326" updated="2013-07-19T22:50:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pathways to College Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Education to award grants to local education agencies to improve college access.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7289-7290"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7290-7291" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student enrollment"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2008--Introduced.
Pathways to College Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive five-year grants to local educational agencies that serve mostly high-need secondary schools for programs to increase the number of students from low-income families who attend college. Defines "high-need secondary schools" as those where at least one-half of the students are from low-income families.Requires grantees to use such funds to: (1) train teachers and counselors to provide students with advice concerning postsecondary education; (2) ensure that each student receives postsecondary information and planning assistance before the end of their first semester of secondary school; (3) inform students and parents regarding the benefits, expenses, and financing of higher education; and (4) ensure that their schools develop comprehensive, school-wide plans of action to strengthen their college-going culture.Directs the Secretary to provide technical assistance to grantees in calculating and analyzing their college-going rates and adopting best practices for elevating such rates.Requires grantees to measure externally verified school-wide college enrollment, track data that leads to increased college-going, and evaluate the success of their grant activities.</summary>
</bill>
