<bill session="110" type="h" number="6493" updated="2013-07-19T22:00:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-22T18:59:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-22T18:59:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Aviation Safety Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Aviation Safety Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to enhance aviation safety.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2008-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2008-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2008-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="E1460-1461"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22T14:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6744-6749" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22T14:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6493.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22T14:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Oberstar moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22T15:14:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22T18:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6793" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22T18:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-07-22T18:59:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="512" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 392 - 0 (Roll no. 512).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6744-6745" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3440"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Contractors"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Customer service"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2008--Passed House amended.
Aviation Safety Enhancement Act of 2008 - Establishes in the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) an Aviation Safety Whistleblower Investigation Office, with a Director appointed by the Secretary of Transportation, which shall receive and assess complaints and information relating to possible violations of aviation safety laws and regulations.Directs the FAA Administrator to modify the FAA customer service initiative, mission and vision, and other policy statements to: (1) remove any reference to air carriers or other entities regulated by the FAA as "customers"; (2) state that in regulating safety the only FAA customers are individuals traveling on aircraft; and (3) state that air carriers and other entities regulated by the FAA do not have the right to select the FAA employees who will inspect their operations.Prohibits any person holding an air carrier operating certificate from knowingly employing, or contracting with, an individual to act as an agent or representative of the certificate holder in any matter before the FAA if, in the preceding two-year period, the individual: (1) served as, or was responsible for oversight of, an FAA flight standards inspector; and (2) had responsibility to inspect, or oversee inspection of, the operations of the certificate holder.Prohibits any individual serving as a principal supervisory inspector of the FAA from being responsible for overseeing the operations of a single air carrier for a continuous period of more than five years. Authorizes appropriations.Directs the FAA Administrator to establish a process by which the FAA air transportation oversight system database is reviewed by a team of FAA employees on a monthly basis to ensure that: (1) any trends in regulatory compliance are identified; and (2) appropriate corrective actions are taken.</summary>
</bill>
