<bill session="111" type="h" number="3454" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Hospice Reform and Savings Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to reform payments and coverage for hospice care under the Medicare Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400392"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2009-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412230" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400368" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2009-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2009--Introduced.
Medicare Hospice Reform and Savings Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise payments and coverage for hospice care under the Medicare program. Prescribes conditions for recovery by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) of repayment demands from a hospice program for any accounting year during the four-year period ending on October 31, 2009. Requires the Secretary to issue evidence-based national coverage determinations for life expectancies covering at least each of those terminal medical diagnoses currently covered by Local Coverage Determinations promulgated by Medicare's fiscal intermediaries. Directs the Secretary to restore the application (and reduce the phase out) of the budget neutrality adjustment factor in the Medicare hospice wage index for FY2010-FY2013 in a manner that will result in an aggregate increase in Medicare expenditures equivalent to the aggregate reductions in expenditures resulting from the issuance of the national coverage determinations.</summary>
</bill>
