<bill session="111" type="s" number="886" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Catastrophe Obligation Guarantee Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a program to provide guarantees for debt issued by State catastrophe insurance programs to assist in the financial recovery from natural catastrophes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2010-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2009-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4729-4730"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4014"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2387"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/23/2009--Introduced.
Catastrophe Obligation Guarantee Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to guarantee holders of debt against loss of principal or interest, or both, on debt issued by eligible state programs designed to: (1) promote the availability of private capital to provide liquidity and capacity to state catastrophe insurance (specifically, residential property insurance and reinsurance) programs; and (2) expedite the payment of claims under such programs and better assist financial recovery from significant natural catastrophes. Limits the total principal amount of debt obligations guaranteed by the Secretary to: (1) $5 billion for eligible state programs that cover earthquake peril; and (2) $20 billion for eligible state programs that cover all other perils. Makes appropriations to satisfy debt guarantee commitments. Requires the Secretary, upon request of an eligible state program, to provide such debt guarantees. Requires an eligible state program to show to the Secretary's satisfaction that covered insured losses in the state are likely to exceed the program's available cash resources, as calculated on the date of the event. Prescribes requirements for eligible state programs. Pledges the full faith and credit of the United States to the payment of all guarantees issued under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
