<bill session="111" type="h" number="4865" updated="2013-07-19T23:56:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Employees and Uniformed Services Retirement Equity Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide that an employee of the Federal Government or member of the uniformed services may contribute to the Thrift Savings Fund any payment that the employee or member receives for accumulated and accrued annual or vacation leave, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400249"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2010-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2010-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400254" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2010-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2010--Introduced.
Federal Employees and Uniformed Services Retirement Equity Act of 2010 - Authorizes a federal employee or Member of Congress, under the Civil Service Retirement System or the Federal Employees Retirement System, to contribute to the Thrift Savings Fund: (1) any amount of such employee's or Member's basic pay for a pay period; and (2) any part of any payment that the employee or Member receives for accumulated and accrued annual or vacation leave. Includes within the definition of employee an employee of the United States Postal Service (USPS) or of the Postal Regulatory Commission. Authorizes a member of the uniformed services making contributions to the Thrift Savings Fund out of basic pay or inactive-duty training compensation to also contribute all or part of any payment such member receives for unused accrued leave. Authorizes the Executive Director of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board to promulgate regulations to implement this Act and to permit a federal employee or member of the uniformed services who is not authorized under this Act to contribute a payment for accumulated and accrued annual or vacation leave to the Thrift Savings Fund to make such contribution if the employee or member is covered by an equivalent federal employee retirement system and is authorized under law to receive such a payment and to contribute to the Fund.</summary>
</bill>
