<bill session="111" type="h" number="2184" updated="2013-07-19T23:31:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prepare All Kids Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assist States in making voluntary high quality universal prekindergarten programs available to 3- to 5-year olds for at least 1 year preceding kindergarten.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2009-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1022"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="839"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2009--Introduced.
Prepare All Kids Act of 2009 - Creates a part I (High Quality Prekindergarten Programs) under title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Implements such part by requiring the Secretary of Education to establish a Prekindergarten Incentive Fund from which matching grants shall be awarded to states and, through them, subgrants to qualified prekindergarten providers to establish, expand, or enhance voluntary high quality full-day prekindergarten programs serving children ages three through five. Directs state grantees to set aside: (1) at least 15% of their grant for quality early childhood development programs for children ages zero through three; and (2) at least 10% of their grant to extend the hours of early childhood programs to create extended day and year programs. Requires prekindergarten subgrantees to: (1) maintain a maximum class size of 20 children, with at least 1 prekindergarten teacher per classroom; and (2) ensure that the ratio of children to prekindergarten teachers and teacher aides does not exceed 10 to 1.</summary>
</bill>
