<bill session="111" type="s" number="1616" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States-China Market Engagement and Export Promotion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize assistance to small- and medium-sized businesses to promote exports to the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2009-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9016"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9016-9017" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2310"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/2009--Introduced.
United States-China Market Engagement and Export Promotion Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) provide grants to states to establish and operate state offices in the People's Republic of China (PRC) to promote U.S. exports to the PRC; (2) establish a program to create China market advocate positions in United States Export Assistance Centers in order to provide assistance to small- and medium-sized U.S. businesses in the export of U.S. goods to the PRC, including assistance for business-related expenses for trade missions to the PRC; and (3) submit to Congress a plan to consolidate fees for Gold Key matching services provided to such U.S. businesses that export U.S. goods or services to more than one market in the PRC. Amends the Small Business Act to require the Office of International Trade of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to provide guidance to U.S. small businesses with respect to the export of U.S. goods and services to the PRC. Establishes in the Office a Director of China Program Grants. Directs the Administrator of SBA, acting through the Director of China Program Grants, to make grants to institutions of higher education to establish and operate Chinese business education programs.</summary>
</bill>
