<bill session="112" type="h" number="2720" updated="2013-07-20T01:33:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify the role of the Department of Veterans Affairs in providing a benefit or service related to the interment or funeral of a veteran, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400089"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2011-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2011--Introduced.
Limits the role of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in interments or funerals, memorial services, or ceremonies of deceased veterans to providing: (1) such veterans with benefits earned by serving the United States, (2) any necessary maintenance of national cemeteries and other facilities under control of the National Cemetery Administration, and (3) any necessary security or traffic control with respect to such services at national cemeteries and facilities under such Administration's control. Directs the Secretary to ensure that: (1) a suitable chapel is provided to the deceased's family, and (2) any requested honor guard or other nongovernmental group is provided access to such services and Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) health care facilities. Requires each VA cemetery director to be a veteran. Prohibits federal government officials, including the Secretary, from interfering with the content and creed of such services, as expressed by the last will and testament of the individual or as determined by the family or agent of the individual, as provided under state law.</summary>
</bill>
