<bill session="111" type="s" number="1380" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC) Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to create a sensible infrastructure for delivery system reform by renaming the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission, making the commission an executive branch agency, and providing the Commission new resources and authority to implement Medicare payment policy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2718"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1110"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare Payment Advisory Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2009--Introduced.
Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC) Reform Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to rename the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC) the Medicare Payment and Access Commission, make it an independent executive branch (instead of a legislative branch) agency, and revise its membership requirements. Makes it a purpose of MedPAC to: (1) act as the regulatory authority for Medicare payment and coverage policies; and (2) implement specified policies. Divides the responsibilities of MedPAC into three categories: (1) reimbursement policy; (2) coverage policy; and (3) financial stability. Directs MedPAC to determine payment policies, methodologies, and rates for items and services under Medicare, as well as coverage policies and methodologies. Requires the Comptroller General to study and report annually to Congress on changes to such policies, methodologies, and rates as a result of the amendments made by this Act. Makes it in order in the Senate or the House to consider any measure that would overrule a MedPAC determination with respect to such matters if three-fifths of the Members agree to such consideration. Authorizes MedPAC to advise the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality and the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), on priorities for health services research. Directs MedPAC to establish: (1) an office of ombudsman; and (2) a council of health and economic advisers. Establishes: (1) a consumer advisory council to advise MedPAC on the impact of Medicare payment policies on consumers; and (2) a federal health advisory council. Directs MedPAC to implement payment policies, methodologies, and rates as well as coverage policies and methodologies estimated to reduce Medicare expenditures by at least 1.5% annually. Requires the Secretary to implement an automatic reduction in reimbursement for service providers and suppliers under the original fee-for-service program under Medicare parts A (Hospital Insurance) and B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) in order to achieve such 1.5% reduction if such policies, methodologies, and rates fail to achieve it. Establishes in Congress the Joint Committee on Medicare to: (1) study the operation and effects of any changes proposed by Congress to the Medicare program; and (2) assist Congress with respect to Medicare-related legislation. Transfers the Office of Research, Development and Information from the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to the Assistant Secretary of HHS for Planning and Evaluation. Requires the Office to design and evaluate Medicare demonstration projects.</summary>
</bill>
