<bill session="112" type="h" number="4629" updated="2013-07-20T01:50:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Comptroller General to conduct an annual audit of the General Services Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412403"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2080"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2012--Introduced.
Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to conduct an annual audit of the General Services Administration (GSA) and to report the audit findings to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works. Requires such audit to include detailed information for each region regarding specific administrative costs, conference spending, bonuses, travel expenses, staffing levels, expenditures on buildings classified as excess, surplus, or underutilized, a detailed accounting of the expenditures of the Federal Buildings Fund, and any other information which a congressional committee may request.</summary>
</bill>
