<bill session="111" type="s" number="2834" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-03">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Security Clearance Modernization and Reporting Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to establish a Security Clearance and Suitability Performance Accountability Council and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2009-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12330"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Select Committee on Intelligence.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12331-12332" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2009--Introduced.
Security Clearance Modernization and Reporting Act of 2009 - Amends the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to extend national security clearance report requirements to the earlier of two years after the Comptroller General has removed all security clearance-related items from the list known as the High-Risk List, or 2017. (Under current law, such report requirement runs through 2011.) Adds to required report information a description of the full range of time required to complete initial clearance applications. Establishes the Security Clearance and Suitability Performance Accountability Council to perform specified duties, and oversee the development of techniques, relating to the enhancement of applicant suitability determinations and security clearances, including holding each U.S. agency accountable for its security procedures. Directs the Council to develop and submit to Congress a strategic plan that identifies the causes of problems with the issuance of security clearances and a description of corrective actions to address such problems. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to submit to Congress an information technology strategy for expediting the security clearance process and for providing security clearance and suitability determination reform consistent with the Report of the Joint Security and Suitability Reform Team, dated December 20, 2008.</summary>
</bill>
