<bill session="110" type="h" number="4074" updated="2013-07-19T21:39:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">San Joaquin River Restoration Settlement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">San Joaquin River Restoration Settlement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the implementation of the San Joaquin River Restoration Settlement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2007-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2007-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2007-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2007-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 25 - 15.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-05-13T20:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-633.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-05-13T20:26:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="395">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 395.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="24"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="24"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="27"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="27"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Water allocation (Policy)"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2008--Reported to House without amendment.
Title I: The San Joaquin River Restoration Settlement Act - (Sec. 101) San Joaquin River Restoration Settlement Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary), in cooperation with the state of California, to implement the Stipulation of Settlement dated September 13, 2006, in Natural Resources Defense Council, et al. v. Kirk Rodgers, et al., United States District Court, Eastern District of California. Directs the Secretary to: (1) enter into agreements with California to facilitate or expedite Settlement implementation; and (2) identify impacts and measures to mitigate impacts on adjacent and downstream water users and landowners. Provides that Settlement implementation and the reintroduction of Chinook salmon shall not result in the involuntary reduction in contract water allocations to Central Valley Project long-term contractors apart from Friant Division contractors.(Sec. 105) Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) purchase property needed to implement the Settlement from willing sellers; and (2) dispose of such property and deposit proceeds into the San Joaquin River Restoration Fund.(Sec. 107) Declares that the Settlement satisfies and discharges the Secretary's obligations under the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992.(Sec. 109) Requires the costs of implementing the Settlement to be covered by payments or in kind contributions made by Friant Division contractors and other non-federal parties, with specified costs shared by California. Directs the Secretary to enter into agreements with California to fund or implement improvements on a project-by-project basis.(Sec. 110) Directs the Secretary to convert specified long-term contracts to provide for the repayment of construction costs.(Sec. 111) Provides for the reintroduction of Chinook salmon into the San Joaquin River, contingent upon the Secretary of Commerce finding that a permit for such reintroduction may be issued under the Endangered Species Act of 1973. (Sec. 112) Directs the Secretary to establish a conservation of resources fee for non-producing federal oil and gas leases in the Gulf of Mexico, revenues from which shall be treated as offsetting receipts.Title II: Study to Develop Water Plan; Report - (Sec. 201) Directs the Secretary: (1) acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to provide direct financial assistance to the California Water Institute to study coordination and integration of sub-regional integrated regional water management plans into a unified Integrated Regional Water Management Plan; and (2) to ensure that a report containing the results of the Plan is submitted to specified congressional committees within 24 months after financial assistance is made available to the Institute. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
