<bill session="111" type="s" number="3859" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Doctor of Nursing Practice and Doctor of Pharmacy Dual Degree Program Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to express the sense of the Senate concerning the establishment of Doctor of Nursing Practice and Doctor of Pharmacy dual degree programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7634"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7634-7635" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Drug and radiation therapy"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2010--Introduced.
Doctor of Nursing Practice and Doctor of Pharmacy Dual Degree Program Act of 2010 - Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) there should be established a Doctor of Nursing Practice (DNP) and Doctor of Pharmacy (PharmD) dual degree program; (2) the development of a joint degree in nursing and pharmacology should combine a DNP with a PharmD; (3) such a program would improve patient outcomes; (4) through such a dual collaborative role health providers will be better able to meet the unique needs of rural communities across the age continuum and in diverse settings; (5) such a program would enhance collaboration between DNPs and physicians regarding drug therapy, provide for research concerning and the implementation of safer medication administration, broaden the scope of practice for pharmacists through education and training in diagnosis and management of common diseases, provide new employment opportunities, and assist in filling the need for primary care providers with an expertise in geriatrics and pharmaceuticals; and (6) additional research and evaluation should be conducted to determine the extent to which graduates of such a program improve primary health care, address disparities, diversify the workforce, and increase quality of service for underserved populations.</summary>
</bill>
