<bill session="109" type="h" number="2796" updated="2013-07-19T19:28:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">DNA Fingerprinting Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand the use of DNA for the identification and prosecution of sex offenders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400159"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="DNA"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2005--Introduced.
DNA Fingerprinting Act of 2005 - Amends the DNA Identification Act of 1994 to expand the scope of DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid) samples to be included in the Combined DNA Index System (CODIS). Repeals exclusions from CODIS of: (1) DNA profiles from arrestees who have not been charged in an indictment or information with a crime; and (2) DNA samples that are voluntarily submitted solely for elimination purposes. Repeals provisions regarding: (1) requirements for expungement of DNA analysis from CODIS in cases where the convictions are overturned; and (2) authority for any person who is authorized to access CODIS for purposes of including DNA information to access it to carry out a one-time keyboard search. Amends the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 to authorize the Attorney General to: (1) collect DNA samples from individuals who are arrested or detained under U.S. authority; (2) delegate this function within the Department of Justice; and (3) authorize and direct any other U.S. agency that arrests or detains individuals or supervises individuals facing charges to carry out any function and exercise any power of the Attorney General. Repeals the exception of sexual abuse cases from provisions providing for the tolling of the statute of limitations in cases in which DNA testing implicates an identified person in the commission of a felony.</summary>
</bill>
