<bill session="113" type="s" number="852" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Health Promotion Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve health care furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs by increasing access to complementary and alternative medicine and other approaches to wellness and preventive care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3042-3043"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3043-3045" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2013--Introduced.
Veterans' Health Promotion Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to designate and operate at least one center of innovation for complementary and alternative medicine in health research, education, and clinical activities in each of the Veterans Integrated Service Networks. Directs the Secretary to carry out a three-year pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of establishing complementary and alternative medicine centers within current VA medical centers in order to promote the use and integration of such services for veterans' mental health diagnoses and pain management. Requires the establishment of at least 15 such centers in 15 different VA medical centers. Requires the Secretary to establish a three-year pilot program for the award of grants to public or private nonprofit entities to assess the feasibility and advisability of using wellness programs to complement the provision of mental health care to veterans and family members eligible for VA counseling services. Directs the Secretary to carry out a two-year pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of promoting health through the payment of fitness center membership for veterans determined to be overweight or obese and who reside more than 15 minutes' driving distance from a VA fitness facility. Requires the Secretary to carry out a three-year pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability, through the establishment of VA fitness facilities, of promoting the achievement of a healthy weight in veterans enrolled in the VA system of annual patient enrollment. Prohibits the assessment of a user fee for program participants using such facilities. Directs the Secretary to conduct a comprehensive study of barriers encountered by veterans in receiving complementary and alternative medicine from the VA.</summary>
</bill>
