<bill session="112" type="h" number="2509" updated="2013-07-20T01:32:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preserving Consumers' Mortgage Origination Choices Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve upon certain provisions of the Truth in Lending Act related to the compensation of mortgage originators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2011-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2011--Introduced.
Preserving Consumer's Mortgage Origination Choices Act of 2011 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act (TILA), as amended by the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, to provide that no provision of TILA shall be construed as prohibiting a mortgage broker from compensating a mortgage originator based on the principal amount of the loan, when compensation is paid directly or indirectly to the mortgage broker by the consumer in connection with such transaction. Authorizes a mortgage originator, when requested by a borrower as the originator is producing a mortgage, to forfeit or contribute toward bona fide third party expenses or origination fees up to 30% of earned compensation to avoid making a high-cost mortgage to a consumer, to make technical corrections, or for any other reason that results in a lower cost to the consumer than if such forfeiture or contribution did not take place.</summary>
</bill>
