<bill session="111" type="s" number="3880" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Officer Daniel Faulkner Children of Fallen Heroes Scholarship Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to increase Federal Pell Grants for the children of fallen public safety officers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Officer Daniel Faulkner Children of Fallen Heroes Scholarship Act of 2010 - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to eliminate the expected family contribution used in determining a student's need for title IV assistance in the case of a student applicant who is eligible for a Pell Grant and whose parent or guardian died as a result of performing service as a law enforcement officer, firefighter, or member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew. Requires such student to be less than 24 years old and enrolled at an institution of higher education at the time of his or her parent's or guardian's death. Gives financial aid administrators the responsibility of verifying that such students are eligible to have their expected family contribution adjusted (or eliminated), and of adjusting (or eliminating) it, unless the Secretary of Education establishes an alternate method of adjusting their expected family contribution. Prohibits the total Pell Grant of a student whose Pell Grant is increased by reason of this Act from being considered in calculating that student's educational assistance benefits under the Public Safety Officer's Benefits program. Alters the source of the annual Pell Grant increase for such students to require that it be provided only to the extent that funds are specifically provided in advance to such students in an appropriation Act for that award year.</summary>
</bill>
