<bill session="110" type="s" number="1836" updated="2013-07-19T22:36:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Comptroller General to address certain questions in connection with the closure of Fort Monmouth, New Jersey, and the transfer of personnel, functions, and activities from Fort Monmouth to Aberdeen Proving Ground, Maryland, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3108"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists in government"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2007--Introduced.
Directs the Comptroller General to require methodological, scientific, and technical experts within the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to undertake a new investigation to address specified questions relating to Fort Monmouth, New Jersey, including: (1) cost estimates with respect to its closing and the transfer of its personnel, functions, and activities to Aberdeen Proving Ground, Maryland; (2) a shortfall of defense scientists and engineers; and (3) the failure of the Department of Defense (DOD) to timely provide a report required by the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission as to whether the transfer of such personnel, functions, and activities will be accomplished without disruption of their support to the Global War on Terror or other critical contingency operations.</summary>
</bill>
