<bill session="113" type="s" number="1" updated="2013-11-02T06:52:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration Reform that Works for America's Future Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform America's broken immigration system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S44" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/2013--Introduced.
Immigration Reform that Works for America's Future Act - Expresses the sense of the Senate that Congress should: create a roadmap for immigrants who are here without legal status to earn citizenship, provided they pay taxes, complete a background check, learn English, and show a commitment to America; allow students who came to America as children to earn citizenship by attending college or joining the Armed Forces; protect the sustainability of the American agricultural industry, including the dairy industry, with a stable and legal agricultural workforce; encourage those who seek to invest in the United States and create American jobs; permit individuals who earn an advanced degree from one of our universities to remain in the United States, rather than using that education to work for our international competitors; fulfill and strengthen our nation's commitments regarding security along our borders and at our ports of entry; strengthen our nation's historic humanitarian tradition of welcoming asylum seekers and refugees and improve existing policies that support immigrant victims of crime and domestic violence; create an effective electronic verification system and strengthen enforcement to prevent employers from hiring people illegally; implement a legal immigration system that promotes job creation by converting the current flow of illegal immigrants into the United States into a more manageable and legal process for admitting immigrants while, at the same time, safeguarding the jobs, rights, and wages of American workers; and adopt practical and fair immigration reforms to help ensure family unity.</summary>
</bill>
