<bill session="110" type="h" number="7063" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">U.S. and the World Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To raise achievement in international education in elementary schools and secondary schools through grants to improve teacher competency and to support programs in international education that supplement core curricula in such schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400356"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2008-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2043"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Geography"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2008--Introduced.
U.S. and the World Education Act - Amends the Department of Education Organization Act to require the Deputy Assistant Secretary for International and Foreign Language Education to: (1) assist the Secretary of Education in administering this Act's grant program; and (2) develop an international education research repository and make it available to states and local educational agencies (LEAs). Directs the Secretary, acting through the Deputy Assistant Secretary, to award competitive grants to LEAs, or partnerships between LEAs and private organizations or institutions of higher education that provide their LEA partners with funding, to promote international education in elementary and secondary schools. Requires each grantee to use: (1) one-half of its grant on enhancing international education within core curricula, such as by increasing teacher competency; and (2) the other half on providing supplemental international education services outside of normal instruction hours. Directs the Secretary to conduct a biennial independent evaluation of such international education programs.</summary>
</bill>
