<bill session="109" type="h" number="1057" updated="2013-07-19T19:13:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">True American Heroes Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To award a congressional gold medal on behalf of all government workers and others who responded to the attacks on the World Trade Center and the Pentagon and perished and people aboard United Airlines Flight 93 who helped resist the highjackers and caused the plane to crash, to award a duplicate in silver of such gold medals to the personal respresentative of each such person, to require the Secretary of Treasury to mint coins in commemoration of the Spirit of America, recognizing the tragic events of September 11, 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2005-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2005-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400139" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2005-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-03-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional gold medals"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Flight crews"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governors"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="Mayors"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Office buildings"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Port authorities"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Silver"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2005--Introduced.
True American Heroes Act of 2005 - Directs the Speaker of the House and the President pro tempore of the Senate to make arrangements for the presentation on behalf of the Congress of a single gold medal on the 5th anniversary of September 11, 2001, in the name of the unknown officer, worker, employee, passenger, or crew member, who was the first to die that day: (1) in the attack on the World Trade Center in New York City; (2) on board United Airlines Flight 93; and (3) in the attack on the Pentagon, Washington, D.C. Requires such presentation to be made to an appropriate representative of all such officers, emergency workers, employees, and other individuals for permanent public display in the Smithsonian Institution. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to strike additional duplicates in silver of such gold medal for permanent public display at: (1) a memorial at the site of the World Trade Center attacks; (2) the crash site of United Airlines Flight 93 near Shanksville, Pennsylvania, and (3) a memorial at the site of the Pentagon attack. Lists sites for permanent display of silver duplicates presented on behalf of responders, resistors aboard Flight 93, and Government workers who responded to and perished in the Pentagon attack. Instructs the Secretary to mint and issue $50 gold coins, $1 silver coins; and half dollar clad coins in commemoration of the Spirit of America. Directs the Secretary to mint and issue $50 gold coins equal to the number of innocent individuals confirmed or presumed to have been killed as a result of the terrorist attacks against the United States on September 11, 2001. States that the design of such coins shall be emblematic of the tragic events that occurred at the Pentagon, in New York City, and in Pennsylvania, on September 11, 2001. Sets forth surcharges on the sale of such coins.</summary>
</bill>
