<bill session="111" type="s" number="1600" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reinstitute and update the Pay-As-You-Go requirement of budget neutrality on new tax and mandatory spending legislation, enforced by the threat of annual, automatic sequestration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2009-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2009-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2920"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1808"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/2009--Introduced.
Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2009 - Requires a Pay-As-You-Go (PAYGO) Act to include by reference an estimate of its budgetary effects as determined by the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (CBA), if timely submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the chairs of the congressional budget committees (chairs) before the vote on it. Requires: (1) the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate, as applicable, also to incorporate by reference such printed estimate into the enrollment of a PAYGO Act; and (2) budgetary effects that are not so included to be determined by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) estimates. Amends the CBA to require the chairs to request from the Director of the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) an estimate of the budgetary effects of a PAYGO Act before a vote in either chamber on it that, if determined in the affirmative, would clear it for enrollment. Directs the chairs to post such estimate on their respective committee websites and cause it to be printed in the Congressional Record under "PAYGO ESTIMATE." Requires OMB to maintain and make publicly available a continuously updated document containing two PAYGO scorecards (the first for a five-year period and the second for a 10-year period for the beginning of each respective budget year) displaying the budgetary effects of PAYGO legislation, applying certain look-back and averaging requirements. Requires OMB to display as a separate addendum the cost estimates of provisions designated in statute as emergency requirements. Requires OMB to: (1) make an annual public PAYGO report, including a up-to-date document containing the PAYGO scorecards, within 14 business days after Congress adjourns to end a session; and (2) prepare for the President an offsetting sequestration order, which the President shall issue, if such report shows a debit on either PAYGO scorecard for the budget year. Prescribes requirements for calculating a sequestration for nonexempt direct spending programs, including Medicare payments and certain nonexempt mandatory programs. Applies to this Act certain sequestration order requirements of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act), as amended by this Act, including the authority of Members of Congress and certain individuals to request an expedited judicial review of a sequestration order. Exempts from sequestration: (1) low-income subsidies and catastrophic subsidies under Part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of the Social Security Act (SSA); and (2) qualified individual (QI) premiums for Medicare cost-sharing for certain dual eligible low-income Medicare beneficiaries under SSA title XIX (Medicaid). Amends the Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act to specify additional Social Security, veterans, Tier I Railroad Retirement benefits and other programs and activities exempt from a sequestration order as well as certain economic recovery programs.</summary>
</bill>
