<bill session="112" type="h" number="3562" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ban Toxic Dispersants Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act with respect to the use of dispersants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400289"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2011-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="501"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1870"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2011--Introduced.
Ban Toxic Dispersants Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to authorize a dispersant, chemical, or other spill mitigating device or substance that is not included on the National Contingency Plan's schedule to be used in carrying out such plan only if such device or substance is proposed to be included on such schedule. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to issue a revised regulation for the development of the schedule for the use of such devices and substances. Requires the Administrator, with respect to such substances, to: (1) establish minimum toxicity and efficacy testing criteria; (2) establish a requirement that the volume of oil or hazardous substance discharged, and the volume and location of any such spill mitigating substance used, be measured and made publicly available on a daily basis; and (3) require the public disclosure of all ingredients of such substance. Requires the Administrator to: (1) require the manufacturer of such a device to study its risks and effectiveness; (2) provide a mechanism for the delisting of any such substance or device that poses a risk to or impact on human health, water quality, or the environment; and (3) initiate a formal review of the potential risks and impacts associated with such substance or device prior to delisting it. Directs the Administrator to: (1) study such potential risks and impacts, including acute and chronic risks, from the use of such substances that may be used to carry out such Plan; (2) impose a temporary moratorium on approval of the use of dispersants until the study is complete; (3) review the schedule for the use of such devises and substances and revise it as necessary every five years; and (4) establish a schedule of fees to be collected from the manufacturers of such substances or devices to offset the costs of evaluating their use.</summary>
</bill>
