<bill session="110" type="h" number="2115" updated="2013-07-19T21:22:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Thomas J. Manton Prostate Cancer Early Detection and Treatment Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act and title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide for a screening and treatment program for prostate cancer in the same manner as is provided for breast and cervical cancer.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400254"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="2131"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="1275"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Blood pressure"/>
    <term name="Cholesterol"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Prostate cancer"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/2007--Introduced.
Thomas J. Manton Prostate Cancer Early Detection and Treatment Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to allow the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to make grants to states to carry out: (1) prostate cancer prevention programs (including screening and referrals for treatment); and (2) demonstration projects to provide preventive health services with respect to prostate cancer (including blood pressure and cholesterol screenings). Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to allow states to provide medical assistance to individuals who have been screened for prostate cancer under this Act and who need treatment for prostate cancer. Applies provisions related to breast and cervical cancer programs to programs under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
