<bill session="113" type="h" number="810" updated="2013-11-02T06:25:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To grant the Secretary of Defense the authority to transfer funding under a continuing resolution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412427" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2013-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-25">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-25">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2013--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Defense to submit to the congressional defense and appropriations committees a detailed outline of, and accounting under the discretionary spending limit for: (1) the efficiencies relating to Department of Defense (DOD) contracting for goods and services, and (2) the DOD budget initiate. Authorizes the Secretary to transfer amounts made available by a continuing resolution among DOD accounts. Prohibits the amount transferred to any account from exceeding that authorized for such account by the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013. Makes such transfer authority inapplicable in the event a regular appropriations Act for DOD is enacted for FY2013. Requires 15 days' advance notification to such committees prior to any such transfer.</summary>
</bill>
