<bill session="111" type="h" number="4795" updated="2013-07-19T23:55:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ticket Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit restrictions on the resale of event tickets sold in interstate commerce as an unfair or deceptive act or practice.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2010-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2010--Introduced.
Ticket Act - Makes it unlawful for any: (1) ticket issuer to prohibit or restrict the resale or offering for resale of an event ticket by a lawful possessor; and (2) person to engage in the primary or resale market for event ticket sales without complying with the consumer protection minimum standards specified in this Act. Treats a violation of such prohibitions as an unfair or deceptive act or practice under the Federal Trade Commission Act. Provides for state enforcement of such prohibitions. Prohibits state action during the pendency of an enforcement action by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). Exempts from such prohibitions resale restrictions imposed by: (1) sponsors or promoters of charitable events for which all tickets are distributed without charge; and (2) not-for-profit educational institutions for athletic events involving their athletes or teams with respect to tickets initially distributed to students, faculty, staff, or alumni without charge, or to members of bona fide booster organizations.</summary>
</bill>
