<bill session="109" type="s" number="3615" updated="2013-07-19T20:44:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safer and Fair Enforcement and Recall for Meat, Poultry, and Food Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAFER Meat, Poultry, and Food Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act, the Poultry Products Inspection Act, and the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for improved public health and food safety through enhanced enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2006-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6801-6802"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="5729"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cattle"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Goats"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat inspection"/>
    <term name="Meat packing industry"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Produce trade"/>
    <term name="Sheep"/>
    <term name="Swine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2006--Introduced.
Safe and Fair Enforcement and Recall for Meat, Poultry and Food Act of 2006 or SAFER Meat, Poultry and Food Act of 2006 - Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act, the Poultry Products Inspection Act and the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to: (1) require a person, other than a household consumer, who has reason to believe meat, poultry, or food products to be adulterated or misbranded to so notify the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as appropriate; (2) provide the Secretary of Agriculture with authority for voluntary and mandatory nondistribution and recall, withdrawal of inspectors from violating facilities, consumer and health official notification, and imposition of civil penalties; and (3) provide the Secretary of Health and Human Services with authority for voluntary and mandatory nondistribution and recall, consumer and health official notification, and imposition of civil penalties.</summary>
</bill>
