<bill session="111" type="h" number="249" updated="2013-07-19T23:14:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Logan's Law</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the head of a Federal department or agency that is carrying out a project involving the construction of a culvert or other enclosed flood or drainage system to ensure that certain child safety measures are included in the project.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400160"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO24" subcommittee="Government Management, Organization, and Procurement" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/2009--Introduced.
Logan's Law - Requires the head of a federal agency that is carrying out a project involving the construction or modification of a culvert or other enclosed flood or drainage system to ensure that: (1) the system intake is protected by a covering sufficient to ensure that a child may not be swept into the system; (2) a sign warning of the hazard for a child is clearly posted at such intake; and (3) the system has a hinged opening, or other type of opening and closing mechanism, to permit emergency services personnel access.Requires a federal agency providing financial assistance to a state or local government or other entity for a project carried out with federal funds to require compliance with this Act as a condition for the award of such assistance or any letter of intent.</summary>
</bill>
