<bill session="113" type="s" number="148" updated="2013-11-02T06:53:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to safeguard America's schools by using community policing strategies to prevent school violence and improve student and school safety.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412586" joined="2013-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services to make grants to local governments and Indian tribes to provide for school resource and safety officers at schools. Defines a "school resource and safety officer" as a career law enforcement officer who is assigned by the employing police department to protect schools and who works in and around schools for not less than 75% of the time the officer is on duty. Requires the Director to: (1) establish guidelines for programs that train school resource and safety officers, and (2) ensure an equitable geographic distribution of grants among regions of the United States and among urban, suburban, and rural areas. Limits grants to: (1) $200,000 for each officer proposed to be hired or each training program proposed to be funded, subject to a waiver; and (2) three fiscal years. Authorizes the Director to make available additional funds if the funds were used in the manner required and the recipient demonstrates significant financial need.</summary>
</bill>
