<bill session="109" type="h" number="5297" updated="2013-07-19T19:51:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving Access to Medicare Part D Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to extend by one year the initial enrollment period for Medicare prescription drug benefits and for Medicare Advantage plans, to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to negotiate fair prices for Medicare prescription drugs, and to express the sense of Congress that the Secretary should conduct activities to improve outreach and educational efforts with respect to such benefits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400095"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman .</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4792"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2487"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2006--Introduced.
Improving Access to Medicare Part D Act of 2006 - Amends part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide for a one-year extension until May 15, 2007, of the 2006 initial enrollment period for Medicare prescription drug benefits and Medicare Advantage (MA) plans. Extends through May 14, 2007, the current extended period of continuous open enrollment and disenrollment. Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of SSA title XVIII to repeal the prohibition against interference by the Secretary of Health and Human Services with prescription drug price negotiations between drug manufacturers and pharmacies and prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsors. Authorizes the Secretary to negotiate prescription drug price contracts with manufacturers of covered part D drugs in order to ensure that each enrollee under a PDP or an MA-PD plan pays the lowest possible price. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary should conduct (and improve current) activities, with respect to individuals eligible for the Medicare prescription drug benefits, to: (1) raise the awareness and improve the education of such individuals about such benefits; (2) improve and enhance outreach and enrollment assistance; and (3) provide for the accessibility of appropriate experts (at national, state, and local levels) to ensure that such individuals understand the benefits for which they are eligible.</summary>
</bill>
