<bill session="113" type="s" number="184" updated="2013-11-02T06:53:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pro-Growth Budgeting Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to provide for macroeconomic analysis of the impact of legislation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412493"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2013-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1874"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Economic theory"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/30/2013--Introduced.
Pro-Growth Budgeting Act of 2013 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to prepare for each major bill or resolution reported by any congressional committee (except the congressional appropriations committees), as a supplement to CBO cost estimates, a macroeconomic impact analysis of the costs of such legislation for: (1) the period for which the cost estimate is prepared, and (2) the 10-fiscal year period beginning with the first fiscal year after the last fiscal year for which such estimate was prepared and each of the next two 10-fiscal year periods. Defines "major bill or resolution" as any bill or resolution whose budgetary effects, for any fiscal year in the period for which a CBO cost estimate is prepared, is estimated to be greater than .25% of the current projected U.S. gross domestic product (GDP) for that fiscal year. Requires the analysis to describe: (1) the potential economic impact of the bill or resolution on major economic variables, including real GDP, business investment, the capital stock, employment, and labor supply; and (2) the potential fiscal effects of the measure, including any estimates of revenue increases or decreases resulting from changes in GDP.</summary>
</bill>
