<bill session="113" type="h" number="821" updated="2013-11-02T06:25:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to provide surviving spouses with certain protections relating to mortgages and mortgage foreclosures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412276"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act, for five years after enactment of this Act, to afford surviving spouses of servicemembers who die while in the military and whose death is service-connected the same protections against sale, foreclosure, and seizure of property currently applicable to their husbands who while in military service are unable to meet an obligation on real or personal property. Requires each lending institution subject to specified requirements for a maximum 6% rate of interest on a servicemember's debts incurred before military service to designate one of its employees as a compliance officer responsible for: (1) ensuring the institution's compliance with such requirements, and (2) distributing information to servicemembers whose obligations and liabilities are covered by such requirements. Requires such a lending institution that had annual assets for the preceding fiscal year of $10 billion or more to maintain a toll-free telephone number and make it available on its primary Internet website. Amends the Honoring America's Veterans and Caring for Camp Lejeune Families Act of 2012 to extend through 2017 the period of specified protections for servicemembers against mortgage foreclosures.</summary>
</bill>
