<bill session="112" type="h" number="1089" updated="2013-07-20T01:19:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sergeant Coleman S. Bean Reserve Component Suicide Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Defense to provide members of the Individual Ready Reserve, Individual Mobilization Augmentees, and inactive members of the National Guard who served in Afghanistan or Iraq with information on counseling to prevent suicide, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412418" joined="2011-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2011-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2011-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2011-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2011-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="579"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2011--Introduced.
Sergeant Coleman S. Bean Reserve Component Suicide Prevention Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to ensure that each of the following individuals receive, at least once every 90 days, a telephone call from properly-trained DOD personnel to determine their emotional, psychological, medical, and career needs and concerns: (1) members of the Individual Ready Reserve who deployed to Afghanistan or Iraq in support of a contingency operation, (2) a member of a reserve component who the Secretary determines is an individual mobilization augmentee who has so deployed, or (3) a member of the inactive National Guard. Requires the person making the call to refer a member identified as being at-risk of self-caused harm to the nearest military medical treatment facility or accredited TRICARE (a DOD managed health care program) provider for immediate evaluation and necessary treatment. Directs the Secretary to refer such member to a private provider upon determining that such provider will ensure that the member will receive treatment and assistance without delay. Requires annual reports from the Secretary to Congress on the number of members so referred, their health and career status, and any situations that may be impeding the counseling calls from reaching all appropriate members. Requires a one-time report from the Comptroller General to Congress on suicide among such members. Directs the Secretary to develop, evaluate, and more widely disseminate programs that promote: (1) connectivity between members of the Armed Forces and their family, peers, and immediate chain of command; and (2) suicide risk identification and response, with particular emphasis on members of reserve components.</summary>
</bill>
