<bill session="112" type="sr" number="233" updated="2013-07-20T02:12:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-13">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution honoring the men and women of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Space Shuttle Program on reaching the historic milestone of the 135th and final flight of the Space Transportation System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2011-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-07-13" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4563-4564" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4563-4564" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4561-4562" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2011--Passed Senate without amendment.
Congratulates the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) on reaching the historic milestone of the 135th and final flight of the Space Transportation System. Honors the men and women of the Space Shuttle Program who worked to design, build, and operate the Space Transportation System in order to promote science, exploration, and international cooperation. Remembers the 14 crewmembers lost during the space shuttle Challenger accident which occurred on January 28, 1986, and the space shuttle Columbia accident, which occurred on February 1, 2003. Recognizes that the Space Shuttle Program has inspired generations of children to become engineers, scientists, and explorers. Acknowledges that the Space Shuttle Program has, through its technological advancements and scientific research, driven innovation in the fields of science, technology, and mathematics (STEM) to benefit the people of the United States and all of humankind.</summary>
</bill>
