<bill session="111" type="s" number="1210" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STEM Education Coordination Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a committee under the National Science and Technology Council with the responsibility to coordinate science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education activities and programs of all Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412329"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2009-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6271-6272"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6272" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1709"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3605"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2009--Introduced.
STEM Education Coordination Act of 2009 - Requires the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) to establish a committee under the National Science and Technology Council that has the responsibility of coordinating federal programs and activities in support of STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) education. Directs such committee to: (1) coordinate the STEM education activities and programs of federal agencies; (2) develop, implement through participating agencies, and update once every five years, a five-year STEM education strategic plan; and (3) establish, periodically update, and maintain an inventory of federally sponsored STEM education programs and activities, including documentation of assessments of the effectiveness of such programs and activities and rates of participation by women, underrepresented minorities, and persons in rural areas. Requires the Director to annually report to Congress on the STEM education strategic plan.</summary>
</bill>
