<bill session="112" type="s" number="715" updated="2013-07-20T02:22:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Collinsville Renewable Energy Promotion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reinstate and transfer certain hydroelectric licenses and extend the deadline for commencement of construction of certain hydroelectric projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-129.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1353"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5625"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/2011--Introduced.
Collinsville Renewable Energy Promotion Act - Authorizes the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to: (1) reinstate the license for either or each of the projects numbered 10822 and 10823, and (2) extend for two years after the date on which either or each such project is reinstated the time period during which the licensee must commence project construction. Directs FERC to: (1) transfer the reinstated licenses to the town of Canton, Connecticut, if it reinstates them and extends the time period during which the licensee is required to commence project construction; and (2) complete an environmental assessment for the projects and update the environmental analysis performed during the licensing process. Sets a deadline for FERC to make a final decision on reinstatement of either or both projects.</summary>
</bill>
