<bill session="112" type="h" number="752" updated="2013-07-20T01:16:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Molalla River Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Molalla River Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the Molalla River in the State of Oregon, as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412315"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2011-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2011-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2011-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-12-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-12-31T12:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-735.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-12-31T12:12:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="537">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 537.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="403"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/31/2012--Reported to House amended.
Molalla River Wild and Scenic Rivers Act - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate specified segments of the Molalla River in Oregon as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior from acquiring by condemnation any land interest in land within the boundaries of the river segments. Prohibits anything in this Act from: (1) establishing or authorizing the establishment of a protective perimeter or buffer zone around the boundaries of the river segments; or (2) prohibiting an activity from being conducted outside those boundaries, including an activity that can be seen or heard. Bars the inclusion of private or non-federal public property within the boundaries of the river segments unless the property owner has consented in writing to having such property included. Renames the Squaw Creek in Oregon as Wychus Creek. Makes technical corrections to the description of the Creek.</summary>
</bill>
