<bill session="112" type="s" number="3341" updated="2013-07-20T02:45:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-22">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Quadrennial Diplomacy and Development Review Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Quadrennial Diplomacy and Development Review Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Quadrennial Diplomacy and Development Review Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require a quadrennial diplomacy and development review, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2012-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4638"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry without amendment. With written report No. 112-220.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-09-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="525">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 525.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2012-09-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/21/2012 S6673-6674" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 9/21/2012 S6673-6674" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-09-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-25T10:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2012--Passed Senate without amendment.
Quadrennial Diplomacy and Development Review Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of State to conduct a review every four years of U.S. diplomacy and development for the next four-year period (quadrennial diplomacy and development review) which shall include: (1) recommendations regarding the long-term diplomacy and development policy and strategic framework of the United States; (2) U.S. diplomatic priorities; and (3) guidance on the related programs, assets, capabilities, budget, policies, and authorities of the Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID). Provides for interagency consultations in the conduct of the diplomacy and development review. Requires each diplomacy and development review to: (1) delineate the U.S. national diplomacy and development policy and strategic framework; (2) prioritize critical national diplomacy and development areas, capabilities, and resources; (3) describe interagency cooperation and preparedness of relevant federal assets; (4) describe the roles of international organizations and multilateral institutions in advancing U.S. diplomatic and development objectives; (5) identify the necessary budget plan; and (6) assess the organizational alignment and management mechanisms of the Department and USAID with the national diplomacy and development policy and strategic framework. Authorizes the Secretary to establish within the Department an Office of Quadrennial Diplomacy and Development Review. Urges the Secretary to apprise the Foreign Affairs Policy Board on an ongoing basis of the work undertaken in the quadrennial diplomacy and development review.</summary>
</bill>
