<bill session="110" type="s" number="336" updated="2013-07-19T22:23:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Barrier Project Consolidation and Construction Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of the Army to operate and maintain as a system the Chicago Sanitary and Ship Canal dispersal barriers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2007-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2007-01-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S764-765" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="553"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="553"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Exotic animals"/>
    <term name="Exotic plants"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/18/2007--Introduced.
Barrier Project Consolidation and Construction Act of 2007 - Requires the Chicago Sanitary and Ship Canal Dispersal Barrier Project constructed as a demonstration project under the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control act of 1990 (Barrier I) and the related project authorized under the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2005 (Barrier II) to be considered to constitute a single project. Directs the Secretary of the Army, at full federal expense, to: (1) upgrade and make permanent Barrier I, construct Barrier II, operate and maintain Barriers I and II as a system, conduct a study of a full range of options and technologies for reducing impacts of hazards that may reduce the efficacy of the Barriers, and provide to each state a credit in an amount equal to that of funds contributed by the state toward Barrier II (which the state may apply to any cost-sharing responsibility for an existing or future federal project with the Corps of Engineers); and (2) conduct a feasibility study of the range of options and technologies to prevent the spread of aquatic nuisance species between the Great Lakes and Mississippi River basins through the Chicago Sanitary and Ship Canal and other aquatic pathways. Changes the authorization for Barrier II to such sums as may be necessary.</summary>
</bill>
