<bill session="110" type="hr" number="63" updated="2013-07-19T20:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to ensure that Members have a reasonable amount of time to read legislation that will be voted upon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E88"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/12/2007--Introduced.
Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to establish a new Rule XXIX to prohibit any vote by the House on any bill, joint resolution, conference report, or amendment unless: (1) the text of the measure has been available to all Members and their staffs in both printed and electronic format for at least 10 days; and (2) any amendment that makes substantive changes has been made available for at least 72 hours. Makes exceptions for: (1) legislation containing classified information if Members have at least seven days to study the contents; and (2) congressional declarations of war or authorization of military force to respond to attacks on the United States. Deems any Member who votes for a measure in violation of such Rule to have violated House ethics rules and to be subject to censure. Allows any citizen who is eligible to vote and who is not an executive or judicial branch employee to petition the Committee on Standards and Official Conduct to investigate allegations of violations of such Rule. Prohibits the Rules Committee from waiving such Rule.</summary>
</bill>
