<bill session="111" type="s" number="3396" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Supply Star Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Supply Star Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to establish within the Department of Energy a Supply Star program to identify and promote practices, companies, and products that use highly efficient supply chains in a manner that conserves energy, water, and other resources.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2010-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4145"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Energy. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-699.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 111-319.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="605">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 605.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG01" subcommittee="Energy" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Supply Star Act of 2010 - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (EPCA) to establish within the Department of Energy (DOE) a Supply Star program to identify and promote practices, recognize companies, and recognize products that use highly efficient supply chains in a manner that conserves energy, water, and other resources. Directs the Secretary of Energy to coordinate efforts with the Energy Star program. Requires the Secretary to: (1) promote practices, recognize companies, and recognize products that comply with the Supply Star program as the preferred practices, companies, and products in the marketplace for maximizing supply chain efficiency; (2) work to enhance industry and public awareness of the program; (3) collect and disseminate data on supply chain energy resource consumption; (4) develop and disseminate metrics, processes, and analytical tools (including software) for evaluating supply chain energy resource use; (5) develop guidance at the sector level for improving supply chain efficiency; (6) work with domestic and international organizations to harmonize approaches to analyzing supply chain efficiency; and (7) work with industry, including small businesses, to improve supply chain efficiency through activities that include developing and sharing best practices and providing opportunities to benchmark supply chain efficiency. Directs the Secretary, in any evaluation of supply chain efficiency carried out by the Secretary with respect to a specific product, to consider energy consumption and resource use throughout the entire lifecycle of a product, including production, transport, packaging, use, and disposal. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants or other incentives on a competitive basis to eligible entities for purposes of: (1) studying supply chain energy resource efficiency; and (2) demonstrating and achieving reductions in the energy resource consumption of commercial products through changes and improvements to the production supply and distribution chain of the products. Directs the Secretary to use funds to support professional training programs to develop and communicate methods, practices, and tools for improving supply chain efficiency. Provides that: (1) the impact on climate change shall not be a factor in determining supply chain efficiency; and (2) the outsourcing of American jobs in the production of a product shall not count as a positive factor in determining supply chain efficiency.</summary>
</bill>
