<bill session="112" type="h" number="2317" updated="2013-07-20T01:30:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Promoting Green Transportation Infrastructure through Research and Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote green transportation infrastructure through research and development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2011-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2011--Introduced.
Promoting Green Transportation Infrastructure through Research and Development Act - Moves the Office of Climate Change and Environment into the Research and Innovative Technology Administration (RITA) of the Department of Transportation (DOT) and requires it to coordinate research, development, and technology transfer activities: (1) that focus on transportation-related emissions and energy reduction strategies, and (2) on the impacts of climate change on surface transportation infrastructure. Revises the surface transportation, research, development, and technology program to direct the Administrator of RITA to make grants to institutions of higher education (including consortia) to establish regional university transportation centers (UTCs) to carry out research, development, and technology transfer activities in the field of green transportation infrastructure (i.e., infrastructure that preserves and restores natural processes, utilizes natural design techniques, and minimizes energy consumption and pollution). Directs the Administrator to establish a pavement research, deployment, and education program.</summary>
</bill>
