<bill session="111" type="s" number="3624" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freedom For Consumer Choice Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to encourage continued investment and innovation in communications networks by establishing a new, competition analysis-based regulatory framework for the Federal Communications Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2010-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2010-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2010-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2010--Introduced.
Freedom for Consumer Choice Act - States U.S. government policy with regard to: (1) the promotion of the widespread availability of communications services; (2) the promotion of the integrity of communications facilities through investment and innovation in advanced communications networks; and (3) the economic regulation of communications markets. Makes it unlawful for providers of electronic communication services to engage or participate in: (1) unfair methods of competition in or affecting electronic communications networks and services; or (2) unfair or deceptive practices in or affecting such networks and services. Authorizes the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), by rule, to define the acts or practices that shall constitute such unfair methods of competition or unfair or deceptive acts or practices. Bars the FCC from having any authority to issue rules that declare unlawful an act or practice on the grounds that it is an unfair method of competition or unfair or deceptive act or practice, except that the FCC may declare an act or practice unlawful if: (1) marketplace competition is insufficient to adequately protect consumer welfare; and (2) such act or practice causes or is likely to cause substantial injury to consumers, is unavoidable by consumers themselves, and is outweighed by countervailing benefits to consumers or to competition. Terminates any rule promulgated under this Act five years after its effective date unless the FCC makes an affirmative determination that such rule continues to be necessary. Grants the FCC the authority to hear complaints from any party injured by a violation of the prohibitions under this Act and to award damages to such party if such a violation has occurred. Sets forth specified additional authorities of the FCC.</summary>
</bill>
