<bill session="111" type="h" number="6109" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Data Collection Improvement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to ensure that each HHS health service program or HHS health survey provides, to the extent the Secretary determines appropriate and practicable, for the voluntary collection of data on the sexual orientation and gender identity of individuals who apply for or receive health services through such program, or who respond to such survey.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2010-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 12 - 10 .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2010--Introduced.
Health Data Collection Improvement Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to ensure that the collection of data on sexual orientation and gender identity is provided for within HHS health service programs and health surveys. Makes the provision of such information by an individual voluntary. Prohibits an agency or person that collects data from an individual from using such data, or the decision of the individual not to provide such data, in any manner that adversely affects the individual. Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop standards for the measurement of, and collection of information about, sexual orientation and gender identity; (2) analyze data collected under this Act to detect and monitor health disparities at the federal and state levels; (3) report to Congress and the public on the results of such analyses; and (4) integrate such data analyses with other activties that identify and analyze health disparities by race, ethnicity, sex, disability, primary language, or other population. Applies privacy protections to data collected under this Act and security safeguards to the collection, analysis and sharing of such data.</summary>
</bill>
