<bill session="112" type="h" number="6238" updated="2013-07-20T02:03:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Post Office Relocation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 39, United States Code, to authorize the United States Postal Service to sell, at fair market value, any post office building subject to relocation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2012-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2012--Introduced.
Community Post Office Relocation Act - Authorizes the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) to sell, at fair market value, to certain tax-exempt private organizations fee simple title to USPS-owned post office buildings containing an office subject to relocation. Requires such tax-exempt private organizations, in order to be considered an eligible buyer, to have operated primarily within the geographic area served by the relevant post office building for at least five years prior to a USPS announcement that the building will be available for sale. Sets forth a procedure for the USPS to enter negotiations with eligible buyers in the order in which buyers submit their offers. Directs the USPS to sell such a building to the first organization submitting an offer for fair market value if all other relevant conditions are met within specified time periods. Permits the USPS, after the sale of a building under this Act, to lease the building from the buyer at fair market value for purposes of operating a post office. Requires the USPS, if a buyer under this Act makes the building available for sale, to maintain a right of first refusal to purchase the building back from the buyer at the lesser of fair market value or the purchase price plus any improvements.</summary>
</bill>
