<bill session="110" type="h" number="1751" updated="2013-07-19T21:19:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Land Avalanche Protection Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a coordinated avalanche protection program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-28">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-28">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-28">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="1703"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1703"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3042"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Artillery"/>
    <term name="Avalanches"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Ordnance"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/28/2007--Introduced.
Federal Land Avalanche Protection Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, to establish an avalanche protection program to: (1) identify the potential for avalanches on federal lands and inform the public about the probability of avalanches and their potential adverse effects; (2) carry out ongoing research to improve avalanche forecasting; and (3) reduce the risks of avalanches and mitigate their effects.Requires the Secretary: (1) to coordinate the program to ensure protection for recreational users of public land under the Secretary of the Interior's jurisdiction, using resources of the Forest Service's National Avalanche Center; (2) to establish an advisory committee to assist in program development and implementation; and (3) with the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of the Army, to establish a central depository for weapons, ammunition, and parts for avalanche control purposes.Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to carry out projects and activities to: (1) assist in the prevention, forecasting, detection, and mitigation of avalanches; (2) maintain essential transportation, utilities, and communications; (3) assist avalanche artillery users to ensure the availability of adequate supplies of artillery and explosives required for avalanche control in specified areas; and (4) assist research and development activities for alternatives to minimize reliance on military weapons for avalanche control.Directs the Secretary to give priority to projects carried out in avalanche zones with a high frequency or severity of avalanches or in which deaths, injuries, or damage to public facilities and communities have occurred. Requires the Administrator of General Services to transfer specified property suitable for avalanche control purposes to a user of surplus ordnance.</summary>
</bill>
