<bill session="109" type="s" number="1247" updated="2013-07-19T20:24:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Youth Service Scholarship Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a scholarship program to encourage and support students who have contributed substantial public services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2005-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2005-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2005-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2005-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6492-6493"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S6493" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Service learning"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="Student employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/2005--Introduced.
Youth Service Scholarship Act of 2005 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a Public Service Incentives college scholarship program to reward low-income students who have, during high school, and who continue, during college, to make significant public service contributions to their communities. Requires 300 hours of public service by the student: (1) during each of two academic years of secondary school, to be eligible for a scholarship for the first year of college; and (2) during the preceding postsecondary academic year, to be eligible for a second, third, or fourth year. Requires such students to: (1) have been eligible for a free or reduced price lunch under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act; and (2) be eligible to receive Federal Pell Grants in the year in which the scholarships are awarded. Sets the scholarship amount at $5,000 for any academic year during a student's first four years of undergraduate education, and provides for adjustments of such amount in the event of insufficient appropriations. Requires applications to demonstrate maintenance of satisfactory academic progress and at least a 3.0 grade point average. Requires program dissemination and promotion.</summary>
</bill>
