<bill session="109" type="s" number="3529" updated="2013-07-19T20:44:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mom's Opportunity to Access Health, Education, Research, and Support for Postpartum Depression Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">MOTHERS Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that new mothers and their families are educated about postpartum depression, screened for symptoms, and provided with essential services, and to increase research at the National Institutes of Health on postpartum depression.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2006-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2006-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2006-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5966"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Childbirth"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Fathers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Mental depression"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mothers"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2006--Introduced.
Mom's Opportunity to Access Health, Education, Research, and Support for Postpartum Depression Act or the MOTHERS Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to: (1) states to provide to women who have recently given birth and their families, before such women leave their birthing centers, education concerning postpartum depression, postpartum mood and anxiety disorders, and postpartum psychosis and to screen new mothers for such postpartum conditions during their first year of postnatal checkup visits; and (2) public or nonprofit private entities to provide for the delivery of essential services to individuals with such postpartum conditions and their families. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, and the heads of other federal agencies that administer federal health programs, to organize a series of national meetings that are designed to develop a research plan for postpartum depression and psychosis. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to expand and intensify research relating to postpartum conditions to carry out such plan.</summary>
</bill>
