<bill session="111" type="s" number="2726" updated="2013-07-20T00:50:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Minuteman Missile National Historic Site Boundary Modification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to modify the boundary of the Minuteman Missile National Historic Site in the State of South Dakota, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11119"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-318.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment. With written report No. 111-262.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-08-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="532">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 532.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5153"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Minuteman Missile National Historic Site Boundary Modification Act - Amends the Minuteman Missile National Historic Site Establishment Act of 1999 to modify the boundary of the Minuteman Missile National Historic Site in South Dakota by including in the Historic Site a visitor facility and administrative site located on a specified parcel of land that consists of approximately 25 acres of land in the Buffalo Gap National Grassland. Transfers administrative jurisdiction over such land from the Secretary of Agriculture to the Secretary of the Interior. Modifies the boundary of the Buffalo Gap National Grassland to exclude the transferred land.</summary>
</bill>
