<bill session="109" type="h" number="2284" updated="2013-07-19T19:24:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transportation Empowerment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To empower States with authority for most taxing and spending for highway programs and mass transit programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Highway use tax"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Military transportation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Tunnels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2005--Introduced.
Transportation Empowerment Act - Authorizes appropriations out of the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) for the interstate maintenance program, the interstate and Indian reservation bridge program, the Federal lands highways program, highway safety programs, and transportation research programs. Authorizes a state, upon determining that excess funds have been made available, to transfer the excess funds to, and use such funds for, any surface transportation purpose (including mass transit and rail) in the state. Revises requirements regarding state apportionments under the interstate maintenance component for resurfacing, restoring, rehabilitating, and reconstructing the Interstate System. Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to: (1) extend the availability of HTF funds for authorized expenditures; (2) set a essential programs financing rate for gasoline, special motor fuels, kerosene, and diesel fuel; (3) establish in the HTF an Infrastructure Special Assistance Fund; and (4) provide for the return of excess tax receipts to states for transportation purposes. Directs the head of each executive agency to: (1) assist state and local governments in efforts to privatize their transportation infrastructure assets; and (2) approve requests from such governments to privatize such assets and waive or modify conditions relating to the original Federal program that funded the asset under specified circumstances. Amends the IRC to reduce taxes on gasoline, diesel fuel, kerosene, and special fuels funding the HTF.</summary>
</bill>
