<bill session="112" type="s" number="1992" updated="2013-07-20T02:33:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Local Flexibility for Transit Assistance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide flexibility of certain transit functions to local entities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2011-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3022"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="3200"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3545"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/14/2011--Introduced.
Local Flexibility for Transit Assistance Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to make urbanized area formula grants for the operating costs of equipment and facilities for use in public transportation in an urbanized area with a population over 200,000 to a designated recipient, direct recipient, or subrecipient that provides public transportation in the area operating less than 100 buses in fixed-route service in the area during peak service hours. Authorizes a designated recipient or direct recipient that operates at least 100 buses in fixed-route service during peak service hours in an urbanized area with a population of more than 200,000 to use grant funds for the operating costs of public transportation equipment and facilities in such projects if: (1) the recipients are certified by the Secretary as being in a crisis period; and (2) the recipients' percentage of revenue for the operating costs of public transportation equipment and facilities from non-federal sources (excluding system-generated revenue) is equal to the previous fiscal year's revenue, or the revenue is derived from dedicated sources. Specifies percentage limitations on the use of funds for urbanized areas with populations between 200,000 and 500,000, between 500,000 and 1 million, and over 1 million. Defines "crisis period" to mean that: (1) the unemployment rate within the recipients' service area is 7% or higher for the preceding month, or (2) the national average retail price of regular gasoline during a quarter has increased by more than 10%.</summary>
</bill>
