<bill session="110" type="h" number="308" updated="2013-07-19T21:06:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">R.S. 2477 Rights-Of-Way Recognition Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To clarify congressional intent with respect to the nature of rights-of-way granted and accepted under former section 2477 of the Revised Statutes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2007--Introduced.
R.S. 2477 Rights-Of-Way Recognition Act - Expresses congressional intent with respect to the nature of authorized rights-of-way granted and accepted for the construction of highways (routes over which the public has a right of passage, including routes used for travel, such as roads for motorized vehicles, carriage ways, navigable rivers, trails, and footpaths) over public lands not reserved for public uses under former section 2477 of the Revised Statutes. Describes the protocols that shall apply with respect to maintenance, repairs, and improvements of R.S. 2477 highways. Acknowledges and recognizes public rights-of-way over federal land (or any federal-land portion of a public right-of-way over both federal and non-federal land) for highways shown in certain official governmental maps and aerial photographs as having validly vested under R.S. 2477 and disclaims all right, title, and interest with respect thereto.</summary>
</bill>
