<bill session="113" type="s" number="964" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a comprehensive review of the adequacy of the training, qualifications, and experience of the Department of Defense personnel responsible for sexual assault prevention and response for the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2013-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2013--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to review the adequacy of the training, qualifications, and experience of each member of the Armed Forces and civilian DOD employee who is currently responsible for sexual assault prevention and response within the Armed Forces. Includes in such review an assessment of the adequacy of the training and certifications required of Sexual Assault Response Coordinators and Sexual Assault Victim Advocates by the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012. Requires the Secretary, upon a determination that any member or civilian employee responsible for sexual assault prevention and response does not have the training, qualifications, or experience required to discharge such responsibilities, to take appropriate responsive actions that include: (1) retraining or recertification, or (2) reassignment and replacement of the member or employee. Directs the Secretary, following the review required by this Act, to prescribe in regulations: (1) appropriate minimum levels of training, qualifications, and experience for such personnel; and (2) requirements for improvements in training, including of Sexual Assault Response Coordinators and Sexual Assault Victim Advocates.</summary>
</bill>
