<bill session="111" type="h" number="5233" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to recognize the contributions made by the spouses of members of the Armed Forces who serve in combat through the presentation of an official lapel button, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2010-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2010-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4043"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2010--Introduced.
Directs that a lapel button be designed, as approved by the Secretary of Defense (DOD), to identify and recognize the spouse of a member of the Armed Forces who is serving or has served in a combat zone for more than 30 days. Requires such button to be known as the spouse-of-a-combat-veteran lapel button. Authorizes the Secretary to use appropriated funds to procure such buttons, and to provide for their presentation to eligible spouses. States that the 30-day service period shall not apply if the member is killed or wounded before its expiration. Expresses the sense of Congress that, as soon as the buttons become available, the Secretary should: (1) widely announce their availability through military and public information channels; and (2) encourage commanders at all levels to conduct ceremonies recognizing the support provided by such spouses and to use such ceremonies as an opportunity for members to present their spouses with the button.</summary>
</bill>
