<bill session="111" type="s" number="3760" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Automatic IRA Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand personal savings and retirement savings coverage by allowing employees not covered by qualified retirement plans to save for retirement through automatic IRAs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6904-6905"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6099"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Automatic IRA Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) require certain employers who do not maintain qualified retirement plans or arrangements to make available to their eligible employees a payroll deposit individual retirement account (IRA) arrangement (automatic IRA arrangement) which grants such employees the right to opt-out of participation; (2) require the Secretary of the Treasury to provide employers with a model notice for notifying employees of automatic IRS arrangements and to establish a program to assist employers in the implementation of such arrangements; (3) allow employers who do not have more than 100 employees a tax credit for costs associated with establishing an automatic IRA arrangement; (4) impose a penalty on employers who fail to provide eligible employees access to automatic IRA arrangements; and (5) increase the tax credit for small employer pension plan start-up costs. Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Labor to jointly conduct feasibility studies on extending spousal consent requirements to automatic IRAs, promoting the use of low-cost lifetime income arrangements, and using investment data to notify individuals with multiple small balance retirement accounts of consolidation options.</summary>
</bill>
