<bill session="112" type="h" number="5965" updated="2013-07-20T02:01:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Chief of the Forest Service to make the Forest Service First and Second Generation Modular Airborne FireFighting System (MAFFS) units available to units of the Air National Guard and Air Force Reserve that have the aircraft capability and pilot and crew member training adequate for utilizing such firefighting systems to help alleviate the shortage of air tankers to fight wildfires.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2012-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2012--Introduced.
Requires the Chief of the Forest Service to make the eight Forest Service First Generation Modular Airborne FireFighting System (MAFFS I) units available, without compensation, to units of the Air National Guard and Air Force Reserve that have C-130H aircraft configured to contain such an MAFFS I unit and adequate pilot and crew member training in its use to fight wildfires. Directs the Chief to make the nine Forest Service Second Generation Modular Airborne FireFighting System (MAFFS II) units immediately available, without compensation, to specified units of the Air National Guard and Air Force Reserve in Wyoming, North Carolina, Colorado, and California. Prohibits the Chief from procuring air tankers to fight wildfires from a foreign government without certifying that MAFFS air tanker support available from units of the Air National Guard and Air Force Reserve is being fully utilized or is insufficient to address wildfires on National Forest System land.</summary>
</bill>
