<bill session="111" type="h" number="368" updated="2013-07-19T23:15:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coastal and Estuarine Land Conservation Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the acquisition of land and interests in land from willing sellers to improve the conservation of, and to enhance the ecological values and functions of, coastal and estuarine areas to benefit both the environment and the economies of coastal communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2009-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2009-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2009-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="170"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/9/2009--Introduced.
Coastal and Estuarine Land Conservation Program Act - Amends the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to authorize the Secretary of Commerce to conduct a Coastal and Estuarine Land Conservation Program to protect important coastal and estuarine areas that have significant conservation, recreation, ecological, historical, or aesthetic values and that are threatened by conversion from their natural, undeveloped, or recreational state to other uses or that could be managed or restored to effectively conserve, enhance, or restore ecological function. Requires the program to be administered by the National Ocean Service of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) through the Office of Ocean and Coastal Resource Management. Authorizes the Secretary to make Program grants to coastal states with approved coastal zone management plans or National Estuarine Research Reserve units for the purpose of acquiring property that will further the goals of an approved Coastal Zone Management Plan or Program, a National Estuarine Research Reserve management plan, a regional or state watershed protection or management plan, or a state coastal land acquisition plan. Provides that grant awards may be used to purchase land, including an easement, only from a willing seller. Provides that grant funds under the Program shall require a 100% match from nonfederal sources, subject to a waiver. Reserves 15% of program funds for acquisitions benefiting the National Estuarine Research Reserve.</summary>
</bill>
