<bill session="113" type="s" number="1279" updated="2013-11-02T07:03:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom to Pray Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the revocation or withholding of Federal funds to programs whose participants carry out voluntary religious activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2013-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="2926"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2013--Introduced.
Freedom to Pray Act - Prohibits the federal government from revoking or withholding federal financial assistance that would otherwise be provided to any recipient on the basis of religious activities that are conducted voluntarily and initiated by participants in a program or activity carried out by such recipient. Prohibits this Act from being construed to authorize the United States or any state or political subdivision to: (1) sponsor a religious activity, (2) prohibit a recipient of federal financial assistance from ensuring that a religious activity does not materially and substantially interfere with the orderly conduct of the program or activities carried out by such recipient, (3) require any person to participate in prayer or other religious activity, or (4) compel any employee or agent of a program or activity that is carried out by a recipient of federal financial assistance to participate in an activity if the content of the speech at the activity is contrary to their beliefs.</summary>
</bill>
