<bill session="110" type="h" number="3290" updated="2013-07-19T21:32:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">School Environment Protection Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to require local educational agencies and schools to implement integrated pest management systems to minimize the use of pesticides in schools and to provide parents, guardians, and employees with notice of the use of pesticides in schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Horticulture and Organic Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Horticulture and Organic Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Integrated pest management"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Playgrounds"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public schools"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School boards"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2007--Introduced.
School Environment Protection Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) establish a National School Integrated Pest Management Advisory System to develop and update uniform standards and criteria for implementing integrated pest management systems in schools; (2) establish a National School Integrated Pest Management Advisory Board; and (3) provide grants to local educational agencies to develop such systems. Prohibits: (1) the application of a pesticide when a school or school ground is occupied or in use; or (2) the use of an area or room treated by a pesticide, other than a least toxic pesticide, during the 24-hour period beginning at the end of the treatment. Requires each local educational agency or school to provide notice of the integrated pest management system of the school district at the beginning of each school year and to give prior notice of any use of a pesticide (other than a least toxic pesticide). Prescribes procedures to be followed if a pest cannot be controlled after having used an integrated pest management system and least toxic pesticides. Prescribes civil penalties for violations of this Act. Establishes the Integrated Pest Management Trust Fund to carry out education, training, propagation, and development activities under school integrated pest management systems.Prohibits, any later than six years after this Act's enactment, the use of any pesticide other than a least toxic pesticide in schools unless the Administrator has met the requirements of this Act. Prohibits the Administrator from removing any pesticide that is included on the list of pesticides exempted from regulation under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act or refusing to add a pesticide to such list solely on the grounds that the pesticide is claimed to be able to be used to control a public health pest.</summary>
</bill>
