<bill session="111" type="h" number="3216" updated="2013-07-19T23:41:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Local Television Freedom Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to permit the retransmission of signals of local television broadcast stations in an adjacent underserved county, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400345"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400026" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412262" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400096" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400177" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412217" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412227" joined="2009-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-14">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-14">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications, Technology, and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications, Technology, and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2009--Introduced.
Local Television Freedom Act of 2009 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to allow retransmission of a television broadcast station's signals by a multichannel video programming distributor to a subscriber located in the station's adjacent underserved county, unless the station certifies to the distributor that it is under no legal obligation restricting its ability to grant retransmission consent to the distributor. Prohibits a television broadcast station that elects retransmission consent from requesting as a condition to receiving retransmission consent that a multichannel video programming distributor not exercise its right to carry any other broadcast station in the station's adjacent underserved county. Allows a satellite carrier to provide service under a statutory license to the adjacent underserved county within which a household is located. Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to revise regulations concerning network nonduplication, syndicated exclusivity, and sports blackout protection against the retransmission by a multichannel video programming distributor to permit such retransmission if the receiving subscriber is in the station's adjacent underserved county. Imposes statutory copyright licensing in certain situations on the secondary transmission of a television broadcast station into an adjacent underserved county, except when dealing with a performance or display of a work made by that station. Defines "adjacent underserved county" as a county within the station's adjacent market that is both: (1) located in the same state as the station's community of license; and (2) not within the local market of any other station that is both affiliated with the same network and located in the same state as such other station's community of license. Declares that the secondary transmission of a performance or display of a work embodied in a primary transmission is not an infringement of copyright if the secondary transmission is to a subscriber in a broadcast station's adjacent underserved county.</summary>
</bill>
