<bill session="112" type="h" number="4225" updated="2013-07-20T01:46:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">School Environment Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to require local educational agencies and schools to implement integrated pest management programs to minimize the use of pesticides in schools and to provide parents, guardians, and employees with notice of the use of pesticides in schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2012-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition and Horticulture .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Nutrition and Horticulture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2012--Introduced.
School Environment Protection Act - Amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA) to require each local educational agency (agency) of a school district to implement an integrated pest management (IPM) program that: (1) applies to school buildings and school ground, (2) establishes an IPM coordinator within the agency, and (3) follows an IPM plan for addressing school pest problems. Prohibits agencies or schools from using: (1) pesticides other than nontoxic or least toxic (as defined in this Act) pesticides, or (2) synthetic fertilizers. Permits an agency or school to use: (1) a least toxic pesticide as part of the IPM program only as a last resort and only if the area or room treated is unoccupied or not in use, and (2) only natural organic fertilizers. Authorizes a school to use a pesticide otherwise if: (1) the school or agency determines that a pest in the school or on school grounds cannot be controlled after having used the IPM program and least toxic pesticides and it is a public health emergency, (2) the IPM coordinator approves of the application of the pesticide product, (3) the area or room treated is vacant during the application and for 24-hours after the application, (4) the application is made by a certified pesticide applicator, and (5) the school notifies the parents or guardians of each student 24 hours before application of the pesticide. Sets forth requirements for such notification. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a National School Integrated Pest Management Advisory Board to: (1) establish uniform standards and criteria for developing IPM, and (2) develop standards for the use of least toxic pesticides in schools. Requires the Administrator to: (1) appoint an official for school pest management within EPA's Office of Pesticide Programs to coordinate the implementation of IPM programs in schools, and (2) publish an IPM plan and a list of products containing the least toxic pesticides and restrictions on their use. Requires each agency, state pesticide lead agency, and the Administrator to create school environments that are protected from pesticides that drift from treated land to school grounds. Establishes the Integrated Pest Management Trust Fund. Requires the Administrator to provide grants to agencies to implement IPM systems.</summary>
</bill>
