<bill session="110" type="hr" number="603" updated="2013-07-19T20:55:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives on the announcement of the Government of the Russian Federation of its intention to suspend implementation of the Treaty on Conventional Armed Forces in Europe.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2007-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-09-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1692"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="sr" number="278"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Conventional weapons"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Georgia (Republic)"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military withdrawal"/>
    <term name="Moldova"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2007--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the government of the Russian Federation's announcement of its intention to suspend implementation of the 1990 Treaty on Conventional Armed Forces in Europe (CFE Treaty) may unnecessarily heighten tensions in Europe and urges the government of the Russian Federation to reconsider such intention and engage in a dialogue to resolve outstanding problems. Recognizes the CFE Treaty as a cornerstone of European security. Calls on the Russian Federation to fulfill its Istanbul Commitments of 1999 and withdraw all remaining forces and military equipment from Georgia and Moldova. Calls on all States Parties to ensure that the resolution of the current disputes surrounding the CFE Treaty be considered a priority at the highest political levels. Encourages officials of the government of the Russian Federation to refrain from belligerent statements that polarize relations and jeopardize security in Europe.</summary>
</bill>
