<bill session="112" type="h" number="2988" updated="2013-07-20T01:36:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Green Export Promotion and Job Creation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to enhance awareness of export promotion activities with respect to clean energy and environmental products and services of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400025"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA18" subcommittee="Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2011--Introduced.
Green Export Promotion and Job Creation Act - Amends the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to revise provisions relating to export promotion to require the Under Secretary for International Trade to establish an online directory for foreign buyers to identify U.S. manufacturers and service providers that are prepared to export products and services in: (1) clean and efficient energy generation, distribution, and use; (2) remediation of air and water pollution; (3) water supply; (4) sanitation, solid waste disposal, and chemical and hazardous waste treatment and containment; and (5) equipment and services for testing, monitoring, and analysis with respect to such areas or otherwise with respect to environmental hazards. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) establish a database, to be accessible only to U.S. government personnel, that identifies potential sales opportunities abroad for U.S. manufacturers and service providers that are prepared to export products and services in such areas; (2) develop and implement a system to evaluate the effectiveness and efficiency of U.S. export promotion activities with respect to clean and efficient energy and environmental products and services; and (3) establish, through the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee, standards for specified actions with respect to the export promotion activities concerning clean and efficient energy and environmental products and services that are engaged in by any federal agency. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to work with the International Renewable Energy Agency (IRENA) to identify countries that receive assistance from IRENA that improve the deployment and adoption of renewable energy in order to promote U.S. exports in clean and efficient energy and environmental products and services to that country.</summary>
</bill>
