<bill session="112" type="h" number="3654" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ALERT ACT</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Allowing Local Emergency Response Technicians to Accept Cellular Texts Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To adopt technology allowing 9-1-1 call centers to receive and respond to emergency text messages, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412497"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2012-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2012-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2012-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2012-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-13">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2011--Introduced.
Allowing Local Emergency Response Technicians to Accept Cellular Texts Act or the ALERT ACT - Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to complete a rulemaking requiring that if a consumer unsuccessfully attempts to communicate with a public safety answering point by sending a text message to 9-1-1 using a commercial mobile service, the provider of such service will respond with an error message to ensure that the consumer knows that the message has not been received by the answering point and to instruct the consumer on proper steps to reach emergency assistance. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to ensure that at least 10% of the federal funds awarded after enactment of this Act for emergency management performance grants authorized by the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 be used to test or implement equipment or services allowing members of the public to send 9-1-1 text messages to obtain emergency assistance.</summary>
</bill>
