<bill session="112" type="h" number="4028" updated="2013-07-20T01:44:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Senior Transportation and Mobility Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to improve transportation for seniors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2012-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1942"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2012--Introduced.
Senior Transportation and Mobility Improvement Act of 2012 - Amends the program providing formula grants to states for the special public transportation needs of older individuals and the disabled to allow states to use a portion of those grants to operate and maintain the capital assets acquired under that program. Sets the federal share of the costs of the mobility management activities such grants may cover at 90%. (Mobility management activities are designed to improve coordination among public and other transportation service providers.) Requires the National Transit Database to include information on the public transportation formula grant program for older individuals and the disabled, and the public transportation formula grant program for nonurban areas. Requires metropolitan planning organizations and states to involve older individuals and the disabled in metropolitan and statewide transportation planning. Directs the Administrator of the Federal Transit Administration (FTA) to enter into a cooperative agreement with the National Center on Senior Transportation to: (1) provide technical assistance to transit and human services organizations, (2) disseminate best practices regarding transportation for older individuals, and (3) make grants to nonprofit organizations to test innovative and replicable approaches for addressing the mobility needs of older individuals. Requires the FTA to make grants to nonprofit aging services organizations to offer mobility management services, and develop and implement enhanced technology to support those services.</summary>
</bill>
