<bill session="112" type="s" number="3396" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia Research Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for a national campaign to increase public awareness and knowledge of Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5135-5136"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2012--Introduced.
Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia Research Act of 2012 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to carry out a national campaign to increase public awareness and knowledge of Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia, including through: (1) the dissemination of information on the definition of Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia and on good neonatal care of Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia patients, (2) outreach to minority populations regarding Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia, and (3) the promotion of good prenatal care and ultrasound to detect Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia in utero. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to evaluate the amount of federal assistance provided for Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia research at NIH to determine whether funding levels are adequate. Expresses the sense of the Senate that the Director should consider allocating funds and other resources for Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia research.</summary>
</bill>
