<bill session="109" type="s" number="1390" updated="2013-07-19T20:25:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-15">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Coral Reef Conservation Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Coral Reef Conservation Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Coral Reef Conservation Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2005-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8233-8234"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8234-8235" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-07-21">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-11-17">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Stevens with amendments. With written report No. 109-182.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-11-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="294">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 294.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13684-13686" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S13684-13685" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2005-12-15" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13685-13686" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T22:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4788"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5622"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5622"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Coral reefs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Salvage"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2677"/>
    <amendment number="s2678"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/15/2005--Passed Senate amended.
Coral Reef Conservation Amendments Act of 2005 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 to extend the award of remaining grant funds under the coral reef conservation program, in addition to projects addressing emerging priorities or threats, to other appropriate projects, as identified by the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), including monitoring and assessment, research, pollution reduction, education, and technical support. Prohibits the Administrator from approving a coral reef conservation project unless it is consistent with a certain coral reef action strategy and will enhance conservation by: (1) promoting activities designed to minimize vessel impacts on coral reefs; and (2) assisting entities to work with local communities, and appropriate governmental and nongovernmental organizations, to support community-based planning and management initiatives for the protection of coral reef systems. (Sec. 3) Authorizes the Administrator to undertake emergency response actions to prevent or minimize the destruction or loss of, or injury to, coral reefs or coral ecosystems from vessel impacts, derelict fishing gear, vessel anchors and anchor chains, or damage from unforeseen or disaster-related circumstances. Requires the Administrator, when possible, to partner with other specified federal agencies and to leverage their resources for such purposes. (Sec. 4) Authorizes, under the national program to conserve coral reefs and coral ecosystems, any activities designed to minimize the likelihood of vessel impacts or other physical damage to coral reefs, including activities to identify certain at-risk coral reefs. (Sec. 5) Directs the Administrator to report triennially to Congress on all activities undertaken to implement the national coral reef action strategy, including: (1) a description of funds obligated by each participating federal agency to advance coral reef conservation; (2) a description of federal interagency and cooperative efforts with states and U.S. territories to prevent overharvesting, coastal runoff, or other anthropogenic impacts on coral reefs; (3) a summary of the information contained in the vessel grounding inventory, including additional funding, needed for response and removal of such vessels; (4) a description of federal disaster response actions taken under the National Response Plan to address damage to coral reefs and coral reef ecosystems; and (5) an assessment of the condition of U.S. coral reefs, accomplishments under this Act, and the effectiveness of management actions to address threats to coral reefs. (Sec. 6) Requires a nonprofit organization that receives project funds from the Coral Reef Conservation Fund to use them to address emergency response actions to prevent or minimize the destruction or loss of, or injury to, coral reefs or coral ecosystems from vessel impacts or other physical damage to coral reefs. Urges such organizations to solicit funding and in-kind services from the private sector (including nongovernmental organizations). Authorizes the Administrator to make community-based planning grants to certain entities to work with local communities and appropriate federal and state entities to implement plans for increased protection of high priority coral reefs. Authorizes the Administrator to: (1) maintain an inventory of all vessel grounding accidents involving coral reef resources; and (2) identify certain at-risk coral reefs that have a high incidence of vessel impacts, including appropriate measures to reduce such impacts. Directs the Administrator to work in coordination with other federal agencies, states, and U.S. territorial governments to implement the national coral reef action strategies (including regional and local strategies) to address multiple threats to coral reefs and coral reef ecosystems such as coastal runoff, vessel impacts, and overharvesting. (Sec. 7) Reauthorizes the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 and authorizes appropriations through FY2012 for: (1) the coral reef conservation program; and (2) community-based planning grants.</summary>
</bill>
