<bill session="111" type="s" number="661" updated="2013-07-20T00:29:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Restoring America's Manufacturing Leadership through Energy Efficiency Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to strengthen American manufacturing through improved industrial energy efficiency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2009-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3572"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3572-3574" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1462"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2009--Introduced.
Restoring America's Manufacturing Leadership through Energy Efficiency Act of 2009 - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to require the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to provide funding for a revolving loan program that enables manufacturers to implement commercially available technologies or processes that significantly reduce systems energy intensity and improve U.S. industrial competitiveness. Requires the Secretary to establish collaborative research and development partnerships with other programs within the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy to promote early stage energy efficiency technology development and achievement of such other programs' goals. Requires the Secretary to implement: (1) a sustainable manufacturing initiative; and (2) a joint industry-government partnership program to research and develop new sustainable manufacturing and industrial technologies and processes that maximize the energy efficiency of systems, reduce pollution, and conserve natural resources. Requires the Secretary to assess the commercial availability of cost competitive energy efficiency technologies that are not widely implemented within the United States for specified energy intensive industries. Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to: (1) make specified research on industry-specific road maps eligible for funding under the Future of Industry Program; and (2) require the Secretary to establish a Center of Excellence at up to 10 of the highest performing industrial research and assessment centers to coordinate with and advise other industrial research and assessment centers. Requires the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to expedite consideration of applications for loans under the Small Business Act that implement such centers' recommendations. Increases the appropriations authorized for FY2010-FY2012 for DOE's program for optimizing energy efficiency and economic competitiveness of energy-intensive industrial and commercial sectors. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to require the Secretary to implement a program to provide funding for state-industry partnerships to develop, demonstrate, and commercialize new technologies or processes for industries that significantly: (1) reduce energy use and energy intensive feedstocks, pollution and greenhouse gas emissions, and industrial waste; and (2) improve domestic industrial cost competitiveness. Requires the Secretary to: (1) arrange with the National Academy of Sciences for a study of the development of advanced manufacturing capabilities for various energy technologies; and (2) establish an advisory steering committee to provide recommendations on planning and implementation of DOE's Industrial Technologies Program.</summary>
</bill>
