<bill session="112" type="hr" number="479" updated="2013-07-20T01:07:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-06T16:12:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-12-06T16:12:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 10) to amend chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, to provide that major rules of the executive branch shall have no force or effect unless a joint resolution of approval is enacted into law, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-01T18:59:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-311, by Mr. Nugent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-01T18:59:00-05:00">
      <text>The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. The resolution waives all points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended. Section 2 provides that during any recess or adjournment of not more than 3 days, the Speaker may reconvene the House at any time. Section 3 of the resolution provides for a conference report and the accompanying joint statement under clause 8(a)(1) of rule XXII.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-12-01T18:59:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="95">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 95.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-12-06T12:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8146-8152" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-06T12:33:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 479.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-06T13:23:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 479, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Ms. Slaughter demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-06T15:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8167-8169" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-06T16:06:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 236 - 184 (Roll no. 889).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8167-8168" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-12-06T16:12:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="890" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 235 - 180 (Roll no. 890).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8146-8147" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-12-06T16:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="10"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/1/2011--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 10) to amend chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, to provide that major rules of the executive branch shall have no force or effect unless a joint resolution of approval is enacted into law.</summary>
</bill>
