<bill session="112" type="h" number="491" updated="2013-07-20T01:14:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-24T16:56:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-04-24T16:56:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify the boundaries of Cibola National Forest in the State of New Mexico, to transfer certain Bureau of Land Management land for inclusion in the national forest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412281"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-02-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-04-16T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-435.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-04-16T17:07:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="302">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 302.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bishop (UT) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2049-2050" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 491.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-04-24T16:56:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2049" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24T16:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2012--Passed House without amendment.
Expands the boundaries of the Cibola National Forest in New Mexico to include the Crest of Montezuma. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to transfer administrative jurisdiction over such land to the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) for inclusion in the Forest. Instructs the Secretary of Agriculture to administer any permit or other land use authorization for such transferred land that is still in effect as of the transfer date in accordance with the terms of such permit or authorization. Permits such Secretary, upon the expiration of such a permit or authorization, to reauthorize the use covered by that permit or authorization under the authorities available to the Secretary on such terms and conditions as considered in the public interest. Allows the Secretary of Agriculture to acquire, with the owner's consent, the private land included within the boundaries of the Forest by this Act. Requires any federally owned lands that have already been or hereafter may be acquired for National Forest System purposes within the Forest's boundaries, as modified by this Act, to be managed as lands acquired under the Act of March 1, 1911, commonly known as the Weeks Act, and according to the other laws and regulations that pertain to the System. Withdraws the Crest of Montezuma from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the public land mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, geothermal leasing, and mineral materials laws.</summary>
</bill>
