<bill session="111" type="h" number="4963" updated="2013-07-19T23:57:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Milk and Dairy Choices in Schools Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the child nutrition laws to require that milk served in school lunch programs be consistent with the Dietary Guidelines for Americans and to expand eligibility for the Special Milk Program, and to establish a pilot program providing low-fat cheeses for school breakfast and lunch programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2010-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2010--Introduced.
Healthy Milk and Dairy Choices in Schools Act of 2010 - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to require the fat content of milk served in school lunches to be consistent with the most recent Dietary Guidelines for Americans. Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to include nonprofit schools and child care institutions that participate in the school lunch or breakfast programs in the special milk program. (Currently, the special milk program reimburses nonprofit schools and child care institutions which do not participate in the school lunch or breakfast programs for the milk they provide to children.) Establishes a three-year pilot program under which the Secretary of Agriculture purchases low-fat cheeses, in addition to commodities currently purchased, for use in the school lunch and breakfast programs. Requires the Secretary to evaluate and report to Congress on the program. Allows the Secretary, through FY2016, to satisfy the requirement that at least 12% of school lunch program assistance be in the form of commodity assistance by using commodities procured by the Secretary under any provision of law.</summary>
</bill>
