<bill session="112" type="h" number="1920" updated="2013-07-20T01:26:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Clean Air Act to conform the definition of renewable biomass to the definition given the term in the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412475"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2011-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="781"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1220"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2011--Introduced.
Amends the Clean Air Act to redefine "renewable biomass" as: (1) materials (including trees, wood, brush, thinnings, and chips) or invasive species from certain National Forest System land and public lands, including slash and other materials, that would not otherwise be used for higher-value manufactured forest products and that are removed to reduce hazardous fuels, to reduce or contain disease or insect infestation, or to restore or maintain ecosystem health or that are removed from a federally approved vegetation management project, and that are harvested in accordance with applicable law and land management plans and specified requirements for old-growth forests; (2) any organic matter, including specified renewable plant material and waste material (including vegetative, animal, food, and yard waste), that is available on a renewable or recurring basis from non-federal land, land belonging to an Indian or Indian tribe that is held in trust by the United States or subject to a restriction against alienation imposed by the United States, or any Indian reservation; and (3) residues or byproducts from wood, pulp, or paper product facilities.</summary>
</bill>
