<bill session="112" type="s" number="1292" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Employment Protection Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to consider the impact on employment levels and economic activity prior to issuing a regulation, policy statement, guidance document, endangerment finding, or other requirement, implementing any new or substantially altered program, or denying any permit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400408"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2011-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1872"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2011--Introduced.
Employment Protection Act of 2011 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), prior to promulgating a regulation, policy statement, guidance document, or endangerment finding, implementing any new or substantially altered program, or issuing or denying any permit, to analyze the impact, disaggregated by state, of such requirements, policy statement, guidance, finding, program, permit, or permit denial on employment levels and economic activity. Requires such analysis to include estimated job losses and decreased economic activity due to the denial or issuance of permits, including permits issued under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act). Requires the Administrator to: (1) post such analysis on EPA's website and request governors of states experiencing more than a de minimis negative impact to post such analysis in their capitols; (2) hold public hearings in each state in which a requirement, program, or permit will have more than a de minimis negative impact on employment levels or economic activity; and (3) give notice of such impact in a state to such state's congressional delegation, governor, and legislature prior to the effective date of such requirement or program or the denial or issuance of a permit. Defines "de minimis negative impact" to mean: (1) a loss of more than 100 jobs (offsetting job gains that result from the hypothetical creation of new jobs through new technologies or government employment may not be used in the job loss calculation); and (2) a decrease in economic activity of more than $1,000,000 in a year (offsetting economic activity that result from the hypothetical creation of new economic activity through new technologies or government employment may not be used in the economic activity calculation).</summary>
</bill>
