<bill session="110" type="s" number="760" updated="2013-07-19T22:26:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Four Corners Television Access Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide certain counties with the ability to receive television broadcast signals of their choice.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400619"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Direct broadcast satellites"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Subscription television"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television relay systems"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2007--Introduced.
Four Corners Television Access Act of 2007 - Amends federal copyright law and the Communications Act of 1934 to allow certain counties and areas to receive broadcast transmissions of network television stations located in the capital of the state in which such counties and areas are located. Allows, notwithstanding any other provision of law, a satellite carrier, cable system, or translator station that elects to provide secondary transmission only to subscribers in the state who otherwise would not receive the primary transmission because the subscribers are in a designated market area outside of that state if: (1) the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) determines that it is in the best interest of the public welfare; and (2) the satellite carrier, cable system, or translator station agrees to also provide the secondary transmission in the assigned designated market area.</summary>
</bill>
