<bill session="112" type="h" number="770" updated="2013-07-20T01:16:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Border Enforcement Security Task Force Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a Border Enforcement Security Task Force program to enhance border security by fostering coordinated efforts among Federal, State, and local border and law enforcement officials to protect United States border cities and communities from trans-national crime, including violence associated with drug trafficking, arms smuggling, illegal alien trafficking and smuggling, violence, and kidnapping along and across the international borders of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400657"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="915"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2011--Introduced.
Border Enforcement Security Task Force Act of 2011 - Establishes in United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) a Border Enforcement Security Task Force (BEST) program to enhance border security by addressing and reducing border security threats and violence by: (1) facilitating collaboration among federal, state, local, tribal, and foreign law enforcement agencies to execute coordinated activities in furtherance of border security and homeland security; and (2) enhancing information-sharing among such agencies. Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), acting through the Assistant Secretary for ICE, to establish BEST units after considering: (1) whether the area where the unit would be established is significantly impacted by cross-border threats; (2) the availability of federal, state, local, tribal, and foreign law enforcement resources to participate in the unit; and (3) the extent to which border security threats are having a significant harmful impact in the area and in other jurisdictions. Authorizes the Secretary, in order to provide federal assistance to the area so designated, to: (1) obligate such sums as are appropriated for the BEST program; (2) direct the assignment of federal personnel to that program; and (3) take other actions to assist state, local, tribal, and foreign jurisdictions to participate. Directs the Secretary to report on the effectiveness of the program in enhancing border security and reducing the drug trafficking, arms smuggling, illegal alien trafficking and smuggling, violence, and kidnapping along and across U.S. borders.</summary>
</bill>
