<bill session="109" type="s" number="2827" updated="2013-07-19T20:38:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">POWER Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Privacy Officer With Enhanced Rights Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to clarify the investigative authorities of the privacy officer of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2006-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2006-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4701-4702, S4702-4703"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4702" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3041"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Oaths"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2006--Introduced.
Privacy Officer With Enhanced Rights Act of 2006 or the POWER Act of 2006 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the privacy officer of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) have access to all records and other materials available to DHS relating to programs and operations for which the privacy officer has responsibilities; (2) make necessary or desirable investigations and reports on the administration of DHS programs and operations; (3) subpoena the production, by persons other than federal agencies, of all information and other data and documentary evidence necessary to performance of the privacy officer's responsibilities; and (4) administer oaths, affirmations, or take affidavits. Requires: (1) the privacy officer to report to and be under the general supervision of the Secretary of DHS; and (2) the Secretary to report to Congress upon removing or transferring the officer to another position or location within DHS.</summary>
</bill>
