<bill session="112" type="h" number="3355" updated="2013-07-20T01:39:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Heroes Hiring Heroes Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a grant program to assist veterans find employment, to make permanent and modify the work opportunity tax credit with respect to unemployed veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2011-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/2011--Introduced.
Heroes Hiring Heroes Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a program to award grants to states to assist the employment of veterans. Allows the Secretary to award more than one grant per state. Limits grant amounts to $100,000. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend through 2016 the work opportunity tax credit for employers hiring previously unemployed veterans after 2011 and before 2017. Increases such credit with respect to such veterans. Provides a special tax credit for veteran-owned employers who hire previously unemployed veterans through a state job fair or forum after 2016.</summary>
</bill>
