<bill session="112" type="s" number="875" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drinking Water Right to Know Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to require additional monitoring of certain contaminants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/3/2011--Introduced.
Drinking Water Right to Know Act - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to require a public water system that detects an unregulated contaminant included in EPA's list of unregulated contaminants to be monitored by public water systems and included in the national drinking water occurrence data base, to continue to monitor&#160;for the detected contaminant for such period, at such frequency, and at such levels of concentration as the Administrator determines to be appropriate. Authorizes the data contained in the national drinking water contaminant occurrence data base to be used by the public. Requires the Administrator to: (1) evaluate the extent to which such data is accessible to and useable by the public; and (2) make such data more accessible to and useable by the public.</summary>
</bill>
