<bill session="111" type="h" number="3722" updated="2013-07-19T23:45:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhanced New Markets and Expanded Investment in Renewable Energy for Small Manufacturers Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to improve the New Markets Venture Capital and Renewable Fuel Capital Investment Programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412286"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Tax.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-21">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated into H.R. 3854.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSM19" subcommittee="Finance and Tax" name="House Small Business"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3854"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2009--Introduced.
Enhanced New Markets and Expanded Investment in Renewable Energy for Small Manufacturers Act of 2009 - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to require (under current law, authorizes) the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to participate in the new markets venture capital program (program) (a program under which investment companies provide capital financing to small businesses). Requires the Administrator, in selecting companies for program participation, to approve at least one company from each SBA geographic region. Provides for new market capital venture investment in, as well as operational assistance to, small businesses located in low-income geographic areas and engaged primarily in manufacturing. Makes the SBA definition of "low-income geographic area" the same as the definition of "low-income community" under the Internal Revenue Code. Expands SBA operational assistance to conditionally-approved companies. Directs the Administrator to grant each such company two years to satisfy capital and other requirements for such assistance. Provides: (1) a streamlined application process for new market venture capital companies; and (2) a simplified formula for operational assistance grants. Increases amounts allocated for investment in small businesses located in low-income geographic areas and engaged primarily in manufacturing. Redesignates (thereby expanding) the SBA's renewable fuel capital investment program as the renewable energy capital investment program. Makes such program permanent (currently a pilot program). Makes eligible under such program all small businesses (under current law, only smaller enterprises). Requires (under current law, authorizes) the Administrator to participate in such program. Increases amounts allocated for operational assistance grants for renewable energy purposes.</summary>
</bill>
