<bill session="113" type="hj" number="70" updated="2013-11-02T06:48:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-02T18:35:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-02T18:35:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Open our national parks and museums bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Park Service Operations, Smithsonian Institution, National Gallery of Art, and United States Holocaust Memorial Museum Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">National Park Service Operations, Smithsonian Institution, National Gallery of Art, and United States Holocaust Memorial Museum Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations for National Park Service operations, the Smithsonian Institution, the National Gallery of Art, and the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400376"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T16:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simpson moved to suspend the rules and pass the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T16:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6071-6077" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6071" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T16:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 70.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T17:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H.J. Res. 70.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T17:36:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T19:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6090-6091" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="508" datetime="2013-10-01T20:02:00-04:00" where="h" result="fail" suspension="1" state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the resolution Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 252 - 176 (Roll no. 508).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 370 Reported to House. The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 70, H.J. Res. 71, H.J. Res. 72, H.J. Res. 73, and H.R. 3230. The resolution provides for 30 minutes of debate on each measure and provides for one motion to recommit each measure. The resolution also provides that it shall be in order at any time through the calendar day of October 6, 2013, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T17:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 370.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6146-6155" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T17:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 70, H.J. Res. 71, H.J. Res. 72, H.J. Res. 73, and H.R. 3230. The resolution provides for 30 minutes of debate on each measure and provides for one motion to recommit each measure. The resolution also provides that it shall be in order at any time through the calendar day of October 6, 2013, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T17:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 70.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6152" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Van Hollen moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6152" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6152" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T17:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Van Hollen motion to recommit with instructions, pending a reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to replace the underlying bill with the Senate Amendment to H.J.Res. 59.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simpson raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Simpson stated that the provisions of the proposed amendment are not germane to the Joint Resolution. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Van Hollen appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simpson moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the Chair.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6154" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T18:29:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the appeal of the ruling of the Chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 230 - 194 (Roll no. 512).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="513" datetime="2013-10-02T18:35:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 252 - 173 (Roll no. 513).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6146" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T18:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read the first time pursuant to the order of Oct. 2, 2013.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 203 pursuant to the order of Oct. 2, 2013.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="370"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="370"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Humanities programs funding"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2013--Passed House without amendment.
National Park Service Operations, Smithsonian Institution, National Gallery of Art, and United States Holocaust Memorial Museum Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 - Makes appropriations for FY2014 for continuing projects or activities that were conducted in FY2013 and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available by the Full-Year Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 (division F of P.L. 113-6) under the following headings: "Department of the Interior--National Park Service--Operation of the National Park System," "United States Holocaust Memorial Museum--Holocaust Memorial Museum," "Smithsonian Institution," and "National Gallery of Art." Requires the rate of operations for each such account to be calculated to reflect the full amount of any reduction required in FY2013 pursuant to: (1) the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013, and (2) the presidential sequestration order dated March 1, 2013, except as attributable to budget authority made available by the Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-2). Makes appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under this joint resolution available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment into law of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution, (2) enactment into law of the applicable appropriations Act for FY2014 without any provision for such project or activity, or (3) December 15, 2013. Requires implementation of this joint resolution so that only the most limited funding action be taken in order to provide for continuation of projects and activities. Authorizes amounts made available for civilian personnel compensation and benefits in each agency to be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to avoid furloughs in such agencies, consistent with the applicable appropriations Act for FY2013, except that such authority shall not be used until after the agency has taken all necessary actions to reduce or defer non-personnel-related administrative expenses. Expresses the sense of Congress that this joint resolution may also be referred to as the Open Our National Parks and Museums Act.</summary>
</bill>
