<bill session="113" type="h" number="28" updated="2013-11-02T06:19:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Working Families' Access to Health Innovations Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to provide loan guarantees for the acquisition of health information technology by eligible professionals in solo and small group practices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/3/2013--Introduced.
Working Families' Access to Health Innovations Act of 2013 - Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to guarantee up to 90% of a loan made to a health care professional for the acquisition of health information technology for use in such professional's medical practice and for the costs associated with its installation. Provides loan guarantee limits, and authorizes the Administrator to impose a loan guarantee fee. Requires services provided by a small business development center to include: (1) facilitating the training of medical professionals in health information technology systems; and (2) establishing and providing a network of small health information technology companies available to such professionals in low-income and underserved areas for assistance in purchasing, utilizing, and maintaining such technology.</summary>
</bill>
