<bill session="110" type="h" number="5772" updated="2013-07-19T21:54:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-17T18:45:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-17T18:45:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Frank Melville Supportive Housing Investment Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Frank Melville Supportive Housing Investment Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Frank Melville Supportive Housing Investment Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 811 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to improve the program under such section for supportive housing for persons with disabilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2008-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2008-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2008-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2008-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2008-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2008-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2008-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-07-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-15T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 110-845.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-15T14:51:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="546">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 546.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-17T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Murphy (CT) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-17T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8358-8363" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-17T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5772.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-09-17T18:45:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8358-8361" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-17T18:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-10-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3593"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2008--Passed House amended.
Frank Melville Supportive Housing Investment Act of 2008 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (the Act) to revise requirements for supportive housing for persons with disabilities. (Retains authority to provide such assistance to private nonprofit organizations to expand the supply of such housing.) Repeals the authority of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to provide tenant-based rental assistance directly to eligible persons with disabilities. Authorizes appropriations for such assistance under section 8 (rental voucher program) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 for persons with disabilities in FY2009 in the amount necessary to provide the same number of incremental vouchers provided in FY2008. Requires the Secretary to issue guidance to public housing agencies (PHAs) receiving voucher assistance under this Act, as well as those that received such assistance under the United States Housing Act of 1937 for incremental vouchers for non-elderly disabled families during FY1997-FY2002, in order to ensure that such vouchers continue to be provided upon turnover to qualified persons with disabilities or to qualified non-elderly disabled families. (Sec. 3) Modifies project rental assistance contract requirements, including renewal of, and increases in, annual contract amounts. Requires initial contracts with the sponsor of a project assisted with any low-income housing tax credit or with any tax-exempt housing bonds to have an initial term of up to 360 months and to provide funding for 60 months. Revises the requirement that all units in housing assisted by capital advances and project rental assistance contracts be made available for occupancy by very low-income persons with disabilities for at least 40 years. Requires the Secretary, within 30 days of issuing certain capital advances for multifamily projects (except group homes or independent living facilities), to delegate review and processing of such projects to a state or local housing agency meeting specified criteria. Revises tenant selection procedures. Requires a lease between a tenant and a housing owner to be for at least one year. Revises the application of cost limitations developed by the Secretary to supportive housing. Authorizes the Secretary to waive such limitations. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a minimum percentage of capital advances per fiscal year for multifamily projects; and (2) carry out a project rental assistance competitive demonstration program to expand the supply of supportive housing for non-elderly adults with disabilities and with extremely low-incomes or for extremely low-income households that include at least one disabled person. (Sec. 5) Repeals the Secretary's authority to require an owner to deposit an amount up to $10,000 in a special escrow account to assure the owner's commitment to the housing. (Sec. 6) Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012. (Sec. 7) Requires the Secretary to issue new regulations and guidance for the program under the Act for supportive housing for persons with disabilities to carry out such program in accordance with the amendments made by this Act. (Sec. 8) Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress on the adequacy and effectiveness of the program in assisting households of persons with disabilities.</summary>
</bill>
