<bill session="112" type="h" number="66" updated="2013-07-20T01:10:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Waste-to-Energy Technology Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for an investment tax credit for waste-to-energy facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2011-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2012-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2011-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2011-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400280" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2011-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
Waste-to-Energy Technology Act of 2011 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a 30% energy tax credit for investment in qualified waste-to-energy property. Defines "qualified waste-to-energy property" as property comprising a system that uses municipal solid waste or sewage sludge as the feedstock for producing solid, liquid, or gas fuel, or for producing energy, and that is certified by the Secretary of the Treasury as eligible for a credit under this Act. Excludes certain landfill facilities from such definition. Requires the Secretary to establish criteria for awarding certifications for waste-to-energy projects, which shall include: (1) the commercial viability of such projects, (2) whether such projects use the least amount of recyclable materials and will provide the greatest net impact in avoiding or reducing air pollutants or anthropogenic emissions of greenhouse gases, (3) whether such projects will have the lowest levelized cost of generated or stored energy or of measured reduction in energy consumption or greenhouse gas emission, and (4) whether such projects pose the fewest risks (other than climate risks) to environmental and human health.</summary>
</bill>
