<bill session="112" type="s" number="1892" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Housing Rights for Victims of Domestic and Sexual Violence Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect the housing rights of victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2011-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7706"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7707-7708" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1925"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2011--Introduced.
Housing Rights for Victims of Domestic and Sexual Violence Act of 2011 - Amends the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 with respect to housing rights of victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking. Prohibits denial or termination of housing assistance on the basis of being such a victim under specified federal housing programs, including the low income housing tax credit program, if the applicant or tenant otherwise qualifies for such admission, assistance, participation, or occupancy. Prohibits denial of assistance, tenancy, or occupancy rights to assisted housing based solely on certain criminal activity directly related to domestic violence engaged in by a member of the individual's household or by any guest or other person under the individual's control, if the tenant or an immediate family member is the victim or threatened victim. Requires each owner or manager of housing assisted under a covered program to adopt an emergency transfer policy for tenants who are victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking. Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish policies and procedures under which a victim requesting such a transfer may receive section 8 (voucher program) assistance under the United States Housing Act of 1937. Makes conforming amendments to the United States Housing Act of 1937.</summary>
</bill>
