<bill session="111" type="hr" number="287" updated="2013-07-19T22:58:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Voting Record Transparency Resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Directing the Clerk of the House of Representatives to post on the public Internet site of the Office of the Clerk a record, organized by Member name, of recorded votes taken in the House, and directing each Member who maintains an official public Internet site to provide an electronic link to such record.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400631"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412011" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2010-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2009--Introduced.
Voting Record Transparency Resolution - Requires the Clerk of the House of Representatives to post on the public Internet site of the Office of the Clerk a record, organized by Member name, of the recorded votes of each Member (including each Delegate or Resident Commissioner) taken in the House, including the roll, date, issue, question, result, and title or description of the vote, and any cost estimate of the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) related to the vote. Requires each Member of the House who maintains an official public Internet site using amounts from the Members' Representation Allowance to provide a clearly presented electronic link on the site to his or her individual recorded vote information.</summary>
</bill>
