<bill session="111" type="h" number="6432" updated="2013-07-20T00:10:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vietnam Democracy Promotion Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote freedom and democracy in Vietnam.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412268"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1969"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1159"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2010--Introduced.
Vietnam Democracy Promotion Act of 2010 - Authorizes: (1) the President to provide assistance, through appropriate nongovernmental organizations and the Human Rights Defenders Fund, for the support of individuals and organizations to promote freedom and democracy in Vietnam; and (2) related appropriations. States that it is U.S. policy to take measures to overcome the jamming of Radio Free Asia by the government of Vietnam. Authorizes related appropriations. States that it is U.S. policy that programs of educational and cultural exchange with Vietnam should promote progress toward freedom and democracy in Vietnam by providing Vietnamese nationals with opportunities to see freedom and democracy in action. States that it is U.S. policy to offer refugee resettlement to nationals of Vietnam (including members of the Montagnard ethnic minority groups) who were eligible for the Orderly Departure Program (ODP), the Humanitarian Resettlement (HR) Program, the Resettlement Opportunities for Vietnamese Returnees (ROVR) Program, the Amerasian Homecoming Act of 1988, or any other U.S. refugee program and who were deemed ineligible due to administrative error or who for reasons beyond the control of such individuals were unable or failed to apply for such programs in compliance with Department of State deadlines. Provides funding for the protection (including resettlement) of Vietnamese refugees and asylum seekers, including Montagnards and ethnic Khmer in Cambodia and Thailand. Prohibits the U.S. government from providing nonhumanitarian assistance to the government of Vietnam in excess of FY2010 amounts unless the President certifies to Congress that the government of Vietnam has made substantial progress respecting political, media, and religious freedoms (and related property issues), minority rights, access to U.S. refugee programs, actions to end trafficking in persons, and treatment of government officials and military personnel of the former government of South Vietnam. Authorizes the President to waive such requirements if increased U.S. nonhumanitarian assistance would promote the purposes of this Act or is otherwise in the U.S. national interest.</summary>
</bill>
