<bill session="110" type="s" number="1293" updated="2013-07-19T22:31:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Education and Vocational Benefits Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend titles 10 and 38, United States Code, to improve educational assistance for members and former members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5585-5586"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S5586-5588" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/3/2007--Introduced.
Veterans' Education and Vocational Benefits Improvement Act of 2007 - Authorizes the accelerated payment of veterans' educational assistance under the Montgomery GI Bill for individuals who, during the period beginning October 1, 2008, and ending September 30, 2012, first enroll in an approved program of education not exceeding two years and not leading to an associate, bachelors, masters, or equivalent degree (in effect, for vocational school). Provides the same benefit for: (1) participants under the survivors' and dependents' educational assistance program; (2) members of the Selected Reserve; and (3) reserve personnel supporting contingency and other combat-related operations. Authorizes, for the latter personnel, the payment of 80% of the total educational assistance allowance for those serving an aggregate of three years or more in support of such contingency or related operations. Authorizes such personnel to make pay contributions for an increased amount of educational assistance.</summary>
</bill>
