<bill session="112" type="h" number="1284" updated="2013-07-20T01:21:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Armed Forces Suicide Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to enhance the suicide prevention program of the Department of Defense by specifically requiring suicide prevention training during recruit basic training, preseparation counseling, and mental health assessments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2012-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2011-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2011-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2011-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/2011--Introduced.
Armed Forces Suicide Prevention Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Defense to enhance the suicide prevention program of the Department of Defense (DOD) through the provision of suicide prevention information and resources to members of the Armed Forces from their initial enlistment or appointment through their final retirement or separation. Requires the Secretary of each military department (Secretary concerned) to include a training component on suicide prevention, which shall include: (1) methods for recognizing suicide risk factors; (2) protocols for responding to crisis situations involving members who may be at high risk for suicide; and (3) information about available suicide prevention services and best practices for suicide prevention. Directs the Secretary concerned to notify members of the the availability of and access to suicide prevention services during their preseparation counseling. Requires medical evaluations for the diagnosis of post-traumatic stress disorder or traumatic brain injury in members who were deployed overseas in support of a contingency operation to also include the provision of information on the availability of suicide prevention services and the member's right of access to such services.</summary>
</bill>
