<bill session="112" type="s" number="1803" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Permanent Guarantee of Sensible Treatment of Farm Dust Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to limit Federal regulation of nuisance dust in areas in which that dust is regulated under State, tribal, or local law, to establish a prohibition against revising any national ambient air quality standard applicable to nuisance dust, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1528"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/2011--Introduced.
Permanent Guarantee of Sensible Treatment of Farm Dust Act of 2011-&#160;Prohibits&#160;the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) from&#160; proposing, finalizing, implementing, or enforcing any regulation revising the national primary ambient air quality standard or the national secondary ambient air quality standard applicable to nuisance dust with an aerodynamic diameter greater than 2.5 micrometers under the Clean Air Act (CAA). Exempts nuisance dust from the CAA and excludes nuisance dust from&#160;references in such Act to particulate matter, except with&#160;respect to geographical areas where such dust is not regulated under state, tribal, or local law&#160;if the Administrator finds that: (1) nuisance dust (or any subcategory of nuisance dust) causes substantial adverse public health and welfare effects at ambient concentrations; and (2) the benefits of applying CAA standards and other requirements to such dust outweigh the costs. Defines "nuisance dust" as particulate matter: (1) generated from natural sources, unpaved roads, agricultural activities, earth moving, or other activities typically conducted in rural areas; or (2) consisting primarily of soil, other natural or biological materials, windblown dust, or some combination thereof.</summary>
</bill>
