<bill session="110" type="h" number="886" updated="2013-07-19T21:11:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-17T12:36:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-04-17T12:36:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wild Sky Wilderness Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Wild Sky Wilderness Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Wild Sky Wilderness Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Wild Sky Wilderness Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance ecosystem protection and the range of outdoor opportunities protected by statute in the Skykomish River valley of the State of Washington by designating certain lower-elevation Federal lands as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400232"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2007-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2007-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2007-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-89.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-04-17T12:00:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="54">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 54.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T12:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3406-3409" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T12:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 886.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-04-17T12:36:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3406" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T12:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-121.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-06-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="255">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 255.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="520"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Columbia River development"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Wild Sky Wilderness Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Designates certain lands in the Skykomish River valley, Washington, as the Wild Sky Wilderness, to be managed by the Secretary of Agriculture. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to establish a trail plan. Authorizes the use of helicopter access to construct and maintain a joint Forest Service-Snohomish County telecommunications repeater site to provide improved communication for safety, health, and emergency purposes. Allows the continued use of floatplanes on Lake Isabel in the Wild Sky Wilderness, subject to reasonable restrictions. Provides that such wilderness designation shall not preclude the operation and maintenance of the existing Evergreen Mountain Lookout in the same manner and degree in which the operation and maintenance were occurring as of the enactment of this Act. (Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary to acquire lands in the Wild Sky Wilderness by purchase, donation, or exchange, with priority to be given to specified Priority Acquisition Lands. Requires the boundaries of the Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest and the Wild Sky Wilderness to be adjusted to encompass any lands so acquired. Directs the Secretary to ensure adequate access to private in-holdings within the Wild Sky Wilderness. States that valuation of private lands shall be determined without reference to any restrictions on access or use which arise out of designation as a wilderness area. (Sec. 5) Requires the Secretary to accept specified lands within the Snoqualmie National Forest, Washington, from the Chelan County Public Utility District if the District offers such lands to the Secretary (in title acceptable to the Secretary, and provided there is no hazardous material on the site) in exchange for a permanent easement, including helicopter access, to maintain an existing telemetry site to monitor snow pack on land within the Wenatchee National Forest, Washington. Provides for extinguishment of the easement and reversion of all conveyed rights to the United States if the District no longer needs to maintain a telemetry site.</summary>
</bill>
