<bill session="113" type="s" number="923" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Balancing Food, Farm, and the Environment Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modernize the conservation title of the Food Security Act of 1985, protect long-term taxpayer investment, increase small and midsize farmer's access to programs, and prioritize modern-day conservation needs through management practices, local engagement, and stewardship.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1890"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Chesapeake Bay"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2013--Introduced.
Balancing Food, Farm, and the Environment Act of 2013 - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to make a producer violating certain conservation requirements under the highly erodible land or wetland programs ineligible for federal crop insurance premiums. Requires producers under the highly erodible land program and the wetland conservation program to comply with specified conservation requirements. Extends and revises: (1) the conservation reserve program, (2) the conservation stewardship program, and (3) the environmental quality incentives program. Establishes: (1) a conservation reserve easement program, and (2) a conservation innovation grant program. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to use Commodity Credit Corporation funds and facilities to carry out the following programs through FY2018: (1) the conservation reserve program, (2) the conservation security program, (3) the conservation stewardship program, (4) the environmental quality incentives program, (5) the conservation innovation grant program, (6) the agricultural conservation easement program, and (7) the conservation loan and loan guarantee program. Authorizes a conservation loan and loan guarantee program. Establishes an agricultural conservation easement program which shall combine the purposes and functions of the wetlands reserve program, the grassland reserve program, and the farmland protection program. Provides: (1) funding for the purchase by eligible entities of agricultural land easements and other interests in eligible land, and (2) assistance to owners of eligible land to restore and protect wetland through easements and related wetland easement plans. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into one or more agreements with a state, nongovernmental organization, or Indian tribe to carry out a special wetlands reserve enhancement program which shall include a reservation of haying and grazing component. Establishes a regional conservation partnership program which shall combine the purposes and functions of the agricultural water enhancement program, the Chesapeake Bay Watershed program, the cooperative conservation partnership initiative, and the Great Lakes basin program for soil erosion and sediment control. Repeals: (1) the emergency forestry conservation reserve program, (2) the wetlands reserve program, (3) the farmland protection program and farm viability program, (4) the grassland reserve program, (5) the environmental easement program, (6) the program of conservation innovation grants and payments, (7) the agricultural water enhancement program, (8) the wildlife habitat incentive program, (9) the Great Lakes Basin program, (10) the cooperative conservation partnership initiative, and (11) the desert terminal lakes program.</summary>
</bill>
