<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1090" updated="2013-07-19T23:05:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing the hearing of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate on the Don't Ask, Don't Tell policy, and the testimony of Secretary of Defense Robert M. Gates and Admiral Michael G. Mullen at the hearing, as an important first step in permitting gay and lesbian Americans to serve openly in the Armed Forces and expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the policy should be repealed in 2010.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2010-02-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-02-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E189"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Senate Committee on Armed Services"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/22/2010--Introduced.
Recognizes the hearing of the Senate Committee on Armed Services on the Don't Ask, Don't Tell policy (concerning sexual orientation in the military), and the testimony of Secretary of Defense Robert M. Gates and Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Admiral Michael G. Mullen, as an important first step in bringing about the repeal of such policy and in permitting gay and lesbian Americans to serve openly in the Armed Forces. Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the policy, as codified under federal law, should be repealed in 2010 and that repeal legislation should be promptly brought to a vote. Expresses the hope that President Obama will continue his leadership on this issue. Urges the Pentagon working group to deliver a repeal implementation plan to Congress as soon as possible while ensuring that the needs and concerns of members of the Armed Forces (members) are taken into consideration. Pledges that the House will do its part to move the repeal planning and implementation process forward in a timeline that is best for all members. Recommends that the Senate Armed Services Committee and the Subcommittee on Personnel Management of the House Armed Services Committee include members, regardless of their sexual orientation, in the upcoming hearings regarding the policy.</summary>
</bill>
