<bill session="111" type="h" number="3134" updated="2013-07-19T23:40:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthcare Innovation Zone Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a Healthcare Innovation Zone pilot program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400647"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7950"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3664"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2009--Introduced.
Healthcare Innovation Zone Program Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a Healthcare Innovation Zone (HIZ) pilot program, consisting of an HIZ planning grant program and an HIZ demonstration project, to increase health care provider integration and align health care provider incentives to improve health and reduce health care costs. Defines an "HIZ" as an integrated health care delivery network that works with local employers, community leaders, and private and governmental payors in a geographic region and that: (1) provides a full spectrum of care, including inpatient, outpatient, post-acute, and preventive care, to individuals, including Medicare beneficiaries; (2) has an academic medical center that provides tertiary and quaternary care, has existing capabilities to conduct health services research, and provides clinical training for health professionals; and (3) is able to accept alternative payment structures beyond fee-for-service and per diem amounts. Directs the Secretary to award between 10 and 25 grants of $250,000 to $1 million each to eligible entities for purposes of researching and preparing an HIZ model plan. Lists required contents of a plan, including: (1) a description of innovative models of care that improve quality and decrease costs; (2) a provider network that will provide the full spectrum of care; and (3) a target population and mechanisms to enroll such population. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish an HIZ demonstration project to test the effectiveness of HIZs in increasing health care provider integration, improving health care services, and reducing health care costs; and (2) select project participants from HIV model plan grant recipients. Requires the project to operate for at least three years, subject to renewal at the Secretary's discretion. Requires an HIZ established under this Act to provide comprehensive health care services to individuals who voluntarily enroll to receive such services for multi-year periods from the HIZ.</summary>
</bill>
