<bill session="111" type="h" number="4419" updated="2013-07-19T23:52:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reverse Mortgage Elder Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 138 of the Truth in Lending Act to establish certain counseling and disclosure requirements with respect to reverse mortgages.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412232"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/12/2010--Introduced.
Reverse Mortgage Elder Protection Act - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to prohibit a creditor from taking an application for a reverse mortgage unless the creditor has provided the applicant with: (1) a specified written cautionary statement before the applicant receives any counseling regarding reverse mortgages; (2) a specified written checklist before meeting with a counseling agency about reverse mortgages; and (3) a referral to a housing counseling agency for reverse mortgage counseling approved by the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). Requires a counseling agency to provide the same kind of written checklist to a consumer that seeks counseling before requesting a loan application for a reverse mortgage. Prohibits a creditor from either accepting a final application for a reverse mortgage, or from assessing any related fees, unless the creditor has received from the consumer or the consumer's authorized representative: (1) a written certification that the consumer has received counseling regarding reverse mortgages from a HUD-approved agency; and (2) a copy of the prescribed checklist signed by the agency counselor and by the consumer.</summary>
</bill>
