<bill session="112" type="h" number="5813" updated="2013-07-20T02:00:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ports as Small Business Incubators Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to provide for the establishment of the Ports as Small Business Incubators Program to provide eligible small businesses with access to commercial real property, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412498"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E837"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2012--Introduced.
Ports as Small Business Incubators Act of 2012 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish the Ports as Small Business Incubators Program. Requires the Administrator to award grants of at least $300,000 and up to $500,000 to port authorities selected by the Administrator. Allows grant funds to be used only for the costs of providing selected small businesses with access to commercial real property. Requires each Program participant, in providing such access, to give a priority to small businesses owned and controlled by women, veterans, or socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, as well as those that the participant determines would create "green" jobs (jobs involving the development of clean energy and the improvement of air and water quality).</summary>
</bill>
