<bill session="113" type="h" number="857" updated="2013-11-02T06:26:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Troops at War Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 251A of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to eliminate the Department of Defense sequestration for fiscal years 2013 and 2014 and sequester such eliminated sums over a period of fiscal years 2015 through 2021.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412513"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2013--Introduced.
Protect Troops at War Act of 2013 - Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to eliminate for FY2013-FY2014 the reductions to discretionary appropriations or direct spending for the defense function of the Department of Defense (DOD). Requires the reductions that would otherwise have occurred to be added to and distributed equally among the sequestration for such function for FY2015-FY2021. Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to transfer amounts appropriated for DOD by the Continuing Appropriations Resolution among DOD accounts. Requires account amounts, after such transfer, to be consistent with amounts appropriated or authorized for such accounts under a DOD appropriations or authorization Act for FY2013. Requires 15 days' advance notice of such transfers to the congressional defense and appropriations committees.</summary>
</bill>
