<bill session="113" type="h" number="3234" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pay Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To withhold the pay of Members of Congress, the President, and the Vice President if a Government shutdown is in effect or the Government is unable to make payments or meet obligations because the public debt limit has been reached, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400165"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3236"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2013--Introduced.
Pay Accountability Act - Requires the pay of Members of Congress, the President, and the Vice President to be withheld during any period of: (1) a lapse in appropriations for any federal agency as a result of a failure to enact a regular appropriations bill or continuing resolution, or (2) the federal government's inability to make payments or meet obligations because the public debt limit. Provides for such withheld amounts to be deposited in an escrow account to be transferred (on the last day of the Congress involved with respect to a Member, or the last day of the term of office involved with respect to the President or Vice President) to the Secretary of the Treasury and deposited in the Treasury for deficit reduction.</summary>
</bill>
