<bill session="110" type="s" number="3329" updated="2013-07-19T22:50:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">CARE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Compensation and Respect for Energy Workers Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to expand the category of individuals eligible for compensation, to improve the procedures for providing compensation, and to improve transparency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400619"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6766"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Brain"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Colon cancer"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Digestive diseases"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estates (Law)"/>
    <term name="Eye diseases"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leukemia"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Lung cancer"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Nervous system diseases"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prostate cancer"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Radiation victims"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Skin cancer"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Thyroid diseases"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2008--Introduced.
Compensation and Respect for Energy Workers Act of 2008 or the CARE Act - Amends the Radiation Exposure Compensation Act to expand the diseases for which individuals who were exposed to radiation from nuclear testing may claim compensation to include chronic lymphocytic leukemia, posterior subcapsular cataracts, nonmalignant thyroid nodular disease, parathyroid adenoma, malignant tumors of the brain and central nervous system, and brochio-alveolar carcinoma, and benign neoplasms of the brain and central nervous system. Amends the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to: (1) provide to potential claimants of compensation a list of physicians qualified to perform medical and impairment screenings and a written notice of benefits for which they may be eligible under such Act; (2) require exposure assessments of contaminated sites to identify by trade name (if any) any chemical commonly used in such sites; (3) require the Secretary of Labor to provide the public with site profiles and other information used to evaluate claims for compensation; (4) require payment of compensation to a claimant's estate if such claimant dies after filing a claim but before any compensation is paid and leaves no survivors; (5) expand the duties of the Office of the Ombudsman in the Department of Labor to include providing benefit information to claimants and contracting for expert services; and (6) extend to one year the limitation period for filing a petition for review in federal district court of any denial of a compensation claim. Allows claimants under the Act 120 days to respond to a request for information from the Secretary.Requires the promulgation of regulations for: (1) the direct payment to providers of personal care services and transportation expenses for claimants who receive medical benefits under the Act; (2) providing clear, concise, and easily understandable explanations of the claims process, including denials of claims; and (3) the retention of records in the Departments of Energy (DOE) and Labor that might be used by claimants in the claims process.</summary>
</bill>
