<bill session="113" type="s" number="1002" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Home Building Lending Improvement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enable Federal and State chartered banks and thrifts to meet the credit needs of home builders in the United States, and to provide liquidity and ensure stable credit in order to meet the need for new homes in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2013-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1255"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2013--Introduced.
Home Building Lending Improvement Act of 2013 - Directs each of the appropriate federal banking agencies to initiate guidance or rulemaking with respect to financial institutions under their respective jurisdictions that make real estate loans to home builders. Requires such rulemaking to provide for: (1) adjustment from 100% to 125% of bank capital the measurement that triggers additional scrutiny on real estate loans in the lending portfolio of any qualified financial institution, (2) a prohibition against compelling lenders to call loans in good standing, and (3) improved composite ratings of a financial institution to take effect immediately. Prohibits a federal banking agency from preventing a qualified financial institution from making a real estate loan to a home builder in good standing that is secured by a viable project, unless there is a legitimate supervisory or accounting reason to do so. Prohibits such banking agencies from requiring a financial institution to reclassify any real estate loan to a homebuilder in good standing on the balance sheet of such institution, unless there is a legitimate supervisory or accounting reason to do so. Prohibits such agency guidance and regulations from superseding state law, except to the extent of state law inconsistency.</summary>
</bill>
