<bill session="110" type="s" number="49" updated="2013-07-19T22:20:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Children in the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to prevent the carriage of child pornography by video service providers, to protect children from online predators, and to restrict the sale or purchase of children's personal information in interstate commerce.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300094"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1965"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Protecting Children in the 21st Century Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to issue regulations requiring video services to prevent child pornography. Amends the Crime Control Act of 1990 to triple the fines on providers of electronic communication services or remote computing services who knowingly and willfully fail to report child pornography. Requires warning labels for websites depicting sexually explicit material. Deleting Online Predators Act of 2007 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require schools and libraries that receive universal service support to enforce a policy that: (1) prohibits access to a commercial social networking website or chat room unless used for an educational purpose with adult supervision; and (2) protects against access to visual depictions that are obscene, child pornography, or harmful to minors. Directs the FCC to issue a consumer alert regarding use of the Internet by child predators and establish a website resource. Children's Listbroker Privacy Act - Makes it unlawful: (1) to sell personal information about an individual the seller knows to be a child (under age 16); (2) to purchase personal information about an individual identified by the seller as a child for the purpose of marketing to that child; or (3) for a purchaser who has provided a certification limiting the use of such information to engage in any practice that violates the certification terms.</summary>
</bill>
