<bill session="111" type="s" number="3084" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Export Promotion Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Export Promotion Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to increase the competitiveness of United States businesses, particularly small and medium-sized manufacturing firms, in interstate and global commerce, foster job creation in the United States, and assist United States businesses in developing or expanding commercial activities in interstate and global commerce by expanding the ambit of the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership program and the Technology Innovation Program to include projects that have potential for commercial exploitation in nondomestic markets, providing for an increase in related resources of the Department of Commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412380" joined="2010-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2010-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2010-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2010-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2010-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1496-1497"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-13">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-289.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="560">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 560.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Panama"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Export Promotion Act of 2010 - (Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of Commerce to increase the number of full-time departmental employees whose primary responsibilities involve promoting or facilitating participation by U.S. businesses in the global marketplace and facilitating the entry into, or expansion of, such participation. Requires the Secretary to ensure that global marketplace promotional activities include promoting and facilitating participation by small and medium-sized manufacturing businesses. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 3) Authorizes appropriations for the Department of Commerce's program to improve access to the global marketplace for goods and services provided by rural businesses. (Sec. 4) Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary to promote or facilitate participation by U.S. businesses in the global marketplace and facilitate the entry into, or expansion of, such participation. Requires the Secretary to give preferences to activities that: (1) assist small and medium-sized businesses in the United States; and (2) will create or sustain the greatest number of jobs in the United States and obtain the maximum return on investment. (Sec. 5) Authorizes appropriations to expand ExporTech, a joint program of the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership Program. (Sec. 6) Authorizes appropriations for the Manufacturing and Services unit of the International Trade Administration (ITA) of the Department of Commerce for the ITA's Market Development Cooperator Program. Requires, in the use of such funds, the same preference to be given to activities described in section 4, above. (Sec. 7) Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to authorize the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), in making awards for the creation and support of regional centers for the transfer of manufacturing technology, to consider whether an applicant has significant potential for enhancing the competitiveness of small and medium-sized U.S. manufacturers in the global marketplace, and to give a preference to applicants for such projects. Authorizes the Director, in making awards under the technology innovation program, to make the same consideration. (Sec. 8) Expresses the sense of the Senate that the Secretary should enhance federal collaboration with the states on export promotion issues. (Sec. 9) Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on the tariff and nontariff barriers imposed by Colombia, the Republic of Korea, and Panama with respect to exports of U.S. firms, including small and medium-sized manufacturing firms.</summary>
</bill>
