<bill session="111" type="s" number="400" updated="2013-07-20T00:26:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financial Crisis Investigation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to expand the authority and responsibilities of the Oversight Panel of the Troubled Asset Relief Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/2009--Introduced.
Financial Crisis Investigation Act of 2009 - Amends the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA) to direct the Oversight Panel of the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) to: (1) investigate all causes, domestic and global, of the current financial and economic crisis in the United States, including the collapse of major financial and commercial firms and the deterioration of the credit and housing markets; (2) investigate the role in the financial and economic crisis, if any, of specified governmental and private sector entities; (3) review the nation's existing financial regulatory structure from top to bottom, and its contribution to the stability or instability of financial markets; (4) review all aspects of financial regulation; and (5) refer to federal and state law enforcement officials any person that the Oversight Panel finds may have violated federal law in relation to such crisis. Requires the Oversight Panel to report its findings, conclusions, and recommendations to the President and Congress.</summary>
</bill>
