<bill session="111" type="s" number="875" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Presidential Signing Statements Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to regulate the judicial use of presidential signing statements in the interpretation of Acts of Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4676-4677"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4677-4678" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/2009--Introduced.
Presidential Signing Statements Act of 2009 - Prohibits any state or federal court from relying on or deferring to a presidential signing statement as a source of authority when determining the meaning of any Act of Congress. Requires any federal or state court, in any action, suit, or proceeding regarding the construction or constitutionality, or both, of any Act of Congress in which a presidential signing statement was issued, to permit the Senate, through the Office of Senate Legal Counsel, or the House, through the Office of General Counsel for the House, or both, to participate as an amicus curiae, and to present an oral argument on the question of the Act's construction or constitutionality, or both. Authorizes the full Congress, in any such suit, to pass a concurrent resolution declaring its view of the proper interpretation of the Act of Congress at issue, clarifying Congress's intent or its findings of fact, or both. Requires the federal or state court in question to permit Congress, through the Office of Senate Legal Counsel, to submit any such passed resolution into the record of the case as a matter of right. Makes it the duty of each federal or state court, including the U.S. Supreme Court, to advance on the docket and to expedite to the greatest possible extent the disposition of any matter brought under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
