<bill session="111" type="s" number="3679" updated="2013-07-20T00:58:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STARS Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Students Taking Action for Road Safety Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a grant program in the Department of Transportation to improve the traffic safety of teen drivers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5949"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
Students Taking Action for Road Safety Act of 2010 or STARS Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish a teen traffic safety grant program to award formula grants to states to implement statewide programs to improve the traffic safety of teen drivers. Authorizes a state to use grant funds to implement such statewide program to improve the traffic safety of teen drivers, including activities to support peer-to-peer education and prevention strategies in schools and communities to increase safety belt use and reduce speeding, impaired and distracted driving, underage drinking, and other destructive teen driver decisions that lead to injuries and fatalities. Authorizes the Secretary to contract with a national, nonprofit organization to establish a technical assistance center to provide training and technical assistance to state and local officials, student leaders, school advisors, and other entities associated with the grant program. Authorizes the center to operate a national teen traffic safety clearinghouse. Directs the Secretary to establish the National Teen Driver Advisory Council to study and develop an education and prevention strategy to reduce teen driver injuries and fatalities.</summary>
</bill>
