<bill session="111" type="h" number="6132" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-28T13:06:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-09-28T13:06:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Benefits and Economic Welfare Improvement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Veterans Benefits and Economic Welfare Improvement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish a transition program for new veterans, to improve the disability claim system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412316" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2010-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>H.R. 6132 incorporates language from H.R. 929, H.R. 4541, H.R. 5064, H.R. 5484 and H.R. 5549.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 111-630.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-09-28T12:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="370">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 370.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T12:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Filner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T12:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7013-7017" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T12:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6132.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-09-28T13:06:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7013-7015" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T13:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2010--Passed House amended.
Veterans Benefits and Economic Welfare Improvement Act of 2010 - (Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) and the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans' Employment and Training to carry out a joint training program to provide eligible veterans with skills relevant to the job market. Makes eligible for such program any veteran who: (1) is not otherwise eligible for education or training services through the VA; (2) has not acquired a marketable skill since being separated or released from military service; (3) was discharged under honorable conditions; and (4) has been unemployed for at least 90 days during the 180-day period preceding program application, or, during such 180-day period, received a maximum hourly pay rate of not more than 150% of the federal minimum wage. Allows for payments to employers for the provision of apprenticeship or on-job training under such program. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the program at the end of FY2016. (Sec. 3) Allows a VA benefits claimant to waive any claim development period upon submission of a fully developed claim, and requires the Secretary to provide expeditious treatment of such a claim. Requires the Secretary to notify a claimant of a non-fully developed claim within 30 days after that determination. Directs the Secretary, in denying a benefit, to include in a notice of that decision any form or application required to appeal the decision. (Sec. 4) Extends the 120-day time limit for the filing of a notice of appeal of a final decision of the Board of Veterans' Appeals for such time as justice may require, upon a showing of good cause. Applies such extension retroactively to final Board decisions issued on or after July 24, 2008. (Sec. 5) Excludes from annual income, for purposes of eligibility for VA pension benefits for veterans and their surviving spouses and children: (1) reimbursements for expenses resulting from any accident, theft or loss, or casualty loss, or medical expenses or pain and suffering related to such accidents or losses; and (2) payments of up to $5,000 paid by a state or municipality as a veterans' benefit due to injury or disease. (Sec. 6) Extends through FY2015 VA authority to obtain veterans' income verification information from the Commissioner of Social Security or the Secretary of the Treasury. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to establish the VetStar Award Program to recognize annually businesses for their contribution to veterans' employment. (Sec. 8) Increases from $1,000 to $2,000 the special monthly pension for Medal of Honor recipients. (Sec. 9) Requires the budgetary effects of this Act to be determined by reference to the latest statement titled "Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation" for this Act, provided such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</summary>
</bill>
