<bill session="112" type="hr" number="443" updated="2013-07-20T01:06:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Establishing the House of Representatives Summer Internship Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1898"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/21/2011--Introduced.
Establishes the House of Representatives Summer Internship Program, to be administered by the Clerk of the House of Representatives. Declares that interns shall serve without pay and shall not be provided with housing. Requires that eligible students: (1) be at least 18 years of age; (2) be U.S. citizens, nationals, or individuals lawfully admitted for permanent residence; (3) be enrolled in an educational program for which an institution of higher education awards a bachelor's or equivalent degree, or be scheduled to enroll after completion of the internship; (4) maintain a specified grade point average; and (5) not be previous House interns or pages. Sets forth an application process. Requires the Speaker and the minority leader jointly to select at least 70 eligible students to serve as interns, two-thirds on behalf of the majority party and one-third on behalf of the minority party. Establishes the House of Representatives Summer Internship Program Oversight Board.</summary>
</bill>
