<bill session="112" type="h" number="1835" updated="2013-07-20T01:26:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State Admission Day Recognition Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Architect of the Capitol to fly the flag of a State over the Capitol each year on the anniversary of the date of the State's admission to the Union.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400617"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="National symbols"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. Capitol"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2011--Introduced.
State Admission Day Recognition Act of 2011 - Requires the Architect of the Capitol (AOC) to honor a state's anniversary of admission to the Union by flying its flag over the Capitol each year on that anniversary. Requires the AOC to fly the first such flag on the first December 7 which occurs after the enactment of this Act in honor of the admission anniversary of Delaware, the first state admitted to the Union. Authorizes the House Committee on House Administration and the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration to promulgate jointly such regulations as may be appropriate to carry out this Act, including regulations permitting the AOC to honor the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the U.S. Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands by flying the flag of each such jurisdiction over the Capitol each year on an appropriate date for that jurisdiction.</summary>
</bill>
