<bill session="111" type="h" number="2516" updated="2013-07-19T23:34:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical Rights Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To guarantee the rights of patients and doctors against Federal restrictions or delay in the provision of privately-funded health care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400222"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412196" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412291" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2009-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2009-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1222-1223"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3970"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2009--Introduced.
Medical Rights Act of 2009 - Prohibits federal funds from being used to permit any federal officer or employee to exercise any supervision or control over: (1) the practice of medicine, the practice of other health care professions, or the manner in which health care services are provided; (2) the provision by a physician or a health care practitioner of advice to a patient about the patient's health status or recommended treatment for a condition or disease; (3) the selection, tenure, or compensation of any officer, employee, or contractor of any institution, business, nonfederal agency, or individual providing health care services; or (4) the administration or operation of any such institution, business, nonfederal agency, or individual with respect to the provision of health care services to a patient. Sets forth exceptions for the Veterans Health Administration, the Department of Defense (DOD), the United States Public Health Service, the Indian Health Service, the National Institutes of Health (NIH), and the Health Resources and Services Administration. Prohibits federal funds from being used by any federal officer or employee to prohibit: (1) any individual from receiving health care services from any provider under terms and conditions mutually acceptable to the patient, the provider, and the patient's group health plan; or (2) any person from entering into a contract with any group health plan, health insurance issuer, or other business for the provision of, or payment to other parties for, health care services. Sets forth provisions to prohibit specified actions to avoid the prohibitions under this Act. Repeals Medicare provisions restricting private contracts between beneficiaries and physicians or practitioners.</summary>
</bill>
