<bill session="112" type="s" number="3431" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Designer Anabolic Steroid Control Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to more effectively regulate anabolic steroids.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2012-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5383-5384"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2012--Introduced.
Designer Anabolic Steroid Control Act of 2012 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to:&#160; (1) expand the list of substances defined as "anabolic steroids";&#160;(2) authorize the Attorney General to issue a temporary order adding a drug or other substance to the list of anabolic steroids;&#160;(3) impose enhanced criminal and civil penalties for&#160;possessing or trafficking in any anabolic steroid, or product containing an anabolic steroid, unless it bears a label clearly identifying the anabolic steroid by the nomenclature used by the International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry;&#160;and (4) authorize the Attorney General to collect data and analyze products to determine&#160;whether they contain anabolic steroids and are properly labeled. Specifies that a substance shall not be considered to be a drug or hormonal substance that is considered to be an anaboloic steroid if it is: (1) an herb or other botanical; (2) a concentrate, metabolite, or extract of, or a constituent isolated directly from, an herb or other botanical; (3) a combination of two or more such substances (i.e., botanical or concentrate, metabolite, or extract); or (4) a dietary ingredient for purposes of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act. Requires any person claiming the benefit of an exemption or exception from being considered a drug or hormonal substance shall bear the burden providing the appropriate evidence. Directs: (1) the United States Sentencing Commission to review and amend federal sentencing guidelines with respect to offenses involving anabolic steroids, and (2) the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) to report every two years on what anabolic steroids have been scheduled on a temporary basis under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
