<bill session="111" type="h" number="4416" updated="2013-07-19T23:52:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Great Ape Conservation Reauthorization Amendments Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Great Ape Conservation Reauthorization Amendments Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the Great Ape Conservation Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2010-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2010-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29T14:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-650.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-29T14:52:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="388">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 388.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Reported to House amended.
Great Ape Conservation Reauthorization Amendments Act of 2010 - Amends the Great Ape Conservation Act of 2000 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to award a multiyear grant to an eligible person to implement a great ape conservation project that the person demonstrates is an effective, long-term conservation strategy for great apes and their habitats. Authorizes the Secretary to implement a program of awards to acknowledge outstanding achievement in great ape conservation, to enhance great ape conservation, and to demonstrate the indebtedness of the world to the commitment made by individuals and local communities to protect and conserve populations of great apes. Requires the Secretary to convene a panel of experts to identify the greatest needs and priorities for the conservation of great apes within a year of this Act's enactment and every five years thereafter (current law authorizes the Secretary to convene a panel to consider the greatest conservation needs every two years). Requires the panel to include representatives from foreign range states with expertise in great ape conservation and to consider relevant great ape conservation plans or strategies, including scientific research and findings related to: (1) conservation needs and priorities of great apes; (2) regional or species-specific action plans or strategies; (3) applicable strategies developed or initiated by the Secretary; and (4) any other applicable conservation plan or strategy. Authorizes the Secretary to pay expenses of convening and facilitating meetings of the panel. Authorizes appropriations for the Great Ape Conservation Fund for FY2011-FY2015.</summary>
</bill>
