<bill session="111" type="h" number="1722" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-09">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Telework Improvements Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Telework Improvements Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Telework Improvements Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Telework Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Telework Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve teleworking in executive agencies by developing a telework program that allows employees to telework at least 20 percent of the hours worked in every 2 administrative workweeks, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To require the head of each executive agency to establish and implement a policy under which employees shall be authorized to telework, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412212"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2010-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2009-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2010-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2009-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E764-765"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-05-04T18:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government. H. Rept. 111-474.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-05-04T18:34:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="269">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 269.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T13:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lynch moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T13:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3158-3163" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3158-3160" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T13:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1722.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-06T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3216" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED" datetime="2010-05-06T12:11:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="251" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 268 - 147 (Roll no. 251).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1509 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1722 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules, shall be considered as adopted. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T13:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1509 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1509.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5577-5590" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5577-5579" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1722 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules, shall be considered as adopted. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T13:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 1722.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5586" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T14:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Issa moved to recommit with instructions to Oversight and Government.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5586-5589" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5586-5587" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House with an amendment to add certain limitations to certain employees authorized to telework.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T15:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5588" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T15:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 303 - 119 (Roll no. 440).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-07-14T15:45:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="441" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 290 - 131 (Roll no. 441).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14T15:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7770" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2010-09-29" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18T11:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1721, Mr. Lynch took from the Speaker's table H.R. 1722 with the Senate amendment thereto, and was recognized for a motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18T11:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Lynch moved that the House agree to the Senate amendment</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7560-7569, H7575" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18T11:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1721, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Lynch motion to agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1722.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18T12:44:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to H.Res. 1721, further proceedings on the motion to agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1722 has been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18T13:24:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7575" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-11-18T13:52:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="578" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 254 - 152 (Roll no. 578).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7563-7568, H7575" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7560-7563" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18T13:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-11-29">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-12-09">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-12-09" type="public" number="111-292">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-292.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="111" type="hr" number="1509"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="1721"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h716"/>
    <amendment number="h717"/>
    <amendment number="s4689"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/9/2010--Public Law.
Telework Enhancement Act of 2010 - (Sec. 2) Requires the head of each executive agency to: (1) establish a policy under which eligible agency employees may be authorized to telework; (2) determine employee eligibility to participate in telework; and (3) notify all employees of their eligibility to telework.Requires the telework policy to: (1) ensure that telework does not diminish employee performance or agency operations; (2) require a written agreement between an agency manager and an employee that outlines the specific work arrangement agreed to; (3) provide that an employee may not be authorized to telework if that employee's performance does not comply with the terms of the agreement; (4) not apply to any agency employee whose official duties require, on a daily basis, direct handling of secure materials determined to be inappropriate for telework or on-site activity that cannot be handled remotely or at an alternate worksite; and (5) be incorporated as part of the agency's continuity of operations plans.Prohibits participation in telework by an employee who has been officially disciplined for being absent without permission for more than five days in any calendar year or for viewing, downloading, or exchanging pornography on a government computer or while performing official government duties.Directs each agency head to ensure that: (1) an interactive telework training program is provided to eligible employees and their managers; (2) an employee has successfully completed that program before entering into a written telework agreement; (3) teleworkers and nonteleworkers are treated the same for purposes of performance appraisals, training, rewarding, reassigning, promotions, reducing in grade, retaining, and removing employees, work requirements, or other acts involving managerial discretion; and (4) the agency shall consult the performance management guidelines of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) when determining what constitutes diminished employee performance.Requires each agency, in developing telework policies, to consult with OPM, which shall: (1) provide policy guidance; (2) assist each agency in establishing appropriate qualitative and quantitative measures and teleworking goals; and (3) consult with the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) on telework policy in areas including continuation of operations, telework centers, technology, equipment, dependent care, and records management. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), in coordination with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), to issue guidelines to ensure the adequacy of information and security protections for information and information systems used while teleworking. Requires each agency to incorporate telework into its continuity of operations plan.Directs: (1) OPM to maintain a central telework website that includes telework links, announcements, and guidance developed by OPM or submitted by FEMA and GSA; and (2) the Director of OMB to issue policy guidance requiring each agency, when purchasing computer systems, to purchase systems that enable and support telework, unless the agency head determines that there is a mission-specific reason not to do so.Directs each agency to designate a Telework Managing Officer, who shall: (1) be devoted to policy development and implementation related to agency telework programs; (2) serve as an advisor for agency leadership, a resource for managers and employees, and a primary agency point of contact for OPM on telework matters; and (3) be a senior agency official who has direct access to the agency head.Requires: (1) the Director of OPM to submit annual reports on the telework programs of each agency (excluding the General Accountability Office [GAO]) to specified congressional committees, the Comptroller General, and OMB; (2) the Comptroller General to submit annual reports a on GAO's telework program to such committees; and (3) the Chief Human Capital Officer of each agency to report annually to the Chair and Vice Chair of the Chief Human Capital Officers Council on agency management efforts to promote telework.(Sec. 3) Authorizes an agency, under a test program approved by the Administrator of General Services, to pay necessary travel expenses for employees participating in a telework program in lieu of otherwise authorized travel or transportation expenses. Requires: (1) an agency to include in any request for approval of such a test program an analysis of the expected costs and benefits and a set of criteria for evaluating program effectiveness; and (2) any such test program to be designed to enhance cost savings or other efficiencies for the government. Prohibits more than 10 test programs from being conducted simultaneously.Requires the Patent and Trademark Office (PTO) to conduct such a test program, under which it may pay travel expenses of an employee for travel to and from a PTO worksite or provide an employee with the option to waive such payment if PTO approves the requested arrangement for reasons of employee convenience instead of an agency need.Terminates the authority to conduct such test programs seven years after enactment of this Act.(Sec. 4) Requires the Director of OPM to: (1) research the utilization of telework by public and private sector entities that identify best practices and recommendations for the federal government; (2) review the outcomes associated with an increase in telework, including the effects of telework on energy consumption, job creation and availability, urban transportation patterns, and the ability to anticipate the dispersal of work during periods of emergency; and (3) make findings available to the public.</summary>
</bill>
