<bill session="112" type="s" number="3689" updated="2013-07-20T02:48:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Senior Airman Michael Malarsie Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a grant program to encourage the use of assistance dogs by certain members of the Armed Forces and veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-12-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8139"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-12-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="943"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/18/2012--Introduced.
Senior Airman Michael Malarsie Act - Directs the Secretaries of Defense (DOD) and Veterans Affairs (VA) to jointly establish the Senior Airman Michael Malarsie Program for the awarding of grants to certain nonprofit organizations to assist them in establishing and operating programs to provide assistance dogs to certain members of the Armed Forces and veterans who have certain visual, hearing, or mobility disabilities. Requires such Secretaries to determine whether such assistance for members or veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder or traumatic brain injury would be appropriate, taking into account the findings of a specified study conducted under the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010. Defines the term "assistance dog" to mean a dog specifically trained to perform physical tasks to mitigate the effects of such a disability, except that such term does not include a dog specifically trained for comfort or personal defense.</summary>
</bill>
