<bill session="112" type="s" number="1669" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program of awarding grants to owners or operators of water systems to increase the resiliency or adaptability of the systems to any ongoing or forecasted changes to the hydrologic conditions of a region of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2011-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6338"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6338-6339" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2738"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2011--Introduced.
Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2011 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) establish the Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Program to provide grants to owners or operators of water systems for programs or projects to increase the resiliency or adaptability of the systems to any ongoing or forecasted changes to the hydrologic conditions of a U.S. region; and (2) give priority to owners or operators of water systems that are at the greatest and most immediate risk of facing significant negative impacts due to changing hydrologic conditions. Requires the Administrator to ensure that the list of grant applications funded include a substantial number that propose to use innovative approaches that: (1) promote more efficient water use, water conservation, water reuse, or recycling; (2) use decentralized, low-impact development technologies and nonstructural approaches, including practices that use, enhance, or mimic the natural hydrological cycle or protect natural flows; (3) reduce stormwater runoff or flooding by protecting or enhancing natural ecosystem functions; (4) modify, upgrade, enhance, or replace existing water system infrastructure in response to changing hydrologic conditions; (5) improve water quality or quantity for agricultural and municipal uses, including through salinity reduction; and (6) provide multiple benefits, including to water supply enhancement or demand reduction, water quality protection or improvement, increased flood protection, and ecosystem protection or improvement.</summary>
</bill>
