<bill session="111" type="h" number="2479" updated="2013-07-19T23:34:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Orthotics and Prosthetics Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to modify the designation of accreditation organizations for prosthetic devices and orthotics and prosthetics, to apply accreditation and licensure requirements to such devices and items for purposes of payment under the Medicare Program, and to modify the payment rules for such devices and items under such program to account for practitioner qualifications and complexity of care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2009--Introduced.
Medicare Orthotics and Prosthetics Improvement Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with respect to recognized independent accreditation organizations which apply quality standards for suppliers of items and services relating to prosthetic devices and orthotics and prosthetics. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to designate and approve an independent accreditation organization for such purposes only if it is the American Board for Certification in Orthotics and Prosthetics, Inc., the Board for Orthotist/Prosthetist Certification, or a program that the Secretary determines has accreditation and approval standards essentially equivalent to those of such a Board. Requires such organization to satisfy all applicable criteria of the provider qualification designation for each of specified categories of prosthetics and orthotics. Requires application to prosthetic devices and orthotics and prosthetics generally of existing accreditation and licensure requirements for certain custom-fabricated prosthetics and custom-fabricated orthotics, as well as those categorized as custom-fitted high or custom-fitted low. Modifies the Medicare payment methodology for prosthetic devices and orthotics and prosthetics to require the Secretary, for payment purposes, to take into account practitioner qualifications and complexity of care. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on: (1) the steps taken by the Department of HHS to ensure that such licensure and accreditation requirements are enforced; and (2) the effect of the requirements of this Act on the occurrence of fraud and abuse under the Medicare program with respect to prosthetic devices and orthotics and prosthetics.</summary>
</bill>
