<bill session="112" type="h" number="2312" updated="2013-07-20T01:30:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Defense Textile and Apparel Procurement Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide a special rule with respect to purchases by the Department of Defense of textile and apparel products of Federal Prison Industries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400209"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2011-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Federal Prison Industries, Inc."/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2011--Introduced.
Department of Defense Textile and Apparel Procurement Fairness Act - Prohibits the Secretary of Defense from purchasing a textile or apparel product (an individual end item purchased by Department of Defense [DOD] or an item with an individual National Stock Number) for which Federal Prison Industries has a market share determined by the Secretary to be greater than 5% of the DOD market for the product. Prohibits Federal Prison Industries from: (1) submitting a DOD contract offer for any textile or apparel product reserved for small businesses; and (2) continuing to perform under a contract for a textile or apparel product under its preference, as specified, if, after receiving the award, the work intended to be done by federal prisoners is subsequently subcontracted to another entity. Directs the DOD, upon reducing the quantity of items to be delivered under any indefinite delivery-indefinite quantity contract for any such product, to reduce Federal Prison Industries' share of the contract by the same percentage that the industry's share is reduced.</summary>
</bill>
