<bill session="111" type="h" number="6074" updated="2013-07-20T00:07:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhancing Quality through Survey System Improvements Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to enhance quality under the Medicaid Program through nursing facility survey system improvements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2010-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
Enhancing Quality through Survey System Improvements Act of 2010 - Amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to revise requirements for the review by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) of state procedures for scheduling and conducing standard skilled nursing facility (SNF) surveys. Authorizes the Secretary to review the SNF survey procedures of contractors other than a state. Makes each top tier SNF and nursing facility subject to a complete on-site standard survey at specified three-year intervals. Requires each state to implement programs to measure and reduce inconsistency in the application of survey results (including the results of both health surveys and life safety surveys) among surveyors. Lists the circumstances for special compliance surveys. Requires any funds collected by a state as an administrative civil monetary penalty to be used for the development of acuity adjusters that will provide more accurate information to the public, SNFs, nursing facilities, and their residents about the quality of care provided by each such facility.</summary>
</bill>
