<bill session="112" type="h" number="2956" updated="2013-07-20T01:35:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair and Equitable Postal Service Access Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 39, United States Code, to provide for additional criteria for the United States Postal Service to consider with respect to closing or consolidating a post office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400661"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2011-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2011-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1661"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy     .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2011--Introduced.
Fair and Equitable Postal Service Access Act - Expands the criteria that the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) must consider in determining whether to close or consolidate a post office to include: (1) whether such closing or consolidation will decrease access to postal or nonpostal services by individuals who are elderly, economically disadvantaged, limited in mobility, or without reliable and affordable Internet access; and (2) during the previous five years, the number of, and revenue derived from, money-order transactions, the volume of processed international mail, and the number of customers served at such post office. Prohibits the USPS from closing or consolidating a post office if it would result in a disproportionate, unreasonable, or undue burden on a class of individuals who are elderly, economically disadvantaged, limited in mobility, or without reliable and affordable Internet access. Applies this Act to any post office: (1) determined necessary for closing or consolidation under existing criteria, or (2) included in a proposal to change the nature of postal services on a nationwide or substantially nationwide basis and for which the USPS has requested a related advisory opinion from the Postal Regulatory Commission.</summary>
</bill>
