<bill session="110" type="h" number="4076" updated="2013-07-19T21:39:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Counterfeit Drug Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tim Fagan's Law</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to increase criminal penalties for the sale or trade of prescription drugs knowingly caused to be adulterated or misbranded, to modify requirements for maintaining records of the chain-of-custody of prescription drugs, to establish recall authority regarding drugs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Drug adulteration"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Product counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/5/2007--Introduced.
Tim Fagan's Law or the Counterfeit Drug Enforcement Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish a criminal fine and/or imprisonment for a person who: (1) knowingly causes a prescription drug to be adulterated, misbranded, or misrepresented as an approved prescription drug and sells or trades the drug; or (2) purchases or trades for such drug knowing or having reason to know that the drug was knowingly adulterated, misbranded, or misrepresented. Requires a manufacturer of a drug to notify the Secretary of Health and Human Services within 48 hours after first receiving or becoming aware of information that reasonably suggests that such a violation may have occurred. Deems a drug to be misbranded if it is not manufactured in accordance with the use of technologies that the Secretary determines are technically feasible and will assist in preventing such violations. Requires the Secretary to establish alternative requirements to the extent that such requirements provide greater certainty on the chain of custody and are technically feasible. Increases funding for Food and Drug Administration (FDA) inspections, examinations, and investigations. Requires the Secretary to educate the public and health care professionals on counterfeit drugs. Directs the Secretary: (1) upon a finding of reasonable probability that a drug intended for human use would cause serious health consequences or death, to issue an order requiring the appropriate person (including the manufacturers, importers, distributors, or retailers of the drug) to cease distribution of the drug and to notify and instruct health professionals to cease administering or prescribing the drug; and (2) amend the order to include a recall if necessary.</summary>
</bill>
