<bill session="113" type="h" number="1363" updated="2013-11-02T06:30:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Exploring for Geothermal Energy on Federal Lands Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote timely exploration for geothermal resources under existing geothermal leases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412419"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2013-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2013--Introduced.
Exploring for Geothermal Energy on Federal Lands Act - Exempts projects determined by the Secretary of the Interior to be geothermal exploration test projects from environmental impact statement requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA). Defines a "geothermal exploration test project" as&#160;the drilling of a well to test or explore for geothermal resources on lands leased by the Department of the Interior for the development and production of geothermal resources, that is completed in less than 45 days, that causes less than&#160;five&#160;acres of soil or vegetation disruption at the location of each well and no more than five additional acres of soil or vegetation disruption during access or egress to the test site, and that is developed: (1) no deeper than 2,500 feet, (2)&#160;less than&#160;eight inches in diameter, (3) in a manner that does not require off-road motorized access other than to and from the well site along an identified off-road route, (4) without construction of new roads other than upgrading of existing drainage crossings for safety purposes, and (5) with the use of rubber-tired digging or drilling equipment vehicles. Requires the restoration of the project site within three years to approximately the condition that existed at the time the project began, unless the site is subsequently used as part of energy development on the lease. Requires: (1)&#160;a&#160;leaseholder intending to carry out a geothermal exploration test project to provide notice to the Secretary within&#160;30 days prior to the start of drilling, (2) the Secretary to review a project within 10 days of receipt of such notice and to notify&#160;such leaseholder either that such NEPA requirements do not apply or that project deficiencies preclude the NEPA exemption, and (3) the Secretary to allow&#160;such&#160;leaseholder an opportunity to remedy any such deficiencies prior to the date&#160;such leaseholder intended to start drilling.</summary>
</bill>
