<bill session="111" type="s" number="2766" updated="2013-07-20T00:50:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical Foods Equity Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the coverage of medically necessary food under Federal health programs and private health insurance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11349"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="4926"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/2009--Introduced.
Medical Foods Equity Act of 2009 - Amends titles XVIII (Medicare), XIX (Medicaid), and XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program) (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP) of the Social Security Act to include coverage of: (1) medically necessary food and food modified to be low protein; and (2) pharmacological doses of vitamins and amino acids used for the treatment of inborn errors of metabolism. Provides for similar coverage under the TRICARE program (military health care). Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (ERISA), the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code to provide coverage in group and individual plans of such food and vitamins and amino acids. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to determine the minimum yearly coverage for all health insurance plans based upon the expanded coverage provided by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
