<bill session="110" type="s" number="1510" updated="2013-07-19T22:33:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Portable Generator Safety Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Consumer Product Safety Commission to promulgate consumer product safety rules concerning the safety and labeling of portable generators.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6872"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6872-6873" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Carbon monoxide"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2007--Introduced.
Portable Generator Safety Act of 2007 - Instructs the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to promulgate consumer product safety rules requiring that every portable generator sold to the public for purposes other than resale be equipped with an interlock safety device that detects the level of carbon monoxide in the areas surrounding the generator and automatically turns off power to it before the level of carbon monoxide reaches a level that would cause serious bodily injury or death to people. Requires the CPSC to issue consumer product safety rules requiring that every such portable generator: (1) prominently display a permanently affixed warning label in English and Spanish regarding the carbon monoxide hazard posed by its incorrect use, including the word "DANGER" printed in a large font; and (2) have affixed to it a large pictogram which clearly states "POISONOUS GAS" and visually depicts the harmful effects of breathing carbon monoxide. Requires a program of public outreach to inform consumers of the dangers associated with the emission of carbon monoxide from portable generators, with an emphasis on doing so during the start of each hurricane season.</summary>
</bill>
