<bill session="113" type="s" number="311" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lower Mississippi River Area Study Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Lower Mississippi River Area Study Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to study the suitability and feasibility of designating sites in the Lower Mississippi River Area in the State of Louisiana as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S712-713"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-03-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-04-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Wyden with an amendment. With written report No. 113-26.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="57">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 57.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/2013--Reported to Senate amended.
Lower Mississippi River Area Study Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, through the National Park Service (NPS), to complete a special resource study that evaluates the national significance of a specified study area located in Plaquemines Parish in Louisiana, and the feasibility of designating such area as a unit of the National Park System. Requires such study to: (1) include cost estimates for the potential acquisition of the study area, and (2) identify alternatives for the management and protection of such area. Allows the Secretary to accept donated funds to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
