<bill session="113" type="sr" number="90" updated="2013-11-02T06:50:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-22">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution standing with the people of Kenya following their national and local elections on March 4, 2013, and urging a peaceful and credible resolution of electoral disputes in the courts.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A resolution congratulating the people of Kenya on their commitment to peaceful elections, as demonstrated on March 4, 2013, and calling on Kenyans to come together to continue to implement political, institutional, and accountability reforms envisioned in the Kenyan constitution.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412390"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2013-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2013-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2338-2339" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="42">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 42.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2013-04-22" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2853-2854" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2853-2854" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2854" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="186"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Kenya"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/2013--Passed Senate without amendment.
Congratulates the people of Kenya on their commitment to peaceful elections, as demonstrated on March 4, 2013. Calls on Kenyans to implement political, institutional, and accountability reforms envisioned in the Kenyan constitution. Affirms that accountability for the 2007-2008 post-election violence is a critical element to ensure Kenya's democracy and long-term stability. Calls on the government of Kenya to seek justice for the victims of political violence, including by honoring its obligations to cooperate with the International Criminal Court. Encourages the people and government of Kenya to support implementation of constitutional reforms, rule of law, and efforts to strengthen governing, security, and judicial institutions. Supports the devolution process in order to enable constitutional reform to be fully implemented. Encourages the government of Kenya to respect the freedom of civil society organizations and activists. Reaffirms that the people of the United States will stand with the people of Kenya in support of democracy, partnership, and peace.</summary>
</bill>
