<bill session="113" type="h" number="2170" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Language Education Partnership Program Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a partnership program in foreign languages.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2013-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1036"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Geography"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Foreign Language Education Partnership Program Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to replace the program providing incentive payments to public elementary schools for foreign language instruction with a partnership program in foreign languages that provides matching grants to partnerships composed of state or local educational agencies and institutions of higher education. Requires such partnerships to establish, improve, or expand model programs of foreign language learning from kindergarten through grade 12 that increase the number of high school graduates who attain advanced proficiency in at least one foreign language. Requires each model program to have a dimension allowing the student to gain an understanding of the historic, geographic, cultural, economic, and other contextual factors of countries whose people speak the language studied. Conditions a partnership's continued funding for two additional five-year periods, after an initial four-year funding period, on its demonstrating its program's effectiveness based on nationally recognized standardized foreign language assessments. Directs the Secretary of Education to collect and analyze data on such programs annually and disseminate aggregated program data nationally, as well as information on successful programs and practices.</summary>
</bill>
