<bill session="109" type="s" number="1565" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tax Shelter and Tax Haven Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to restrict the use of abusive tax shelters and offshore tax havens to inappropriately avoid Federal taxation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2005-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9481-9486"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9486-9491" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Internal revenue law"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Investment advisers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax havens"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax preparers"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax shelters"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Introduced.
Tax Shelter and Tax Haven Reform Act of 2005 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase penalties for: (1) promoting abusive tax shelters; and (2) aiding and abetting the understatement of tax liability. Imposes a penalty for making fee arrangements for tax services based upon projected or actual tax savings. Requires federal banking agencies and the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to develop examination techniques to detect abusive tax shelter activities by certain financial institutions. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to disclose tax return information requested by the SEC, federal banking agencies, or the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board to aid in the investigation of tax shelter activity. Directs the Secretary to require tax practitioners to meet certain standards for the issuance of tax opinions. Provides for awards to individuals (whistleblowers) who provide information about tax law violations to the Secretary. Establishes a Whistleblower Office in the Internal Revenue Service. Denies a tax deduction for fines or penalties for violations of law, except for amounts constituting restitution. Expresses the sense of the Senate with respect to IRS enforcement efforts against abusive tax shelter activities. Sets forth rules for the application of the economic substance doctrine. Imposes additional penalties for understatements of tax resulting from transactions lacking economic substance. Requires disclosure of payments of $10,000 or more to accounts or persons located in an uncooperative tax haven. Imposes enhanced penalties for underpayments of tax related to certain offshore financial arrangements.</summary>
</bill>
