<bill session="110" type="h" number="7062" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Space Station Guaranteed Access Plan For Integrated Launch and Low Earth Rendezvous Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ISS GAP FILLER Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to develop a plan to guarantee access to the International Space Station, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400131"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2008-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="2008-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" name="House Science and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2008--Introduced.
International Space Station Guaranteed Access Plan for Integrated Launch and Low Earth Rendezvous Act or ISS GAP FILLER Act - Authorizes appropriations for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) for Space Shuttle operations and the Exploration Systems Mission Directorate. Requires: (1) the utilization flights ULF-4 and ULF-5 to be considered part of the Space Shuttle baseline flight manifest to ensure adequate logistics and on-orbit spares are available to the International Space Station (ISS); and (2) the flight of one additional Space Shuttle flight to deliver the Alpha Magnetic Spectrometer to the ISS. Authorizes NASA to: (1) continue Space Shuttle operations through FY2012; and (2) maintain the capability to safely fly at least two Shuttle missions per year through FY2012. Directs the Administrator of NASA to suspend any NASA activity that, if continued, would inhibit or preclude the continued safe and effective operation of the Space Shuttle through FY2012. Requires an assessment of the actions that have been taken and are planned to be taken to fully comply with the intent of the recertification recommendation of the Columbia Accident Investigation Board. Sets forth provisions for a crewed vehicle demonstration of a capsule and associated crew escape system capable of carrying astronauts to the ISS and returning them safely to Earth. Requires an evaluation of the actions necessary to human-rate Evolved Expendable Launch Vehicles. Directs the Administrator to initiate discussions with representatives of the European Space Agency to determine the feasibility of development of a human-rated space transportation system to provide a backup capability to the Russian Soyuz. Sets forth provisions concerning the development of a means of providing crew transfer and crew rescue services for the ISS. Requires a commercial space launch range study. Restricts the use of the Orion Crew Exploration Vehicle to only those missions carrying astronauts beyond low Earth orbit.Provides for discussions among space-faring nations of a common docking system standard. Authorizes the President to make extraordinary payments to the Russian Federal Space Agency or any entity under such agency for equipment and services related to the ISS.</summary>
</bill>
