<bill session="110" type="h" number="5738" updated="2013-07-19T21:54:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commercial Seafood Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the protections afforded under Federal law to consumers from contaminated seafood by directing the Secretary of Commerce to establish a program, in coordination with other appropriate Federal agencies, to strengthen activities for ensuring that seafood sold or offered for sale to the public in or affecting interstate commerce is fit for human consumption.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400345"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG29" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5956"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2688"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2008--Introduced.
Commercial Seafood Consumer Protection Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) to establish a program to strengthen federal activities for ensuring that commercially distributed seafood meets federal food quality and safety requirements. Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into an agreement to strengthen cooperation on seafood safety, including regarding testing, inspections of foreign facilities, technical assistance of foreign facilities, establishing a distribution chain tracking system, and labeling. Directs the Secretary to increase the number of laboratories certified to Food and Drug Administration (FDA) standards. Directs the Secretary to increase the number and capacity of laboratories operated by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) involved in testing and other activities under this Act, as provided for in appropriations Acts. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to refuse admission of all imports of seafood or seafood products originating from a country or exporter if that Secretary determines the shipments are not likely to meet federal requirements. Allows admittance of individual shipments from that country or exporter on evidence from an inspection or a certified laboratory. Authorizes the Secretary to send inspectors to an originating country or exporter.</summary>
</bill>
