<bill session="111" type="h" number="993" updated="2013-07-19T23:20:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Guadalupe-Hidalgo Treaty Land Claims Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a Presidential commission to determine and evaluate the validity of certain land claims arising out of the Treaty of Guadalupe-Hidalgo of 1848 involving the descendants of persons who were Mexican citizens at the time of the Treaty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412293"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2009--Introduced.
Guadalupe-Hidalgo Treaty Land Claims Act of 2009 - Establishes the Guadalupe-Hidalgo Treaty Land Claims Commission to determine the validity of land claims arising out of the Treaty of Guadalupe-Hidalgo of 1848. Authorizes three or more eligible descendants of the same community land grant to petition the Commission on behalf of themselves and all other descendants. Directs the Commission to recommend appropriate relief to a valid petition, including whether the community land grant should be reconstituted and its non-federal lands restored. Directs the Commission to establish a Community Land Grant Study Center at the Onate Center in Alcalde, New Mexico, to assist the Commission with necessary research and investigations. Directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to make necessary personnel, equipment, and facilities available to the Commission. Terminates the Commission 180 days the Commission submits its final report as required by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
