<bill session="113" type="h" number="30" updated="2013-11-02T06:19:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Investment Enhancement and Tax Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958, to provide for a small business early-stage investment program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2013-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1285"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/3/2013--Introduced.
Small Business Investment Enhancement and Tax Relief Act - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish and carry out an early-stage investment program (program) to provide, through participating investment companies, equity financing to support early-stage businesses (gross annual sales of $15 million or less in any of the previous three years). Outlines investment company application requirements and selection procedures. Allows the Administrator to make one or more equity financings to a participating company, with a limit of $100 million to any one company. Requires the company to make all of their investments in small businesses, of which at least 50% shall be early-stage small businesses. Establishes in the Treasury a separate fund for equity financings under the program. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a small business investment tax credit of 20% of the amount paid or incurred for small business investments. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to conduct a study of the effectiveness of the tax credit in providing incentives for investment in small businesses.</summary>
</bill>
