<bill session="109" type="s" number="3897" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Data Access and Research Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend titles XI and XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for the sharing of certain data collected by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services with certain agencies, research centers and organizations, and congressional support agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2006-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9633-9634"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9634-9636" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional Budget Office"/>
    <term name="Congressional Research Service"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug utilization"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare Payment Advisory Commission"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Vital statistics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/2006--Introduced.
Medicare Data Access and Research Act - Amends title XI of the Social Security Act (SSA) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, to: (1) enter into data release agreements with specified agencies to provide access to relevant data submitted by prescription drug (PD) plans and MedicareAdvantage-Prescription Drug (MA-PD) plans under part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of SSA title XVIII (Medicare) and linked to hospital, physician, and other relevant medical claims, utilization, and diagnostic Medicare and Medicaid (SSA title XIX) data; and (2) permit such an agency to link such data with other relevant health data as needed to accomplish its research objectives. Directs the Secretary to: (1) enter into data use agreements with specified research centers and organizations to provide access to the same kind of data; (2) permit them to link it with other relevant health data for research purposes; and (3) prepare the linked sets of data for release not later than July 1, 2007. Amends SSA title XVIII to direct the Secretary to provide a congressional support agency upon request with Medicare part D information for use in carrying out its functions and activities as mandated by Congress.</summary>
</bill>
