<bill session="111" type="h" number="3448" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Streamline America's Future Energy Nuclear Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish an expedited schedule for the issuance of a Combined Construction and Operating License for nuclear reactors that meet certain conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400320"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412231" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400016" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2009-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2010-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2009-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2009-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2009--Introduced.
Streamline America's Future Energy Nuclear Act - Directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to establish and implement an expedited procedure for issuing a Combined Construction and Operating License for a nuclear reactor. Directs the NRC to: (1) reduce by one-half the time necessary for reactor design certification; and (2) outline to Congress an approach that will allow the NRC to develop technology-neutral guidelines for future nuclear plant licensing. Instructs the NRC to request additional funding and personnel resources from Congress to implement this Act without delaying consideration of applications for Combined Construction and Operating Licenses or reactor design certifications not subject to expedited procedures under this Act. Requires each national laboratory with expertise in the nuclear field to dedicate personnel to support expedited licensing and design certification procedures. Directs the NRC and the Department of Energy (DOE) to direct educational funding to programs to enhance or directly support the activities authorized by this Act. Instructs the Secretary of Energy to establish a National Nuclear Energy Council. Authorizes appropriations for the Nuclear Power 2010 program. Directs DOE and the NRC to reevaluate the Next Generation Nuclear Power Plant schedule for purposes of significant acceleration. Prohibits use of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to arbitrarily prevent uranium mining on federal lands. Prohibits the federal government from collecting additional leasing fees, beyond those currently applicable to mine uranium on federal lands. Requires that any remediation fees collected in association with commercial uranium mining on federal lands be applied only to remediation of sites that incurred damage as a result of commercial nuclear activities. Prohibits the application of such fees to remediation of sites that incurred damage as a result of government or government-sponsored activities.</summary>
</bill>
