<bill session="112" type="h" number="6129" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to prohibit the use of consumer reports and consumer information in making any determination involving auto insurance with respect to a consumer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2012-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2012-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2012--Introduced.
Ban the Use of Credit Scores in Auto Insurance Act - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to prohibit: (1) a consumer reporting agency from furnishing a consumer report or consumer information to any person for use in making a decision to underwrite or rate auto insurance, and (2) any person from either using or obtaining a consumer report or consumer information in connection with the underwriting or rating of any consumer regarding an auto insurance transaction. Exempts from this ban property loss data regarding auto insurance as well as information on driver history, such as accidents or moving violations.</summary>
</bill>
