<bill session="110" type="s" number="3097" updated="2013-07-19T22:48:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vietnam Education Foundation Amendments Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Vietnam Education Foundation Amendments Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Vietnam Education Foundation Act of 2000.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2008-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2008-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-06-24">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-12">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden without amendment. With written report No. 110-458.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="957">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 957.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Vietnam Education Foundation Amendments Act of 2008 - Amends the Vietnam Education Foundation Act of 2000 to establish the Vietnam Education Foundation within the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs of the Department of State. (Current law establishes the Foundation as an independent establishment in the executive branch.) Transfers all functions and assets of the Foundation to the Bureau. Replaces the existing Board of Directors with a Vietnam Education Foundation Advisory Committee. Revises fellowship provisions to provide: (1) fellowships for post-secondary studies at U.S. institutions of higher education (current law provides fellowships for graduate and postgraduate levels); and (2) fellowship priority for students studying the basic sciences. Authorizes the Secretary of State, through the Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs, to award grants to institutions of higher education for a partnership with the government of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam to establish an American Research College in Vietnam for undergraduate studies.</summary>
</bill>
