<bill session="113" type="h" number="1484" updated="2013-11-02T06:31:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Payment Rate Disclosure Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to make publicly available on the official Medicare Internet site Medicare payment rates for frequently reimbursed hospital inpatient procedures, hospital outpatient procedures, and physicians' services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2013-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2013--Introduced.
Medicare Payment Rate Disclosure Act of 2013 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make publicly available on the official Medicare Internet site during a specified initial period: (1) Medicare payment rates for frequently reimbursed hospital inpatient and outpatient procedures and services, as well as for physicians' services; and (2) the period for which payment rates are applicable. Requires posting also after the initial period of an expanded selection of such items. Directs the Secretary to select at least 30 procedures and services for the basic posting and at least 100 procedures and services for the expanded posting.</summary>
</bill>
