<bill session="113" type="h" number="2528" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a task force in the Department of Veterans Affairs to assess the retention and training of claims processors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412318"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412559" joined="2013-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="928"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2013--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a task force to assess retention and training of claims processors and adjudicators that are employed by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) and other federal agencies. Directs the task force to: identify key skills required by claims processors and adjudicators throughout the federal government; identify reasons for employee attrition from claims processing positions; develop a government-wide strategic and operational plan for promoting employment of veterans in claims processing positions; establish performance measures to assess such plan and its implementation and revise such plan as appropriate; coordinate with educational institutions to develop training and educational programs to prepare members of the Armed Forces for such employment; identify and coordinate offices of the Department of Defense (DOD) and the VA to provide information about, and promotion of, available claims processing positions to members of the Armed Forces transitioning to civilian life and to veterans with disabilities; and establish performance measures to evaluate the task force's effectiveness.</summary>
</bill>
