<bill session="112" type="h" number="57" updated="2013-07-20T01:10:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disaster Recovery Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to make improvements in the provision of Federal disaster assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2011-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412452" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2011-10-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
Disaster Recovery Improvement Act - Directs the President to issue and begin to implement regulations required by the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (Stafford Act) regarding the repair, restoration, reconstruction, and replacement of public facilities damaged or destroyed by a major disaster to provide for cost estimation procedures that expedite recovery and to reduce the costs and time for completion of recovery projects through the creation of financial and performance incentives. Amends such Act to require a decision regarding an appeal of any decision regarding eligibility for, or the amount of, federal disaster assistance to be rendered within 60 (currently, 90) days after the designated federal official receives notice of the appeal. Requires: (1) the federal official to provide a written explanation to the applicant of a failure to satisfy that requirement, and (2) the President to transmit quarterly reports on such failures. Directs the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), in cooperation with representatives of state and local emergency management agencies, to review, update, and revise through rulemaking the factors considered when evaluating a governor's request for a major disaster declaration to measure the severity, magnitude, and impact of a disaster, in order to provide more objective criteria for evaluating the need for assistance to individuals and to speed such declaration. Authorizes the President, in any emergency, to provide assistance for rescue, care, shelter, and essential needs to individuals with household pets and service animals and to such pets and animals.</summary>
</bill>
