<bill session="111" type="hr" number="908" updated="2013-07-19T23:03:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-19T12:00:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-11-19T12:00:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2781) to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the Molalla River in Oregon, as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400065"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-17T16:30:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-339, by Mr. Cardoza.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-17T16:30:00-05:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rules XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-11-17T16:30:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="132">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 132.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T10:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13272-13279" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T10:28:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 908.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T11:25:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 908, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the yeas had prevailed. Ms. Foxx demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T11:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13279-13281" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T11:53:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 176 (Roll no. 902).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13279, H13279-13280" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-11-19T12:00:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="903" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 244 - 176 (Roll no. 903).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13272" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19T12:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="2781"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2781) to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the Molalla River in Oregon, as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</summary>
</bill>
