<bill session="111" type="s" number="3533" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Responsible Estate Tax Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reinstate estate and generation-skipping taxes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5764"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2010--Introduced.
Responsible Estate Tax Act - Repeals provisions of the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 (EGTRRA) eliminating the tax on estates and generation-skipping transfers and the step-up in basis provisions for property acquired from a decedent for estates of decedents dying after 2009 (thus restoring prior law). Declares that the sunset provision (general terminating date of December 10, 2010) of EGTRRA shall not apply to title V of such Act ( Estate, Gift, and Generation-Skipping Transfer Tax Provisions). Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) revise estate tax brackets for estates over $750,000 and&#160;impose a maximum tax rate of 55% on estates over $50 million; (2) impose a 10% surtax on estates over $500 million; (3) increase to $3 million the reduction in valuations of farmland for estate tax puposes; (4) increase to $2 million the maximum estate tax exclusion for contributions of conservation easements; (5) require executors of estates to file information returns and provide valuations and&#160;consistent basis information&#160;to persons acquiring property from decedents or by gift; (6) set forth estate valuation rules for certain transfers of nonbusiness assets and limit estate tax discounts for certain individuals with minority interests in a business acquired from a decedent; and (7) revise rules for valuing assets in grantor retained annuity trusts to require that the right to receive fixed amounts from an annuity last for a term of not less than 10 years, that such fixed amounts not decrease during the first 10 years of the annuity term, and that the remainder interest have a value greater than zero when transferred.</summary>
</bill>
