<bill session="113" type="h" number="1700" updated="2013-11-02T06:33:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Disaster Preparedness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the President to issue guidance on Federal response to a large-scale nuclear disaster.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2013-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2013--Introduced.
Nuclear Disaster Preparedness Act - Directs the President to issue guidance on the federal response to any nuclear disaster that: (1) may be caused by a natural catastrophe, an accident, or a terrorist or other attack; (2) occurs initially at a nuclear power plant; and (3) disperses radiation off the reactor site and into the surrounding area. Requires such guidance to: designate the single federal agency responsible for coordinating the government's efforts in response to a nuclear disaster (coordinating agency), including making a formal declaration that a nuclear disaster exists; identify the circumstances under which such declaration will occur; designate the single agency responsible for recommending the evacuation of the area within a 10-mile to 50-mile radius from the nuclear power plant; identify the circumstances under which such recommendation will be made; designate the single agency responsible for developing plans for, educating the public regarding, and conducting, such evacuation; designate the single agency responsible for recommending that evacuees may return following a nuclear disaster; identify the circumstances under which such recommendation will be made; designate the single agency responsible for conducting cleanup of a nuclear disaster; and identify what cleanup standards will apply.</summary>
</bill>
