<bill session="111" type="h" number="2169" updated="2013-07-19T23:31:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Limitation on Government Spending Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit Federal spending to a percentage of GDP.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400116"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2009-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="897"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2009--Introduced.
Limitation on Government Spending Act of 2009 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to define GDP as the gross domestic product for the relevant fiscal year as most recently estimated by the Congressional Budget Office (CBO). Defines federal spending limits for: (1) FY2011, as outlays not exceeding 22% of the GDP; (2) FY2012, as outlays not exceeding 21% of the GDP; and (3) FY2013 and fiscal years thereafter, as outlays not exceeding 20% of the GDP. Makes it out of order in the Senate or the House of Representatives to consider any legislation that includes any provision that would result in a deficit for a fiscal year that exceeds the maximum deficit amount or federal spending limit, as applicable, for such fiscal year. Permits waiver or suspension of such prohibition, or successful appeals from rulings of the Chair, only by an affirmative vote of three-fifths (60) of the Senate.</summary>
</bill>
