<bill session="112" type="s" number="1226" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Offshore Energy and Jobs Permitting Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to address air pollution from Outer Continental Shelf activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2021"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2011--Introduced.
Offshore Jobs and Energy Permitting Act of 2011 - Amends the Clean Air Act to require any air quality impact of Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) sources to be measured or modeled and determined solely with respect to the impacts in the corresponding onshore area. Provides that: (1) emissions from any vessel servicing or associated with an OCS source, including emissions while at the OCS source or in route to or from the OCS source within 25 miles of the OCS source, shall be considered direct emissions from the OCS source (current law) but shall not be subject to any emission control requirement applicable to such source; (2) an OCS source, for platform or drill ship exploration, is established when drilling commences at a location and ceases to exist when drilling activity ends at such location or is temporarily interrupted because the platform or drill ship relocates; and (3) an OCS source activity includes platform and drill ship exploration, construction, development, production, processing, and transportation. Requires: (1) final agency action on a permit application for platform or drill ship exploration for an OCS source under such Act to be taken no later than 180 days after the filing of&#160;such&#160; application;&#160;(2) such final agency action to be considered to be nationally applicable under judicial review; and (3) judicial review of such action to be without additional administrative review or adjudication. Prohibits: (1) the Environmental Appeals Board of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) from having any authority to consider any matter relating to the consideration, issuance, or denial of such permit;&#160;and (2) extending any administrative stay of the effectiveness of such permit beyond 180 days after the date of filing of such application.</summary>
</bill>
