<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1031" updated="2013-07-19T23:05:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Impeaching G. Thomas Porteous, Jr., judge of the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Louisiana, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2010-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-01-27">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-04T15:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 111-427.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-04T15:50:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="170">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 170.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11T10:46:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1031.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1327-1328, H1329-1337" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11T11:57:00-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to Article I of the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 412 - 0 (Roll no. 102).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1335" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11T12:04:00-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to Article II of the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 410 - 0 (Roll no. 103).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1335-1336" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11T12:10:00-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to Article III of the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 416 - 0 (Roll no. 104).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1335-1336" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11T12:44:00-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to Article IV of the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 423 - 0 (Roll no. 105).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1336-1337" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11T12:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-07">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>The motion to disaggregate the Articles of Impeachment are disagreed to by Yea-Nay Vote. 0 - 94. Record Vote Number: 260.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>The Senate adjudges that G. Thomas Porteous, Jr., judge of the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Louisiana, is guilty as charged in the first Article of Impeachment by Yea-Nay Vote. 96 - 0. Record Vote Number: 261.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>The Senate adjudges that G. Thomas Porteous, Jr., judge of the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Louisiana, is guilty as charged in the second Article of Impeachment by Yea-Nay Vote. 69 - 27. Record Vote Number: 262.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>The Senate adjudges that G. Thomas Porteous, Jr., judge of the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Louisiana, is guilty as charged in the third Article of Impeachment by Yea-Nay Vote. 88 - 8. Record Vote Number: 263.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>The Senate adjudges that G. Thomas Porteous, Jr., judge of the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Louisiana, is guilty as charged in the fourth Article of Impeachment by Yea-Nay Vote. 90 - 6. Record Vote Number: 264.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>The motion to forever disqualify G. Thomas Porteous, Jr. to hold and enjoy any office of honor, trust, or profit under the United States agreed to by Yea-Nay Vote. 94 - 2. Record Vote Number: 265.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="sr" number="458"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2010--Passed House without amendment.
Impeaches G. Thomas Porteous, Jr., judge of the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Louisiana, for high crimes and misdemeanors. Sets forth articles of impeachment. Declares that, while a U.S. district court judge, G. Thomas Porteous, engaged in a pattern of conduct incompatible with the trust and confidence placed in him as a judge. Declares that Judge Porteous denied a motion to recuse himself from a case where one of the parties was represented by a corrupt law firm with which he had a financial relationship. Declares that Judge Porteous made intentionally misleading statements at the recusal hearing and engaged in corrupt conduct after the trial, and while he had the case under advisement. Declares that Judge Porteous: (1) engaged in a longstanding pattern of corrupt conduct that demonstrates his unfitness to serve as a U.S. District Court Judge; and (2) engaged in a pattern of conduct inconsistent with the trust and confidence placed in him as a federal judge by knowingly and intentionally making material false statements and representations under penalty of perjury related to his personal bankruptcy filing, and by repeatedly violating a court order in his bankruptcy case. Declares that Judge Porteous knowingly made material false statements about his past to both the U.S. Senate and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) in order to obtain the office of U.S. District Court Judge. Declares that Judge Porteous is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors and should be removed from office.</summary>
</bill>
