<bill session="112" type="h" number="6087" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Protecting Girls by Preventing Child Marriage Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect girls in developing countries through the prevention of child marriage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2012-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2012-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400097" joined="2012-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2012-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2012-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2012-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2012-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2012-11-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2012-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2012-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2012-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2012-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2012-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2012-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2012-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="414"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2012--Introduced.
International Protecting Girls by Preventing Child Marriage Act of 2012 - Defines "child marriage" as the marriage of a girl or boy not yet the minimum age for marriage stipulated in law in the country in which the girl or boy is a resident, or where there is no such law, under the age of 18. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) child marriage is a violation of human rights and its prevention and elimination should be a U.S. foreign policy goal; and (2) expanding educational opportunities for girls, economic opportunities for women, and reducing maternal and child mortality are critical to achieving the Millennium Development Goals and U.S. global health and development objectives, including efforts to prevent HIV/AIDS. Authorizes the President to provide assistance, including through multilateral, nongovernmental, and faith-based organizations, to prevent child marriage in developing countries and to promote the educational, health, economic, social, and legal empowerment of girls and women. Directs the President to establish a multi-year strategy to prevent child marriage and promote the empowerment of girls at risk of child marriage in developing countries, and should include addressing the unique needs, vulnerabilities, and potential of girls under age 18 in developing countries. Expresses the sense of Congress that the President and all relevant agencies should collect and make available data on the incidence of child marriage in countries that receive U.S. foreign or development assistance where the practice of child marriage is prevalent. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to require that Department of State country reports on human rights practices include a description of the status of child marriage for each country in which child marriage is prevalent.</summary>
</bill>
