<bill session="112" type="h" number="830" updated="2013-07-20T01:17:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-10T16:36:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-03-10T16:36:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FHA Refinance Program Termination Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">FHA Refinance Program Termination Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">FHA Refinance Program Termination Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To rescind the unobligated funding for the FHA Refinance Program and to terminate the program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412420"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2011-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 22.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-03-07T18:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 112-25.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-03-07T18:54:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="13">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 13.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-03-08T19:12:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 150 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 830 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-09T14:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 150 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 150.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1678-1704" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="text of Section 1"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1686" label="as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="text of Section 2"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1690" label="as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="text of Section 3"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1690" label="as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 830 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 150 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Charles F. Bass to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T12:26:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 830.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T13:33:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 150, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Maloney amendment number 9 under the five minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T13:56:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 150, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Fitzpatrick amendment number 11 under the five minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T14:00:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 150, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Lynch amendment number 3 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T14:14:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lynch amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Frank (MA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T14:15:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 150, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Paulsen amendment number 4 under the five minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T14:19:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 150, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Inslee amendment number 12 under the five minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T14:24:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on pro forma amendments under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T14:29:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 150, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Waters amendment number 5 under the five minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T14:37:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 150, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Loretta Sanchez amendment in the nature of a substitute number 15 under the five minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T14:42:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 150, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Inslee amendment number 14 under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T14:52:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 150, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Holt amendment number 8 under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T14:56:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 150, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Garamendi amendment number 7 under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T15:04:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 150, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on pro forma amendments under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T15:21:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 150, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Waters amendment number 6, as modified, under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T15:27:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on adoption of the Waters amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Biggert demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T15:28:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T16:00:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 830.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T16:00:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1702" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T16:00:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T16:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Deutch moved to recommit with instructions to Financial Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1702-1704" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1702" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T16:03:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Deutch motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with amendments which provide a continuation of the provisions of the program for senior homeowners.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T16:12:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1703" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T16:30:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 185 - 243 (Roll no. 170).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-03-10T16:36:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="171" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 256 - 171 (Roll no. 171).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T16:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-10T16:36:00-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 830.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="150"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1315"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h175"/>
    <amendment number="h176"/>
    <amendment number="h177"/>
    <amendment number="h178"/>
    <amendment number="h179"/>
    <amendment number="h180"/>
    <amendment number="h181"/>
    <amendment number="h182"/>
    <amendment number="h183"/>
    <amendment number="h184"/>
    <amendment number="h185"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/10/2011--Passed House amended.
FHA Refinance Program Termination Act - Rescinds and permanently cancels all unexpended funding remaining available and allocated for the Federal Housing Administration (FHA) Refinancing Program of the Making Home Affordable initiative of the Secretary of the Treasury (under which borrowers owing more on their mortgage than the value of their home are provided opportunities to refinance into a FHA loan). Terminates the program. Requires all such unobligated balances so rescinded and permanently canceled to be retained in the general fund of the Treasury for reducing the debt of the federal government. Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to study: (1) the extent to which the FHA Refinancing Program is used by homeowners who are active duty members of the Armed Forces (or their spouses or parents), veterans, Gold Star-eligible widows, parents, or next of kin of Armed Forces members who died in military operations, or members or veterans with service-connected injuries (and their survivors and dependents); and (2) the impact of the program on such homeowners. Directs the HUD Secretary to publish a statement on the HUD website as to: (1) termination of the FHA Short [sic] Refinance Program; and (2) the availability of a Member of Congress to assist any borrower having trouble paying a mortgage and needing help contacting the borrower's lender or servicer to negotiate or acquire a loan modification.</summary>
</bill>
