<bill session="112" type="s" number="1336" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Immigration Fraud Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prevent immigration fraud and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2012-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4452"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4452-4453" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/2011--Introduced.
Immigration Fraud Prevention Act of 2011 - Amends the federal criminal code to subject to a fine, up to five years in prison, or both a person who: (1) knowingly and falsely represents that he or she is an attorney or accredited representative authorized to represent aliens in immigration proceedings, including removal proceedings; or (2) knowingly executes an immigration-related scheme to defraud a person, or to receive money or anything of value from any person by false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to direct the Attorney General (DOJ) to: (1) compile and update a list of persons who have provided pro bono representation during the most recent 12-month period to aliens in removal proceedings; and (2) compile, update, and make available to the public a list of individuals, organizations, and practices determined to be prohibited in the provision of representation in immigration proceedings, including individuals that have been convicted of immigration fraud under provisions of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
