<bill session="110" type="s" number="3531" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Afghan Freedom Support and Security Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize assistance for Afghanistan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2008-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economic stabilization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Food supply"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations economic assistance"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2008--Introduced.
Afghan Freedom Support and Security Act of 2008 - Authorizes funds for assistance to Afghanistan under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961. Directs the President to: (1) implement a system to monitor assistance provided under this Act on a program-by-program basis; and (2) provide assistance to enhance the government of Afghanistan's capacity to monitor programs carried out by the national, provincial, and local governments in Afghanistan. Authorizes appropriations. Directs: (1) the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of State and the Office of the Inspector General of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) in Afghanistan to oversee the programs authorized under this Act; and (2) the Office of Technical Assistance of the Department of the Treasury to conduct an annual assessment of Afghanistan's public finance system. Authorizes appropriations. Expresses the sense of Congress: (1) supporting the United Nations Assistance Mission in Afghanistan; and (2) that the President should expand assistance programs to innocent Afghan individuals, families, and communities that suffered losses from U.S. and allied military operations. Directs the President to appoint a coordinator who shall: (1) design an overall non-military strategy to advance U.S. interests in Afghanistan; (2) ensure policy coordination among federal agencies, including the Department of Defense; (3) coordinate with other countries and international organizations, including those supporting counter-insurgency and counter-narcotics efforts; and (4) review major security and development contracts. Directs the President to appoint a special envoy who shall coordinate U.S. policy on issues relating to strengthening relations between the nations of South and Central Asia. Authorizes appropriations for daily Radio Free Afghanistan broadcasting in the Dari and Pashto languages.</summary>
</bill>
