<bill session="110" type="s" number="2157" updated="2013-07-19T22:39:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Expanded Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish pilot programs in expanded school attendance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Citizenship education"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Rating of teachers"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="School libraries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social sciences"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Student activities"/>
    <term name="Student housing"/>
    <term name="Student transportation"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Theater"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Year round schools"/>
    <term name="Youth violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/2007--Introduced.
Expanded Education Act - Amends title I of the the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to create a new part I (Expanded Education) program awarding grants to states for the conduct of separate expanded day, week, or year pilot programs. Requires that for each of the expanded day and week programs at least: (1) 20 schools in each small state and 50 schools in each large state participate; (2) 50% of each participating school's student population consist of low-income students; (3) one entire grade in each participating school be involved in the program. Requires each expanded day and week program to: (1) increase student proficiency in reading and language arts, and mathematics; (2) provide education in new areas or directions, so that it is not wholly remedial; and (3) include sufficient recreational, social, or extra-curricular cultural activities. Allows each participating state to conduct expanded year programs through one or a combination of three school-based models: (1) two to be conducted by participating schools, institutions of higher education (IHE), or nonprofit organizations in schools at least 50% of whose students are low-income students, but differing in whether they require the mandatory participation of at least one entire grade or allow the voluntary participation of at least two grades at participating schools; and (2) one requiring the state to establish a voluntary summer learning institute for low-income students at an IHE to be run by the IHE or a nonprofit organization. Requires each expanded year program to: (1) provide education in new areas or directions, or increase student expertise; (2) emphasize non-remedial work; and (3) include sufficient recreational, social, or extra-curricular cultural activities.</summary>
</bill>
