<bill session="109" type="h" number="1661" updated="2013-07-19T19:18:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act and the Communications Act of 1934 to increase participation by small businesses in spectrum auctions conducted by the Federal Communications Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400350"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E662-663"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Television frequency allocation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Small Business Act to establish within the Small Business Administration (SBA) an Associate Administrator for Telecommunications Finance (Associate Administrator) to supervise and manage SBA financing in the area of telecommunications. Authorizes the Associate Administrator to approve SBA loan guarantees with respect to Federal Communications Commission (FCC) spectrum licenses (for radio and television broadcasting) acquired in the secondary market. Establishes a Telecommunications Finance Office. Establishes the Telecommunications Spectrum Installment Loan Program to: (1) make direct loans to qualified telecommunications borrowers (borrowers) for the acquisition of spectrum licenses through FCC auction; and (2) guarantee loans to borrowers for telecommunications equipment and working capital in connection with spectrum license acquisitions. Establishes the Telecommunications Accelerated Certified Lender Program for the guarantee by certified lenders of loans made to borrowers for: (1) the acquisition of spectrum licenses through either FCC auction or the secondary market; and (2) telecommunications equipment and working capital in connection with spectrum license acquisitions. Requires certified lenders to be insured depository institutions approved by the SBA. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to: (1) establish the Telecommunications Loan Guarantee Fund for financing loans authorized under this Act; and (2) require the FCC, with respect to FCC spectrum auctions, to accept from a borrower a letter of credit in lieu of any upfront payment or other earnest money required by FCC regulation.</summary>
</bill>
