<bill session="112" type="hr" number="788" updated="2013-07-20T01:09:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-20T14:24:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-20T14:24:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 118) providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Office of Family Assistance of the Administration for Children and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services relating to waiver and expenditure authority under section 1115 of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1315) with respect to the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families program; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3409) to limit the authority of the Secretary of the Interior to issue regulations before December 31, 2013, under the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977; and providing for proceedings during the period from September 22, 2012, through November 12, 2012.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T19:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-680, by Mr. Bishop (UT).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-19T19:53:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of both H.J.Res. 118 and H.R. 3409. H.J. Res. 118 is debatable for one hour and is closed to amendments. H.R. 3409 is debatable for one hour and specified amendments are in order. Motions to recommit are in order. The resolution also provides for approval of the Journal on specified days; appointing of Members to perform duties of the Chair; not counting of legislative days for the purposes of the War Powers Act, purposes of clause 7 of rule XIII, and the purposes of clause 7(c)(1) of rule XXII.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-09-19T19:53:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="162">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 162.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20T12:32:00-04:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Mr. Bishop (UT) called up the resolution H. Res. 788, and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20T12:38:00-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER AGAINST CONSIDERATION - Ms. Moore stated that the provisions of H. Res. 788 violate section 426(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 and made a point of order against the consideration of the resolution. Subsequently, the Chair noted that the required threshold of identifying the specific language in question had been met, and the House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the question of consideration. At the conclusion of debate on the question of consideration, the Chair will put the question to wit: Will the House now consider the resolution?</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20T12:53:00-04:00">
      <text>On question of consideration of the Resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20T12:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6165-6167, H6173-6174" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20T12:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 788.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20T14:10:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 238 - 179 (Roll no. 587).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6173-6174" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2012-09-20T14:24:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="588" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 233 - 182 (Roll no. 588).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6165" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hj" number="118"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3409"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2012--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 118) providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Office of Family Assistance of the Administration for Children and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services relating to waiver and expenditure authority under section 1115 of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1315) with respect to the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families program; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3409) to limit the authority of the Secretary of the Interior to issue regulations before December 31, 2013, under the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977; and providing for proceedings during the period from September 22, 2012, through November 12, 2012.</summary>
</bill>
