<bill session="109" type="h" number="3810" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a Special Inspectors General Council for Hurricane Katrina.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2005-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2005-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1860"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2005--Introduced.
Establishes in the executive branch a Special Inspectors General Council for Hurricane Katrina. Provides for the membership of the Council to include: (1) the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security, who shall act as Chairman of the Council; and (2) the Inspector General of each of eight specified federal departments and agencies. Designates the Council as the principal interagency forum for ensuring appropriate and effective oversight of, and accountability for, the expenditure of funds relating to recovery from Hurricane Katrina. Specifies the responsibilities of the Council, including: (1) to facilitate the immediate opening of Council offices in the Gulf Cost region, with auditor and investigative personnel detailed and deployed immediately as needed; (2) to establish hotlines and websites to report waste, fraud, and abuse; and (3) to provide continuous monitoring and reporting related to the recovery efforts to the heads of the federal entities that are Council members and to Congress. Requires the Chairman of the Council to submit semiannual reports summarizing the activities of the Council.</summary>
</bill>
