<bill session="111" type="h" number="6543" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drug Safety Enhancement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to improve the safety of drugs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2010-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2010-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2010-12-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/17/2010--Introduced.
Drug Safety Enhancement Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to expand safety and inspection requirements for the manufacture and importation&#160;of drugs by: (1) expanding registration requirements for foreign and domestic drug producers; (2) requiring drug manufacturers to have in effect and implement an effective quality system; (3) expanding and equalizing inspection requirements for foreign and domestic drug producers; (4) imposing additional requirements relating to the notification, nondistribution, and recall of adulterated or misbranded drugs; (5) permitting the detention of drugs found to be in violation of drug safety requirements; (6) allowing for the destruction of drugs that pose a significant adverse health effect; (7) providing enhanced civil and criminal penalties and forfeiture for violations of drug safety requirements and enhanced subpoena authority for investigating violations; (8) prohibiting the importation of drugs into the United States lacking documentation of safety; (9) requiring unique identification numbers for drug establishments and importers; and (10) expanding protections for whistleblowers who refuse to violate, or who disclose violations of, this Act.</summary>
</bill>
