<bill session="113" type="s" number="891" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Jobs in American Forests Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the employment of Americans by requiring State workforce agencies to certify that employers are actively recruiting Americans and that Americans are not qualified or available to fill the positions that the employer wants to fill with H-2B nonimmigrants.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1596"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="744"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2013--Introduced.
American Jobs in American Forests Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Labor, as a component of the H-2B (temporary nonagricultural workers) labor certification process for employment in forestry, to take specified actions to recruit U.S. workers before petitioning to hire H-2B workers. Requires a prospective H-2B employer to submit a separate petition for each state in which the employer plans to employ H-2B non-immigrants for a period of at least seven days. Prohibits the Secretary from granting a temporary labor certification to a prospective H-2B employer until the Director of the state workforce agency has determined that: (1) employer recruitment requirements have been met, and (2) U.S. nationals are not qualified or available to fill such employment opportunities.</summary>
</bill>
