<bill session="109" type="h" number="4645" updated="2013-07-19T19:45:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preventing Medicare Seniors from being Confused due to Abusive Marketing (Prevent Medicare SCAMs) Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide broader and more informed protection to Medicare eligible individuals from abusive marketing practices of Medicare prescription drug plans and MA-PD plans to permit enrollees under Medicare prescription drug plans that have been sanctioned to elect to enroll under other plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400647"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2005-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-18">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health care fraud"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Telemarketing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/18/2005--Introduced.
Preventing Medicare Seniors from being Confused due to Abusive Marketing (Prevent Medicare SCAMs) Act of 2005 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide for: (1) enhanced penalties for Medicare Advantage-Prescription Drug (MA-PD) plans and Medicare prescription drug plans that violate marketing requirements; and (2) public notification about plans that habitually receive intermediate sanctions. Permits Medicare beneficiaries enrolled under prescription drug plans suspended under this Act to enroll under other plans during the period of suspension. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress on each anti-fraud and abuse provision (including related intermediate sanctions) applicable to an MA-PD plan or a Medicare prescription drug plan, and assess its effectiveness and the overall compliance of such plans.</summary>
</bill>
