<bill session="111" type="s" number="633" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tribal Health Promotion and Tribal Colleges and Universities Advancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Advancing Tribes Through Tribal Colleges and Universities Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">AT TCUs Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">THE PATH Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Through Higher Education: Promoting the Advancement of Tribal Health Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a program for tribal colleges and universities within the Department of Health and Human Services and to amend the Native American Programs Act of 1974 to authorize the provision of grants and cooperative agreements to tribal colleges and universities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2009-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2009-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2009-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3376-3377"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 111-66.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2009--Introduced.
Tribal Health Promotion and Tribal Colleges and Universities Advancement Act of 2009 - Through Higher Education: Promoting the Advancement of Tribal Health Act or THE PATH Act - Defines "tribal college or university" as having the meaning given the term by specified provisions of the Higher Education Act of 1965. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into a memorandum of agreement with the American Indian Higher Education Consortium for equitable Native American participation in HHS programs, services, and resources and to provide technical assistance to tribal colleges and universities. Requires grants to, or cooperative agreements with, tribal colleges and universities for: (1) health and wellness fairs, health promotion and disease prevention programs, and programs to reduce tribal community health disparities; (2) developing and strengthening public health professional degree programs; (3) research, grant management, and coordination of tribal college and university activities; and (4) research on health promotion and disease prevention. Establishes the Tribal College and University Rural Health Equity Endowment Fund to endow a tribal health professions workforce development program. Advancing Tribes Through Tribal Colleges and Universities Act or the AT TCUs Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to require the Secretary of Labor to establish the TCU Native Prosperity Program of grants to, or cooperative agreements with, tribal colleges and universities for economic development, entrepreneurship, community development, and sound fiscal leadership in Indian communities.</summary>
</bill>
