<bill session="112" type="s" number="1046" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Guantanamo Bay Detention Facility Detention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the detention at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, of high-value enemy combatants who will be detained long-term.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2011--Introduced.
Guantanamo Bay Detention Facility Detention Act of 2011 - Requires each high-value enemy combatant captured or otherwise taken into long-term custody or detention by the United States to, while under such U.S. detention, be detained at the Guantanamo Bay Detention Facility (GTMO) at U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba. Defines "high-value enemy combatant" as an enemy combatant who: (1) is a senior member of al-Qaeda, the Taliban, or any associated terrorist group; (2) has knowledge of an imminent terrorist threat against the United States or its territories, the U.S. Armed Forces, or U.S. people, organizations, or allies; (3) has, or has had, direct involvement in planning or preparing a terrorist action against the United States or a U.S. ally or in assisting the leadership of al-Qaeda, the Taliban, or any associated terrorist group in planning or preparing such a terrorist action; or (4) would, if released from detention, constitute a clear and continuing threat to the United States or any U.S. ally.</summary>
</bill>
