<bill session="113" type="h" number="2704" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Budget Planning Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit to Congress a Future-Years Veterans Program and a quadrennial veterans review, to establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs a Chief Strategy Officer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400274"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2013-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2013--Introduced.
Department of Veterans Affairs Budget Planning Reform Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to submit annually to Congress a future-years veterans program (program) reflecting estimated expenditures and proposed appropriations included in the budget for that fiscal year. Requires each program to set forth a five-year VA plan to address the U.S. commitment to veterans and the resources necessary to meet that commitment. Requires the Secretary, in 2017 and quadrennially thereafter, to conduct a review of the strategy for meeting such commitment and resources requirement (quadrennial veterans review). Requires each review to be coordinated with the above program. Directs the Secretary to report to the congressional veterans committees on each review. Directs the Secretary to provide annually to the appropriate VA officials written policy guidance for the preparation and review of the planning and program recommendations and budget proposals of the VA elements of such officials. Requires the Secretary to designate a Chief Strategy Officer to advise the Secretary on long-range VA strategy and implications. Directs the Secretary to study (through an independent contractor) and report to the veterans committees on the functions and organizational structure of the Office of the Secretary and the VA, including the most efficient and economical allocation and structure for assisting the Secretary in carrying out duties and responsibilities.</summary>
</bill>
