<bill session="111" type="h" number="2987" updated="2013-07-19T23:38:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cure and Understanding through Research for Alzheimer's Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">La Cura Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to ensure sufficient resources and increase efforts for research at the National Institutes of Health relating to Alzheimer's disease, to authorize an education and outreach program to promote public awareness and risk reduction with respect to Alzheimer's disease (with particular emphasis on education and outreach in Hispanic populations), and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400355"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2010-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2009-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2009-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400620" joined="2009-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2009-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2009-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Behavioral sciences"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2009--Introduced.
Cure and Understanding through Research for Alzheimer's Act of 2009 or La Cura Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to ensure sufficient resources for activities relating to Alzheimer's disease and Hispanic communities, including by: (1) increasing efforts in epidemiological work in Hispanic subgroups; (2) allocating resources to the National Institute on Aging Alzheimer's disease research centers and other academic centers involved in such research to increase participation of Hispanics and other underrepresented ethnic groups in research and clinical trials in sufficient numbers to draw valid conclusions; and (3) conducting social, behavioral, and health services research to understand the underlying reasons why Hispanic individuals delay diagnosis and underutilize services, to identify culturally and linguistically appropriate approaches to address such delays and underutilization, and to identify approaches for providing, and improving the quality of, culturally competent care. Requires the Director to expand and intensify NIH efforts to educate communities about the importance of research relating to Alzheimer's disease and to respond effectively to cultural concerns about participation in such research.Authorizes appropriations for a program of grants to states to carry out demonstration programs related to Alzheimer's disease. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to conduct an aggressive, evidence-based education and outreach program to promote public awareness and risk reduction with respect to Alzheimer's disease, particularly to Hispanic populations.</summary>
</bill>
