<bill session="112" type="h" number="6614" updated="2013-07-20T02:07:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fire-Damaged Home Rebuilding Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to allow the rebuilding of certain structures located in special flood hazard zones, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400663"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/29/2012--Introduced.
Fire-Damaged Home Rebuilding Act of 2012 - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to prohibit certain mandatory land use and control measures in an area from being considered to be in compliance with land management criteria for participation in the flood insurance program unless those measures authorize the granting of a variance from compliance for a residential structure located in an area having special flood hazards but which is substantially damaged, instead, by non-flood related causes. Requires such a variance to allow for the repair and restoration of the structure to its predamaged condition on its original location without any higher elevation, but only if its owner at the time of the damage repairs and restores the structure for continued occupancy. Allows a variance to be granted only by the appropriate regional director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), subject to specified considerations. Requires chargeable flood insurance premium rates for a residential structure granted such a variance to equal, after repair and restoration, the rates which would have been applicable if the structure had not been substantially damaged, repaired, and restored under the variance.</summary>
</bill>
