<bill session="111" type="s" number="1781" updated="2013-07-20T00:39:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">REDUCE Demonstration Program</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reducing Emergency Department Utilization through Coordination and Empowerment Demonstration Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for a demonstration program to reduce frequent use of health services by Medicaid beneficiaries with chronic illnesses by providing coordinated care management and community support services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-10-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/14/2009--Introduced.
Reducing Emergency Department Utilization through Coordination and Empowerment Demonstration Program Act or the REDUCE Demonstration Program - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish the REDUCE demonstration program under which the Secretary shall enter into agreements with states to provide for the development, implementation, and evaluation of innovative approaches to coordinated care management and increased access to community support services for targeted beneficiaries under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act in order to reduce hospital admissions and the use of emergency health care services.</summary>
</bill>
