<bill session="110" type="h" number="7305" updated="2013-07-19T22:07:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">REAP Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Responsibly Ending Authority to Purchase Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To immediately terminate the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury under the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 to purchase troubled assets, to require the Secretary to make insurance of troubled mortgage-backed securities available for purchase, and to provide incentives to reinvest foreign earnings in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400651"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-11-20">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-11-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2008--Introduced.
Responsibly Ending Authority to Purchase Act of 2008 or the REAP Act of 2008 - Terminates the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to establish the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) under the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA). Amends the EESA to convert the program to guarantee troubled assets into a program to guarantee troubled mortgage-backed securities. Terminates such program on December 31, 2009. Renames the Troubled Assets Insurance Financing Fund the Troubled Mortgage-Backed Securities Insurance Financing Fund. Defines troubled mortgage-backed securities as a residential or commercial mortgage or any instrument originated or issued on or before March 14, 2008, that is based upon or related to such mortgage. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a deduction for between 85% and 100% of dividends received from controlled foreign corporations by certain corporations which are U.S. shareholders. Requires such deduction to be invested in the United States pursuant to a specified domestic reinvestment plan, including as a source for the funding of worker hiring and training, infrastructure, research and development, capital investments, or the financial stabilization of the corporation for the purposes of job retention or creation. States that such reinvestment requirements shall be met if amounts repatriated are invested in distressed debt for at least one year.</summary>
</bill>
