<bill session="109" type="h" number="5305" updated="2013-07-19T19:51:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Headwaters Protection and Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To address the forest and watershed emergency in the State of Colorado that has been exacerbated by the bark beetle infestation, to provide for the conduct of activities in the State to reduce the risk of wildfire and flooding, to promote economically healthy rural communities by reinvigorating the forest products industry in the State, to encourage the use of biomass fuels for energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400020" joined="2006-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, Energy and Commerce, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman .</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-23">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Dairy, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF15" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="2604"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Insect control"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Private forests"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Tree diseases"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2006--Introduced.
Headwaters Protection and Restoration Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior (for Bureau of Land Management [BLM] land) or the Secretary of Agriculture (for National Forest System land) to consider emergency event procedures in response to watershed and forest emergencies. Authorizes the Secretary concerned to: (1) carry out projects in Colorado to reduce hazardous fuel or prevent the spread of bark beetles to adjacent trees; (2) prepare emergency event proposals or consider proposals from the governor, the state forester, a water conservation district, or an at-risk community; and (3) conduct emergency event evaluations in response to a request or to an emergency event that affects a municipal water supply system, a wildland-urban interface, or other public or private property and that has caused or will cause significant damage o to federal land or adjacent nonfederal land. Requires the Secretary concerned to carry out a program in Colorado to: (1) ensure the long-term health of forests; and (2) reduce the risk of catastrophic fire, flooding, and watershed destruction. Extends the authority of the Secretaries to enter into federal and state cooperative watershed restoration and protection agreements and contracts. Requires the Secretary concerned to provide: (1) financial assistance for long-term stewardship projects in certain areas; and (2) grants and low-cost loans to small business concerns in the Colorado forest product industry. Establishes the Colorado Forest Health Fund from which amounts shall be transferred to the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out measures to improve forest health and reduce hazardous fuels. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) provide grants for research and development and marketing of forest products and for research in higher elevation forests; and (2) collaborate on research on and the development and transfer of broader landscape treatment strategies and ways to integrate best science with community needs. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to provide: (1) financial assistance under the Community and Private Land Fire Assistance Program to the Colorado State Forest Service to establish a grant program to help improve private forest land; and (2) grants to Colorado for the Colorado Fuels for Schools program under the Energy Policy Act of 2005.</summary>
</bill>
