<bill session="113" type="hr" number="310" updated="2013-11-02T06:18:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Calling for more accountable foreign assistance for Cambodia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412553" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412540" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412569" joined="2013-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2013-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2013--Introduced.
States that in order to be credible the July 2013 parliamentary elections in Cambodia must implement the recommendations in the July 16, 2012, Report of the United Nations Special Rapporteur on human rights in Cambodia, and must include the participation of all political parties leaders, including Sam Rainsy. Urges the Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) not to support national or local elections in Cambodia if such United Nations (U.N.) recommendations are ignored, and if political parties and opposition leaders are excluded or hampered from freely participating in electoral processes. States that: (1) any election in Cambodia that the Secretary of State determines is not credible should be deemed as an illegitimate expression of the Cambodian peoples' will; and (2) a resulting Cambodian government should not be eligible for direct U.S. government assistance, and the Department of State and USAID should reduce assistance for Cambodia and urge international financial institutions to do the same.</summary>
</bill>
