<bill session="111" type="s" number="3933" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Electricity Reliability Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect electricity reliability by prohibiting the use of funds for carrying out certain policies and procedures that adversely affect domestic coal mining operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300014"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="6113"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Electricity Reliability Protection Act of 2010 - Prohibits the use of funds made available to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the Corps of Engineers, or the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement (OSMRE) of the Department of the Interior to implement, administer, or enforce any policy or procedure set forth in either the memorandum entitled "Enhanced Surface Coal Mining Pending Permit Coordination Procedures" or the EPA guidance entitled "Improving EPA Review of Appalachian Surface Coal Mining Operations under the Clean Water Act, National Environmental Policy Act, and the Environmental Justice Executive Order," until the EPA, the Corps of Engineers, or OSMRE promulgates regulations to implement it after providing notice and an opportunity for comment in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</summary>
</bill>
