<bill session="111" type="h" number="6024" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">E. coli Traceability and Eradication Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act to develop an effective sampling and testing program to test for E. coli in boneless beef manufacturing trimmings and other raw ground beef components, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG29" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
E. coli Traceability and Eradication Act - Amends the the Federal Meat Inspection Act to require that specified slaughterhouses, processing establishments, and grinding facilities perform specified tests for the presence of Shiga toxin-producing E. coli in beef. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to make grants to assist certain slaughterhouses, processing establishments, and grinding facilities in complying with such requirements. Terminates grant assistance on December 1, 2013. Subjects imported trim, bench trim, and ground beef to the same testing requirements as domestic trim, bench trim, and ground beef. Defines "enteric foodborne pathogen" as live bacteriological matter that is commonly present in the digestive systems of animals for slaughter, including Shiga toxin-producing E. coli and salmonella, the presence of which in meat food products may indicate unsanitary conditions at the point of slaughter. Directs the Secretary to implement sampling protocols to enable the Food Safety and Inspection Service to rapidly trace potential adulteration and contamination of meat and meat food products by enteric foodborne pathogens to possible preceding sources of the adulteration and contamination, including preparation, packaging, and slaughtering establishments, to determine the original site source of the adulteration or contamination. Requires the Secretary: (1) if a meat or meat food product sample tests positive for adulteration or contamination by enteric foodborne pathogens, to conduct a trace to identify all sites of adulteration and contamination, including preparation, packaging, and slaughtering establishments, and to identify the original source of adulteration or contamination; and (2) if a raw ground meat sample tests positive for adulteration or contamination by enteric foodborne pathogens at a preparation, packaging, or slaughtering establishment, to require subsequent daily sampling at the establishment and any supplying establishments for a minimum of 15 consecutive days after the date on which the sample is collected.</summary>
</bill>
