<bill session="112" type="h" number="2349" updated="2013-07-20T01:30:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-11T15:29:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-10-11T15:29:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Benefits Training Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Veterans' Benefits Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Veterans' Benefits Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to annually assess the skills of certain employees and managers of the Veterans Benefits Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the determination of annual income with respect to pensions for certain veterans, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot program to assess the skills of certain employees and managers of the Veterans Benefits Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2011-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs Prior to Referral.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-07">
      <text>Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-06T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 112-241.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-10-06T16:18:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="159">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 159.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T15:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T15:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6695-6698" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T15:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2349.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-10-11T15:29:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6695-6696" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1898"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1707"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1847"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/2011--Passed House amended.
(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on October 6, 2011. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Veterans' Benefits Act of 2011 - (Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to conduct a four-year pilot program to: (1) biennially assess the skills of appropriate Veterans Benefits Administration employees and managers responsible for processing VA compensation and pension benefit claims; (2) develop and implement individualized training plans related to such skills; (3) provide remediation for deficiently skilled employees or managers receiving a less than satisfactory result on any portion of the assessment; and (4) take appropriate disciplinary actions with respect to individuals failing to receive a satisfactory result after being given two opportunities for such remediation. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Secretary to report annually during the program period to the congressional veterans committees on such assessment and the training conducted. (Sec. 3) Excludes from annual income, for purposes of eligibility for pensions for veterans and their surviving spouses and children, reimbursements resulting from: (1) any accident; (2) any theft or loss; (3) any casualty loss; (4) medical expenses resulting from any such accident, theft, or loss; and (5) pain and suffering (including insurance settlement payments and general damages awarded by a court) related to such accident, theft, or loss. Extends through November 18, 2011, VA authority to obtain veterans' income verification information from the Secretary of the Treasury or the Commissioner of Social Security. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to notify VA benefits claimants by the most effective means available, including electronic communication or notification in writing, of any information or medical or lay evidence not previously provided to the Secretary that is necessary to substantiate a claim. (Current law does not specify the means of notice.) (Sec. 5) Requires the Secretary, in assisting claimants in obtaining relevant records in support of a claim, to make at least two requests to a custodian of a private medical record, unless it is made evident by the first request that a second request would be futile. Directs the Secretary to encourage claimants to submit relevant private medical records if such submission does not burden the claimant. Allows the claimant to instead authorize the Secretary to obtain such records. Provides procedures for the obtaining of public records by the Secretary. (Sec. 6) Prohibits, in any case arising out of the administration of laws and benefits by VA, considering any person who is mentally incapacitated, deemed mentally incompetent, or experiencing an extended loss of consciousness from being considered adjudicated as a mental defective for purposes of the right to receive or transport firearms without the order or finding of a judge, magistrate, or other judicial authority of competent jurisdiction that such person is a danger to himself or herself or others. (Sec. 7) Provides criminal penalties against any person who solicits, contracts for, charges, or receives any fee or compensation from a veteran, other than that currently permitted under law, for: (1) advice on how to file a benefits claim; or (2) the preparation, presentation, or prosecution of a claim before the date on which a notice of disagreement is filed in a proceeding on the claim. (Sec. 8) Prohibits the Secretary from paying more than $2 million in Senior Executive Service performance awards for each of FY2012-FY2016.</summary>
</bill>
