<bill session="110" type="h" number="6236" updated="2013-07-19T21:58:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Disability Benefits Claims Modernization Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to modernize the disability benefits claims processing system of the Department of Veterans Affairs to ensure the accurate, consistent, and timely delivery of compensation to veterans and their families and survivors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="2008-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412226" joined="2008-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="2008-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400334" joined="2008-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2008-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5892"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2008--Introduced.
Veterans Disability Benefits Claims Modernization Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct a study on adjusting the schedule for rating veterans' disabilities in order to base such schedule on current standards, practices, and codes in common use by the medical, mental health, and disability professions. Establishes in the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) the Advisory Committee on Disability Compensation to consult with and advise the Secretary with respect to the maintenance and periodic readjustment of the above schedule. Directs the Secretary to conduct a study on the: (1) employee work credit system of the VA's Veterans Benefits Administration (VBA), which is used to measure the work production of VBA employees; and (2) VBA work management system, with the goal of improving accountability, quality, and accuracy and reducing the time for processing claims. Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop a certification examination for VBA employees and managers responsible for processing benefits claims; and (2) evaluate the training of VBA employees responsible for matters relating to veterans' compensation or pension benefits. Directs the Secretary to conduct a study of the use of information technology at the VBA, including the technology known as "VistA." Allows a claim beneficiary to be substituted as a claimant in the case of the death of a veteran claimant while a claim is awaiting adjudication or appeal.</summary>
</bill>
