<bill session="110" type="s" number="1185" updated="2013-07-19T22:30:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Graduation Promise Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide grants to States to improve high schools and raise graduation rates while ensuring rigorous standards, to develop and implement effective school models for struggling students and dropouts, and to improve State policies to raise graduation rates, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2007-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2007-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4843-4844"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4844-4851" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2928"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/2007--Introduced.
Graduation Promise Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to states and, through them, subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) for differentiated high school improvement systems targeting support to schools with low student achievement and graduation rates after the school fails for two consecutive years to make adequate yearly progress (AYP) pursuant to state academic performance standards. Requires state grantees to establish comprehensive school performance indicators and minimum annual improvement benchmarks for use, in addition to current AYP measures, in analyzing school performance and determining the improvement category into which a school is placed. Directs LEA subgrantees to convene a local school improvement team for each school placed in an improvement category that will use performance indicators to conduct a school needs assessment and develop a multiyear school improvement plan tailored to the school's need categorization. Permits LEAs to use funds to improve feeder middle schools. Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive grants to: (1) LEAs, nonprofit organizations, and institutions of higher education to develop and implement, or replicate, effective school models for struggling students and dropouts; and (2) states to adjust their policies to allow for educational innovations that improve high school graduation rates while ensuring rigorous education content standards and assessments, if such states implement differentiated high school improvement systems and statewide longitudinal student data systems.</summary>
</bill>
