<bill session="111" type="h" number="5649" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Digital Goods and Services Tax Fairness Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote neutrality, simplicity, and fairness in the taxation of digital goods and digital services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2010-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1255-1256"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2010--Introduced.
Digital Goods and Services Tax Fairness Act of 2010 - Prohibits a state or local jurisdiction from imposing multiple or discriminatory taxes on or with respect to the sale or use of digital goods or services delivered or transferred electronically to a customer. Restricts taxation of digital goods and services to the retail sale of such goods and services and by the jurisdiction encompassing a customer's tax address. Prohibits the use of existing regulations or administrative rulings relating to the taxation of tangible personal property or other services to impose any tax on the sale or use of digital goods or services. Prohibits taxation on or with respect to the sale or use of digital medical, education, or energy management services. Provides that if charges for digital goods and services are not separately stated from charges for other goods or services, the charges for digital goods and services may be taxed at the same rate and on the same basis as charges for other goods and services unless the seller can reasonably identify the charges for digital goods and services from its business records. Grants jurisdiction to federal district courts to prevent a violation of this Act. Expresses the sense of Congress that each state shall take reasonable steps to prevent multiple taxation of digital goods and services where a foreign country has imposed a tax on such goods and services.</summary>
</bill>
