<bill session="109" type="s" number="803" updated="2013-07-19T20:20:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HEART Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Help Expand Access to Recovery and Treatment Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide parity with respect to substance abuse treatment benefits under group health plans and health insurance coverage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300032" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2005-04-27" withdrawn="2005-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3680"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3680-3682" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1258"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2005--Introduced.
Help Expand Access to Recovery and Treatment Act of 2005 or the HEART Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and the Internal Revenue Code to prohibit a group health plan or group health coverage that provides both medical and surgical benefits and substance abuse benefits from imposing treatment limitations or financial requirements on the substance abuse treatment benefits unless similar limitations or requirements are imposed for medical and surgical benefits. Excludes such requirements for plans and coverage for small employers and for cases in which the application of such requirements results in an increase in the cost under the plan of at least one percent. Applies such requirements to health insurance coverage offered in the individual market.</summary>
</bill>
