<bill session="111" type="s" number="1603" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Education Tuition Support Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">VETS Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend section 484B of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for tuition reimbursement and loan forgiveness to students who withdraw from an institution of higher education to serve in the uniformed services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2010-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2010-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2456"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2561"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/2009--Introduced.
Veterans Education Tuition Support Act of 2009 or the VETS Act of 2009 - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education to refund to students the tuition and fees paid for education they will not receive due to their withdrawal from school to serve in the Armed Forces. Waives the application of any requirement that students return title IV funds upon withdrawing from school to students whose withdrawal is necessitated by service in the Armed Forces. Provides loan forgiveness under the Federal Family Education Loan, Direct Loan, and Perkins Loan programs to students whose withdrawal from school is necessitated by service in the Armed Forces.</summary>
</bill>
