<bill session="110" type="h" number="108" updated="2013-07-19T21:04:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Small Business Regulatory Assistance Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish a program to provide regulatory compliance assistance to small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400095"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
National Small Business Regulatory Assistance Act of 2007 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), acting through the Associate Administrator for Small Business Development Centers, to establish a program to provide regulatory compliance assistance to small businesses through participating Small Business Development Centers (Centers), the Association for Small Business Development Centers (Association), and Federal compliance partnership programs. Requires the Administrator to enter into arrangements with participating Centers to provide: (1) access to regulatory information and resources; (2) training and education activities; (3) confidential counseling to owners and operators of small businesses regarding compliance with Federal and State regulations; and (4) technical assistance. Directs the Administrator to contract with the Association to act as the repository of and clearinghouse for data and information submitted by Centers. Requires the Administrator, giving substantial weight to the Association's recommendations, to select the Centers programs of two States from each of ten groups of States for participation in the program. Authorizes the Administrator to make additional selections after three years, with a preference for programs that have a plan for consulting with Federal and State agencies to ensure that assistance provided under this Act is not duplicated by any other Federal or State program. Sets forth the formula for determining program grant amounts.</summary>
</bill>
