<bill session="112" type="s" number="757" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Carbon Dioxide Capture Technology Prize Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide incentives to encourage the development and implementation of technology to capture carbon dioxide from dilute sources on a significant scale using direct air capture technologies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2011-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2011-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2011-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-22.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 112-33.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-07-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="100">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 100.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2011--Reported to Senate amended.
Carbon Dioxide Capture Technology Prize Act of 2011 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to direct the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to establish and award competitive technology financial awards for the development and implementation of technology to capture carbon dioxide from media in which the concentration of carbon dioxide is dilute. Conditions receipt of such a financial award on an applicant agreeing to vest the intellectual property derived from the technology in one or more entities that are incorporated in the United States. Establishes the Carbon Dioxide Capture Technology Advisory Board to advise the Secretary in carrying out duties under this Act. Terminates the Board and all authorities under this Act five years after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
