<bill session="109" type="hr" number="904" updated="2013-07-19T19:02:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Commending the American press for its long history of keeping the American public informed of its government's actions both at home and abroad.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2006-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Censorship"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Journalism"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Reporters and reporting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2006--Introduced.
Commends the American press for its long history of keeping the American public informed of its government's actions both at home and abroad. Repudiates censorship of the press and reaffirms that a vital characteristic of any democratic society is a free press. Finds that the press helps to educate the American people and provides all Americans a vital means of understanding the actions of the Congress, the Administration, and the Supreme Court, in addition to reporting important state and local government actions. Condemns those regimes which censor the press. Praises the government of Iraq for its commitment to a free press as well as the brave Iraqi journalists who have put their lives at risk to institutionalize a free press in Iraq. Expects that all elected representatives of the American people hold true to their oath to defend the Constitution and not use the trust of their office to weaken the vital role of a free press.</summary>
</bill>
