<bill session="112" type="sr" number="493" updated="2013-07-20T02:14:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution recognizing that the occurrence of prostate cancer in African-American men has reached epidemic proportions and urging Federal agencies to address that health crisis by supporting education, awareness outreach, and research specifically focused on how prostate cancer affects African-American men.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2012-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2012-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2012-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4206-4207"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4206" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="313"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="sr" number="529"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/2012--Introduced.
Recognizes: (1) that prostate cancer has created a health crisis for African American men; and (2) the importance of health coverage and access to care, as well as promoting informed decision-making between men and their doctors, in screening and treatment options for prostate cancer. Urges federal agencies to support: (1) prostate cancer research and education, awareness, and early detection efforts at the grass roots levels to end such crisis; and (2) the Office of Minority Health of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) in improving health and health care outcomes for African Americans at an elevated risk of prostate cancer. Urges investment by the National Cancer Institute and National Institute of Biomedical Imaging and Bioengineering, other elements of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), and the Department of Defense (DOD) in research focusing on the improvement of early detection and treatment of prostate cancer.</summary>
</bill>
