<bill session="109" type="h" number="5768" updated="2013-07-19T19:55:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reclaiming the Nation's Water Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to provide standards and procedures for the review of water reclamation and reuse projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400290"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="3639"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2006--Introduced.
Reclaiming the Nation's Water Act - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to remove requirements providing for appraisal investigations and feasibility studies. Establishes as purposes of the Act to: (1) assist in the development of permanent local and regional water reclamation and reuse projects in Arizona, California, Colorado, Hawaii, Idaho, Kansas, Montana, Nebraska, Nevada, New Mexico, North Dakota, Oklahoma, Oregon, South Dakota, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming (reclamation states); and (2) further improvements in water reclamation and reuse technologies through research and demonstration activities in those states. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to participate in opportunities for water reclamation and reuse, including water recycling and desalination activities, in reclamation states. Directs the Secretary to evaluate project proposals developed and submitted by nonfederal project sponsors. Requires the proposals to provide: (1) sufficient evidence to demonstrate that the project is technically viable and has a financially capable sponsor; and (2) information on each of specified factors (including water costs, quality and quantity, the cost-effectiveness of the project, and the extent to which the project would help serve an identified federal interest). Requires submission to Congress, within 180 days after the Secretary's determination that a proposal includes information sufficient to determine technical and financial viability, of a notice of findings that includes an explanation of viability and a concise recommendation on authorization for construction. Requires projects to be authorized for construction by Congress before funds may be expended by the Secretary for that purpose. Limits the federal share of costs of projects authorized after enactment of this Act to no more than 20%. Prohibits use of federal funds for operation and maintenance. Provides a procedure for deauthorization of projects that have not received federal funding. Authorizes the Secretary to cooperate with nonfederal project sponsors in the preparation of any plan for the development of reclaimed water for reuse applications or environmental benefits that are in the public interest. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
