<bill session="111" type="s" number="1064" updated="2013-07-20T00:33:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhanced Oversight of State and Local Economic Recovery Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Enhanced Oversight of State and Local Economic Recovery Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to provide for enhanced State and local oversight of activities conducted under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2009-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with amendments. With written report No. 111-56.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-07-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="121">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 121.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2182"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2182"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2009--Reported to Senate amended.
Enhanced Oversight of State and Local Economic Recovery Act - Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to require federal agencies receiving funds under such Act, subject to guidance from the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), to reasonably adjust applicable limits on administrative expenditures for federal awards to help award recipients defray costs of data collection, auditing, contract and grant planning and management, and investigations of waste, fraud, and abuse required under such Act. Authorizes state and local governments receiving funds to set aside up to .5% of such funds, in addition to any funds already allocated to administrative expenditures, to conduct planning and oversight to prevent and detect waste, fraud, and abuse. Authorizes the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) to provide for the use by state and local governments of GSA federal supply schedules for goods or services that are funded by such Act. Makes participation by a firm that sells to a state or local government through such schedule voluntary. Requires the Administrator, for authorized nonfederal users of federal supply schedules, to: (1) review the existing ordering guidance and, as necessary, prescribe additional guidance to ensure proper usage and to maximize task and delivery order competition; (2) make available the online electronic Request for Quote/Request for Proposal system; and (3) make available, free of charge, training related to proper schedule usage, including online training courses. Requires the OMB Director to issue guidance to ensure accurate and consistent reporting of "jobs created" and "jobs retained" as those terms are used in such Act. Amends the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 to require OMB to ensure that the federal awards website established under such Act: (1) clearly differentiates between projects funded under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (ARRA) and other federal awards; and (2) provides users with the ability to perform searches for information in the website relating only to amounts funded by ARRA. Requires the website Recovery.gov (established under ARRA) to prominently display a link to the federal awards website on its front page.</summary>
</bill>
