<bill session="110" type="h" number="6858" updated="2013-07-19T22:03:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Administrative Review Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to make amendments to certain provisions of title 5, United States Code, enacted by the Congressional Review Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2008-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-10">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/2008--Introduced.
Administrative Review Improvement Act of 2008 - Amends the Congressional Review Act to require that the chairman and ranking member of each relevant committee (currently, each standing committee) of the House of Representatives receive copies of reports required to be submitted before a federal agency rule can go into effect.Defines "relevant committee" to mean: (1) each committee with jurisdiction under House rules to report a bill to amend the legal provision under which the rule is issued; and (2) the House Judiciary Committee as the committee with jurisdiction to report a bill to amend federal administrative procedure provisions.Directs the Comptroller General's report on each major rule to be provided to each relevant committee (currently, the committees of jurisdiction) in the House.Requires joint resolutions introduced to disapprove a rule to be referred to the appropriate committees (currently, the committees with jurisdiction) in each House.</summary>
</bill>
