<bill session="109" type="h" number="4789" updated="2013-07-19T19:46:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-27T23:05:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-27T23:05:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Douglas County, Washington, PUD Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Douglas County, Washington, PUD Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain public land located wholly or partially within the boundaries of the Wells Hydroelectric Project of Public Utility District No. 1 of Douglas County, Washington, to the utility district.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-23">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06T20:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-634.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-06T20:22:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="374">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 374.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pearce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7653-7654" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4789.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2006-09-27T23:05:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7653" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27T23:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2006--Passed House amended.
Douglas County, Washington, PUD Conveyance Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, if the Public Utility District No. 1 of Douglas County, Washington (PUD), submits to the Secretary an offer to acquire certain public land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) for the appraised value, to convey to the PUD all interest of the United States in and to such public land. Instructs the Secretary complete an appraisal of the public land, which shall be conducted in accordance with specified standards. Requires the PUD to pay to the Secretary an amount equal to the appraised value of such land. Requires any costs related to the conveyance to be paid by the PUD. Provides for the deposit of the proceeds from the sale of the public land in the working capital fund of BLM. Withdraws the public land from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws, and all amendments thereto; (2) location, entry, and patenting under the mining laws, and all amendments thereto; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws, and all amendments thereto. Terminates this amendment two years after enactment of this Act or upon the completion of the conveyance, whichever is earlier.</summary>
</bill>
