<bill session="111" type="h" number="1623" updated="2013-07-19T23:26:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Megan's Law of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect children from sexual exploitation by mandating reporting requirements for convicted sex traffickers and other sex offenders against minors intending to engage in international travel, providing advance notice of intended travel by high risk sex offenders outside the United States to the government of the country of destination, preventing entry into the United States by any foreign sex offender against a minor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2009-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2009-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400096" joined="2009-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2009-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2009-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412301" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5138"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2009--Introduced.
International Megan's Law of 2009 - Requires registered sex offenders to notify appropriate jurisdictions of their intent to travel not later than 21 days before their departure or arrival in the United States. Imposes a fine and/or prison term of up to 10 years for failure to report such travel. Requires diplomatic or consular missions in each foreign country to establish and maintain a countrywide sex offender registry for sex offenders from the United States who temporarily or permanently reside in such country. Directs the Commissioner of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement to issue directives for the assessment of sex offenders whose travel is reported to determine whether such offenders are high risk sex offenders. Directs the President to establish the International Sex Offender Travel Center to monitor the travel of high risk sex offenders. Authorizes the Secretary of State to rescind the passports of individuals awaiting trial for a sex offense against a minor or a permanent resident who has been convicted of such an offense. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to make convicted sex offenders inadmissible to the United States. Amends the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 to include in the annual report of the Secretary of State on the status of severe forms of human trafficking efforts of foreign countries to identify and provide notice of international travel by sex offenders. Encourages the President to use authorities under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to assist foreign countries in identifying and providing notice of sex offenders traveling to the United States and other countries. Sets forth reporting requirements relating to the travel of international sex offenders and the implementation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
