<bill session="111" type="h" number="2747" updated="2013-07-19T23:36:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Technology Development and Outreach Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to improve outreach and support activities and to increase award recipients from rural areas with respect to the Small Business Innovation Research Program and the Small Business Technology Transfer Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412279"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Contracting and Technology .</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSM23" subcommittee="Contracting and Technology" name="House Small Business"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2009--Introduced.
Rural Technology Development and Outreach Act - Amends provisions of the Small Business Act relating to the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Program and the Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) Program to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to make grants to organizations to: (1) conduct outreach efforts to increase participation in such programs; and (2) provide application, entrepreneurial, and business skills support to prospective program participants. Requires organizations receiving such funds to direct activities toward small businesses: (1) located in areas that are underrepresented in SBIR and STTR programs; or (2) owned and controlled by women, service-disabled veterans, and minorities. Directs the Administrator to establish an advisory board to carry out authorized activities. Provides a two-year period for each grant award. Requires federal agencies, in making SBIR and STTR grant awards, to prioritize applications so as to increase the number of recipients from rural areas. Directs each federal agency conducting an SBIR program to: (1) receive consent to identify the small business applicant to appropriate local and state economic development organizations; and (2) encourage partnerships between SBIR awardees and prime contractors, venture capital investment companies, business incubators, and larger businesses for the purpose of facilitating the progress of SBIR awardees to the third phase of the program.</summary>
</bill>
