<bill session="113" type="h" number="575" updated="2013-11-02T06:23:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Second Amendment Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To express the sense of the Congress that the United States should not adopt any treaty that poses a threat to national sovereignty or abridges any rights guaranteed by the United States Constitution, such as the right to keep and bear arms, and to withhold funding from the United Nations unless the President certifies that the United Nations has not taken action to restrict, attempt to restrict, or otherwise adversely infringe upon the rights of individuals in the United States to keep and bear arms, or abridge any of the other constitutionally protected rights of citizens of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410396"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2013-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2013-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2013--Introduced.
Second Amendment Protection Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should not adopt any treaty that poses a threat to national sovereignty or abridges the rights guaranteed by the Constitution, such as the right to bear arms, and should cease the provision of financial support to any entity that does so. Prohibits the United States from providing any funding to the United Nations (U.N.) for a fiscal year unless the President certifies to Congress that the U.N. has not taken action to infringe on the rights of individuals in the United States to possess a firearm or ammunition, or abridge any of the other constitutionally protected rights of U.S. citizens.</summary>
</bill>
