<bill session="113" type="h" number="2104" updated="2013-11-02T06:36:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting the Privacy of Social Security Numbers Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, and the Social Security Act to limit the misuse of Social Security numbers, to establish criminal penalties for such misuse, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400142"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2013--Introduced.
Protecting the Privacy of Social Security Numbers Act of 2013 - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit the display, sale, or purchase of Social Security numbers without the affirmatively expressed consent of the individual, except in specified circumstances. Establishes a public records exception to the prohibition. Grants the Attorney General rulemaking authority to enforce this Act's prohibition and to implement and clarify the permitted uses occurring as a result of an interaction between businesses, governments, or business and government. Prohibits a commercial entity from requiring an individual to provide a Social Security number when purchasing a commercial good or service or denying an individual the good or service for refusing to provide that number, with exceptions. Establishes civil and criminal penalties. Extends civil monetary penalties for misuse of a Social Security number. Authorizes: (1) criminal penalties under SSA title II for the misuse of a Social Security number, (2) civil actions and civil penalties against persons who violate this Act, and (3) federal injunctive authority with respect to any violation by a public entity.</summary>
</bill>
