<bill session="113" type="hc" number="53" updated="2013-11-02T06:49:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Urging all parties to the conflict in Syria to work through the United Nations and with the international community to hold the Assad regime accountable and resolve the crisis in Syria through a negotiated political settlement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400237"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2013-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2013--Introduced.
Urges the United States to work with the United Nations (U.N.) and the international community to exhaust all diplomatic and non-military options to facilitate a negotiated settlement in Syria and hold the Assad regime and all responsible parties accountable for human rights violations, including the use of chemical weapons, through efforts such as: (1) requiring Syria to allow unfettered access to humanitarian organizations; (2) engaging in diplomacy to advance a negotiated settlement; (3) strengthening multilateral sanctions against the assets of President Bashar al-Assad and others who may be involved in crimes under international law; (4) investigating and prosecuting crimes against humanity and other crimes under international law, including referring the situation in Syria to the International Criminal Court; (5) working with member states of the Chemical Weapons Convention to prevent the deployment and use of weapons of mass destruction, including urging Syria to become a Convention signatory, and formulating a plan to place Syria's chemical weapons stockpile under international control; (6) working with the international community to establish a Syrian war crimes tribunal; and (7) enabling U.S. courts to investigate and prosecute crimes against humanity and other crimes under international law committed in Syria.</summary>
</bill>
