<bill session="113" type="h" number="3166" updated="2013-11-02T06:45:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To appropriate such funds as may be necessary to ensure certain important functions of the Government continue during a Governmentwide shutdown, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400234"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2013-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, Energy and Commerce, Agriculture, House Administration, Oversight and Government Reform, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, and Nutrition.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, and Nutrition" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="171"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2013--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, during a government-wide shutdown, to make available, out of any amounts in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such amounts as are necessary to provide: pay and allowances to members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard, including reserve components, who perform active service during the funding gap; pay and allowances, at the discretion of the Secretary of Defense, to civilian personnel and contractors of the Department of Defense (DOD) who are providing support to such members of the Armed Forces; amounts necessary to carry out the authority of the Department of the Treasury to pay with legal tender the principal and interest on debt held by the public; such amounts as the President certifies to Congress are necessary to carry out vital national security priorities, as well as government functions necessary for protecting public health and safety; and amounts necessary to make payments under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (SSA), as well as payments under the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly food stamps). Defines "government-wide shutdown" as any portion of a fiscal year during which none of the appropriation bills for the fiscal year have become law and an Act or joint resolution making continuing appropriations for the fiscal year is not in effect. Directs the Managing Trustee of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund (including the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund), during such a shutdown, to make available to the Commissioner of Social Security such amounts as the Commissioner determines to be necessary for the uninterrupted payment of monthly insurance benefits under SSA title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) and benefits under SSA title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI). Prohibits Members of Congress and the President from receiving basic pay during a government-wide shutdown and from receiving such forfeited pay retroactively.</summary>
</bill>
