<bill session="112" type="s" number="1154" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Honoring Promises to Service-Disabled Veterans Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require transparency for Executive departments in meeting the Government-wide goals for contracting with small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-10-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3552" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2011--Introduced.
Honoring Promises to Service-Disabled Veterans Act of 2011 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the head of each executive department to submit a quarterly report to the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) containing the percentage of the total value of all prime contracts awarded by the executive department during the preceding three-month period to small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, including, along with other specified percentages, for contracts awarded to certain contractors required to submit a subcontracting plan, the negotiated percentage goal for utilization of such subcontractors and the total value of subcontracts entered into by the contractor awarded to service-disabled veteran small business concerns. Requires the Administrator to: (1) annually rank the executive departments and contractors concerned based on specified contracting and subcontracting percentages; (2) publish and update at least quarterly, on a publicly accessible website, subject to exceptions for information detrimental to national security, such information reported by the executive departments and the Administrator's annual rankings; and (3) submit to Congress an annual report on the progress of each executive department toward meeting the government-wide goal for service-disabled veterans (a government-wide goal that at least 3% of the total value of all prime contracts and subcontracts be awarded to small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans each fiscal year) established in the Veterans Entrepreneurship and Small Business Development Act of 1999.</summary>
</bill>
