<bill session="109" type="h" number="5482" updated="2013-07-19T19:52:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Identity Theft Protection Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to provide individuals the ability to control access to their credit reports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2006-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2006-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2006-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2006-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2006-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2006-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2006-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E993"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5285"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3648"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2006--Introduced.
Identity Theft Protection Act of 2006 - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to permit a consumer to request a consumer reporting agency to place a security freeze upon his consumer report. Prohibits a consumer reporting agency, if a security freeze is in place, from releasing a consumer report to a third party without prior express authorization from the consumer. Prescribes procedures for removal and temporary suspension of a security freeze. Requires a consumer reporting agency to notify the consumer in writing before removing the security freeze. Identifies specified entities, including governmental agencies, to which these prohibitions and requirements do not apply. Permits a consumer reporting agency to charge a reasonable fee for placing or temporarily suspending a security freeze on a consumer report. Prohibits a consumer reporting agency from charging a fee for placing, removing, or temporarily suspending a security freeze if a consumer: (1) has either filed a police report, or made a complaint to a police department concerning identity theft; or (2) has received notice that a breach of data security has occurred with respect to information required by law to be maintained securely and in confidence. Exempts specified entities from this Act, including certain aggregators and other agencies acting only as resellers of credit information which do not maintain a permanent data base of consumer information from which new consumer reports are produced.</summary>
</bill>
