<bill session="111" type="s" number="1428" updated="2013-07-20T00:36:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mercury Pollution Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to phase out the use of mercury in the manufacture of chlorine and caustic soda, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2065"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2190"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2009--Introduced.
Mercury Pollution Reduction Act - Declares that is the policy of the United States that the United States should develop policies and programs that will reduce: (1) mercury use and emissions; (2) mercury releases from the reservoir of mercury currently in use or circulation; and (3) exposures to mercury, particularly of women of childbearing age and young children. Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to prohibit: (1) the manufacture of chlorine or caustic soda using a mercury cell; and (2) the export of any mercury, mercury cell, mercury compound, or mixture containing mercury by the owner or operator of a chlor-alkali facility. Requires the owner or operator of each chlor-alkali facility to report to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Administrator and the state in which the facility is located on mercury waste, emissions, and content in products. Requires the Administrator to: (1) conduct a comprehensive mercury inventory covering the life and closure of chlor-alkali facilities that cease operations on or after January 1, 2009; and (2) obtain mercury purchase records and such other information from each such facility as the Administrator determines to be necessary to determine the magnitude and nature of mercury releases from the facility into air and other environmental media.</summary>
</bill>
