<bill session="112" type="h" number="3293" updated="2013-07-20T01:38:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Defense (and the Secretary of Homeland Security in the case of the Coast Guard) to issue, at no cost to the United States, a military service identification card to persons who served in the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412447" joined="2011-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/2011--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD), and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) with respect to the Coast Guard, to design a military service identification card to identify and recognize the service of a member of the Armed Forces after the retirement or other separation of the member from the Armed Forces. Requires the card to include, at a minimum, the information contained on the Certificate of Release or Discharge from Active Duty. Directs the Secretary concerned to: (1) establish an application process for a person to request such a card, and (2) make the card available to retired and former members of the Armed Forces who retired or were separated before enactment of this Act. Conditions the issuance of the card upon the payment of an amount sufficient to cover the costs incurred by the United States to manufacture and issue it.</summary>
</bill>
