<bill session="113" type="h" number="633" updated="2013-11-02T06:24:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness for High-Skilled Immigrants Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to eliminate the per-country numerical limitation for employment-based immigrants, to increase the per-country numerical limitation for family-sponsored immigrants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412531" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412544" joined="2013-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412532" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412419" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2013-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412514" joined="2013-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration And Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="293"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="310"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2013--Introduced.
Fairness for High-Skilled Immigrants Act of 2013 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) eliminate the per country numerical limitation for employment-based immigrants, and (2) increase the per country numerical limitation for family based immigrants from 7% to 15% of the total number of family-sponsored visas. Amends the Chinese Student Protection Act of 1992 to eliminate the provision requiring the reduction of annual Chinese (PRC) immigrant visas to offset status adjustments under such Act. Sets forth the following transition period for employment-based second and third preference (EB-2 and EB-3) immigrant visas: (1) for FY2013, 15% of such visas allotted to natives of countries other than the two countries with the largest aggregate numbers of natives obtaining such visas in FY2011; (2) for FY2014, 10% of such visas allotted in each category to natives of countries other than the two with the largest aggregate numbers of natives obtaining such visas in FY2012; and (3) for FY2015, 10% of such visas allotted in each category to natives of countries other than the two with the largest aggregate numbers of natives obtaining such visas in FY2013. Sets forth the following per country distribution rules: (1) for transition period visas, not more than 25% of the total number of EB-2 and EB-3 visas for natives of a single country; and (2) for non-transition period visas, not more than 85% of EB-2 and EB-3 visas for natives of a single country. Provides that the amendments made by this Act will take place as if enacted on September 30, 2012, and shall apply beginning in FY2013.</summary>
</bill>
