<bill session="112" type="s" number="2274" updated="2013-07-20T02:36:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a nonprofit corporation to be known as the Foundation for Food and Agriculture Research.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2012-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3240"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/2012--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to establish the Foundation for Food and Agriculture Research to: (1) advance USDA's research mission by supporting agricultural research focused on addressing key problems of national and international significance; and (2) foster collaboration with agricultural researchers from the federal government, institutions of higher education, industry, and nonprofit organizations. Directs the Foundation to: (1) award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, scientists and entities to advance Foundation goals; (2) identify and coordinate existing and proposed federal research and development programs relating to Foundation purposes; (3) identify unmet and emerging agricultural research needs; (4) facilitate technology transfer and information release to the agricultural research community; and (5) promote the development of the next generation of agricultural research scientists.</summary>
</bill>
