<bill session="110" type="h" number="2643" updated="2013-07-19T21:26:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-27T18:12:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-06-27T18:12:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Department of the Interior, environment, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400109"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-11T20:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-187, by Mr. Dicks.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-06-11T20:14:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="111">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 111.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-06-22T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Appropriations, H. Rept. 110-187, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-25T17:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 514 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2643 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T11:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 514 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Dicks asked unanimous consent that, during consideration of H.R. 2643 pursuant to House Resolution 514, the Chair may reduce to two minutes the minimum time for eletronic voting under clause 6 of rule XVIII and clauses 8 and 9 or rule XX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 514.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7087-7197" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7094, H7096, H7098-7100, H7103, H7104-7105, H7105-7106, H7108-7109, H7110-7111, H7112-7113" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7125, H7126-7127, H7129, H7130-7132" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7132, H7135-7137, H7137-7139, H7139-7140" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7140-7142" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7142, CR 6/27/2007 H7259" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T11:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2643 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T11:06:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 514 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T11:06:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Stephanie Tubbs Jones to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T11:07:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2643.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T12:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Bishop of Utah amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T12:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Bishop of Utah amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T12:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hastings of Florida amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T12:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Weiner amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T12:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King of Iowa amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T13:03:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the King (IA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. King (IA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T13:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Shays amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T13:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Dicks amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T13:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Weiner amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T13:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee of the Whole rose informally to receive a message from the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T13:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Subsequently, the Committee resumed it's sitting.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T13:44:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Lamborn amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Lamborn amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T13:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Peterson(PA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T15:08:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Peterson(PA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Tiahrt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Peterson (PA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T15:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Conaway amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Conaway amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Conaway demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McHugh amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T15:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Price(GA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Gingrey En Bloc amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T16:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jindal amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T16:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Conaway amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T16:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Bishop(UT) amendment under the five-minute rule pending, reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Bishop (UT) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Dicks moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2643 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Dicks asked unanimous consent that during further consideration of H.R. 2643 in the Committee of the Whole pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 514, no further amendment to the bill will be in order except those provided on a list at the desk. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the LoBiondo amendment. pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sullivan amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T17:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Barton amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T17:53:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Barton (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Barton (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bishop(UT) amendment, pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the E.B. Johnson amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:10:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Eddie Bernice Johnson (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Tiahrt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bishop(UT) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Dent amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Dent amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Dent demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kingston amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2643 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:41:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pearce amendment, pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pearce amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Pearce demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee of Texas amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T18:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment, pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hensarling demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment, pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T19:25:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hensarling demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T19:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T19:38:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hensarling demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T19:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hensarling demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee of the Whole rose informally to receive a message from the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T19:52:00-04:00">
      <text>RESUMED - The Committee of the Whole resumed it's sitting.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T19:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Andrews amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T20:17:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Andrews amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Andrews demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T20:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gary Miller of California amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T20:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ginny Brown-Waite(FL) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T20:44:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ginny Brown-Waite(FL) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Ginny Brown-Waite(FL) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T20:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Campbell amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T20:53:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Campbell amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Campbell demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T20:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Harman amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T20:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Campbell amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T21:12:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Campbell amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Campbell demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T21:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conaway amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T21:19:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of certain amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-26T22:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2643 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T10:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7213-7270" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T10:44:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T10:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T10:57:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Flake demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T10:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T11:10:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Flake demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T11:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T11:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T11:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T11:52:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Flake demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T11:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stupak amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T11:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Jordan amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jordan amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Jordan demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T12:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Price (GA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T13:24:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Price (GA) amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Price (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the Musgrave amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T14:07:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Musgrave amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Musgrave demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T14:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Peterson (PA) amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T14:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T14:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Inslee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T15:03:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Inslee amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Inslee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T15:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Udall (CO) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Udall (CO) amendment Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Udall (CO) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Udall (CO) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T15:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeFazio amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T15:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lamborn amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T15:48:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lamborn amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Lamborn demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T15:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous special order, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cannon amendment, pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation of a point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T15:56:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cannon amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cannon demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T17:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Dicks moved for the Committee of the Whole to rise and report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T17:22:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to rise and report Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T17:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2643.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7259" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the remaining amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T17:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lewis (CA) moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7269" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T17:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lewis (CA) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to add a new title to the bill which spells out requirements for an effective date based upon certification related to domestic energy policy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7269" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7269" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T18:05:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 186 - 233 (Roll no. 578).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-06-27T18:12:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="579" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 272 - 155 (Roll no. 579).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-06-27T18:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-06-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="240">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 240.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="514"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2764"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="1696"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1696"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Cattle"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commission of Fine Arts"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Elephants"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Everglades"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-territorial relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Forestry"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Insect control"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Lighting"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="National Capital Planning Commission"/>
    <term name="National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Old growth forests"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Palau Islands"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Poisons"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Primates"/>
    <term name="Private forests"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Railroad land grants"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Reforestation"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Rhinoceroses"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tigers"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Turtles"/>
    <term name="Underground storage"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban forestry"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h395"/>
    <amendment number="h396"/>
    <amendment number="h397"/>
    <amendment number="h398"/>
    <amendment number="h399"/>
    <amendment number="h400"/>
    <amendment number="h401"/>
    <amendment number="h402"/>
    <amendment number="h403"/>
    <amendment number="h404"/>
    <amendment number="h405"/>
    <amendment number="h406"/>
    <amendment number="h407"/>
    <amendment number="h408"/>
    <amendment number="h409"/>
    <amendment number="h410"/>
    <amendment number="h411"/>
    <amendment number="h412"/>
    <amendment number="h413"/>
    <amendment number="h414"/>
    <amendment number="h415"/>
    <amendment number="h416"/>
    <amendment number="h417"/>
    <amendment number="h418"/>
    <amendment number="h419"/>
    <amendment number="h420"/>
    <amendment number="h421"/>
    <amendment number="h422"/>
    <amendment number="h423"/>
    <amendment number="h424"/>
    <amendment number="h425"/>
    <amendment number="h426"/>
    <amendment number="h427"/>
    <amendment number="h428"/>
    <amendment number="h429"/>
    <amendment number="h430"/>
    <amendment number="h431"/>
    <amendment number="h432"/>
    <amendment number="h433"/>
    <amendment number="h434"/>
    <amendment number="h435"/>
    <amendment number="h436"/>
    <amendment number="h437"/>
    <amendment number="h438"/>
    <amendment number="h439"/>
    <amendment number="h440"/>
    <amendment number="h441"/>
    <amendment number="h442"/>
    <amendment number="h443"/>
    <amendment number="h444"/>
    <amendment number="h445"/>
    <amendment number="h446"/>
    <amendment number="h447"/>
    <amendment number="h448"/>
    <amendment number="h449"/>
    <amendment number="h450"/>
    <amendment number="h451"/>
    <amendment number="h452"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/27/2007--Passed House amended.
Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008 - Makes appropriations for the Department of the Interior, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and related agencies for FY2008. Title I: Department of the Interior - Makes appropriations for FY2008 to the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) for: (1) land and resource management; (2) construction; (3) land acquisition; (3) Oregon and California grant lands; (4) range improvements; (5) service charges, deposits, and forfeitures with respect to public lands; (6) miscellaneous trust funds; and (7) wildland fire management (including transfer of funds). Appropriates funds for FY2008 to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (FWS) for: (1) resource management; (2) construction; (3) land acquisition; (4) expenses related to carrying out the Endangered Species Act of 1973; (5) the National Wildlife Refuge Fund; (6) expenses related to carrying out the North American Wetlands Conservation Act; (7) financial assistance for projects to promote the conservation of neotropical migratory birds; (8) expenses related to carrying out, through the Multinational Species Conservation Fund, the African Elephant Conservation Act, the Asian Elephant Conservation Act of 1997, the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act of 1994, the Great Ape Conservation Act of 2000, and the Marine Turtle Conservation Act of 2004; and (9) wildlife conservation grants to states, the District of Columbia, U.S. territories, and Indian tribes. Makes appropriations for FY2008 to the National Park Service (NPS) for: (1) the National Park System (including expenses for carrying out programs of the U.S. Park Police); (2) expenses related to cost share agreements for Centennial Challenge signature projects and programs; (3) expenses for national recreation and preservation programs; (4) expenses related to carrying out the Historic Preservation Act of 1966 and the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 (including transfers of funds); (5) construction; (6) land acquisition and state assistance from the Land and Water Conservation Fund. Rescinds specified contract authority to obligate funds from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for FY2008. Makes appropriations for FY2008 to: (1) the U.S. Geological Survey for surveys, investigations, and research; (2) the Minerals Management Service for royalty and offshore minerals management and oil spill research; (3) the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement for regulation and technology and the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund; (4) the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) for operation of Indian programs, (including transfer of funds), construction (including transfer of funds), Indian land and water claim settlements and miscellaneous payments to Indians, and Indian guaranteed loans; (5) the Office of the Secretary for departmental offices; (6) provide assistance to U.S. territories and to carry out the Compacts of Free Association with respect to the Marshall Islands, Palau, and Micronesia; (7) the Office of the Solicitor; (8) the Office of Inspector General; (9) provide for the operation of trust programs for Indians; (10) provide for a program for consolidation of fractional interests in Indian lands by direct expenditure or cooperative agreement; (11) make payments in lieu of taxes to units of local government containing certain federally owned lands; (12) the Central Hazardous Materials Fund for expenses of the Department of the Interior and its component offices and bureaus for the remedial action of hazardous waste substances, pollutants, or contaminants pursuant to the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act; and (13) the Department of the Interior natural resource damage assessment and restoration. Sets forth authorized and prohibited uses of specified funds. (Sec. 113) Makes funds appropriated for FY2008 under this Act available to the tribes within the California Tribal Trust Reform Consortium, the Salt River Pima-Maricopa Indian Community, the Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes of the Flathead Reservation, and the Chippewa Cree Tribe of the Rocky Boys Reservation through the same methodology as funds were distributed in FY2003. Prohibits the Department from imposing its trust management infrastructure upon or altering existing trust resource management systems of such tribes which have a self-governance compact and operate in accordance with the Tribal Self-Governance Program. (Sec. 114) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire lands, waters, or interests therein for the purpose of operating and maintaining facilities in the support of transportation and accommodation of visitors to Ellis, Governors, and Liberty Islands. (Sec. 115) Prohibits the use of any funds in this Act to issue any new lease that authorizes production of oil or natural gas under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to any lessee under an existing lease issued by the Department of the Interior pursuant to the Outer Continental Shelf Deep Water Royalty Relief Act where such existing lease is not subject to limitations on royalty relief based on market price.Title II: Environmental Protection Agency - Makes appropriations for FY2008 to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) for: (1) science and technology; (2) expenses for supporting activities of the Commission on Climate Change Adaptation and Mitigation established by this Act (including transfers of funds); (3) environmental programs and management; (4) the Office of Inspector General; (5) buildings and facilities; (6) the Hazardous Substance Superfund (including transfers of funds); (7) the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund Program; (8) expenses to carry out EPA 's responsibilities under the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 concerning oil spill response; and (9) state and tribal assistance grants for environmental programs and infrastructure assistance. Rescinds a specified amount from unobligated balances for carrying out projects and activities authorized under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act with regard to the reimbursement of certain publicly owned treatment works on which construction was initiated after June 30, 1966, but before July 1, 1973.Title III: Related Agencies - Makes appropriations for FY2008 to the Department of Agriculture for the Forest Service for: (1) forest and rangeland research; (2) state and private forestry; (3) the National Forest System; (4) capital improvement and maintenance (including transfers of funds); (5) land acquisitions, including specified National Forest areas in Utah, Nevada, and California; (6) range rehabilitation, protection, and improvement; (7) gifts, donations, and bequests for forest and rangeland research; (8) federal land management in Alaska; and (9) wildland fire management (including transfers of funds). Makes appropriations for FY2008 to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) for: (1) the Indian Health Service (IHS) and Indian health facilities; and (2) the National Institutes of Health (NIH) for the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences and the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry. Makes appropriations for FY2008 in specified amounts for various purposes to the: (1) Executive Office of the President; (2) Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board; (3) Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation; (4) Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development; (5) Smithsonian Institution; (6) National Gallery of Art; (7) John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts; (8) Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars; (9) National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities, including the National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) and the National Endowment for the Humanities; (10) Commission of Fine Arts, including expenses for National Capital Arts and Cultural Affairs; (11) Advisory Council on Historic Preservation; (12) National Capital Planning Commission; (13) U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum; (14) Presidio Trust Fund; and (15) White House Commission on the National Moment of Remembrance (including transfer of funds). Title IV: General Provisions - Sets forth limitation on the use of funds under this Act. (Sec. 405) Requires: (1) estimated overhead charges, deductions, reserves or holdbacks from programs, projects, activities and subactivities to support governmentwide, departmental, agency or bureau administrative functions or headquarters, regional or central operations to be presented in annual budget justifications and subject to approval by the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations; and (2) changes to such estimates to be presented to such Committees for approval. (Sec. 412) Permits the Secretaries of Agriculture and of the Interior to make reciprocal agreements in which the individuals furnished by an agreement to provide fire management services are considered, for tort liability, employees of the foreign country receiving the services when the individuals are fighting fires. Prohibits the Secretaries from making any agreement in which a foreign country does not assume any and all responsibility for acts or omissions of American firefighters who are firefighting in such foreign country. (Sec. 413) Allows the Secretaries, in awarding a federal contract for any of specified purposes with funds made available by this Act, notwithstanding federal government procurement and contracting laws, to give consideration to local contractors who are from economically disadvantaged rural communities and who provide employment and training for dislocated and displaced workers. Allows the Secretaries, notwithstanding such laws, to award contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements in certain areas to various entities, including local non-profits and the Youth Conservation Corps. Includes in such areas habitat restoration or management and forest hazardous fuels reduction. (Sec. 414) Limits the amounts of funds made available by this Act or any other Act to the Department of the Interior to initiate or continue competitive sourcing studies in FY2008 for programs, projects, and activities for which funds are appropriated by this Act. Prohibits any of the funds available to the Forest Service from being used in FY2008 for competitive sourcing studies and related activities. Directs agencies funded in this Act, in preparing any reports to the Committees on Appropriations on competitive sourcing activities, to include the incremental cost directly attributable to conducting the competitive sourcing competitions, including costs attributable to paying outside consultants and contractors and, in accordance with full cost accounting principles, all costs attributable to developing, implementing, supporting, managing, monitoring, and reporting on competitive sourcing, including personnel, consultant, travel, and training costs associated with program management. Instructs the Secretary of of the Interior, in carrying out any competitive sourcing study involving Department of the Interior employees, to: (1) determine whether any of the employees concerned are also qualified to participate in wildland fire management activities; and (2) take into consideration the effect that contracting with a private sector source would have on the ability of the Department of the Interior to effectively and efficiently fight and manage wildfires. (Sec. 415) Extends the authority for: (1) the pilot program for enhancing Forest Service administration of rights-of-way and other land uses; and (2) the deposit of all fees collected to recover the costs of processing applications for, and monitoring compliance with, authorizations to use and occupy National Forest System lands pursuant to certain Acts. (Sec. 416) Amends the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2003 to extend the authority for cooperative agreements between the Secretary of Agriculture and public or private agencies, organizations, institutions, and persons covering Forest Service programs to facilitate the administration of Forest Service programs and activities when the principal purpose of the resulting relationship is to the mutually significant benefit of the Forest Service and the other party or parties to the agreement, including nonprofit entities. Title V: Global Climate Change - (Sec. 501) Expresses the sense of Congress that there should be enacted a comprehensive and effective national program of mandatory, market-based limits and incentives on emissions of greenhouse gases that slow, stop, and reverse the growth of such emissions at a rate and in a manner that: (1) will not significantly harm the U.S. economy; and (2) will encourage comparable action by other nations that are major trading partners and key contributors to global emissions. (Sec. 502) Prohibits the use of any funds made available by this Act to condemn land. (Sec. 503) Prohibits the use of any funds in this Act to plan, design, study, or construct, for the purpose of harvesting timber by private entities or individuals, a forest development road in Tongass National Forest.(Sec. 504) Provides for the amount otherwise provided in this Act for the "Historic Preservation Fund" to be reduced by $1 million and increased by $1 million.Title VI: Additional General Provisions - (Sec. 601) Prohibits the use of funds to eliminate or restrict programs that are for the reforestation of urban areas. (Sec. 602) Prohibits the use of funds to limit outreach programs administered by the Smithsonian Institution.(Sec. 603) Prohibits the use of funds to purchase light bulbs unless they have the "ENERGY STAR" or "Federal Energy Management Program" designation. (Sec. 604) Prohibits the use of funds to promulgate or implement the EPA proposed regulations concerning National Emission Standards for Hazardous Air Pollutants: General Provisions published in the Federal Register on January 3, 2007. (Sec. 605) Prohibits the use of funds for the Division of Criminal Investigation of the EPA in contravention of the criminal investigator requirements of the Pollution Prosecution Act of 1990. (Sec. 606) Prohibits the use of funds: (1) to prepare or publish final regulations regarding a commercial leasing program for oil shale (and tar sands) resources on public lands pursuant to requirements of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 with regard to a programmatic environmental impact statement for such program; or (2) to conduct an oil shale lease sale pursuant to such Act.</summary>
</bill>
