<bill session="110" type="s" number="3533" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Daniel Webster Congressional Clerkship Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Daniel Webster Congressional Clerkship Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="6475"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2008--Introduced.
Daniel Webster Congressional Clerkship Act of 2008 - Establishes the Daniel Webster Congressional Clerkship Program for the appointment of individuals who are graduates of accredited law schools to serve as Congressional Clerks in the Senate or House of Representatives.Requires the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration and the House Committee on House Administration to each select at least six individuals for a one-year term to serve as employees in their respective chambers.Specifies eligibility criteria for a Congressional Clerk, including that the selected candidate be a graduate of such a law school as of the starting date of his or her clerkship.Requires the committees to ensure that Congressional Clerks selected under this Act are apportioned equally between majority and minority party offices.Entitles each clerk selected to the same compensation as, and comparable benefits to, an individual who holds the position of a judicial clerkship for the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia within three months of graduating from law school.</summary>
</bill>
