<bill session="112" type="h" number="2782" updated="2013-07-20T01:34:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Wind Energy Research and Development Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a program of wind energy research, development, and demonstration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412319"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2011--Introduced.
Wind Energy Research and Development Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to carry out a research and development program to: (1) improve the energy efficiency, reliability, and capacity of wind turbines; (2) optimize the design and adaptability of wind energy systems to the broadest practical range of atmospheric conditions; and (3) reduce the cost of construction, generation, and maintenance of such systems.Directs the Secretary to conduct a wind energy demonstration program to measure wind energy system performance under the full productive range of wind conditions in the United States. Requires awards under such programs to be made on a competitive basis with an emphasis on technical merit. Requires the Secretary, in carrying out this Act, to: (1) coordinate with the Office of Minority Economic Impact and with the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization; and (2) provide special consideration to applications submitted by institutions, businesses, or entities containing majority representation of women, minorities, or persons with disabilities in science and engineering.</summary>
</bill>
