<bill session="111" type="s" number="4006" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ACCESS ADAP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Addressing Cost Containment Measures To Ensure the Sustainability and Success of ADAP</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the use of unobligated discretionary stimulus dollars to address AIDS Drug Assistance Program waiting lists and other cost containment measures impacting State ADAP programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2010-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-12-03">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-12-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="672">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 672.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3401"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Drug and radiation therapy"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2010--Introduced.
Addressing Cost Containment Measures To Ensure the Sustainability and Success of ADAP Act or the ACCESS ADAP Act - Requires specified funds to be transferred to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) from discretionary amounts appropriated under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act that remain unobligated, to be obligated during the FY2010 grant period under the AIDS Drug Assistance Program to provide assistance in reducing waiting lists and to address other cost containment measures that state AIDS Drug Assistance Programs implement after January 1, 2009. Requires amounts transferred under this Act to be used by states in a manner consistent with their state programs. Requires the Secretary, in allocating such funds, to: (1) give special consideration to the total scope and the basis of a state's needs, including the total number of patients on a waiting list, eligibility requirements, and other cost containment measures; and (2) ensure that funds be used only to provide treatments to individuals who were eligible to participate in the state program on the date of enactment of this Act or who would have been eligible to participate in the state program&#160; but were not so eligible because of the implementation of cost-containment measures after January 1, 2009.</summary>
</bill>
