<bill session="111" type="h" number="947" updated="2013-07-19T23:20:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ON TIME Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Our Nation's Trade, Infrastructure, Mobility, and Efficiency Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish and collect a fee based on the fair market value of articles imported into the United States and articles exported from the United States in commerce and to use amounts collected from the fee to make grants to carry out certain transportation projects in the transportation trade corridors for which the fee is collected, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400057"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2009-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-10">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-10">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-10">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2009--Introduced.
Our Nation's Trade, Infrastructure, Mobility, and Efficiency Act of 2009 or the ON TIME Act of 2009 - Declares that it is the purpose of this Act to: (1) address major transportation investment needs in national trade gateway corridors; (2) reduce freight congestion along current and future trade corridors along surface transportation routes that are or will be congested as a result of current or future growth in international trade; and (3) develop corridors that will increase freight transportation system reliability. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to assess and collect a national trade gateway corridor fee on each article imported into, and exported from, the United States. Requires collected fees to be deposited in the National Trade Gateway Corridor Fund for projects in the transportation trade corridors for the Customs port of unloading of imported, or loading of exported, articles. Sets forth requirements with respect to: (1) the allocation of Fund amounts in the form of grants to state departments of transportation to carry out eligible projects in the corridors for the Customs ports of entry; and (2) project selection and eligibility. Requires the Secretary to establish a transportation trade corridor for each Customs port of entry where fees are collected.</summary>
</bill>
