<bill session="113" type="h" number="3285" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make technical corrections to the Pay Our Military Act to include midshipmen at the United States Merchant Marine Academy, who are appointed as midshipmen in the Navy Reserve.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412451"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2013-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2013-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2013-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2013-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2013-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2013-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2013-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2013-10-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3210"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1568"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Pay Our Military Act (P.L. 113-39) to specify that FY2014 continuing appropriations provided for pay and allowances to members of the Armed Forces, including reserve components, is to include cadets in the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy appointed as midshipmen in Navy Reserve (including the Merchant Marine Reserve, Navy Reserve) who perform active service for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for FY2014 are not in effect. Makes continuing appropriations for pay and allowances to civilian personnel of the Department of Transportation (DOT) whom the Secretary of Transportation determines are providing support to such members of the Armed Forces, including reserve components, performing active service during such period (under such Act only civilian personnel and contractors of the Department of Defense [DOD], and the Department of Homeland Security [DHS] in the case of the Coast Guard, whom the Secretary concerned determines are providing such support). Provides for pay and allowances to DOD, DHS, and DOT civilian personnel providing support to those in training for such service.</summary>
</bill>
