<bill session="109" type="h" number="3900" updated="2013-07-19T19:38:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Justice for Peace Officers Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to increase the penalty on persons who are convicted of killing peace officers and who flee the country, and to express the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State should renegotiate the extradition treaty with Mexico.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2005-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2006-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2005-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2005--Introduced.
Justice for Peace Officers Act - Amends the federal criminal code to prescribe penalties to be imposed on anyone who: (1) murders a federal, state, or local peace officer engaged in, or on account of the performance of, official duties and moves or travels in foreign commerce with intent to avoid prosecution or confinement after conviction of that crime; or (2) is an accessory after the fact to such a crime. Authorizes the prosecution of such violations only after formal approval in writing, upon consultation with the appropriate state or local prosecutor, by the Attorney General, Deputy Attorney General, Associate Attorney General, or Assistant Attorney General. Directs the Secretary of State to notify the Mexican government of the desire of the United States to enter into formal discussions regarding the Extradition Treaty between the United States of America and the United Mexican States, signed in Mexico City on May 4, 1978, and available actions that the Mexican government may take to persuade the Mexican Supreme Court to reconsider its October 2001 ruling, so that the possibility of a sentence of life imprisonment will not have an effect on the timely extradition of a criminal suspect from Mexico to the United States.</summary>
</bill>
