<bill session="109" type="s" number="976" updated="2013-07-19T20:21:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-29">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill striking the Specific Privatization Criteria in ORBIT for Intelsat Separated Entities (New Skies) and Inmarsat and Other Technical Corrections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300015"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2005-04-29" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 4/28/2005 S4607" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 4/28/2005 S4607" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-05-02T14:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication satellites"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2005--Passed Senate without amendment.
Amends title VI (Open-market Reorganization for the Betterment of International Telecommunications Act or ORBIT Act) of the Communications Satellite Act of 1962 by striking: (1) all specific criteria for Intelsat (a global satellite provider of voice, data, and Internet services) separated entities privatization (New Skies, formed through Intelsat) provisions; and (2) the reaffiliation prohibition and the interlocking directorates or employees privatization criteria provisions for Inmarsat (a global mobile satellite communications provider), while maintaining GMDSS (Global Maritime Distress and Safety System) provisions. Directs the Federal Communications Commission to review competitive market conditions of domestic and international satellite communications services and include in an annual report an analysis of those conditions.</summary>
</bill>
