<bill session="109" type="s" number="1334" updated="2013-07-19T20:25:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Professional Sports Integrity and Accountability Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for integrity and accountability in professional sports.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300014"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2005-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2005-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/1/2005 S7906-7907" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7905-7906, S7907"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-525.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="1960"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and athletes"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Steroids"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2005--Introduced.
Professional Sports Integrity and Accountability Act - Prohibits a professional sports league from any involvement in a professional sports event without adopting and enforcing a testing policy for performance-enhancing drugs. Requires each such league to adopt policies and procedures that: (1) proscribe the use of prohibited substances and methods; (2) provide for random testing of each professional athlete at least three times a year; and (3) proscribe any person associated with the league from complicity in a violation by an athlete. Prohibits all substances and methods prohibited by the United States Anti-Doping Agency Protocol for Olympic Movement Testing and any other appropriate substance or method as determined by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). Includes as a violations of the testing policy: (1) the presence of a prohibited substance or its metabolites or markers; (2) refusing to submit to a test; (3) administering or attempting to administer a prohibited substance or method to any athlete; and (4) assisting, encouraging, aiding, abetting, covering up, or any other type of complicity involving a violation by a professional athlete. Allows a league to provide an individual athlete with an exemption for a particular prohibited substance or method for a documented medical condition. Sets the penalties for the first violation at a minimum of two years suspension, permanent suspension for any subsequent violation, and public disclosure of the name of the violator and substance involved. Allows the FTC to seek civil penalties for violations of this Act. Expresses the sense of Congress that the individual records of athletes achieved while using performance-enhancing drugs should be invalidated.</summary>
</bill>
