<bill session="112" type="h" number="4219" updated="2013-07-20T01:46:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Consumer Protection Home Inspection Counseling Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 1451 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to establish programs to provide counseling to homebuyers regarding voluntary home inspections and to train counselors to provide such counseling, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/2012--Introduced.
Consumer Protection Home Inspection Counseling Act of 2012 - Amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to publish a Mortgagee Letter informing mortgagees of their obligation to provide prospective homebuyers with specified HUD public outreach publications concerning the importance of obtaining independent home inspections. Requires persons providing housing counseling for HUD-approved counseling agencies to: (1) be trained through a certain voluntary home inspection training module, and (2) distribute and explain certain counseling aids. Requires any homeownership counseling program under HUD auspices or administration to be provided only by organizations or counselors HUD-certified as competent to provide voluntary home inspection counseling. Authorizes HUD to withhold, withdraw, or suspend housing counseling certifications for any non-compliant housing counselor or counseling entity. Requires HUD to establish a comprehensive program to train HUD staff, contractors, individuals, and entities that provide housing counseling under specified HUD-funded programs also to provide counseling to consumers on voluntary home inspection. Requires such training program to include development of a training module to: (1) train counselors as well as counseling aids for use by housing counselors and suitable for distribution to consumers; and (2) be comprehensible to untrained consumers with or without ongoing assistance from housing counselors. Requires HUD, at the Secretary's discretion, to develop a new independent protocol, or amend existing protocols, to certify that such housing counselors have successfully completed training using the voluntary home inspection training module and counseling aids established under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
