<bill session="113" type="h" number="817" updated="2013-11-02T06:25:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Justice Global Advisory Committee Authorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To further the mission of the Global Justice Information Sharing Initiative Advisory Committee by continuing its development of policy recommendations and technical solutions on information sharing and interoperability, and enhancing its pursuit of benefits and cost savings for local, State, tribal, and Federal justice agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2013-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2013--Introduced.
Department of Justice Global Advisory Committee Authorization Act of 2013 - Authorizes the Attorney General to provide technical and financial assistance and support to the Global Justice Information Sharing Initiative Advisory Committee. Requires the Committee to: (1) gather views from federal, state, local, and tribal agencies that work to support public safety and justice; (2) recommend to the Attorney General measures to improve the administration of justice and protect the public by promoting practices and technologies for database interoperability and the secure sharing of justice and public safety information between local, state, and tribal governments and the federal government; and (3) report annually on issues considered and recommendations made. Expresses the sense of Congress that state, local, and tribal governments and other relevant entities should use the recommendations developed by the Committee to evaluate, improve, and develop effective strategies and technologies to improve public safety and information sharing. Directs the Attorney General to require any applicant for a funding solicitation from the Department of Justice (DOJ) for the implementation of an information sharing solution to include within the application: (1) how the solution would comply with Committee standards, or (2) the reason for any non-compliance with such standards. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) review the state of information sharing between state, local, and tribal corrections and law enforcement agencies and the federal government; and (2) identify barriers and best practices and assess ways for information sharing to improve the awareness and safety of law enforcement and corrections officials.</summary>
</bill>
