<bill session="111" type="s" number="1035" updated="2013-07-20T00:32:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Drinking Water Adaptation, Technology, Education, and Research (WATER) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance the ability of drinking water utilities in the United States to develop and implement climate change adaptation programs and policies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5442-5443" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="3727"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2009--Introduced.
Drinking Water Adaptation, Technology, Education, and Research (WATER) Act - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish and provide funding for a program of directed and applied research, to be conducted through a nonprofit water research foundation and sponsored by drinking water utilities, to assist the utilities in adapting to the effects of climate change. Requires research areas to include: (1) water quality impacts and solutions; (2) impacts on groundwater supplies from carbon sequestration; (3) water quantity impacts and solutions; (4) infrastructure impacts and solutions for water treatment and wastewater treatment facilities and underground pipelines; (5) desalination, water reuse, and alternative supply technologies; (6) energy efficiency and greenhouse gas minimization; (7) regional and hydrological basin cooperative water management solutions; (8) utility management, decision support systems, and water management models; (9) greenhouse gas emissions reduction and improvement of energy demand management; (10) water conservation and demand management; and (11) communications, education, and public acceptance.</summary>
</bill>
