<bill session="111" type="sc" number="19" updated="2013-07-20T00:22:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress that the Shi'ite Personal Status Law in Afghanistan violates the fundamental human rights of women and should be repealed.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4699" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-05-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="61">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 61.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5883-5884" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5883" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>The committee substitute agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2009-05-21" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5883-5884" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-05-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hc" number="108"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1224"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Passed Senate amended.
Urges the government of Afghanistan to revise the Shi'ite Personal Status Law, including its provisions on marital rape and women's freedom of movement, to ensure its consistency with internationally recognized rights of women, including those contained in treaties to which Afghanistan is a party. Supports President Karzai's decision to analyze the draft law and strongly urges him not to publish it until it has been revised to be consistent with internationally recognized rights of women. Encourages the Secretary of State, the Special Representative to Afghanistan and Pakistan, the Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women's Issues, and the U.S. Ambassador to Afghanistan to consider the status of women's rights and security in Afghanistan. Encourages the government of Afghanistan to solicit information and advice from the Ministry of Justice, the Ministry of Women's Affairs, the Afghanistan Independent Human Rights Commission, and women-led nongovernmental organizations to ensure that legislation and policies uphold the equal rights of women.</summary>
</bill>
