<bill session="109" type="s" number="1128" updated="2013-07-19T20:23:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pharmaceutical Advertising and Prudent Purchasing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide for increased rebates under the medicaid program for prescription drugs that are directly advertised to consumers, to require other Federal programs purchasing or reimbursing for such drugs to establish payment and reimbursement mechanisms that reduce the costs of those drugs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2005-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6056-6057"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug advertising"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2005--Introduced.
Pharmaceutical Advertising and Prudent Purchasing Act - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to provide for increased rebates under the Medicaid program for prescription drugs directly advertised to consumers. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to develop and implement procedures under which any master agreement, pricing agreement, or contract for the procurement or purchase of a covered drug or a covered outpatient drug by a federal agency or reimbursement program shall provide that the agency or program shall pay a negotiated reduced price for such drug unless the manufacturer has certified to the head of the agency or program that the drug was not directly advertised to consumers during the 12-month period preceding the date of such procurement or purchase. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on strategies to reduce the cost of prescription drugs covered under the Medicare and other federal programs directly advertised to consumers.</summary>
</bill>
