<bill session="110" type="s" number="3146" updated="2013-07-19T22:49:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Needed Offshore Under Gas Hikes Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the exploration of oil and natural gas in coastal areas to reduce the dependence of the United States on foreign energy sources, and to reduce gasoline and natural gas prices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2008--Introduced.
Energy Needed Offshore Under Gas Hikes Act - Allows the governor of a state, during any period in which the price of regular gasoline is equal to or greater than $5, with the concurrence of the state legislature, to petition the Secretary of the Interior to make a new producing area of the state eligible for: (1) oil leasing, gas leasing, or both, as determined by the state in accordance with the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act and the Mineral Leasing Act; or (2) natural gas leasing only. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to deposit 45% of all rentals, royalties, bonus bids, and other sums due and payable to the United States from leases for new producing areas (qualified revenues) in the outer Continental Shelf into the general fund of the Treasury. Requires 55% of qualified revenues to be deposited into a special account in the Treasury, from which the Secretary shall disburse: (1) 37.5% to eligible producing states for new producing areas; (2) 12.5% to provide assistance to states in accordance with the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965; and (3) 5% to states for historic offshore production distribution.</summary>
</bill>
