<bill session="109" type="hr" number="469" updated="2013-07-19T18:58:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-29T11:45:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-29T11:45:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 68) making continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 2006, and for other purposes; for consideration of motions to suspend the rules; and addressing a motion to proceed under section 2908 of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400328"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T19:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 109-239, by Mr. Putnam.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28T19:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to section 2, it shall be in order at any time on the legislative day of Thursday, October 6, 2005, for the Speaker to entertain motions to suspend the rules. The Speaker or his designee shall consult with the Minority Leader or her designee on the designation of any matter for consideration pursuant to this resolution. Pursuant to section 3, a motion to proceed to section 2908 of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 shall be in order only if offered by the Majority Leader or his designee</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-09-28T19:01:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="97">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 97.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29T11:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8525-8528" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29T11:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 469.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29T11:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8528" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2005-09-29T11:45:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8525-8526" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29T11:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="109" type="hj" number="68"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2005--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for: (1) consideration of H.J. Res. 68 (FY2006 continuing appropriations); (2) consideration of motions to suspend the rules on October 6, 2005; and (3) addressing a motion to proceed pursuant to section 2908 of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 if offered by the Majority Leader.</summary>
</bill>
