<bill session="112" type="h" number="3399" updated="2013-07-20T01:39:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare and Medicaid FAST Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare and Medicaid Fighting Fraud and Abuse to Save Taxpayers' Dollars Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to curb waste, fraud, and abuse in the Medicare and Medicaid programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412202"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412502" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2012-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2012-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400065" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412407" joined="2011-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400442" joined="2011-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2012-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2011-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412422" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412466" joined="2012-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412393" joined="2012-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2012-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412225" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2012-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-10">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-10">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1251"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/2011--Introduced.
Medicare and Medicaid Fighting Fraud and Abuse to Save Taxpayers' Dollars Act or Medicare and Medicaid FAST Act - Amends part D (Prescription Drug Benefits) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to prohibit sponsors of prescription drug plans (PDPs) from paying claims for prescription drugs that do not include the valid National Provider Identifier for the drug's prescriber. Directs the Secretary of HHS to establish procedures and rules to restrict access to the National Provider Identifier Registry in order to deter fraudulent use of it. Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid), for any state that has established a State Prescription Drug Monitoring Program meeting certain requirements, to decrease by 10% the federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) with respect to any amounts recovered by or paid to the state related to an overpayment due to fraud, waste, or abuse. Allows the state to use such amounts to support its State Prescription Drug Monitoring Program. Directs the Secretary of HHS and the Attorney General jointly to establish a Commission to examine interoperability and other issues related to State Prescription Drug Monitoring Programs. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) update daily the Drug Enforcement Agency (DEA) database of persons registered to manufacture, distribute, or dispense a controlled substance under the Controlled Substances Act to reflect any changes in the information in the Death Master File of the Social Security Administration; (2) agree with the Commissioner of Social Security to obtain death information in order to update such database; (3) establish procedures and rules to restrict access to the database to deter its fraudulent use; and (4) establish procedures and rules to review and investigate pharmacy claims under Medicare part D that contain a registration number not assigned to a practitioner by the Attorney General under the Controlled Substances Act. Amends SSA title XVIII to require certain annual reports to describe the types and financial costs to the Medicare program of improper payment vulnerabilities identified by Recovery Audit Contractors (RACs). Requires the Secretary of HHS to develop a plan to revise the beneficiary incentive program under the Health Instance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) to encourage greater participation by individuals in reporting fraud and abuse in the Medicare program. Requires the Secretary of HHS to: (1) establish and implement procedures to eliminate the unnecessary collection, use, and display of Social Security account numbers of Medicare beneficiaries; and (2) ensure that each newly issued Medicare identification card meets specified requirements. Directs the Secretary of HHS to establish a pilot program utilizing smart card technology to evaluate its applicability to the Medicare program and whether such cards would be effective in preventing Medicare fraud. Directs the Secretary of HHS to establish policies and procedures for a process to require prior authorization for initial claims for reimbursement for standard power wheelchairs. Requires the Secretary of HHS, the HHS Inspector General, and the Attorney General to increase coordination and data sharing. Directs the Secretary of HHS to establish: (1) automated prepayment review of all Medicare claims, (2) a plan to facilitate the inclusion of states in the Medicare-Medicaid Data Match Program, and (3) a plan that allows each state Medicaid agency access to relevant data on improper or erroneous Medicare payments for items or services for dual eligible individuals. Prohibits Medicaid payments as well as payments under SSA title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program) (CHIP) unless a claim contains a valid beneficiary identification number and a valid National Provider Identifier. Directs the Secretary to establish Medicare administrative contractor error reduction incentives. Requires the provider enrollment process and provider screening to be separate from any contract to serve as a Medicare administrative contractor. Directs the Secretary of HHS to report to Congress on measurable metrics for improving Medicare contractor performance. Amends SSA title XI to establish penalties for the illegal distribution of a Medicare, Medicaid, or CHIP beneficiary identification number or billing privileges.</summary>
</bill>
