<bill session="111" type="h" number="6000" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Thou Shalt Not Kill Thy Customers Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for criminal liability for the denial of health care coverage of a treatment or an individual, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412276"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
Thou Shalt Not Kill Thy Customers Act - Imposes a fine and/or prison term of up to one year on any responsible officer or employee of an insurance entity that engages in a denial of coverage under a health plan in violation of provisions of the Public Health Service Act. Makes such offense punishable as involuntary manslaughter if it results in death. Directs the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) establish a website and a toll-free telephone number to receive reports of instances of denial of health care treatment or coverage by insurance entities for investigation of such reports; and (2) report instances for which sufficient evidence exists of a violation of this Act to the Attorney General for further investigation and prosecution. Expresses the sense of Congress that each state should thoroughly investigate violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
