<bill session="110" type="h" number="3310" updated="2013-07-19T21:32:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Earning and Living Opportunities Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968 to ensure improved access to employment opportunities for low-income people.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Housing management"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2007--Introduced.
Earning and Living Opportunities Act - Amends the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968 to set forth as a condition of federal housing and community development assistance that: (1) a public or Indian housing agency or contractor shall require that at least 20% of employee hours be performed by low- or very low-income persons; and (2) a recipient of assistance for housing rehabilitation, construction, or other public construction projects and their contractors shall require that at least 20% of new employee hours be performed by low- or very low-income persons. Directs the Secretary to require a public or Indian housing agency and other recipients of federal housing and community development assistance to: (1) establish a section 3 committee of interested parties to oversee all aspects of compliance with section 3 of such Act; (2) advertise training and employment opportunities generated by development assistance; and (3) maintain a registry of eligible low- and very low-income persons who express interest in those opportunities. (Section 3 declares the policy of the Congress to ensure that the employment and other economic opportunities generated by federal financial assistance for housing and community development programs shall, to the greatest extent feasible, be directed toward low- and very low-income persons, particularly those who are recipients of government assistance for housing.) Prescribes requirements for: (1) contractor compliance and job training; and (2) agency recruitment and referral. Establishes fines for noncompliance.</summary>
</bill>
