<bill session="109" type="h" number="2593" updated="2013-07-19T19:27:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Narco-Terrorism Enforcement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To encourage more vigorous investigation and prosecution, under section 2339B of title 18, United States Code, of drug crimes committed to provide material support to terrorist organizations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1073"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2005--Introduced.
Narco-Terrorism Enforcement Act of 2005 - Authorizes and encourages the Attorney General, through the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration and other appropriate means, to investigate foreign production and trafficking in illicit narcotics and other controlled substances from which the illicit proceeds help support or sustain foreign terrorist organizations, and to prosecute these offenses, regardless of whether such substances are intended for or enter the United States. Increases maximum, and establishes minimum, terms of imprisonment for providing material support to terrorists and designated foreign terrorist organizations. Sets minimum and maximum penalties applicable if the provision of material support or resources consisted of prohibited drug activity or transferring the proceeds from such activity, or if death results from the offense.</summary>
</bill>
