<bill session="111" type="h" number="219" updated="2013-07-19T23:13:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security Preservation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to ensure the integrity of the Social Security trust funds by requiring the Managing Trustee to invest the annual surplus of such trust funds in marketable interest-bearing obligations of the United States and certificates of deposit in depository institutions insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and to protect such trust funds from the public debt limit.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412265" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2009-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2009-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2009-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2009-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400207" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2009-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400235" joined="2009-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400254" joined="2009-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2009-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2009-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2009-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2009-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2009-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400405" joined="2010-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2009-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E3"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/2009--Introduced.
Social Security Preservation Act of 2009 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to require the Managing Trustee of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund (Social Security Trust Funds) to ensure that the annual surplus of the Social Security Trust Funds is invested in: (1) marketable interest-bearing obligations of the United States or obligations guaranteed by the United States; or (2) certificates of deposit in insured depository institutions. Outlines requirements for determining the annual surplus of the Trust Funds. Prohibits disinvestment of Social Security Trust Fund amounts from public debt obligations, any refraining from making such investments, or any delay in making normal deposits in such Trust Funds for public debt limit-related purposes. Authorizes, with certain conditions, the sale of Social Security Trust Fund public debt obligations for the payment of cash benefits and administrative expenses.</summary>
</bill>
