<bill session="112" type="h" number="1184" updated="2013-07-20T01:20:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care Waiver Transparency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require greater transparency concerning the criteria used to grant waivers to the job-killing health care law and to ensure that applications for such waivers are treated in a fair and consistent manner, irrespective of the applicant's political contributions or association with a labor union, a health plan provided for under a collective bargaining agreement, or another organized labor group.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2011-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412424" joined="2011-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="650"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2011--Introduced.
Health Care Waiver Transparency Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to publish detailed criteria used by the Secretary to approve a waiver, adjustment, or other compliance relief provided for under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act or the health care provisions of the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010, including how significant of a decrease in benefits or increase in premiums would need to occur in order to be approved for a waiver. Directs the Secretary to publish each application for a waiver and the approval or rejection of the waiver while ensuring the confidentiality of proprietary information of each applicant. Prohibits any preferential treatment to be given to an applicant based on political contributions or association with a labor union, a health plan provided for under a collective bargaining agreement, or another organized labor group.</summary>
</bill>
