<bill session="109" type="h" number="2728" updated="2013-07-19T19:28:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care Access and Availability Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to expand health care access and choice of coverage through Individual Membership Associations (IMAs).</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400368"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2005--Introduced.
Health Care Access and Availability Act of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to provide for health benefits coverage through individual membership associations (IMAs), which are organizations operated under the direction of an association that: (1) has been in existence for at least five years; (2) was formed for purposes other than obtaining insurance; and (3) does not condition membership on any health status-related factor. Prohibits an IMA from offering health benefits coverage to any member unless the same coverage is offered to all members of the IMA. Provides that the IMA shall provide health benefits coverage only through contracts with health insurance issuers and shall not assume insurance risk with respect to such coverage. Allows an IMA to provide administrative services for members, including accounting, billings, and enrollment information. Requires an IMA to file with the Secretary of Health and Human Services information that demonstrates the IMA's compliance with the requirements of this Act. Requires that health benefits coverage offered through an IMA be: (1) underwritten by a health insurance issuer that is licensed under state law and meets all state standards relating to consumer protection; and (2) approved or otherwise be permitted under state law.</summary>
</bill>
