<bill session="111" type="h" number="5786" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Cosmetics Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title VI of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to ensure the safe use of cosmetics, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2010-08-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2010--Introduced.
Safe Cosmetics Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to expand the regulation of cosmetics, including to require: (1) annual registration of any establishment engaged in manufacturing, packaging, or distributing cosmetics for use in the United States; (2) new fees to provide for oversight and enforcement of cosmetics regulations; (3) ingredient labeling and disclosure of information on ingredients; and (4) adverse event reporting. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a list of prohibited or restricted ingredients and a list of ingredients that are safe without limits for use in cosmetics; and (2) develop a priority assessment list of ingredients that cannot be included on either of the other two lists because of a lack of authoritative information on the safety of the ingredient; and (3) establish minimum data requirements and test protocols to be used by manufacturers to assess the safety of cosmetic ingredients. Sets forth provisions related to: (1) nanotechnology in the formulation of cosmetics; (2) the voluntary and mandatory recall of cosmetics; and (3) alternatives to animal testing. Establishes the Interagency Council on Cosmetic Safety to share data and promote collaboration on cosmetic safety among federal agencies. Deems a cosmetic that fails to meet the requirements set forth by this Act to be adulterated. Deems a cosmetic that fails to meet the labeling requirements under this Act to be misbranded. Requires the Secretary of Labor to promulgate an occupational safety and health standard that requires an expanded material safety data sheet to be made available to cosmetics distributors and employers using such products for professional use.</summary>
</bill>
