<bill session="112" type="s" number="41" updated="2013-07-20T02:16:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Office for Social Work Research Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the establishment of a National Office for Social Work Research.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2011--Introduced.
National Office for Social Work Research Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the Office of Social Work Research in the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to conduct, support, and disseminate targeted research concerning social work methods and outcomes related to problems of significant social concern. Requires the Office to: (1) promote research and training to inform social work practices, and (2) provide policymakers with research to better understand complex social issues and make informed funding decisions about service effectiveness and cost efficiency. Sets forth duties of the Director of the Office, which shall include: (1) recommending an agenda for conducting and supporting social work research through the national research institutes and centers; (2) promoting coordination and cooperation among such institutes and centers; (3) promoting the sufficient allocation of NIH resources for such research; and (4) promoting and encouraging the establishment of a centralized clearinghouse for social work research to provide understandable information about this research to the public, social service professionals, medical professionals, patients, and families. Requires the Director to serve as the principal adviser to the Director of NIH and to provide advice to other relevant agencies. Authorizes the Director of the Office to enter into cooperative agreements with, and make grants to, public or private nonprofit entities to pay all or part of the cost of planning, establishing, or strengthening, and providing basic operating support for centers of excellence for clinical and psychosocial research, training in, and demonstration of social work research.</summary>
</bill>
