<bill session="109" type="sr" number="503" updated="2013-07-19T20:11:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-09">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution mourning the loss of life caused by the earthquake that occurred on May 27, 2006, in Indonesia, expressing the condolences of the American people to the families of the victims, and urging assistance to those affected.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2006-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2006-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2006-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2006-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5604" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-09">
      <text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2006-06-09" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5685" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5685" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Military civic action"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2006--Passed Senate without amendment.
Mourns the loss of life and suffering caused by the earthquake that occurred on May 27, 2006, in Indonesia. Expresses the condolences of the American people to the families, communities, and government of the victims. Expresses sympathy for the hundreds of thousands of people who have been seriously affected. Commends the international humanitarian response to the earthquake by the governments of many countries, the United Nations and other international organizations, and nongovernmental organizations. Expresses gratitude and respect for the work of all individuals providing aid, including U.S. civilian and military personnel. Urges the President and the U.S. government to provide all appropriate assistance to the government of Indonesia and people of the affected region. Recognizes the lead role of the Indonesian government in providing assistance and promoting recovery.</summary>
</bill>
