<bill session="110" type="h" number="6954" updated="2013-07-19T22:04:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Senior Financial Empowerment Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent mail, telemarketing, and Internet fraud targeting seniors in the United States, to promote efforts to increase public awareness of the enormous impact that mail, telemarketing, and Internet fraud have on seniors, to educate the public, seniors, their families, and their caregivers about how to identify and combat fraudulent activity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2008-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2008-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2008--Introduced.
Senior Financial Empowerment Act of 2008 - Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to: (1) review and amend its sentencing guidelines to include the age of a crime victim in its criteria for determining whether a sentencing enhancement is appropriate; and (2) report to Congress on issues relating to the age of crime victims. Directs the Attorney General to establish and administer a competitive grant program for mail, telemarketing, and Internet fraud prevention education programs for senior citizens. Expresses the sense of Congress with respect to public awareness of the impact of mail, telemarketing, and Internet fraud on senior citizens.</summary>
</bill>
