<bill session="109" type="s" number="430" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Arrest Methamphetamine Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to arrest methamphetamine abuse in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1649"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1650-1651" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="3324"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Community policing"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug courts"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family courts"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public health administration"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State-local relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2005--Introduced.
Arrest Methamphetamine Act of 2005 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Attorney General, through the Bureau of Justice Assistance (BJA), to make grants to States to address the manufacture, sale, and use of methamphetamine to enhance public safety, including for activities to: (1) arrest individuals violating methamphetamine related laws; (2) undertake methamphetamine clandestine lab seizures and environmental cleanup; (3) provide for community based education, awareness, and prevention; (4) provide child support and family services to assist methamphetamine users and their families; and (5) procure equipment, technology, or support systems, or pay for resources, where expenditures would result in reduction in methamphetamine use, sale, and manufacture. Sets forth application requirements. Authorizes the Attorney General, through BJA, to make grants to States, Indian tribal governments, and multijurisdictional or regional consortia to develop a comprehensive, cooperative strategy to address the use, sale, and manufacture of methamphetamine. Allocates funding for enforcement. Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) collect systematic data on the effectiveness of programs assisted under this Act; (2) establish a national clearinghouse of information on effective programs for dissemination to State and local agencies; (3) establish a program within the Department of Justice to facilitate the sharing of best practices among States; and (4) provide technical assistance to State and local agencies. Urges the President to seek commitments from the Canadian Government to take effective measures to stem the availability of pseudoephedrine in Canada and its illegal importation into the United States.</summary>
</bill>
