<bill session="111" type="h" number="3389" updated="2013-07-19T23:42:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bring Assistance to Heroes Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 37, United States Code, to ensure that members of the Armed Forces stationed outside the United States during 2009 can take full advantage of the credits available for first-time home buyers, to provide for the waiver of recapture of the credit for members who are restationed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400137"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2009--Introduced.
Bring Assistance to Heroes Act of 2009 - Extends the first-time homebuyer credit (credit) through December 1, 2010, for certain military personnel stationed outside the United States. Excludes credit-recipient military personnel from: (1) the increased tax credit recapture provision; and (2) accelerated credit recapture regarding disposition of a principal residence if such member receives extended duty orders after the residence's purchase and before the date that such recapture would apply.</summary>
</bill>
