<bill session="111" type="h" number="4915" updated="2013-07-19T23:56:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-18">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Aviation Administration Extension Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Surface Transportation Extension Modification Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Federal Aviation Administration Extension Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Surface Transportation Extension Modification Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the funding and expenditure authority of the Airport and Airway Trust Fund, to amend title 49, United States Code, to extend authorizations for the airport improvement program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An Act to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make technical corrections to the pension funding provisions of the Preservation of Access to Care for Medicare Beneficiaries and Pension Relief Act of 2010.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2010-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-23">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24T10:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Costello moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24T10:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2268-2273" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24T10:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4915.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-03-24T11:18:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2268-2269" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-18">
      <text>Senate Committee on Finance discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-18">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10696" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2010-12-18" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-12-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1512"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3607"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4217"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4853"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4853"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4957"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4957"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5147"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5611"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5900"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6190"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6473"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3187"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3187"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4848"/>
    <amendment number="s4849"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/18/2010--Passed Senate amended.
(Sec. 1) Makes technical amendments to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code (IRC), as amended by the Preservation of Access to Care for Medicare Beneficiaries and Pension Relief Act of 2010 (PACMBPRA), regarding the election to apply specified requirements in an eligible plan year with respect to the shortfall amortization base in minimum funding standards for a single-employer defined benefit pension plan. Treats a plan as eligible for such an election only if: (1) the plan sponsor is not a debtor in a case under bankruptcy law or similar federal or state law, (2) there are no unpaid minimum required contributions with respect to the plan for purposes of the excise tax when minimum required contributions are not paid when due, (3) there are no outstanding liens in favor of the plan for a person's failure to make required contributions, and (4) the plan sponsor has not initiated a distress termination of the plan. (Sec. 2) Amends the Pension Protection Act of 2006 (PPA), as amended by PACMBPRA, with respect to the exemption from certain PPA requirements for and restrictions on the funding of multiple employer plans of eligible charities. Redefines an eligible charity plan as one maintained by one or more employers with employees accruing benefits based on service for the plan year, where: (1) such employees are employed in at least 20 states, (2) more than 98% of them are employed by a tax-exempt charitable organization whose primary exempt purpose is to provide services with respect to children, and (3) the plan sponsor elects to be treated as an eligible charity plan. Applies this redefinition to plan years beginning after December 31, 2010, but allows a plan sponsor to elect to apply it to earlier plan years. (Sec. 3) Amends the Worker, Retiree, and Employer Recovery Act of 2008 to extend through plan years beginning during the period October 1, 2008-December 31, 2011, certain funding-based limits on benefit accruals for single-employer plans with severe funding shortfalls. Revises the adjusted funding target attainment percentage factor in such limits for that period. Amends ERISA and the IRC with respect to the allowance of a one-time prohibited payment by a single-employer plan. Declares that, in the case of payments the annuity starting date for which occurs on or before December 31, 2011, payments under a Social Security leveling option shall be treated as not in excess of the monthly amount paid under a single life annuity (plus an amount not in excess of a Social Security supplement). Permits a plan sponsor to elect to apply such treatment to payments whose annuity starting date occurs before January 1, 2011. Repeals related existing requirements as if they had never been enacted. (Sec. 4) Amends ERISA and the IRC, as amended by PACMBPRA, to revise the threshold date, under rules for special relief from minimum funding standards, for the period during which a solvent multiemployer plan may treat, as an item separate from other experience losses, to be amortized over 30 years, the portion of any experience loss or gain attributable to net investment losses incurred in either or both of certain plan years. Changes the identity of such plan years from the first two plan years ending after August 31, 2008, to the first two plan years ending after June 30, 2008.</summary>
</bill>
