<bill session="109" type="h" number="5706" updated="2013-07-19T19:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part D of title IV of the Social Security Act to provide for the pass through of all child support collected on behalf of families receiving assistance under the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400351"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2006-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2006-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2006-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2006-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2006-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2006--Introduced.
Amends part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) of title IV of the Social Security Act to revise requirements for the pass-through of child support collected on behalf of families receiving assistance under the program of block grants to states for temporary assistance for needy families (TANF). Requires pass-through to a family receiving TANF of the total amount of collected child support. (Currently the federal government receives its share and the state retains or distributes to the family the state share of such child support.) Requires payment to: (1) the federal government of its share of foster care maintenance payments; (2) the state for retention, or distribution to the family, of the state share of such payments; and (3) the family of any remaining amount.</summary>
</bill>
