<bill session="110" type="s" number="1632" updated="2013-07-19T22:34:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vessel Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that vessels of the United States conveyed to eligible recipients for educational, cultural, historical, charitable, recreational, or other public purposes are maintained and utilized for the purposes for which they were conveyed.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7749-7750"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7750" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7812-7813"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Warships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/2007--Introduced.
Vessel Conveyance Act - Subjects the conveyance of a U.S. government vessel to an eligible entity for use as an educational, cultural, historical, charitable, or recreational or other public purpose to conditions that such vessel will be maintained and used for such purposes. Requires a vessel that is not maintained and used for such purposes to revert to the United States. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to convene a working group composed of representatives from the Maritime Adminsitration, the Coast Guard, and the U.S. Navy to review and make recommendations on a common set of conditions for the conveyance of U.S. vessels to eligible entities. Sets forth civil penalties for violations of the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
