<bill session="111" type="s" number="3416" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to provide for an exclusion from Red Flag Guidelines for certain businesses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2010-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="3763"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/25/2010--Introduced.
Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act with respect to the duties of users of consumer reports who take adverse actions on the basis of information contained in such reports. Excludes any health care practice, accounting practice, or legal practice with 20 or fewer employees from the meaning of creditor subject to Red Flag Guidelines regarding identity theft promulgated by the proper federal financial regulatory agency. Excludes any other business which the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) determines: (1) knows all its customers or clients individually; (2) only performs services in or around the residences of its customers; or (3) has not experienced incidents of identity theft, and identity theft is rare for businesses of that type. States that such exclusion shall no longer apply to any business that can no longer meet such eligibility criteria.</summary>
</bill>
