<bill session="110" type="h" number="6435" updated="2013-07-19T22:00:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Highway Chokepoint Congestion Relief Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To relieve traffic congestion.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2008-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2008-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2008--Introduced.
National Highway Chokepoint Congestion Relief Act - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) issue regulations to establish a chokepoint congestion relief program; and (2) develop criteria for designating national chokepoint regions in a state. Authorizes the Secretary to make capital improvement grants to states in order to carry out eligible projects that reduce traffic congestion in the national chokepoint regions. Sets forth a formula for the apportioning of grant funds. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) states should adopt both interim and long-term objectives for significantly reducing traffic congestion at chokepoint areas; (2) establishment of performance measures and quantitative goals will allow states to make efficient use of available resources on projects that have the maximum impact in reducing traffic congestion and improving mobility at chokepoint areas; and (3) alleviation of traffic congestion requires Congress to commit to authorizing and funding nonautomotive travel modes as well as travel demand management, growth management, and land use strategies. Requires the Administrator of the Research and Innovative Technology Administration (RITA), through the Volpe National Transportation Systems Center, to study and report to specified congressional committees on the extent to which congestion pricing can encourage travelers to drive during off-peak hours, or change their mode of transportation, and can also generate revenue and thus require less tax-based funding.</summary>
</bill>
