<bill session="112" type="h" number="5835" updated="2013-07-20T02:00:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Access to Capital Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act and the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to provide for additional loan programs for veteran-owned small businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/2012--Introduced.
Veterans Access to Capital Act of 2012 - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to authorize the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), using up to 20% of annual amounts available for SBA loans to state and local development companies, to make loans directly to small businesses owned and controlled by veterans to be used on projects having a sound business purpose. Provides loan limits and requires partial project funding by such small business. Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Administrator to make up to 20% of the annual amounts available for SBA section 7(a) general small business loans available for loans to veteran-owned small businesses. Directs the Administrator, for purposes of loans or loan guarantees to veteran- or disabled veteran-owned small businesses, to reduce any applicable requirement relating to the veteran's credit score, as long as the veteran has complied with other conditions that the Administrator may require.</summary>
</bill>
