<bill session="113" type="s" number="135" updated="2013-11-02T06:53:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Title X Abortion Provider Prohibition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title X of the Public Health Service Act to prohibit family planning grants from being awarded to any entity that performs abortions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412556" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2013-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="61"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="217"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2013--Introduced.
Title X Abortion Provider Prohibition Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Service (HHS) from providing any federal family planning assistance to an entity unless the entity certifies that, during the period of such assistance, the entity will not perform, and will not provide any funds to any other entity that performs, an abortion. Excludes an abortion where: (1) the pregnancy is the result of rape or incest; or (2) a physician certifies that the woman suffered from a physical disorder, injury, or illness that would place the woman in danger of death unless an abortion is performed, including a condition caused by or arising from the pregnancy. Excludes hospitals from such requirement so long as the hospital does not provide funds to any non-hospital entity that performs an abortion. Requires the Secretary to provide Congress annually: (1) information on grantees who performed abortions under the exceptions, and (2) a list of entities to which grant funds are made available.</summary>
</bill>
