<bill session="109" type="s" number="735" updated="2013-07-19T20:19:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Offshore Fairness Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Submerged Lands Act to make the seaward boundaries of the States of Louisiana, Alabama, and Mississippi equivalent to the seaward boundaries of the State of Texas and the Gulf Coast of Florida.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Offshore structures"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/2005--Introduced.
Offshore Fairness Act of 2005 - Amends the Submerged Lands Act to require the Secretary of the Interior to convey the interest of the United States in the expanded submerged land of the states of Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama, if the state involved demonstrates that specified conditions will be met. Numbers among such conditions the requirement that the state enact, and keep updated, laws or promulgate regulations equivalent to federal law or regulations regarding: (1) the environmental protection, safety, and operations of any operation pipeline in existence on the date of conveyance; and (2) valuation of oil, gas, or other mineral production from existing interests for royalty purposes. Provides that if any existing federal oil and gas or other mineral lease or unit would be divided by the expanded seaward boundary of a state, the federal interest in the leased minerals underlying the portion of the lease or unit that lies within the expanded submerged boundary shall not be considered to be conveyed to the state until the date on which the lease or unit expires or is relinquished by the United States.</summary>
</bill>
