<bill session="111" type="s" number="1324" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care Freedom Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Health Care Choice Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">MCAP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Medical Care Access Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that every American has a health insurance plan that they can afford, own, and keep.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2009-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2009--Introduced.
Health Care Freedom Act of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for qualified health insurance costs. Allows a health savings account or an Archer medical savings account to be used to purchase a high deductible health plan. Medical Care Access Protection Act of 2009 or the MCAP Act - Sets forth provisions regulating lawsuits for health care liability claims related to the provision of health care services, including limiting noneconomic and punitive damages. Health Care Choice Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to provide that the laws of the state designated by a health insurance issuer (primary state) shall apply to individual health insurance coverage offered by that issuer in the primary state and in any other state (secondary state), but only if the coverage and issuer comply with specified conditions. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award block grants to states to provide for the development of innovative models that ensure affordable health insurance coverage for Americans with preexisting health conditions. Sets forth disclosure requirements, including requiring: (1) the provision of price information to Medicare or Medicaid patients; and (2) the provision of allowable payment information to enrollees of group health plans. Prohibits the Secretary of the Treasury from making any payment or obligation under the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008. Provides for collection of revenues relating to such Act. Rescinds any funds available under such Act that have not been obligated and makes such funds available to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
