<bill session="109" type="s" number="1570" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Employer Work Incentive Act for Individuals with Severe Disabilities</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote employment of individuals with severe disabilities through Federal Government contracting and procurement processes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2005-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2005-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9492-9493" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Introduced.
Employer Work Incentive Act for Individuals with Severe Disabilities - Amends the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to require the head of an executive agency, in entering into a contract, to give preference in the source selection process to each offeror that submits with its offer a written pledge that the contractor is an eligible business. Defines an eligible business as a nonprofit or for-profit business entity that: (1) has established an integrated employment setting; (2) on average employs individuals with severe disabilities in not less than 25% of the full-time equivalent positions; (3) pays wages to each of the individuals with severe disabilities at not less than the applicable rate under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (FLSA), regardless of whether the individuals are engaged in supported employment or training under a contract with an executive agency or a program that receives federal funds, and does not employ any individual with a severe disability pursuant to a special certification issued under FLSA; and (4) makes contributions for at least 50% of the total cost of the annual premiums for health insurance coverage for its employees. Requires: (1) the Federal Acquisition Regulation to set forth the pledge that is to be used in the administration of this Act; and (2) the Secretary to maintain on the Department of Labor's Internet website a list of contractors that have submitted the pledge.</summary>
</bill>
