<bill session="110" type="s" number="3668" updated="2013-07-19T22:53:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Crime Victims with Disabilities Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to create a grant program for collaboration programs that ensure coordination among criminal justice agencies, adult protective services agencies, victim assistance programs, and other agencies or organizations providing services to individuals with disabilities in the investigation and response to abuse of or crimes committed against such individuals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-10-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10326"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-10-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10326-10328" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2008--Introduced.
Crime Victims with Disabilities Act of 2008 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Attorney General to make grants to states, local governments, Indian tribes, or tribal organizations to plan for or implement a collaboration program to investigate and remediate abuse of or crimes committed against individuals with disabilities and to provide services to such individuals. Requires the Attorney General to establish a national center to evaluate the effectiveness of such programs.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) establish a national interdisciplinary advisory council to develop a methodology for collecting data on violence against people with developmental and related disabilities; and (2) award grants to collect such data.</summary>
</bill>
