<bill session="112" type="sr" number="428" updated="2013-07-20T02:14:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution condemning the Government of Syria for crimes against humanity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2012-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2012-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2012-04-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2552-2553"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2551-2552" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/19/2012--Introduced.
Condemns the government of Syria, Syrian security forces, and the President of the Syrian Arab Republic for attacks against the civilian population of Syria. Commends the President for the U.S. vote at the U.N. Security Council to condemn the violations of human rights and fundamental freedoms by the Syrian authorities. Urges the President to collect information on incidents in Syria that may constitute crimes against humanity and take action to ensure that the government of Syria, its leaders, and senior officials who are responsible for such crimes are brought to account in an appropriately constituted tribunal. Urges the President to formally establish the Atrocities Prevention Board and for the Board to provide recommendations to the President concerning the prevention of mass atrocities in Syria. Urges the international community to review legal processes available to hold officials of the government of Syria, Syrian security forces, and the President of the Syrian Arab Republic accountable for crimes against humanity and violations of human rights. Supports the people of Syria as they seek to exercise universal rights and pursue peaceful democratic change.</summary>
</bill>
