<bill session="111" type="h" number="1901" updated="2013-07-19T23:28:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a comprehensive study by the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences to assess the water management, needs, and conservation of the Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint River System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400044"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400107" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412198" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2009-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="805"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="805"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Army to enter into an agreement with the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a comprehensive study of the water management, needs, and conservation of the Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint River System. Requires that the study include: (1) a summary of the existing body of scientific knowledge on the ecology, hydrology, geomorphology, and biogeochemistry of the Apalachicola River and the greater River System, the ecosystem services provided by that River, the impact of variation in freshwater flow on the ecology of the river and downstream coastal ecosystems, and how to restore the natural hydraulic function of the System; (2) assessments of models that serve as the basis for the master manuals of the System, of water availability, supply options, demand-management alternatives, and socioeconomic factors that influence uses in the System, and of policies, regulations, and other factors that affect federal water project operations; and (3) recommendations for an approach to determine water limits that recognize the needs of all water users along the System and for additional measures to address the long-term watershed management needs of the System.</summary>
</bill>
