<bill session="110" type="s" number="2124" updated="2013-07-19T22:39:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Montana Cemetery Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Montana Cemetery Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey certain land in the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest, Montana, to Jefferson County, Montana, for use as a cemetery.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-485.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-05-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-361.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="793">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 793.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3702"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3702"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3702"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3702"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Montana Cemetery Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, through the National Forest Service (NFS), to convey to Jefferson County, Montana, the parcel of National Forest System land known as the Elkhorn Cemetery to be used as a county cemetery. Requires the county to agree to manage the cemetery with due consideration and protection for the historic and cultural values of the cemetery. Grants to the county an easement across certain National Forest System land to provide access to the conveyed land.Provides for reversion of the land conveyed to the county, at the election of the Secretary, if such land is used for a purpose other than as a county cemetery or managed by the county in a manner that is inconsistent with the management of the cemetery as described above.</summary>
</bill>
