<bill session="113" type="s" number="152" updated="2013-11-02T06:53:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">America Needs Eielson Air Force Base Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Air Force to retain the current leadership rank, aircraft, and core functions of the 354th Fighter Wing and the 18th Aggressor Squadron at Eielson Air Force Base and to require reports on proposed activities at such installation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-01-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2013--Introduced.
America Needs Eielson Air Force Base Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of the Air Force to maintain the current leadership rank, aircraft, and core functions of the 354th Fighter Wing and 18th Aggressor Squadron at Eielson Air Force Base, Alaska, with the same mission elements, responsibilities, and capabilities as existed on November 1, 2011, until the later of: (1) 180 days after the National Commission on the Structure of the Air Force submits an Air Force structure study report as required under the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013, and (2) the date on which the Secretary of Defense (DOD) submits to the congressional defense and appropriations committees a report on the strategic importance of Eielson Air Force Base (required under this Act). Prohibits the Secretary of the Air Force from changing the aircraft or core functions of the 354th Wing and 18th Squadron at Eielson, or the existing mission elements, responsibilities, and capabilities of such installation, until the completion of an environmental impact statement and a record of decision relating to the proposed changes.</summary>
</bill>
