<bill session="110" type="s" number="1520" updated="2013-07-19T22:33:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Price Gouging Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit price gouging relating to gasoline and diesel fuels in areas affected by major disasters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2007--Introduced.
Price Gouging Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to direct the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), after the President declares a major disaster, to: (1) consult with the Attorney General, the U.S. Attorney for that area, and state and local law enforcement officials to determine whether any supplier is charging unconscionably excessive prices for gasoline or diesel fuel; (2) establish a toll-free hotline for a consumer to report price gouging; and (3) establish a program to develop and distribute public informational materials in English and Spanish to assist consumers in detecting and avoiding price gouging. Makes it unlawful to charge unconscionably excessive prices for any gasoline or diesel fuel during the 180-day period after the President declares a major disaster. Requires the FTC, if it determines a supplier is in violation, to take any action it determines appropriate to remedy the violation. Authorizes civil penalties. Requires imprisonment for knowing violations. Authorizes victims and any state attorney general to bring a civil action against violators of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
