<bill session="112" type="h" number="6521" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide payment for patient navigator services under title XIX of the Social Security Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2012-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require a state Medicaid plan to provide for state reimbursement of an eligible entity for any patient navigator service provided to a Medicaid-eligible individual. Includes within the definition of "medical assistance" certain patient navigator services defined under the Public Health Service Act (PHSA) as assisting in specified ways individuals who are at risk for or who have cancer or other chronic diseases. Treats as eligible entities those identified under PHSA as public or nonprofit private health centers (including federally qualified health centers), health facilities operated by or pursuant to a contract with the Indian Health Service, hospitals, cancer centers, rural health clinics, academic health centers, or nonprofit entities that enter into a partnership or coordinate referrals with such a center, clinic, facility, or hospital to provide patient navigator services.</summary>
</bill>
