<bill session="110" type="h" number="1013" updated="2013-07-19T21:12:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to prohibit the approval or continuation of section 1115 waivers insofar as they provide coverage of nonpregnant adults under the State Children's Health Insurance Program (SCHIP).</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400127" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2007-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1941"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5596-5601"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7474-7475"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Welfare waivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/13/2007--Introduced.
Amends title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance) (SCHIP) of the Social Security Act to revise the prohibition against approval by the Secretary of Health and Human Services of any waiver, experimental, pilot, or demonstration project that allows funds made available under SCHIP to be used to provide child health assistance or other health benefits coverage to a nonpregnant childless adult. Repeals the limitation of such prohibition with respect to childless nonpregnant adults, and the exclusion of caretaker relatives from consideration as childless adults denied such assistance or other health benefits coverage. (Thus extends such prohibition to the use of such funds for assistance to or coverage of all nonpregnant adults, regardless of whether they do or do not have children, or whether they are caretaker relatives.) Terminates all such coverage under current waivers as of December 31, 2007.</summary>
</bill>
