<bill session="112" type="s" number="1302" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-15">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Administrator of General Services to convey a parcel of real property in Tracy, California, to the City of Tracy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 112-40.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-07-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="117">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 117.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2011-08-02" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5283" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5283" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-08-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-05T10:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07T16:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Issa moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07T16:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2299-2300" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07T16:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1302.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2012-05-07T17:03:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2299" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2012-05-15" type="public" number="112-119">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-119.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2406"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2406"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2012--Public Law.
Authorizes the Administrator of General Services (GSA) to offer to enter into a binding agreement with the city of Tracy, California, under which the Administrator may convey to the city any reversionary interest retained by the United States in a specified parcel of land conveyed to the city for educational or recreational purposes and all other terms, conditions, reservations, and restrictions imposed in connection with the conveyance of such parcel. Requires the city to pay to the Administrator not less than the appraised fair market value of the parcel, as determined by the Administrator pursuant to an appraisal, based on the highest and best use of the parcel. Treats such determination regarding the value of such parcel as being final. Makes the city responsible for reimbursing the Administrator for costs associated with the implementation of this Act, including the costs of each applicable appraisal and survey. Requires the net proceeds from such conveyance to be deposited into the Federal Buildings Fund and made available for expenditure for any lawful purpose consistent with the Administrator's authority. Prohibits anything in this Act from affecting or limiting the application of or obligation to comply with any environmental law.</summary>
</bill>
