<bill session="109" type="s" number="1133" updated="2013-07-19T20:23:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Coal Research, Development, Demonstration, and Deployment Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Energy to develop and implement an accelerated research, development, and demonstration program for advanced clean coal technologies for use in coal-based generation facilities and to provide financial incentives to encourage the early commercial deployment of advanced clean coal technologies through the retrofitting, repowering, replacement, and new construction of coal-based electricity generating facilities and industrial gasification facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2005-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2005-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6029-6030"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural wastes"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Ammonia"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy demand"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Feedstock"/>
    <term name="Fertilizers"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Industrial research"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Paper and paper products"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Plants"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sulphur"/>
    <term name="Sulphur dioxide"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley development"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2005--Introduced.
Clean Coal Research, Development, Demonstration, and Deployment Act of 2005 - Instructs the Secretary of Energy to establish a clean coal power initiative to provide assistance to specified projects that: (1) operate within the United States with U.S. coal; and (2) advance efficiency, reliability, environmental performance, and cost competitiveness, or develop alternative technology pathways beyond the levels of technologies that are either currently in commercial service, or have demonstrated that commercial service is viable. Directs the Secretary to conduct a program of technology research, development, demonstration, and commercial application for coal and power systems. Sets forth a program to provide federal financial: (1) assistance for projects that will use integrated gasification combined cycle or other advanced coal-based generation technologies; and (2) incentives for deployment of advanced coal-based generation technologies. Amends the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to designate certified coal property as entitled to the energy investment tax credit. Allows a credit against tax for holders of clean energy bonds. Instructs the Secretary to: (1) establish an industrial gasification technology research, development, and demonstration program; (2) establish an Office of Industrial Gasification Coordination; and (3) identify cost and performance goals of industrial gasification technologies whose deployment would permit the continued cost-competitive gasification of certain fuels to produce chemical feedstocks or ammonia-based fertilizers and liquid transportation fuels. Directs the Secretary to establish a competitive program to consider and award certifications for investment and production tax credits to industrial gasification project sponsors. Amends the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow: (1) a synthesis gas production tax credit for production from certified industrial gasification projects; and (2) an investment tax credit for property involved in such projects.</summary>
</bill>
