<bill session="111" type="s" number="1465" updated="2013-07-20T00:36:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Anthony DeJuan Boatwright Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to require child care providers to provide to parents information regarding whether such providers carry liability insurance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2009-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2009-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7643-7644"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1662"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2009--Introduced.
Anthony DeJuan Boatwright Act - Amends the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 to require a state to provide assurances that the state includes, as part of its regulatory process for issuance and renewal of licenses to providers of child care services, a recommendation to each provider that it carry current liability insurance. Requires state plans for the use of child care and development block grant funds to certify that there are in effect state or local health and safety requirements that each child care provider: (1) post publicly and conspicuously in the service area of its premises a notice specifying whether it carries current liability insurance; and (2) give written notice to parents about whether it carries such insurance, obtain the signature of at least one parent per child acknowledging receipt of such notice, and maintain records of such signed notice while a child receives services.</summary>
</bill>
