<bill session="111" type="h" number="1331" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">REFI for Homeowners Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Responsible, Equitable, and Fair Insurance for Homeowners Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To replace the HOPE for Homeowners Program with a new program developed and implemented by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2009-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2009--Introduced.
Responsible, Equitable, and Fair Insurance for Homeowners Act of 2009 or the REFI for Homeowners Act of 2009 - Amends the National Housing Act to direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to insure any mortgage covering a troubled homeowner's one- to four-family primary residence that is made to pay or prepay (refinance) outstanding obligations under an existing mortgage or mortgages meeting specified requirements. Prohibits the refinancing of liar loans, zero-down loans, or loans with equity removed. Authorizes the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) to purchase mortgage-backed securities guaranteed by the Government National Mortgage Association (GNMA [Ginnie Mae]) that are either backed by loans originated under this Act, or whole loans originated and purchased under this Act. Authorizes GNMA to hold, sell, and securitize such whole loans. Amends the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA) to reduce Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) funds to offset costs of this Program.</summary>
</bill>
