<bill session="111" type="h" number="1051" updated="2013-07-19T23:21:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sole Community Hospital Preservation Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to extend and improve protections for sole community hospitals under the Medicare Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400395"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412220" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2009-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2009-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/2009--Introduced.
Sole Community Hospital Preservation Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with respect to the prospective payment system (PPS) for hospital outpatient department (OPD) services, particularly the transitional adjustment for sole community hospitals to limit any decline in payment. Continues to hold sole community hospitals harmless from any decline in payment. Increases the payment for covered OPD services furnished on or after January 1, 2010, in a sole community hospital by the amount of any difference between the pre-Balanced Budget Act of 1997 (pre-BBA) amount and a lesser PPS amount. Prescribes an increase of 7.1% in payment for such services (before the application of outliers and coinsurance). Permits the Secretary of Health and Human Services to revise such percentage based on a study comparing costs incurred by sole community hospitals located in rural areas by ambulatory payment classification groups (APCs) to costs incurred by hospitals located in urban areas. Bars any such increase in payment for devices, drugs, or biologicals.</summary>
</bill>
