<bill session="112" type="h" number="1701" updated="2013-07-20T01:25:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Eagle and Summit County Wilderness Preservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate certain lands in the State of Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, to designate the Red Table Mountain, Pisgah Mountain, Castle Peak, Tenmile, Hoosier Ridge, and Porcupine Gulch Special Management Areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412308"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/3/2011--Introduced.
Eagle and Summit County Wilderness Preservation Act - Amends the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 to designate certain lands in Colorado in the White River National Forest and certain public lands administered by Colorado River Valley Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System (NWPS). Releases the portions of the Castle Peak and Bull Gulch wilderness study areas that are not designated as wilderness by this Act from further study for designation as wilderness. Designates certain BLM administered lands and certain lands in the White River National Forest as the Red Table Mountain, Pisgah Mountain, and Castle Peak Areas. Provides for the eventual designation of the Castle Peak and Pisgah Mountain Areas as the Castle Peak Wilderness and Pisgah Mountain Wilderness, respectively, upon publication of a notice in the Federal Register that such areas are no longer needed by the Colorado Army National Guard for helicopter training, testing, or evaluation. Designates certain federal lands in the White River National Forest as: (1) the Tenmile and Hoosier Ridge Special Management Areas, and (2) the Porcupine Gulch Special Management Area.</summary>
</bill>
