<bill session="112" type="h" number="2196" updated="2013-07-20T01:29:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Renewable Energy Expansion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FREE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct President, utilizing the Western Area Power Administration, to acquire renewable energy in amounts sufficient to ensure that, of the total amount of electric energy the Federal Government consumes during any fiscal year, certain minimum amounts shall be renewable energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO30" subcommittee="Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2011--Introduced.
Federal Renewable Energy Expansion Act or FREE Act - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 with respect to renewable energy purchase requirements for the federal government. Directs the President, utilizing the Western Area Power Administration for electric energy procurement when practicable, to increase the maximum percentage of electric energy the federal government consumes during any fiscal year which must be renewable energy. Specifies increasing percentages from FY2014 up to FY2025 and beyond. Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to seek to maximize the amounts of renewable energy produced on federal lands and Indian land for compliance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
