<bill session="112" type="s" number="908" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the addition of certain real property to the reservation of the Siletz Tribe in the State of Oregon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2744"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-626.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6141"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2011--Introduced.
Amends the Siletz Tribe Indian Restoration Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to take into trust for the Siletz Tribe additional lands that lie within the original 1855 Siletz Coast Reservation and are located in Benton, Douglas, Lane, Lincoln, Tillamook, or Yamhill County in Oregon. Requires such land to be considered and evaluated as an on-reservation acquisition and become part of the Tribe's reservation if the county in which the land is located submits a written approval of such evaluation and consideration to the Secretary. (Off-reservation land acquisition requests require the Secretary to give greater scrutiny to the tribe's justification of the anticipated benefits from the acquisition.) Prohibits gaming on lands taken into trust pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
