<bill session="113" type="h" number="2818" updated="2013-11-02T06:42:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Surveillance State Repeal Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal the USA PATRIOT Act and the FISA Amendments Act of 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2013-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2013-10-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), Financial Services, Foreign Affairs, Energy and Commerce, Education and the Workforce, Transportation and Infrastructure, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2013--Introduced.
Surveillance State Repeal Act - Repeals the USA PATRIOT Act and the FISA Amendments Act of 2008 (thereby restoring or reviving provisions amended or repealed by such Acts as if such Acts had not been enacted), except with respect to reports to Congress regarding court orders under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) and the acquisition of intelligence information concerning an entity not substantially composed of U.S. persons that is engaged in the international proliferation of weapons of mass destruction. Extends from 7 to 10 years the maximum term of FISA judges. Makes such judges eligible for redesignation. Permits FISA courts to appoint special masters to advise on technical issues raised during proceedings. Requires orders approving certain electronic surveillance to direct that, upon request of the applicant, any person or entity must furnish all information, facilities, or technical assistance necessary to accomplish such surveillance in a manner to protect its secrecy and produce a minimum of interference with the services that such carrier, landlord, custodian, or other person is providing the target of such surveillance (thereby retaining the ability to conduct surveillance on such targets regardless of the type of communications methods or devices being used by the subject of the surveillance). Prohibits information relating to a U.S. person from being acquired pursuant to FISA without a valid warrant based on probable cause. Prohibits the federal government from requiring manufacturers of electronic devices and related software to build in mechanisms allowing the federal government to bypass encryption or privacy technology. Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to report annually on the federal government's compliance with FISA. Permits an employee of or contractor to an element of the intelligence community with knowledge of FISA-authorized programs and activities to submit a covered complaint to the Comptroller General, to the House or Senate intelligence committees, or in accordance with a process under the National Security Act of 1947 with respect to reports made to the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community. Defines a "covered complaint" as a complaint or information concerning FISA-authorized programs and activities that an employee or contractor reasonably believes is evidence of: (1) a violation of any law, rule, or regulation; or (2) gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety. Subjects an officer or employee of an element of the intelligence community to administrative sanctions, including termination, for taking retaliatory action against an employee or contractor who seeks to disclose, or who discloses, such information.</summary>
</bill>
