<bill session="110" type="h" number="5708" updated="2013-07-19T21:53:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Everglades National Park Boundary Adjustment Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To adjust the boundary of the Everglades National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="2804"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Everglades"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Sailing ships"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2008--Introduced.
Everglades National Park Boundary Adjustment Act of 2008 - Adjusts the boundary of the Everglades National Park in Florida to include the Tarpon Basin property comprising approximately 600 acres of land and water surrounding Tarpon Basin and located in South Key Largo. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire through a voluntary donation, sale, or exchange any land or interest in the Tarpon Basin property.Requires the lands and waters added to the Park by this Act to be administered as part of the Park. Authorizes the Secretary to issue a permit to any owner of a sailing vessel who had secured the sailing vessel in Hurricane Hole to protect it from a tropical storm or hurricane. Allows the inclusion in such a permit of any term or condition determined necessary to protect the Park's resources and to ensure the safety of the public in the Park.</summary>
</bill>
