<bill session="109" type="s" number="5" updated="2013-07-19T20:13:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Class Action Lawsuits bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Class Action Fairness Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Class Action Fairness Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Class Action Fairness Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Class Action Fairness Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Class Action Fairness Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the procedures that apply to consideration of interstate class actions to assure fairer outcomes for class members and defendants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300004" joined="2005-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2005-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2005-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2005-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="2005-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300045" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300050" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300069" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2005-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2005-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2005-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2005-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2005-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-02-03">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-02-03">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Specter without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-02-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-02-07">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S999-1009" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1076-1086, S1086-1110" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1150-1152, S1157-1189" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1225-1252" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2005-02-10" how="roll" result="pass" roll="9" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 72 - 26. Record Vote Number: 9.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1249-1252" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-02-14T12:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-14">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-14T15:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-15T19:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 96 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of S. 5 with 1 hour and 30 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-16T12:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 96 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17T10:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 96.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H723-755" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17T10:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of S. 5 with 1 hour and 30 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17T10:16:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour and thirty minutes of debate on S. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17T11:53:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 96, the House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the Conyers amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H743-746" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17T13:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Brown (OH) moved to commit with instructions to Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17T13:07:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brown (OH) motion to commit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House forthwith with amendments which provide that the term "class action" does not include any action arising by reason of the use of the drug Vioxx.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17T13:20:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to commit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17T13:37:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to commit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 175 - 249 (Roll no. 37).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H752-754" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-02-17T13:46:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="38" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 279 - 149 (Roll no. 38).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H723-726" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17T13:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-02-18">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-02-18" type="public" number="109-2">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-2.</text>
    </enacted>
    <action datetime="2005-02-28">
      <text>By Senator Specter from Committee on the Judiciary filed written report. Report No. 109-14. Additional and Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="109" type="hr" number="96"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank holding companies"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consent decrees"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Expert witnesses"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h11"/>
    <amendment number="s2"/>
    <amendment number="s3"/>
    <amendment number="s4"/>
    <amendment number="s5"/>
    <amendment number="s6"/>
    <amendment number="s7"/>
    <amendment number="s8"/>
    <amendment number="s9"/>
    <amendment number="s10"/>
    <amendment number="s11"/>
    <amendment number="s12"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>2/18/2005--Public Law.
Class Action Fairness Act of 2005 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Federal judicial code to specify the calculation of contingent and other attorney's fees in proposed class action settlements that provide for the award of coupons to class members. Prohibits a Federal district court from approving: (1) a proposed coupon settlement absent a finding that the settlement is fair, reasonable, and adequate; (2) a proposed settlement involving payments to class counsel that would result in a net monetary loss to class members, absent a finding that the loss is substantially outweighed by nonmonetary benefits; or (3) a proposed settlement that provides greater sums to some class members solely because they are closer geographically to the court. Specifies requirements for serving notices of proposed settlements on appropriate State and Federal officials. Prohibits issuance of an order giving final approval to a proposed settlement earlier than 90 days after such service. Allows class members to refuse compliance with settlement agreements or consent decrees absent notice. (Sec. 4) Grants district courts original jurisdiction of any civil action in which the matter in controversy exceeds $5 million, exclusive of interest and costs, and that is between citizens of different States, or citizens of a State and a foreign State or its citizens or subjects. Lists those factors pursuant to which a district court may, in the interests of justice and based on the totality of the circumstances, decline to exercise jurisdiction over a class action in which more than one-third but less than two-thirds of the members of the proposed plaintiff classes in the aggregate and the primary defendants are citizens of the State in which the action was originally filed, based on consideration of whether: (1) the claims involve matters of national or interstate interest; (2) the claims will be governed by laws of the State where the action was originally filed or by the laws of other States; (3) the class action has been pleaded in a manner that seeks to avoid Federal jurisdiction; (4) the action was brought in a forum with a distinct nexus with the class members, the alleged harm, or the defendants; (5) the number of citizens of the State of original filing in all proposed plaintiff classes in the aggregate is substantially larger than the number of citizens from any other State and the citizenship of other proposed class members is dispersed; and (6) during the three-year period preceding filing, one or more other class actions asserting the same or similar claims on behalf of the same persons have been filed. Specifies those circumstances in which a district court must decline jurisdiction, including those class actions in which: (1) more than two-thirds of the members of the proposed plaintiff classes in the aggregate are citizens of the State where the action was originally filed, at least one defendant is a defendant from whom significant relief is sought, whose alleged conduct forms a significant basis for the claims asserted, and who is a citizen of the State where the action was originally filed, and principal injuries resulting from the alleged or related conduct were incurred in such State; and (2) during the three-year period preceding filing, no other class action has been filed asserting the same or similar factual allegations against any of the defendants on behalf of the same or other persons; or (3) two-thirds or more of the members of all proposed plaintiff classes in the aggregate, and the primary defendants, are citizens of the State where the action was originally filed. Makes provisions of this Act concerning the application of Federal diversity jurisdiction applicable to any class action before or after entry of a class certification order. (Sec. 5) Sets forth provisions governing the removal of interstate class actions to Federal district court and the review on appeal of remand orders. (Sec. 6) Directs the Judicial Conference of the United States to report on class action settlements, incorporating recommendations for best court practices to ensure fairness for class members and appropriate fees for counsel. (Sec. 7) States that amendments to Federal Rule of Civil Procedure 23 (governing class actions) set forth in the Supreme Court order entered on March 27, 2003, shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act or on December 1, 2003, whichever occurs first. (Sec. 8) Retains the authority of the Supreme Court and Judicial Conference to propose and prescribe general rules of practice and procedure.</summary>
</bill>
