<bill session="112" type="h" number="4485" updated="2013-07-20T01:48:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Credible Military Option to Counter Iran Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To further the preparedness of the United States Armed Forces, in cooperation with regional allies, to prevent the Government of Iran from obtaining a nuclear weapon, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400655"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412413" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2012-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Azerbaijan"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Kuwait"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf States"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Arab Emirates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2012--Introduced.
Credible Military Option to Counter Iran Act - States that it shall be the policy of the United States to take all necessary measures, including military action if required, to prevent Iran from threatening the United States, its allies, or Iran's neighbors with a nuclear weapon. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) U.S. military exercises in the Persian Gulf emphasize U.S. resolve in support of the above policy; and (2) the President should require the U.S. military to develop a comprehensive plan to augment the presence of the U.S. Fifth Fleet in the Middle East and to conduct military deployments, exercises, or other military readiness activities to underscore such policy. Directs the Secretary of Defense to prepare and submit to the congressional defense committees such a plan. Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for FY2012-FY2013 to enhance U.S. military capabilities in the Central Command Area of responsibility (Middle East), including for procurement, research and development, and operation and maintenance. Expresses the sense of Congress in support of specified action to assist in the defense of Israel, including joint missile defense systems, defense articles, intelligence, defense services, and additional weaponry and munitions for the forward-deployed U.S. stockpile in Israel. Directs the President to report to Congress on the status of Israel's qualitative military edge in light of current trends and instability in the region. Directs the Secretary to develop and submit to Congress: (1) a plan to enhance the military capabilities of Persian Gulf allies to bolster their posture in relation to Iran, and (2) a plan to increase the strategic partnership with regional allies to provide U.S. Armed Forces with the broadest set of geographic approaches to militarily access Iran.</summary>
</bill>
