<bill session="111" type="s" number="569" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Incorporation Transparency and Law Enforcement Assistance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that persons who form corporations in the United States disclose the beneficial owners of those corporations, in order to prevent wrongdoers from exploiting United States corporations for criminal gain, to assist law enforcement in detecting, preventing, and punishing terrorism, money laundering, and other misconduct involving United States corporations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2009-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2009-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3026-3029"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3029-3030" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6098"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2009--Introduced.
Incorporation Transparency and Law Enforcement Assistance Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to: (1) establish uniform requirements for states relating to the disclosure of beneficial owners of corporations and limited liability companies formed in such states and the updating of such disclosures; (2) require states to maintain beneficial ownership disclosure information for five years after a corporation or limited liability company is terminated; (3) impose additional identification requirements for the beneficial owners of corporations or limited liability companies who are not U.S. citizens or lawful permanent residents of the United States; and (4) provide for additional civil and criminal penalties for individuals who provide false beneficial ownership information to a state. Defines "beneficial owner" as an individual who has a level of control over a business entity that enables such individual to control, manage, or direct such entity.Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to publish a proposed and final rule to require persons involved in forming a corporation, limited liability company, partnership, trust, or other legal entity to establish anti-money laundering programs. Requires the Comptroller General to study and report to the House Committee on Homeland Security and the Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs on: (1) state requirements for the disclosure of beneficial ownership information; (2) whether the lack of such information has impeded investigations into entities suspected of terrorism, money laundering, and other criminal activities; and (3) whether the failure to require beneficial ownership information for partnerships and trusts formed or registered in the United States has elicited international criticism and what steps the United States has taken or is planning to take in response.</summary>
</bill>
