<bill session="111" type="h" number="4224" updated="2013-07-19T23:50:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Together We Care Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a pilot program to train public housing residents as home health aides and in home-based health services to enable such residents to provide covered home-based health services to residents of public housing and residents of federally-assisted rental housing, who are elderly and disabled, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2010-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2010-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2010-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2010-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2009-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2009--Introduced.
Together We Care Act of 2009 - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish a pilot program to make grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities for the training of public housing residents as home health aides and providers of home-based health services to enable them to provide covered home-based health services (i.e., services for which medical assistance is available under a state Medicaid plan or for which financial assistance is available under this Act) to residents of: (1) public housing who are elderly or disabled, or both; and (2) federally-assisted rental housing who are elderly or disabled, or both, subject to criteria that the Secretary may establish.Authorizes the use of grant funds: (1) to establish or maintain and carry out a program to train public housing residents to provide covered home-based health care services to elderly and disabled public housing residents and to elderly and disabled residents of federally-assisted rental housing; (2) for the transportation and child care expenses of public housing residents in training; and (3) for the administrative expenses of carrying out such a program.Provides that for any resident of public housing who is trained as a home health aide or as a provider of home-based health services under the program, any income received for providing covered home-based health services shall apply towards eligibility for benefits under federal housing programs as specified, based on length of time following completion of the training.</summary>
</bill>
