<bill session="113" type="hc" number="9" updated="2013-11-02T06:48:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Govern Before Going Home Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Prohibiting the House or Senate from adjourning for a period of more than 5 days during a fiscal year unless the House involved has adopted a concurrent resolution on the budget for such fiscal year and has approved legislation to provide funding for the operations of the government for the entire fiscal year.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412483"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2013-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2013-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/2013--Introduced.
Govern Before Going Home Resolution - Prohibits the House of Representatives or Senate from adjourning for a period of more than five days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, except when the House or Senate is in session on such a day) during a fiscal year unless, at the time the period of adjournment begins, the House or Senate (as the case may be) has: adopted a concurrent resolution on the budget for such fiscal year; and approved each regular appropriation bill for such fiscal year or, to the extent that it has not approved such a bill, has approved a continuing resolution to provide funding for the entire fiscal year for the projects and activities covered by it.</summary>
</bill>
