<bill session="110" type="s" number="3676" updated="2013-07-19T22:53:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Volunteer Firefighter and EMS Support Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to support the recruitment and retention of volunteer firefighters and emergency medical services personnel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-10-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Life insurance"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2008--Introduced.
Volunteer Firefighter and EMS Support Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a program to provide funds to a state or local government, nonprofit firefighter association, or governmental or nongovernmental emergency medical services (EMS) organization, that carries out a volunteer firefighter incentive program in accordance with this Act.Directs the Secretary, for each fiscal year in which a state or local government, nonprofit firefighter association, or governmental or nongovernmental EMS organization carries out a volunteer firefighter incentive program, to pay such government, association, or organization (organization), out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated for such fiscal year, a sum equal to the total expenditures of funds not received from the federal government made by such organization for that fiscal year to carry out the program. Declares that this constitutes budget authority in advance of appropriations Acts and represents the obligation of the federal government to provide payment to a state or local government, nonprofit firefighter association, or governmental or nongovernmental EMS organization any amount so provided.Requires reports from recipients, and from the Secretary annually, to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
