<bill session="112" type="s" number="730" updated="2013-07-20T02:22:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Southeast Alaska Native Land Entitlement Finalization and Jobs Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the settlement of certain claims under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2011-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2135-2136"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2136-2138" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-131.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1408"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/5/2011--Introduced.
Southeast Alaska Native Land Entitlement Finalization and Jobs Protection Act - Authorizes Sealaska, the regional Alaska Native Corporation for southeast Alaska, subject to certain conditions and restrictions, to select and receive conveyance of its remaining land entitlement under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (ANCSA) from federal land in southeast Alaska that is outside the areas for selection delineated by the ANCSA. Includes in these lands certain sites: (1) identified on specified maps as having traditional, recreational, and renewable energy use value; and (2) identified by Sealaska as having sacred, cultural, traditional, or historic significance. Prohibits Sealaska from selecting: (1) sacred, cultural, traditional, or historic sites that are within the National Park System; or (2) land from the mapped sites, other than trade and migration route land, that lies within a conservation system unit. (A conservation system unit includes any unit of the National Park System, National Wildlife Refuge System, National Wild and Scenic Rivers Systems, National Trails System, National Wilderness Preservation System, or a National Forest Monument.) Amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act to designate specified lands within Tongass National Forest as conservation areas that are to be given Land Use Designation II status and managed by the Secretary of Agriculture to protect subsistence activities and unique biological and geological resources, and prohibit commercial timber harvests or new road construction.</summary>
</bill>
