<bill session="109" type="s" number="2403" updated="2013-07-19T20:34:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-12-07">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Grand Teton National Park Extension Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Grand Teton National Park Extension Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Grand Teton National Park Extension Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to include in the boundaries of the Grand Teton National Park land and interests in land of the GT Park Subdivision, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">An act to modify the boundaries of Grand Teton National Park to include certain land within the GT Park Subdivision, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2006-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-447.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 109-308.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-07-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="551">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 551.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-08-09">
      <text>Star Print ordered on on Report No. 109-308.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2006-12-07" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11537-11543" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11540" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-12-08T10:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-08T12:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land subdivision"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/7/2006--Passed Senate amended.
Grand Teton National Park Extension Act of 2006 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to: (1 ) accept from any willing seller the donation of any land or interest in land of the GT Park Subdivision; and (2) upon acquisition of land or an interest, include the land or interest in the boundaries of Grand Teton National Park and administer the land or interest as part of the Park. States that it is the intent of Congress that the acquisition of land or an interest in land be completed not later than one year after the enactment of this Act. Prohibits the Secretary from donating, selling, exchanging, or otherwise transferring any land acquired under this Act without express authorization from Congress. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
