<bill session="111" type="h" number="5692" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Americans Making Power Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to promote energy independence and self-sufficiency by providing for the use of net metering by certain small electric energy generation systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2010-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2895"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/2010--Introduced.
Americans Making Power Act - Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to require each state regulatory authority, and each nonregulated electric utility, to adopt the net metering standard established in this Act unless the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) determines that the net metering requirement in effect for such state complies with the federal standard. Establishes that net metering standard and related requirements. Requires retail electric suppliers to make net metering available to customer-generators on a first-come-first-served basis. Directs FERC to: (1) publish model standards for the physical connection between local distribution systems and qualified generation units; and (2) modify its Small Generator Interconnection Procedures to expedite permitting of qualified generation units up to 2,000 kilowatts Directs FERC to promulgate regulations to ensure that simplified contracts will be used for the interconnection of qualified generation units by a retail electric supplier or local distribution company</summary>
</bill>
