<bill session="111" type="sr" number="694" updated="2013-07-20T00:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution condemning the Government of Iran for its state-sponsored persecution of religious minorities in Iran and its continued violation of the International Covenant on Human Rights.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2010-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2010-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2010-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2010-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2010-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2010-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2010-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2010-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2010-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8477-8478" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2010--Introduced.
Condemns the government of Iran for its state-sponsored persecution of religious minorities and its continued violation of the International Covenants on Human Rights. Calls on the government of Iran to release the seven leaders of the Baha'i community and all other prisoners held solely on account of their religion, including Mrs. Fariba Kamalabadi, Mr. Jamaloddin Khanjani, Mr. Afif Naeimi, Mr. Saeid Rezaie, Mr. Behrouz Tavakkoli, Mrs. Mahvash Sabet, Mr. Vahid Tizfahm, Ms. Raha Sabet, Mr. Sasan Taqva, Ms. Haleh Roohi, and Ms Rozita Vaseghi. Calls on the President and Secretary of State, in cooperation with the international community, to continue to condemn the government of Iran's ongoing violation of human rights and demand the immediate release of these prisoners. Urges the President and Secretary to consider implementing further sanctions against officials directly responsible for human rights violations. Calls on the U.S. government to continue to support an annual U.N. General Assembly resolution condemning human rights violations in Iran. Calls for the restoration of the position of United Nations Special Rapporteur on the situation of human rights in Iran.</summary>
</bill>
