<bill session="113" type="hr" number="335" updated="2013-11-02T06:18:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To refer H.R. 3068, a bill making congressional reference to the United States Court of Federal Claims pursuant to sections 1492 and 2509 of title 28, United States Code, the Indian trust-related claims of the Grand Traverse Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians of Michigan as well as its individual members.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412436"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3068"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/2013--Introduced.
Refers the bill (H.R. 3068) entitled "Relating to members of the Grand Traverse Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians of Michigan" to the chief judge of the U.S. Court of Federal Claims for a determination as to whether the tribe and its members have Indian trust-related legal or equitable claims against the United States other than the legal claims pending in such Court on the date of enactment of this resolution. Directs the chief judge, notwithstanding any statute of limitations, to report back to the House of Representatives providing: (1) findings of fact and conclusions of law to inform Congress of the nature, extent, and character of the Indian-trust related claims of such Band and its tribal members for compensation in such legal or equitable claims against the United States; and (2) the amount, if any, legally or equitably due from the United States to such claimants.</summary>
</bill>
