<bill session="111" type="h" number="4966" updated="2013-07-19T23:57:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stored Value Device Registration and Reporting Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 5316 of title 31, United States Code, to establish a reporting requirement for any stored value device carried out of, into, or through the United States, to establish registration requirements for stored value device businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2010-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5127"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3175"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2010--Introduced.
Stored Value Device Registration and Reporting Act of 2010 - Treats as a financial institution subject to federal regulation any person engaged in the business of issuing stored value devices or processing transactions related to such devices, including accessing information pertaining to the funds stored on a device, retrieving such funds, or adding funds to be stored on the device. Treats such stored value devices as monetary instruments. Prescribes procedures for mandatory registration of such devices with the Secretary of the Treasury. Subjects to a civil penalty noncompliance with such requirement Instructs the Secretary to: (1) prescribe regulations establishing a threshold point under which small stored value device businesses are exempt from such registration requirements; and (2) study and report to Congress on specified uses of such devices, including the extent to which they are used to provide payments related to drug trafficking and human trafficking or financial support to terror cells operating within the United States.</summary>
</bill>
