<bill session="113" type="h" number="2723" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Embassy Security and Enhancement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance security for facilities and personnel at United States diplomatic and consular posts abroad, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412512" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412576" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412529" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412532" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412543" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412560" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412534" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2013-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2013--Introduced.
Embassy Security and Enhancement Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of State to: (1) submit to Congress a list of diplomatic and consular posts designated as high risk, high threat posts; and (2) determine if a post should be so designated before its opening or reopening. Directs the Secretary, before opening or reopening a high risk, high threat post, to establish a working group responsible for the geographic area in which such post is to be opened or reopened. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary should complete a strategic review of the Department of State's Bureau of Diplomatic Security to ensure that the Bureau is fulfilling Department needs. Authorizes FY2014 appropriations for the capital security cost sharing program. Expresses the sense of Congress that the program should prioritize the construction of new facilities and the maintenance of existing facilities at high risk, high threat posts. Authorizes the Secretary to transfer to, and merge with, any appropriation for embassy security, construction, and maintenance such amounts appropriated for any other purpose related to the administration of foreign affairs on or after October 1, 2013. Authorizes the Secretary to provide physical security enhancements at overseas educational facilities established for the children of U.S. government employees. Revises requirements for: (1) local guard contracts abroad, and (2) computation of the death gratuity payable to surviving dependents of Foreign Service employees who die from injuries sustained in the performance of duty abroad. Makes permanent the Secretary's authority to waive the annuity termination of a temporarily reemployed annuitant in a position for which there is exceptional difficulty in recruiting or retaining a qualified employee. Expresses the sense of Congress regarding: (1) application of the Overseas Security Policy Board's security standards to all facilities; and (2) assignment of key personnel at high risk, high threat posts. Requires security training for permanent or long-term personnel assigned to high risk, high threat posts. Urges that language training be provided for diplomatic security personnel assigned to permanent or long-term duty at high threat, high risk posts. Authorizes the Secretary to provide a group life insurance supplement for a Foreign Service employee who dies while on duty abroad as a result of a terrorist attack. Directs the Secretary to provide educational assistance to a widow, widower, familial designee, or child of any U.S. national Foreign Service employee who dies while on duty abroad as a result of a terrorist attack.</summary>
</bill>
