<bill session="113" type="s" number="1275" updated="2013-11-02T07:03:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REFI Pacific Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Revitalizing the Economy of Fisheries in the Pacific Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Commerce to issue a fishing capacity reduction loan to refinance the existing loan funding the Pacific Coast groundfish fishing capacity reduction program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2013-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2646"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2013--Introduced.
Revitalizing the Economy of Fisheries in the Pacific Act or the REFI Pacific Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce (upon receipt of such assurances as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States) to issue a loan to refinance the existing debt obligation funding the fishing capacity reduction program for the West Coast groundfish fishery implemented under the Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2003. Requires such loan to have a maturity that expires 45 years after the date of issuance. Permits the Secretary to extend the loan under specified conditions if there is an outstanding balance after such period. Prohibits the fee with respect to such loan from exceeding 3% of the ex-vessel value of the harvest from each fishery for which the loan is issued. Sets forth requirements for direct loan interest rates, subloans, and the calculation of the ex-vessel landing fee to be collected for payment of such loan.</summary>
</bill>
