<bill session="112" type="h" number="5882" updated="2013-07-20T02:00:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-08T12:01:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-06-08T12:01:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2013</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2013</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2013</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2013</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2013, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400086"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Legislative Branch. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-778.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-15">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Legislative Branch. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-778.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-22">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Legislative Branch. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-778.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-01T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-511, by Mr. Crenshaw.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-06-01T10:28:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="359">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 359.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T09:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 679.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3665-3690" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3671-3675" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T09:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 436 and H.R. 5882. General debate on H.R. 5882 will continue for not to exceed one hour, equally divided and controlled. Specified amendments to H.R. 5882 are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T09:15:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 679 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T09:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Charles F. Bass to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T09:15:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 5882.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T09:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions H. Res. 679, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T09:49:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T09:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions H. Res. 679, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Broun (GA) amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T09:58:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Broun (GA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Honda demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T09:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions H. Res. 679, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Holt amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T10:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions H. Res. 679, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Scalise amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T10:19:00-04:00">
      <text>POSPTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Scalise amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Scalise demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T10:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions H. Res. 679, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moran amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T10:30:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Moran amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Dan Lungren (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T10:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions H. Res. 679, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Harper amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T10:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions H. Res. 679, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T10:46:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Crenshaw demanded a recorded vote and the Chair post poned further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T10:46:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T11:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 5882.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T11:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3688" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T11:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T11:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Pingree (ME) moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3688-3689" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3688" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T11:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pingree motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to reduce funds available for the Members' Representational Allowances, including Members' clerk hire, official expenses, and official mail, by $3,099,244.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T11:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3689" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 101 - 309 (Roll no. 376).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-06-08T12:01:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="377" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 307 - 102 (Roll no. 377).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported by Senator Nelson NE, with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 112-197.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-08-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="466">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 466.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSAP08" subcommittee="Legislative Branch" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="679"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Architect of the Capitol"/>
    <term name="Books and print media"/>
    <term name="Congressional Budget Office (CBO)"/>
    <term name="Congressional Research Service (CRS)"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional leadership"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government Printing Office (GPO)"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Appropriations"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Joint Committee on Taxation"/>
    <term name="Joint Economic Committee"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="U.S. Capitol"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1278"/>
    <amendment number="h1279"/>
    <amendment number="h1280"/>
    <amendment number="h1281"/>
    <amendment number="h1282"/>
    <amendment number="h1283"/>
    <amendment number="h1284"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Reported to Senate amended.
Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2013 - Title I: Legislative Branch - Makes appropriations to the Senate for FY2013 for: (1) expense allowances; (2) representation allowances for the Majority and Minority Leaders; (3) salaries of specified officers, employees, and committees (including the Committee on Appropriations); (4) agency contributions for employee benefits; (5) inquiries and investigations; (6) the U.S. Senate Caucus on International Narcotics Control; (7) the Offices of the Secretary and of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate; (8) miscellaneous items; (9) the Senators' Official Personnel and Office Expense Account; and (10) official mail costs. Makes appropriations to the House of Representatives for FY2013 for: (1) salaries and/or expenses of the House leadership offices, committees (including the Committee on Appropriations), officers and employees; and (2) Members' representational allowances. (Sec. 101) Requires deposit in the Treasury of any amounts of a Member's representational allowance remaining after all payments are made, to be used for federal deficit reduction, or, if there is no deficit, federal debt reduction. (Sec. 102) Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1998 to require reimbursement to the Secretary of Labor for unemployment compensation payments to former House employees out of the House account for making payments to the Employees' Compensation Fund. (Sec. 103) Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1993, with respect to authorized transfer of amounts appropriated for any fiscal year among specified headings, to add "Joint Items" (to the extent that amounts appropriated to a joint committee are disbursed by the House Chief Administrative Officer) and "Office of the Attending Physician" to the current list consisting of "House Leadership Offices," "Members' Representational Allowances," "Committee Employees," "Salaries, Officers, and Employees," and "Allowances and Expenses." (Sec. 104) Requires the House Office of the Inspector General (IG) to: (1) provide the House Committee on Appropriations with a copy of each produced IG audit and investigative report, and (2) consult regularly with the Committee with respect to the Office's operations. Makes FY2013 appropriations for salaries and/or expenses of: (1) the Joint Economic Committee and the Joint Committee on Taxation; (2) the Office of the Attending Physician; (3) the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services; (4) the Capitol Police; (5) the Office of Compliance; (6) the Congressional Budget Office (CBO); and (7) the Architect of the Capitol (AOC), including for the care and operation of Capitol buildings and grounds, Senate office buildings, House office buildings, the Capitol power plant, the Library of Congress buildings and grounds, the Capitol Police buildings, grounds, and security, the Botanic Garden, and the Capitol Visitor Center. (Sec. 1102) Makes balances of expired U.S. Capitol Police appropriations available to the Capitol Police for deposit to the credit of the mandatory Employees' Compensation Fund. Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2003 to eliminate the separate Capitol Police account for making worker's compensation payments to Capitol Police employees. (Sec. 1201) Makes balances of expired AOC appropriations available to the AOC for deposit to the credit of the mandatory Employees' Compensation Fund. Appropriates FY2013 funds to: (1) the Library of Congress for salaries and expenses, the Copyright Office, the Congressional Research Service (CRS), and Books for the Blind and Physically Handicapped; (2) the Government Printing Office (GPO) for congressional printing and binding (including transfer of funds); (3) the GPO for the Office of Superintendent of Documents (including transfer of funds); (4) the GPO Revolving Fund; (5) Government Accountability Office (GAO) for salaries and expenses; (6) the Open World Leadership Center Trust Fund; and (7) the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Development Trust Fund. (Sec. 1301) Establishes an upper limit of $178.958 million for the FY2013 obligational authority of the Library of Congress with regard to certain reimbursable and revolving fund activities. Authorizes the Librarian of Congress to transfer temporarily up to $1.9 million of funds appropriated in this Act for Library of Congress salaries and expenses to the revolving fund for the FEDLINK Program and the Federal Research Program. (Sec. 1302) Authorizes the transfer of FY2013 Library of Congress appropriations between any subheading under the heading "Library of Congress," up to 10% per category, upon the approval of the congressional appropriations committees. (Sec. 1303) Amends the Library of Congress Fiscal Operations Improvement Act of 2000 to modify the use of the revolving fund for duplication and delivery services associated with the national audiovisual conservation center to include preservation and storage of audiovisual materials and associated collections. Renames the revolving fund established for the Library's gift shop, decimal classification, photo duplication, and related services as the revolving fund for the Library's sales shop and other services. Adds traveling exhibitions, exhibition materials, and training to the authorized uses of the revolving fund. (Sec. 1304) States that nothing shall be construed as prohibiting or restricting the Librarian of Congress from accepting non-personal services and voluntary and uncompensated personal services (as well as, under current law, gifts or bequests of money) for immediate disbursement in the interest of the Library, its collections, or its service. Prescribes reporting requirements for the Librarian regarding such gifts or bequests. (Sec. 1305) Modifies requirements for the use of appropriations to the Library of Congress for the purchase of books and sound-reproduction records for blind and other physically handicapped U.S. residents to change the terminology used to identify such individuals as "residents or persons with disabilities." Limits the lending of such books, recordings, reproducers, musical scores, instructional texts, and other specialized materials by the Library's local or regional centers to blind and other U.S. residents with disabilities (including the several States, Territories, insular possessions, and the District of Columbia). (Sec. 1401) Makes balances of expired GAO appropriations available to GAO for deposit to the credit of the mandatory Employees' Compensation Fund. Title II: General Provisions - Specifies authorized and prohibited uses of funds appropriated by this Act identical or similar to corresponding provisions of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2012. (Sec. 207) Authorizes the AOC to maintain and improve the landscape features, excluding streets, in specified grassy areas of Washington, DC, SW. (Sec. 209) Prohibits the use of funds made available to the AOC in this Act to eliminate or restrict guided tours of the U.S. Capitol led by congressional employees and interns. Allows temporary suspension or restriction of such tours for security or related reasons to the same extent as guided tours of the U.S. Capitol led by the AOC. (Sec. 210) Adds to the Capitol Grounds certain property (defined in this Act as Union Square), including any monument or other facility located within such area, which was transferred to AOC jurisdiction and control under title I of division G of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2012 (CAA, 2012). Authorizes the Capitol Police to: (1) issue a permit authorizing a person to engage in commercial activity in Union Square in a manner that does not interfere with Congress; (2) establish and collect permit application fees; and (3) establish and collect other fees for the use of Union Square, all Capitol Police or AOC costs incurred resulting from such use, and costs to monitor the permitted activity. Establishes a Union Square Commercial Account in the Treasury consisting of all such fees, to be made available, without fiscal year limitations or further appropriation, for disbursement by the Capitol Police to defray expenses associated with Union Square and to reimburse the AOC for costs incurred relating to its use. Requires the Capitol Police Board, subject to congressional approval, to promulgate regulations for commercial use of Union Square which shall: (1) describe the types of commercial activity authorized (which shall be substantially similar to the types permitted in Union Square on the day before enactment of CAA, 2012); and (2) provide for payment of fees and costs substantially similar to those collected by the National Park Service (NPS) on the day before such enactment. States that nothing in this Act or in CCA, 2012 shall be be construed to affect any permit for engaging in commercial activity in Union which was issued by the NPS before enactment of CAA, 2012.</summary>
</bill>
