<bill session="112" type="s" number="206" updated="2013-07-20T02:18:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SOAR Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize the DC Opportunity Scholarship Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2011-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2011-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2011-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-01-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S283"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S283-287" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-16">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-195.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="471"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2011--Introduced.
Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act 2011or SOAR Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award five-year grants on a competitive basis to nonprofit organizations to carry out a program to provide expanded school choice opportunities to students who are District of Columbia (DC) residents and who come from households: (1) receiving assistance under the supplemental nutrition assistance program under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008; or (2) with incomes not exceeding 185% of the poverty line, except in certain grandfathered circumstances. Prescribes special rules for funding opportunity scholarships for DC students. Prescribes requirements for schools participating in such grant programs. Requires each participating school to administer a nationally norm-referenced standardized test in reading and mathematics to each enrolled student receiving an opportunity scholarship. Repeals the DC School Choice Incentive Act of 2003 (title III of division C of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2004). Deems this Act as the reauthorization of the opportunity scholarship program under such Act.</summary>
</bill>
