<bill session="113" type="h" number="550" updated="2013-11-02T06:23:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Phantom Fuel Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the renewable fuel program under section 211(o) of the Clean Air Act to require the cellulosic biofuel requirement to be based on actual production.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412280"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2013-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1462"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="251"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2013--Introduced.
Phantom Fuel Reform Act of 2013 - Amends the Clean Air Act to revise the renewable fuel program by requiring the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, in estimating the projected volume of cellulosic biofuel to be sold or introduced into commerce in the next year, to determine for each facility producing such biofuel during the current year: (1) the average monthly volume of biofuel produced by such facility based on the actual volume produced through October 31, and (2) the estimated annualized volume of biofuel production for such facility for the current year based on such average monthly production. Requires the estimate of cellulosic biofuel projected to be sold or introduced into commerce in the following year to equal the total of the estimated annual volumes of cellulosic biofuel production for all such facilities. Requires (currently, authorizes) the Administrator, in any year in which the Administrator reduces the applicable volume of cellulosic biofuel required in gasoline, to also reduce the applicable volume of renewable fuel and advanced biofuels required by the same (currently, by the same or a lesser) volume.</summary>
</bill>
