<bill session="110" type="hr" number="763" updated="2013-07-19T20:57:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-23T16:40:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-10-23T16:40:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1011) to designate additional National Forest System lands in the State of Virginia as wilderness or a wilderness study area, to designate the Kimberling Creek Potential Wilderness Area for eventual incorporation in the Kimberling Creek Wilderness, to establish the Seng Mountain and Bear Creek Scenic Areas, to provide for the development of trail plans for the wilderness areas and scenic areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400065"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22T18:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-403, by Mr. Cardoza.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22T18:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1011 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-10-22T19:01:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="137">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 137.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-10-23T15:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11888-11894" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-23T15:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 763.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-23T15:51:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 763, the Chair put the question of ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Sessions demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-23T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11897-11898" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-23T16:40:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 225 - 190 (Roll no. 990).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11894, H11897-11898" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2007-10-23T16:40:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11888" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-10-23T16:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="110" type="h" number="1011"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/2007--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 1011 (Virginia Ridge and Valley Act of 2007).</summary>
</bill>
