<bill session="112" type="h" number="1869" updated="2013-07-20T01:26:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lifelong Learning Accounts Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish lifelong learning accounts to provide an incentive for employees to save for career-related skills development and to promote a competitive workforce through lifelong learning.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400233"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2011-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2011--Introduced.
Lifelong Learning Accounts Act of 2011 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) establish tax-exempt lifelong learning accounts to pay certain educational expenses, including tuition, fees, books, supplies, and information technology devices required for the education of, or courses of instruction of, the account beneficiary; (2) allow individuals between ages 18 and 71 an income-based tax credit for cash contributions to their lifelong learning accounts; (3) exclude from employee gross income employer contributions to a lifelong learning account; and (4) allow employers a tax credit for contributions made to the lifelong learning accounts of their employees and for administrative costs associated with small employer lifelong learning accounts.</summary>
</bill>
