<bill session="112" type="h" number="5807" updated="2013-07-20T02:00:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FEMA Regional Office Oversight Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require an audit of the extent to which regional FEMA offices are able to support coordinated and integrated Federal preparedness, protection, response, recovery, and mitigation capabilities to respond to an act of terrorism or other incident, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response and Communications.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM12" subcommittee="Emergency Preparedness, Response, and Communications" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2012--Introduced.
FEMA Regional Office Oversight Act - Directs the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to audit how all regional offices within the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) are carrying out delegated authorities pursuant to the Post-Katrina Emergency Management and Reform Act of 2006 and a memorandum executed in July 2009 by the FEMA Administrator. Requires the audit to assess: (1) the ability of each regional office to support federal preparedness, protection, response, recovery, and mitigation capabilities to respond to an act of terrorism, to foster better regional emergency communications capabilities, to oversee the use of funding to promote preparedness and response capabilities, to coordinate with state, local, and tribal governments and emergency response providers on regional priorities, to identify critical gaps in regional capabilities to respond to populations with special needs, to conduct all procurements in a timely and secure manner that prevents waste and fraud, and to engage in employment practices that are transparent, efficient, and ethical; (2) the impact of the delegation of authorities on the Administrator's ability to achieve consistency throughout the regions; (3) the adequacy of oversight by the Administrator of how the regions are executing the delegated authorities and carrying out assigned responsibilities; and (4) the impact of the delegation of authorities on FEMA and specific regions to address Office of Inspector General and Comptroller General (GAO) recommendations in a timely manner.</summary>
</bill>
