<bill session="109" type="s" number="956" updated="2013-07-19T20:21:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Jetseta Gage Prevention and Deterrence of Crimes Against Children Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to provide assured punishment for violent crimes against children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2005-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2005-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2005-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4569-4570"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4570-4571" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8021"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2318"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2388"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2005--Introduced.
Jetseta Gage Prevention and Deterrence of Crimes Against Children Act of 2005 - Rewrites provisions of the federal criminal code regarding penalties for crimes against children to require a person convicted of a federal crime of violence against an individual under age 15 to be sentenced to: (1) death or life imprisonment if the crime results in the death of the victim; (2) life or at least 30 years imprisonment if the crime is a kidnaping, sexual assault, or maiming or results in serious bodily injury; (3) life or at least 14 years imprisonment if the crime results in bodily injury to a person under age 12; (4) life or at least ten years imprisonment if a dangerous weapon was used during and in relation to the crime; and (5) life or at least two years imprisonment in any other case. Increases penalties for sexual abuse of children, sexual exploitation and other abuse of children, and conduct relating to child prostitution. Christy Ann Fornoff Act - Denies a court, justice, or judge jurisdiction to consider claims relating to the judgment or sentence in an application for writ of habeas corpus on behalf of a person in custody pursuant to the judgment of a state court for a crime that involved the killing of a person under age 18. Sets timetables for proceedings. Extends certain rights associated with habeas corpus proceedings to victims of the state offense at issue. Makes this Act applicable to pending cases.</summary>
</bill>
