<bill session="113" type="s" number="1086" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize and improve the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2013-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2013-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3908-3909"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="624"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Allergies"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2013--Introduced.
Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 2013 - Reauthorizes the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 through FY2019. Revises the Act to allow a joint interagency office, designated by the governor, to serve as the lead agency for a state desiring to receive a community services programs child care and development block grant. Increases from two to three years the period that must be covered by a state child care and development plan. Revises and expands plan requirements to include, among others, compliance with state and local health and safety requirements, compliance with child abuse reporting requirements, protection for working parents, and coordination with other programs. Prescribes early learning and developmental guidelines. Authorizes a state to use funds to establish or support a system of local or regional child care resource and referral organizations. Requires a state receiving funds under such Act to carry out at least two of specified activities affecting the quality of child care. Requires states receiving grant funds under such Act to carry out criminal background checks for child care staff members of child care providers. Makes ineligible for employment by a licensed, regulated, or registered child care provider any individual who: (1) refuses to consent to a criminal background check, (2) knowingly makes a materially false statement in connection with such a background check, (3) is registered or is required to be registered on a state sex offender registry or the National Sex Offender Registry, or (4) has been convicted of one or more specified felonies. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to operate a national toll-free hotline and website. Defines "child with a disability" as one under age 13 who is eligible for early intervention services under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</summary>
</bill>
