<bill session="112" type="s" number="3405" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Small Business Protection Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to treat small businesses bequeathed to spouses and dependents by members of the Armed Forces killed in line of duty as small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans for purposes of Department of Veterans Affairs contracting goals and preferences, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2012-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2012-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5213-5214"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6563"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3555"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2012--Introduced.
Veterans Small Business Protection Act of 2012 - Treats a small business acquired by the surviving spouse or dependent from a member of the Armed Forces killed during active duty as a small business owned and controlled by a service-disabled veteran, for purposes of Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) small business contracting goals and preferences. Continues such treatment for the period beginning on the date of the member's death and ending on the earlier of: (1) the date on which the surviving spouse remarries or relinquishes such ownership interest or ten years after the member's death, or (2) the date on which the surviving dependent relinquishes such ownership interest or ten years after the member's death.</summary>
</bill>
