<bill session="112" type="s" number="1098" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family and Retirement Health Investment Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve access to health care through expanded health savings accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2010"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3682"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
Family and Retirement Health Investment Act of 2011 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to health savings accounts (HSAs), to allow: (1) both spouses to make increased catch-up contributions to the same HSA; (2) Medicare Part A beneficiaries to establish and contribute to an HSA; (3) veterans eligible for service-connected disability benefits and individuals eligible for Indian health service assistance to establish an HSA; (4) individuals eligible to receive benefits under certain TRICARE plans to establish an HSA; (5) a carryforward of unused benefits, up to $500, in a flexible spending arrangement; (6) payments from an HSA for prescription and over-the-counter medicine or drugs; (7) the use of HSAs to purchase certain health insurance coverage and long-term care insurance; and (8) payment of certain medical expenses incurred before the establishment of an HSA. Amends the bankruptcy code to treat HSAs as tax-exempt individual retirement accounts (IRAs) for purposes of exempting them from creditor claims. Reauthorizes the use of Medicaid health opportunity accounts. Treats as medical care for purposes of the tax deduction for medical expenses certain exercise equipment and physical fitness programs, nutritional and dietary supplements, and periodic fees paid to a primary physician, physician assistant, or nurse practitioner. Repeals provisions of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act that impose annual limitations on deductibles for health plans offered in the small group market.</summary>
</bill>
