<bill session="109" type="h" number="4307" updated="2013-07-19T19:42:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Illegal Border Crossers Reporting Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to annually compile data relating to unauthorized aliens who cross the borders into the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400341"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2005-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2005-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Mexicans"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/2005--Introduced.
The Illegal Border Crossers Reporting Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to annually compile data on the following categories of information: (1) the number of unauthorized aliens who require medical care taken into custody by Border Patrol officials; (2) the number of unauthorized aliens with serious injuries or medical conditions Border Patrol officials refer to local hospitals or other health facilities; (3) the number of unauthorized aliens with serious injuries or medical conditions who arrive at U.S. ports of entry and subsequently are admitted into the United States for emergency medical care; (4) the number of unauthorized aliens described in clauses (2) and (3) who subsequently are taken into Department of Homeland Security (DHS) custody; and (5) a breakdown of the number of Mexicans and Other Than Mexicans described in clauses (1) through (3).</summary>
</bill>
