<bill session="111" type="h" number="1266" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Non-Foreign AREA Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Non-Foreign Area Retirement Equity Assurance Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for retirement equity for Federal employees in nonforeign areas outside the 48 contiguous States and the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2009-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="507"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2009--Introduced.
Non-Foreign Area Retirement Equity Assurance Act of 2009 or the Non-Foreign AREA Act of 2009 - Revises federal employee locality-based comparability payments provisions to include U.S. territories and possessions, including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, within a pay locality. Sets forth maximum rates of pay for Senior Executive Service (SES) personnel in such areas. Revises the calculation of allowances based on living costs and conditions of environment for pay of employees stationed outside the continental United States or in Alaska to apply it only to areas designated as of December 31, 2009. Provides a formula for adjustment of such rate using a transition schedule for calendar years 2010-2012. Requires adjustment of special rates of pay determined to be necessary to obtain or retain the services of persons specified by statute in such a cost-of-living area in accordance with regulations to be prescribed by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) under this Act. Allows a temporarily raised limitation on the amount of special rates during the transition period of January 1, 2010, to January 1, 2012. Expresses the sense of the Congress with respect to pay disparities and locality areas for federal positions located in Alaska, Hawaii, or a U.S. territory. Defines "covered employees" for purposes of this Act, including employees who were eligible, before enactment, to be paid a cost-of-living allowance (COLA) but not a locality-based comparability payment. Describes application of this Act to postal employees. Allows an employee subject to this Act's transition schedule who retires from service during the period from January 1, 2010, through December 31, 2012, to elect to have any COLA paid during that period considered as basic pay for purposes of annuity computation.</summary>
</bill>
