<bill session="111" type="s" number="1641" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to modify and waive certain requirements under title 23, United States Code, to assist States with a high unemployment rate in carrying out Federal-aid highway construction projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2009-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3313"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3313"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/2009--Introduced.
Increases the federal share of federal-aid highway construction projects for FY2011 and FY2012 for any state with an unemployment rate equal to or exceeding 11% at any time during FY2009 and FY2010. Increases the federal share of costs for FY2011-FY2012: (1) from 90% to 95% for Interstate System projects; and (2) from 80% to 85% for other transportation projects. Suspends certain eligibility requirements with respect to the use of tolls as a credit toward the non-federal share of project costs in such states for those fiscal years. Makes eligible for use as such a credit for such fiscal years any tolls that were not previously eligible. Suspends, as well, certain state transportation capital expenditure maintenance of effort requirements during FY2011-FY2012.</summary>
</bill>
