<bill session="109" type="s" number="1936" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hurricanes Katrina and Rita Flood Insurance Buy-In Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to strengthen the national flood insurance program, encourage participation in the program, and provide owners of properties not located in flood hazard zones a one-time opportunity to purchase flood insurance coverage for a period covering such hurricane.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300069"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3922"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/27/2005--Introduced.
Hurricanes Katrina and Rita Flood Insurance Buy-In Act of 2005 - Establishes a temporary flood insurance buy-in program. Instructs the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to make flood insurance coverage available under such program for eligible structures (but not their contents) for flooding resulting from Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita. Limits eligibility to structures located in an area not subject to the mandatory purchase requirements of the national flood insurance program, and which were not covered by such insurance at the time of the hurricanes. Prescribes a formula for determination of premiums, which may be paid by deduction from the amount of any claims payable under coverage by the buy-in program.</summary>
</bill>
