<bill session="110" type="h" number="6239" updated="2013-07-19T21:58:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">NCLB Recess Until Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to suspend temporarily the process of identifying schools and local educational agencies as in need of improvement and of imposing sanctions on such schools and local educational agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412210" joined="2008-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400345" joined="2008-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2008-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2008-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2008--Introduced.
NCLB Recess Until Reauthorization Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to suspend, during the 2008-2009 school year, new identifications of schools or local educational agencies as needing: (1) improvement, after they fail to make adequate yearly progress (AYP) toward state academic performance standards for two consecutive years; (2) corrective action, after they fail to make AYP for an additional two years after being identified as needing improvement; or (3) restructuring, after they fail to make AYP after a year of corrective action. Lifts such suspension on the earlier of the last day of the 2008-2009 school year or the authorization of FY2009 appropriations for title I (Improving the Academic Achievement of the Disadvantaged) of the Act.</summary>
</bill>
