<bill session="113" type="s" number="935" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quicker Veterans Benefits Delivery Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to prohibit the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from requesting additional medical examinations of veterans who have submitted sufficient medical evidence provided by non-Department medical professionals and to improve the efficiency of processing certain claims for disability compensation by veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412378"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-12">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1980"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2013--Introduced.
Quicker Veterans Benefits Delivery Act of 2013 - Prohibits the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA), during the six-year period after the enactment of this Act, from requesting a medical examination in connection with a claim for veterans' disability compensation when the claimant submits medical evidence provided by a non-VA medical professional that is competent, credible, probative, and otherwise adequate for making a claim decision. Requires the Secretary, during the same period: (1) to assign a prestabilization disability rating of total, 50%, or 30%, as appropriate; (2) to provide temporary minimum disability ratings for veterans not assigned a permanent rating; and (3) to not count any veteran assigned a prestabilization or temporary minimum rating under any backlog of unassigned ratings. Authorizes the Secretary, during the same period, to certify benefit payments by mail or account deposit before the first day of the month for which such payments are due.</summary>
</bill>
