<bill session="109" type="h" number="620" updated="2013-07-19T19:09:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Security Measures Feasibility Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on the development and implementation by States of security measures for driver's licenses and identification cards and a study on the consequences of denying driver's licenses to aliens unlawfully present in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2005-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Entitlements"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2005--Introduced.
Security Measures Feasibility Act - Requires the Comptroller General to conduct a study evaluating: (1) the ability of the States to develop and implement specified security measures (including the incorporation of anti-fraud features, the use of uniform machine-readable technology, and implementation of a social security number confirmation system) for the issuance and use of driver's licenses and identification cards; (2) the cost of developing and implementing each such measure for each State; and (3) the amount of time that such development and implementation would require for each State. Directs the Comptroller General to conduct a study of the potential adverse consequences of preventing aliens unlawfully present in the United States from obtaining driver's licenses. Requires the Comptroller General to report findings of both studies to appropriate congressional committees and to the Secretary of Homeland Security, incorporating any recommendations for administrative or legislative action.</summary>
</bill>
