<bill session="112" type="h" number="3602" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Spouse Equity Election Clarification Amendment Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide that an employee or Member who dies within the 2-year notification period with respect to a survivor annuity shall be presumed to have elected to provide a former spouse with such an annuity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-07">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-07">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/7/2011--Introduced.
Spouse Equity Election Clarification Amendment Act of 2011 - Provides that a federal employee or Member of Congress who dies before the expiration of the two-year period for electing to provide a former spouse with an annuity benefit under the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) or the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) shall be deemed to have elected to provide such benefit to such former spouse. Requires a former spouse to notify the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) within six months of the death of the employee or Member under whom an annuity benefit may be allowed.</summary>
</bill>
