<bill session="111" type="s" number="3151" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhancing Quality Assistance and Leadership and Improving Transparency for Women Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">EQUALITY Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Office for Global Women's Issues and the Women's Development Advisor to facilitate interagency coordination and the integration of gender considerations into the strategies, programming, and associated outcomes of the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2010-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2010-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2010--Introduced.
Enhancing Quality Assistance and Leadership and Improving Transparency for Women Act or the EQUALITY Act - Establishes in the Office of the Secretary of State the Office for Global Women's Issues which shall be headed by an Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women's Issues. Establishes in the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) the Women's Development Advisor who shall coordinate USAID efforts to integrate gender in foreign assistance design, strategy, and programs. Directs the Comptroller General of the United States to report to Congress regarding U.S. government financial assistance to further international economic, social, and legal development for women and girls.</summary>
</bill>
