<bill session="113" type="hj" number="89" updated="2013-11-02T06:48:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-08T19:49:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-08T19:49:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Federal worker pay fairness bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Deficit Reduction and Economic Growth Working Group Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Excepted Employees' Pay Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Deficit Reduction and Economic Growth Working Group Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Excepted Employees' Pay Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the salaries and related expenses of certain Federal employees during a lapse in funding authority for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">Making appropriations for the salaries and related expenses of certain Federal employees during a lapse in funding authority for fiscal year 2014, to establish a bicameral working group on deficit reduction and economic growth, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400340"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 373.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6384-6389" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 373, the House proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 89.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6389" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T18:14:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on adoption of the Joint Resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Crenshaw demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Joint Resolution until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6397-6398" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="535" datetime="2013-10-08T19:49:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 420 - 0 (Roll no. 535).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6385" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-08T19:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="214">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 214.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="373"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3273"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2013--Passed House without amendment.
Excepted Employees' Pay Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 - Makes appropriations for FY2014 to pay the salaries and related expenses of federal employees excepted from provisions of the Antideficiency Act (prohibiting any expenditure or obligation that exceeds an amount available in an appropriation or other fund) who work during the period beginning October 1, 2013, and ending December 15, 2013. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to report to the congressional Appropriations Committees specifying the use of funds made available to the executive branch by this joint resolution. Expresses the sense of Congress that this joint resolution may be referred to as the Federal Worker Pay Fairness Act. Deficit Reduction and Economic Growth Working Group Act of 2013 - Establishes the Bicameral Working Group on Deficit Reduction and Economic Growth, comprised of 20 Members of Congress, to recommend to the House of Representatives and Senate overall levels of discretionary spending, including for FY2014, changes in the statutory limit on the public debt, and reforms in direct spending programs. Directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Majority Leader of the Senate to each appoint 10 members of their respective chamber to serve on the Working Group. Designates a co-chair in each chamber and allows the Minority Leaders of the House and Senate to each recommend the appointment of 4 of the 10 members in each chamber. Requires the Working Group to report its recommendations, including any required legislative language, to the House and Senate within three days after their adoption. Prohibits the Working Group from reporting any recommendation that does not receive the support of a majority of its members. Requires the termination of the Working Group immediately after the transmission of its recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
