<bill session="112" type="s" number="1708" updated="2013-07-20T02:31:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Historical Park Establishment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Historical Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412384" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-10-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6512-6513"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6513" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-401.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3191"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/2011--Introduced.
John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Historical Park Establishment Act - Establishes the John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Historical Park in the states of Massachusetts and Rhode Island as a unit of the National Park System. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, through the National Park Service (NPS), to prepare a general management plan for the Park. Requires the plan to consider ways for using pre-existing or planned visitor facilities and recreational opportunities developed in the John. H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into cooperative agreements with the states, political subdivisions of the states, nonprofits (including Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor, Inc.), and private property owners to provide technical assistance and interpretation in the Park and Corridor; and (2) provide financial assistance on a matching basis for activities to protect the Corridor's resources.</summary>
</bill>
