<bill session="113" type="s" number="872" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Holding Company Registration Threshold Equalization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, to make the shareholder threshold for registration of savings and loan holding companies the same as for bank holding companies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400408"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2013-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="801"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="798"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2013--Introduced.
Holding Company Registration Threshold Equalization Act of 2013 - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require an issuer that is a savings and loan holding company to register with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) if: (1) its assets exceed $10 million, and (2) it has a class of equity security held of record by 2,000 or more persons. Requires termination of such registration after a savings and loan holding company certifies that its holders of record of such class of security has been reduced to fewer than 1,200 persons. Suspends automatically the duty of a savings and loan holding company to file supplementary and periodic information if the securities of each class to which the registration statement relates (other than any class of asset-backed securities) are held of record by fewer than 1,200 persons.</summary>
</bill>
