<bill session="112" type="s" number="3498" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Syria Humanitarian Support and Democratic Transition Assistance Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide humanitarian assistance and support a democratic transition in Syria, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2012-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5984-5986" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Jordan"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2012--Introduced.
Syria Humanitarian Support and Democratic Transition Assistance Act of 2012 - Directs the President to appoint a Special Envoy for Syria to coordinate U.S. engagement with the country and to ensure U.S. support for efforts to bring about a democratic transition in Syria. Urges the President to: (1) support humanitarian activities taking place in and outside Syria, (2) support efforts for a peaceful resolution of the conflict in Syria, and (3) contribute to future capacity building for governing institutions after a political transition takes place in Syria. Urges: (1) the allocation of funding for bilateral assistance programs in Syria; and (2) the United States to work with other donor nations to increase international contributions for the people of Syria; (3) the President to increase bilateral funding to countries, including Iraq, Jordan, Turkey, and Lebanon, that have experienced an influx of Syrian refugees; and (4) the United States to work with regional partners to secure conventional and unconventional weapons stockpiles in Syria and prevent their illicit sale or transfer out of Syria. Directs the President to instruct the Secretary of State to work with the appropriate United Nations (U.N.) agencies, regional organizations, nongovernmental organizations, and the broader international community to establish an international donors group to provide humanitarian assistance for the people of Syria.</summary>
</bill>
