<bill session="113" type="h" number="1607" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Livestock Disaster Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to extend certain supplemental agricultural disaster assistance programs to cover fiscal years 2012 through 2018, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412475"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2013-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG16" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities and Risk Management" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1947"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="954"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2013--Introduced.
Livestock Disaster Protection Act - Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to make FY2012-FY2018 livestock indemnity payments (at 75% of market value) to eligible producers on farms that have incurred livestock death losses in excess of the normal mortality due to: (1) attacks by animals reintroduced into the wild by the federal government or protected by federal law, including wolves and avian predators; or (2) adverse weather, including losses due to hurricanes, floods, blizzards, extreme heat, disease, or wildfires. Provides FY2012-FY2018 compensation for losses to eligible livestock producers for livestock grazing losses due to specified drought or fire circumstances. Excludes from coverage grazing losses on conservation reserve program land used for haying or grazing. Provides FY2012-FY2018 emergency relief to eligible producers of livestock, honeybees, and farm-raised fish to reduce losses due to disease, adverse weather, or other conditions, such as blizzards and wildfires.</summary>
</bill>
