<bill session="112" type="s" number="2022" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">CINCH Demonstration Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Integrated Nursing Care Homes Demonstration Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a demonstration program to test the viability of community integrated small-house nursing care homes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2011-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2011--Introduced.
Community Integrated Nursing Care Homes Demonstration Program Act or the CINCH Demonstration Program Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish the CINCH demonstration program to test the viability of multiple small-house nursing care homes that are embedded within residential neighborhoods and collectively certified to provide services through a single eligible operating entity in order to reduce administrative costs and provide cost savings to Medicare and Medicaid programs. Sets forth requirements a small-house nursing care home must meet to be eligible to participate, including requirements to: (1) be certified by a government entity to operate a nursing home; (2) operate in compliance with any direct care and certified nurse assistant staffing requirements under federal, state, and local law; (3) provide nursing home services that shall not be less comprehensive or high-acuity than services provided by the eligible operating entity within the immediate surrounding community; (4) provide for meals cooked in the nursing home; (5) meet specified staffing, care, service, and training levels; and (6) consist of a specified physical environment that is designed to look and feel like a home, rather than an institution. Directs the Secretary to: (1) conduct the program for a five-year period; (2) select up to six sites to participate, each to be operated by a different entity, with not less than two sites located in rural areas; (3) develop a process to allow a site, after the demonstration program, to continue operation through a single entity and to receive certification as a single provider for purposes of Medicare and Medicaid; and (4) select a technical assistance provider responsible for selecting, assisting, and evaluating the performance of eligible operating entities and ensuring that small-house nursing care homes satisfy this Act's requirements.</summary>
</bill>
