<bill session="110" type="s" number="460" updated="2013-07-19T22:24:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Trade CLAIM Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Trade Complaint and Litigation Accountability Improvement Measures Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make determinations by the United States Trade Representative under title III of the Trade Act of 1974 reviewable by the Court of International Trade and to ensure that the United States Trade Representative considers petitions to enforce United States Trade rights, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1436-1437"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/31/2007--Introduced.
Trade Complaint and Litigation Accountability Improvement Measures Act or the Trade CLAIM Act - Amends the federal judicial code to grant the Court of International Trade exclusive jurisdiction of any civil action commenced by a petitioner requesting de novo review of a U.S. Trade Representative (Trade Representative) decision concerning the enforcement of U.S. trade rights. Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to revise requirements concerning the enforcement of U.S. trade rights with respect to presidential authority and the responsibility of the Trade Representative. Permits the Trade Representative to take further action to enforce U.S. rights, based on the Trade Representative's monitoring, when a petitioner considers that the actions of a foreign country in implementing a measure have not been satisfactory.</summary>
</bill>
