<bill session="111" type="sr" number="476" updated="2013-07-20T00:20:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution honoring the lives of President of Poland Lech Kaczynski, his wife, and 94 others who perished on April 10, 2010, in a plane crash while en route to memorialize those Polish officers, officials, and civilians who were massacred by the Soviet Union 70 years ago.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2212"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2212" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Poland"/>
    <term name="World history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/2010--Introduced.
Recognizes the tragedy that took place on April 10, 2010, when an aircraft carrying a delegation of current and former Polish officials, family members, and others crashed and killed all passengers while en route to memorialize the massacres of more than 22,000 Polish government officials, military officers, and civilians executed by the NKVD in April-May of 1940. Honors: (1) the late President of Poland Lech Kaczynski and all the Poles who perished in the April crash; and (2) the more than 22,000 massacred Polish government officials, military officers, and civilians. Supports the Polish people as they restore leadership in the institutions of the government of Poland that were impacted by the April crash. Requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to the Ambassador of Poland to the United States.</summary>
</bill>
