<bill session="112" type="s" number="1047" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-12-30">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-12-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment of 1992 to require the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to take actions to improve environmental conditions in the vicinity of the Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel in Lake County, Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3227-3228"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3228" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-129.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-11-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-01-13">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman under authority of the order of the Senate of 12/17/2011 without amendment. With written report No. 112-122.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-01-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="284">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 284.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2012-12-30" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8552-8556" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8553-8554" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-12-31T12:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-31">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-31T17:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/30/2012--Passed Senate without amendment.
Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Act of 2011 - Amends the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992 to expand requirements for the operation and maintenance of the Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel, Colorado, to require the Secretary of the Interior to take any action necessary to maintain the structural integrity of the Tunnel to maintain public safety and to prevent an uncontrolled release of water from the tunnel portal. Makes the Secretary responsible for the operation and maintenance of the water treatment plant, including authorized sludge disposal. Authorizes the Secretary to offer to enter into one or more contracts with any appropriate individual or entity for the conduct of any required service. Includes within the Tunnel any surface water diverted into it and water collected by the dewatering relief well installed in June 2008. Authorizes the Secretary: (1) to enter into an agreement with any other entity or government agency to provide funding for an increase in any operation, maintenance, replacement, capital improvement, or expansion cost that is necessary to improve or expand the Treatment Plant; and (2) upon entering into an agreement, to make any necessary capital improvement to or expansion of the water treatment plant.Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to consult with the Secretary regarding each feature of the proposed new or amended Record of Decision for operable unit 6 of the California Gulch National Priorities List Site that may require any alteration to, or otherwise affect the operation and maintenance of, the Tunnel or the water treatment plant. Authorizes the Secretary to implement any improvement to the Tunnel or expansion of the plant as a result of a new or amended Record of Decision for operable unit 6 only upon entering into an agreement with the EPA Administrator or other entity or agency to provide funding for the improvement or expansion.</summary>
</bill>
