<bill session="111" type="h" number="3471" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">REAL ID Repeal and Identification Security Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To repeal title II of the REAL ID Act of 2005, to reinstitute section 7212 of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004, which provides States additional regulatory flexibility and funding authorization to more rapidly produce tamper- and counterfeit-resistant driver's licenses, and to protect privacy and civil liberties by providing interested stakeholders on a negotiated rulemaking with guidance to achieve improved 21st century licenses to improve national security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2009-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412220" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Information Policy, Census, and National Archives.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO23" subcommittee="Information Policy, Census, and National Archives" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1261"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2009--Introduced.
REAL ID Repeal and Identification Security Enhancement Act of 2009 - Repeals title II of the Real ID Act of 2005. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) establish by regulation minimum standards for acceptance of state-issued driver's licenses and personal identification cards by federal agencies; (2) establish a negotiated rulemaking process before publishing such standards; and (3) award grants to states to assist them in conforming to such standards. Prohibits federal agencies from accepting state-issued driver's licenses and personal identification cards after specified deadlines unless such identification conforms to the minimum standards promulgated under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
