<bill session="112" type="h" number="839" updated="2013-07-20T01:17:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-29T19:44:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-03-29T19:44:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HAMP Termination Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">HAMP Termination Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">HAMP Termination Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 to terminate the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to provide new assistance under the Home Affordable Modification Program, while preserving assistance to homeowners who were already extended an offer to participate in the Program, either on a trial or permanent basis.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400644"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2011-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400145" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2011-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2011-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-03-09">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 32 - 23.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11T19:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 112-31.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-03-11T19:33:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="15">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-03-14T19:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Financial Services, H. Rept. 112-31, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-15T18:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 170 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 839 and H.R. 861 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. With respect to each measure, the resolution provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment and shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 170.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1994-2017" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T14:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 839 and H.R. 861 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measures will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. With respect to each measure, the resolution provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment and shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 170 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ted Poe to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T14:24:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 839.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T15:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 170, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Hanna amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T15:42:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hanna amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Ms. Biggert demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 170, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Ellison amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T15:56:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 170, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Canseco amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T16:08:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 170, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Miller (NC) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 170, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Waters amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T16:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 170, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T16:30:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson Lee(TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson Lee(TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 170, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Matsui amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 170, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Maloney amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T16:50:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Maloney amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Maloney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 170, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Loretta Sanchez amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Biggert moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 839 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2018-2022" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 170 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ted Poe to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T18:36:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 839.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T19:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2020" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T19:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2003" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T19:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Larsen (WA) moved to recommit with instructions to Financial Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2020-2022" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2020" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T19:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Larsen (WA) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment which adds a new paragraph entitled "CONTINUATION OF PROGRAM FOR MEMBERS OF THE ARMED FORCES AND GOLD STAR RECIPIENTS".</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T19:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2021" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T19:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 185 - 238, 1 Present (Roll no. 197).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-03-29T19:44:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="198" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 252 - 170, 1 Present (Roll no. 198).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T19:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29T19:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 839 as may be necessary to reflect the actions of the House in amending the bill, to include striking "paragraph (1)" on page 5, line 16, and inserting in lieu thereof "subparagraph (A)".</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="170"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="170"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5652"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6688"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="527"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h199"/>
    <amendment number="h200"/>
    <amendment number="h201"/>
    <amendment number="h202"/>
    <amendment number="h203"/>
    <amendment number="h204"/>
    <amendment number="h205"/>
    <amendment number="h206"/>
    <amendment number="h207"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/11/2011--Passed House amended.
HAMP Termination Act of 2011 - Amends the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA) to terminate the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to provide new mortgage modification assistance under the Home Affordable Modification Program (HAMP), except with respect to existing obligations on behalf of homeowners already extended an offer to participate in the program. Declares unavailable after the enactment of this Act for obligation or expenditure under HAMP any amounts made available for HAMP under EESA title I that: (1) have been allocated for use but not yet obligated, and (2) are not necessary for providing HAMP assistance on behalf of those homeowners already extended an offer to participate in HAMP. Urges that such amounts be covered into the General Fund of the Treasury for use only in reducing the budget deficit of the federal government. Directs the Secretary to study: (1) the extent to which HAMP is used by homeowners who are active duty members of the Armed Forces (or their spouses or parents), veterans, or Gold Star-eligible widows, parents, or next of kin of Armed Forces members who died in military operations; and (2) the impact of the program on them. Requires the Secretary to publish on the departmental website a statement as to: (1) termination of HAMP; and (2) the availability of a Member of Congress to assist any borrower having trouble paying a mortgage and needing help contacting the borrower's lender or servicer to negotiate or acquire a loan modification. Requires the Secretary to give notice of this information to each individual who applied for HAMP and will not be considered for a mortgage modification because of the program's termination. Declares that Congress encourages banks to work with homeowners to: (1) provide loan modifications to those that are eligible, and (2) assist them as well as prospective homeowners with foreclosure prevention programs and information on loan modifications.</summary>
</bill>
