<bill session="112" type="s" number="1320" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Fuel Storage Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to offer to enter into temporary used fuel storage facility agreements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4296-4297"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4297" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2011--Introduced.
Nuclear Fuel Storage Improvement Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to offer to enter into temporary used fuel storage facility agreements in accordance with this Act. Sets a deadline by which a local governmental unit may, with the approval of the state governor, notify the Secretary that it is willing to have a privately owned and operated temporary used fuel storage facility located within its jurisdiction. Requires the Secretary to pay $1 million per year to up to three such governmental units. Makes funding available from the Nuclear Waste Fund for compensation and payments. Directs the Secretary to offer to enter into a long-term contract for the storage of used fuel from civilian nuclear power plants with a private owner or operator of an independent used fuel storage facility licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC). Authorizes the Secretary, upon request of a contract signatory, to enter into an agreement for a settlement of all claims against the Secretary for failure to dispose of high-level radioactive waste or used nuclear fuel by January 31, 1998. Directs the Secretary to grant priority for the acceptance of fuel produced by a facility that has produced used nuclear fuel, been decommissioned, and shut down permanently. Requires the Secretary to: (1) provide for the transportation of accepted used fuel, and (2) use NRC-approved transportation and storage casks.</summary>
</bill>
