<bill session="113" type="s" number="753" updated="2013-11-02T06:58:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for national security benefits for White Sands Missile Range and Fort Bliss.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412281"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2013-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2013--Introduced.
Withdraws parcels 1, 2, 3, and 4 and any lands acquired by the federal government within the boundaries of those parcels with respect to White Sands Missile Range in New Mexico and Fort Bliss in Texas and New Mexico from specified public land laws. Bars the withdrawal of parcel 4 for purposes of the issuance of oil and gas pipeline rights-of-way. Reserves parcel 1 for use by the Secretary of Army (the Secretary) for military purposes in accordance with a specified public land order. Transfers administrative jurisdiction over parcel 2 from the Secretary to the Secretary of the Interior (acting through the Bureau of Land Management [BLM]). Requires the Secretary to reimburse the Secretary of the Interior for the costs incurred by such Secretary in the implementation of this Act with regard to parcel 1.</summary>
</bill>
