<bill session="113" type="h" number="251" updated="2013-11-02T06:21:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal features of the electric distribution system to the South Utah Valley Electric Service District, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412270"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-17T15:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-78.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3264-3265" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 251.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11T17:11:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3269-3270" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="212" datetime="2013-06-11T18:54:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 404 - 0 (Roll no. 212).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3264" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="85">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 85.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2013-07-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5623" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2013-07-12">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2013-07-18">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-19" type="public" datetime="2013-07-18" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-19.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="25"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="25"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2013--Public Law.
South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior, insofar as the Strawberry Water Users Association conveyed its interest in an electric distribution system to the South Utah Valley Electric Service District, to convey and assign to the District: (1) all interest of the United States in all fixtures owned by the United States as part of the electric distribution system and the federal lands and interests where the fixtures are located, (2) license for use in perpetuity of the shared power poles, and (3) licenses for use and access in perpetuity to specified project lands and interests and corridors where federal lands and interests are abutting public streets and roads and can provide access to facilities. Requires the District to assume all liability from the United States for the administration, operation, maintenance, and replacement of such electric distribution system. Requires the Secretary, before conveying such lands, interests, and fixtures, to be in compliance with all applicable requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, the Endangered Species Act of 1973, and any other law applicable to such land and facilities. Prohibits anything, except for the uses as granted by license in the shared power poles, from being construed as granting or conveying to the District or any other party, any interest in any facilities comprising a part of the Strawberry Valley Project power generation system or the federally owned parts of the 46 kilovolt transmission system, the ownership of which shall remain in the United States. Prohibits, upon conveyance of any land or facility under this Act: (1) the conveyed and assigned land and facilities from any longer being considered as part of a federal reclamation project; (2) the District from being entitled to receive any future Bureau of Reclamation benefits respecting such land and facilities, except for those that would be available to other non-Bureau facilities; and (3) the United States from being liable for damages arising out of any act, omission, or occurrence related to the land and facilities, including the transaction specified above between the Association and the District. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the status of such conveyance, any obstacles to completing it, and the anticipated date for its completion, if the conveyance is not completed within one year of enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
