<bill session="109" type="h" number="6152" updated="2013-07-19T19:58:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Education for All Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to provide assistance for developing countries to promote quality basic education and to establish the achievement of universal basic education in all developing countries as an objective of United States foreign assistance policy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2006-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="3909"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Extremist movements in politics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2006--Introduced.
Education for All Act of 2006 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to state that it is U.S. policy to work with foreign countries and international organizations to: (1) assist developing countries committed to serious reforms to provide all children with quality elementary and secondary education; and (2) provide incentives to encourage educational system reform and educational service improvement in countries lacking such commitment. Requires the President to establish an Education for All Task Force to carry out such policy and to develop a unified strategy to promote universal basic education. Authorizes the President to provide funds or other assistance to eligible entities to assist a foreign country in developing and implementing a comprehensive national education plan that allows its citizens to access and complete basic education. Sets forth plan requirements. Authorizes the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to establish an education fellowship program to increase the expertise of agency personnel in promoting universal basic education and to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
