<bill session="111" type="h" number="1263" updated="2013-07-19T23:23:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Retirement Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Thrift Savings Plan Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for the automatic enrollment of new participants in the Thrift Savings Plan, and to clarify the method for computing certain annuities based on part-time service; to allow certain employees of the District of Columbia to have certain periods of service credited for purposes relating to retirement eligibility; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400249"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2009-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-03">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1804"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2009--Introduced.
Federal Retirement Reform Act of 2009 - Thrift Savings Plan Enhancement Act of 2009 - Requires the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board to provide for: (1) automatic enrollment in the Thrift Savings Plan (TSP) at a specified default percentage (between 2% and 5%) of basic pay of anyone appointed, transferred, or reappointed to a position in which that individual is eligible to contribute to TSP; (2) the inclusion in TSP of a qualified Roth contribution program and (3) the addition of a self-directed investment window under TSP, if it would be in the best interests of participants, limited to low-cost, passively-managed index funds that offer diversification. Requires the total service of an employee who retires eligible for an annuity under the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS) or who dies leaving a survivor entitled to benefits, to include the employee's days of unused sick leave for annuity computation purposes. Exempts a federal employee's part-time service performed before April 7, 1986, from proration requirements for purposes of annuity computation under the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS). District of Columbia Court, Offender Supervision, Parole, and Public Defender Employees Equity Act of 2009 - Entitles any individual who is treated as a federal employee under CSRS or FERS to have certain qualifying District of Columbia service included in calculating that individual's creditable federal service for specified purposes, including annuity eligibility. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow federal annuitants and members of the Armed Forces to elect to exclude retirement plan distributions for health insurance and long-term care premiums from gross income.</summary>
</bill>
