<bill session="112" type="h" number="1439" updated="2013-07-20T01:22:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Business Activity Tax Simplification Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Business Activity Tax Simplification Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To regulate certain State taxation of interstate commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2011-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2011-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412226" joined="2011-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2011-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2011-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2011-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E674-675"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-01">
      <text>Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-21T10:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 112-257.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-10-21T10:31:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="173">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 173.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/21/2011--Reported to House without amendment.
Business Activity Tax Simplification Act of 2011 - Expands the prohibition against state taxation of interstate commerce to include: (1) taxation of out-of-state sales transactions involving all forms of property, including intangible personal property and services (currently, only sales of tangible personal property are protected); and (2) all other business activity taxes in addition to net income taxes. Exempts from state taxation persons who enter a state merely to furnish information to customers and&#160;affiliates, to cover news or other events, or to gather information in the state. Sets forth jurisdictional standards for states in imposing, assessing, or collecting&#160;a net income tax or other business activity tax on interstate activities.&#160; Defines "physical presence in a state" as: (1) being an individual physically in a state or assigning one or more employees to be in a state, (2) using the services of an agent to establish or maintain the market in a state, and (3) leasing or owning tangible personal or real property in a state (excluding the leasing or licensing of computer software).&#160; Excludes from the definition of "physical presence" presence in&#160;a state for less than 15 days in a taxable year or presence in a state to conduct limited or transient business activity. Provides that this Act shall not be construed to modify or affect any state business activity tax on a partnership, an S corporation or limited liability company,&#160;or a trust or estate that has a physical presence in the state or to supersede the authority of a state to enact a law or bring a&#160;law enforcement action against persons or entities engaged in illegal activity or sham transactions. Sets forth a rule for computing the net income tax or other business activity tax liability of an affiliated group. Makes this Act applicable to taxable periods beginning on or after January 1, 2012.</summary>
</bill>
