<bill session="112" type="s" number="877" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protect Life Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prevent taxpayer-funded elective abortions by applying the longstanding policy of the Hyde amendment to the new health care law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2011-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2011-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2011-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="358"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2011--Introduced.
Protect Life Act - Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to prohibit federal funds from being to used to cover any part of the costs of any health plan that includes coverage of abortion services. (Currently, federal funds cannot be used for abortion services and plans receiving federal funds must keep federal funds segregated from any funds for abortion services.) Requires any qualified health benefit plan offered through an Exchange that includes coverage for abortions to also offer a qualified health benefit plan through the Exchange that is identical in every respect except that it does not cover abortions. Prohibits a federal agency or program and any state or local government that receives federal financial assistance under PPACA from requiring any health plan created or regulated under PPACA to discriminate against any institutional or individual health care entity based on the entity's refusal to undergo training in the performance of induced abortions, require or provide such training, or refer for such training. Creates a cause of action for any violations of the abortion provisions of PPACA. Gives federal courts jurisdiction to prevent and redress actual or threatened violations of such provisions by issuing any form of legal or equitable relief, including injunctions and orders preventing the disbursement of all or a portion of federal financial assistance until the prohibited conduct has ceased. Gives standing to institute an action to affected health care entities and the Attorney General. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to designate the Director of the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to receive and investigate complaints alleging a violation of PPACA abortion provisions. Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to ensure that no multistate qualified health plan offered in an Exchange provides coverage of abortion services.</summary>
</bill>
