<bill session="111" type="h" number="5696" updated="2013-07-20T00:04:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">e-KNOW Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Electric Consumer Right to Know Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to provide electric consumers the right to access certain electric energy information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2010-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4860"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3487"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/2010--Introduced.
Electric Consumer Right to Know Act or e-KNOW Act - Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to grant an electric consumer the right to access the consumer's retail electric energy information in electronic machine-readable form, in a manner that is timely and provides adequate protections for the information's privacy and security. Directs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to issue a model rule prescribing minimum national standards to implement such right of access. Includes within such right of access an Internet website of retail electric energy information. Requires the Secretary of Energy, in determining whether to award federal smart grid support to a retail electric utility, to give preference to any applicant that has implemented policies for electric consumer access to retail electric energy information at least as stringent as those prescribed by the model rule. Sets forth procedures for state consideration of the FERC model.</summary>
</bill>
