<bill session="113" type="h" number="2951" updated="2013-11-02T06:43:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require certain preconditions for allowing premium tax credits, reductions in cost-sharing, and funding of Navigators and related Exchange enrollment activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400659"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
Disallows specified subsidy payments under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA), including the tax credit for health care coverage premium assistance and reduction in cost-sharing, or any funding for the operation of a PPACA Navigator Program until: (1) the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) certifies to Congress that verification methods under PPACA to determine eligibility for subsidies have been tested to verify their accuracy and have safeguards in place to protect personally identifiable information; and (2) the Inspector General of HHS reviews such verification methods and certifies to Congress the quality, accuracy, response time, and integrity of such methods and that the level of improper subsidy payments is not likely to exceed 3% of the level of the total subsidy payment. Requires the Inspector General of HHS to review verification methods annually to determine the level of improper subsidy payments and suspend such subsidies in years in which they exceed 3% of the total subsidy payment.</summary>
</bill>
