<bill session="110" type="s" number="2637" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Beginning Farmers and Ranchers Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an exclusion for gain from the sale of farmland to encourage the continued use of the property for farming, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="5134"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family farms"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2008--Introduced.
Beginning Farmers and Ranchers Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income 100% of the gain, up to $500,000, from the sale of qualified farm property to a first-time farmer who certifies that such property will be used for farming purposes for 10 years. Allows: (1) a 50% exclusion for the sale of qualified farm property to any other person who certifies that such property will be used for farming purposes for 10 years; and (2) a 25% exclusion for the sale of qualified farm property to any other person for any other use. Defines "qualified farm property" as real property located in the United States which is used for farming purposes for a specified three-year period and in which there was material participation by the taxpayer or the taxpayer's spouse or family member. Requires the recapture of tax benefits if qualified farm property is sold or ceases operation as a farm before the required 10-year period. Increases dollar limitations on bonds issued to finance assistance programs for first-time farmers.</summary>
</bill>
