<bill session="111" type="s" number="3825" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">State Wolf Management Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to remove certain portions of the distinct population segment of the Rocky Mountain gray wolf from the list of threatened species or the list of endangered species published under the Endangered Species Act of 1973, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412322"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2010-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7358-7359"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6028"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6208"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6485"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6486"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3864"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3919"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2010--Introduced.
State Wolf Management Act - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to provide that the inclusion of the portion of the distinct population segment of the Rocky Mountain gray wolf located in Idaho, Montana, or specified areas of Washington, Oregon, and Utah on any list of threatened or endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 shall have no force or effect. Permits the Secretary of the Interior, five years after this Act's enactment, to initiate a process to include the Rocky Mountain gray wolf on such a list upon certifying to Congress that a state, by and through its management plan, has not provided for the maintenance within the state of not fewer than 10 breeding pairs and an aggregate of 100 Rocky Mountain gray wolves.</summary>
</bill>
