<bill session="111" type="h" number="1838" updated="2013-07-19T23:28:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-07T10:07:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-11-07T10:07:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to modify certain provisions relating to women's business centers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2009-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2009-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Rural Development, Entrepreneurship and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated into H.R. 2352.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T10:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Velazquez moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T10:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12469-12471" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T10:16:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1838.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T10:29:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Ms. Velazquez objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-07T09:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12595-12596" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-11-07T10:07:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="877" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 428 - 4 (Roll no. 877).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/6/2009 H12469-12470" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-11-07T10:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSM21" subcommittee="Rural Development, Entrepreneurship and Trade" name="House Small Business"/>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2352"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/7/2009--Passed House amended.
Amends the Small Business Act relating to the women's business centers program to require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to: (1) disburse funds to a women's business center (center) no later than one month after its application is approved; (2) annually publish on the SBA website information on the financing of each center; (3) establish a standardized process to communicate with centers regarding program administration matters; and (4) notify each center of the opportunity for notice and comment on proposed program rules. Replaces the five-year projects for the benefit of small businesses owned and controlled by women with a three-tiered program of five-year (first tier), three-year (second tier), and three-year (third tier) projects, with each tier commencing after the previous tier is being completed. Allows the maximum award of assistance ($150,000) for first-tier projects that possess the capacity to train existing or potential business owners in the fields of green technology, clean technology, or energy efficiency. Revises matching funds requirements for all projects. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the SBA to: (1) establish center performance measures; and (2) require each center to submit an annual funding and strategies plan. Amends the Women's Business Ownership Act of 1988 to require the National Women's Business Council to perform studies of: (1) the impact of the 2008-2009 financial markets crisis on women-owned businesses; and (2) the use of SBA programs by women-owned businesses. Authorizes appropriations for the Council for FY2010-FY2011. Includes under criteria for the selection of project participants whether the applicant has the capacity to train existing or potential business owners in the fields of green technology, clean technology, or energy efficiency.</summary>
</bill>
