<bill session="111" type="sr" number="415" updated="2013-07-20T00:19:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-11">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution calling for a renewed focus on the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran's violations of internationally-recognized human rights as found in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2010-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2010-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2010-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2010-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-02-11" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S589-592" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S592" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S571" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2010--Passed Senate without amendment.
Pays tribute to the democracy and human rights advocates in the Islamic Republic of Iran who are engaged in peaceful efforts to encourage democratic reform. Notes that it is the right of the people of the Islamic Republic of Iran to peacefully assemble and to express their opinions without intimidation and violence. Supports freedom of speech and judicial due process in the Islamic Republic of Iran. Expresses concern over the government of the Islamic Republic of Iran's suppression of its citizens through censorship, imprisonment, and violence and denounces the atmosphere of impunity in Iran for those who employ intimidation or violence to suppress freedoms of speech, expression, assembly, and the press. Calls upon the Islamic Republic of Iran to observe the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights and abide by U.N. General Assembly resolutions. Communicates deep concern that, despite the Islamic Republic of Iran's standing invitation to all thematic special procedures mandate holders, it has not fulfilled any requests from those special mechanisms to visit the country in four years and has not answered numerous communications from those special mechanisms. Encourages the U.N. Human Rights Council to fully examine these issues during its Universal Periodic Review of the Islamic Republic of Iran on February 15, 2010.</summary>
</bill>
