<bill session="111" type="s" number="3984" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-22">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Museum and Library Services Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Museum and Library Services Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Museum and Library Services Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Museum and Library Services Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Museum and Library Services Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend and extend the Museum and Library Services Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2010-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2010-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2010-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2010-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2010-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2010-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-11-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8246-8247"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S8247-8250" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-12-01">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-12-03">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Harkin without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-12-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="671">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 671.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2010-12-07" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8602-8605" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8602-8605" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08T10:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14T16:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14T16:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8318-8321" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14T16:07:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3984.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-12-14T16:13:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8318-8321" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14T16:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-12-14">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-12-16">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-12-22">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-12-22" type="public" number="111-340">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-340.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Humanities programs funding"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/22/2010--Public Law.
Museum and Library Services Act of 2010 - Title I: General Provisions - (Sec. 102) Amends the Museum and Library Services Act (the Act) to give the Director of the Institute of Museum and Library Services primary responsibility to develop and implement a policy to ensure the availability of museum, library, and information services that are adequate in meeting the essential information, education, research, economic, cultural, and civic needs of the people of the United States. Requires the Director to: (1) advise the President, Congress, and other federal agencies and offices on museum, library, and information services so as to ensure the creation, preservation, organization, and dissemination of knowledge; (2) engage governmental agencies and private entities in assessing the museum, library, and information services needs of the people of the United States; (3) carry out programs of research and development, data collection, and financial assistance in order to extend and improve such services; and (4) ensure that those services are fully integrated into the nation's information and education infrastructures. Authorizes the Director to: (1) enter into interagency agreements to promote or assist with the museum, library, and information services-related activities of other federal agencies; and (2) use funds under this Act for the costs of such activities. Revises requirements for the coordination of policies and activities of the Institute with those of other federal agencies and offices to add requirements ensuring that such policies and activities are coordinated with: (1) programs and activities under the Head Start Act; (2) activities under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998; and (3) federal programs and activities that increase the capacity of libraries and museums to act as partners in economic and community development, education and research, improvement of digital literacy skills, and the dissemination of health information. Requires the Director to collaborate with the heads of relevant federal departments and agencies with respect to certain activities of libraries and museums. (Sec. 103) Revises requirements regarding the number and compensation of technical and professional employees appointed by the Director to help carry out the duties of the Institute. Authorizes the Director to utilize experts and consultants who may be employed on a temporary or intermittent basis. (Sec. 104) Revises requirements regarding the membership and the duties and powers of the National Museum and Library Services Board. (Sec. 105) Restates provisions concerning national awards and medals for library and museum services. (Sec. 106) Requires the Director to annually conduct policy research, analysis, and data collection in order to extend and improve the nation's museum, library, and information services. Sets forth the objectives of the policy research, analysis, and data collection, including the development of plans to improve museum, library, and information services and to strengthen national, state, local, regional, and international communications and cooperative networks. Instructs the Director to widely disseminate the results of such policy research, analysis, and data collection. Authorizes the Director to: (1) enter into arrangements with federal agencies and other organizations to carry out the objectives; and (2) publish and disseminate reports, findings, studies, and other materials that were prepared to accomplish those objectives. Authorizes appropriations for FY2011-FY2016 to carry out this section. (Sec. 107) Authorizes the Director to hold hearings at such times and places as determined appropriate to carry out the Act's purposes. (Sec. 108) Requires the Director to establish an account from which to pay the federal administrative costs of carrying out the Act and limits the amount of appropriated funds placed in such account. Title II: Library Services and Technology - (Sec. 201) Expands and revises the purposes under the Library Services and Technology Act (LSTA). (Sec. 202) Authorizes appropriations through FY2011-FY2016 to carry out the LSTA, including the Laura Bush 21st Century Librarian Program (established by section 207 of this Act). Repeals the limitation on the amount of funding under the LSTA that may be used for federal administrative costs. (Sec. 203) Increases the dollar amount of the minimum allotment available to each state and U.S. territory for grants under the LSTA. (Sec. 204) Requires each state plan to describe how the state library administrative agency will work with other state agencies and offices to coordinate resources, programs, and activities and leverage federal and state investment in elementary and secondary education, early childhood education, workforce development, and other federal programs and activities that relate to library services, including economic and community development and health information. (Sec. 205) Expands and revises the types of activities for which a state library administrative agency shall expend at least 96% of its grant funds. Restates the special rule regarding the apportionment of funds to meet the needs of an individual state. (Sec. 206) Expands and revises the activities that may be carried out under national leadership grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements. Permits the use of such a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement for the development of emergency plans that would ensure the preservation of knowledge and library collections in the event of a disaster. (Sec. 207) Establishes the Laura Bush 21st Century Librarian Program to: (1) recruit and educate the next generation of librarians; (2) develop faculty and library leaders; and (3) enhance the training and professional development of librarians and the library workforce to meet the needs of their communities. Authorizes the Director to enter into arrangements with libraries, library consortia and associations, institutions of higher education, and other entities to conduct projects that further the purpose of the Program. Title III: Museum Services - (Sec. 301) Expands the purposes of the Museum and Library Services Act relating to museum services. (Sec. 302) Modifies the definition of "museum" to include museums that have tangible and digital collections. (Sec. 303) Authorizes the Director to enter into arrangements with museums and other entities as well as with states and local governments (under current law, only with museums and other entities) to pay the federal share of the cost of the support of certain museum services activities, as expanded and revised under this Act, including for statewide assessments of museum services and needs and the development of state plans to improve and maximize museum services. Requires the Director to consider the equitable distribution of grants to various sizes and types of museums and to different U.S. geographic areas in awarding grants to pay the federal cost share for those activities. (Sec. 304) Authorizes appropriations through FY2011-FY2016 to carry out the Act's provisions relating to museum services and sets forth a special funding rule. Removes the limitation on the amount of funds that may be used to pay the administrative expenses. Title IV: Repeal of the National Commission on Libraries and Information Science Act - (Sec. 401) Repeals the National Commission on Libraries and Information Science Act. Transfers the functions, personnel, assets, contracts, property, and records of the National Commission on Libraries and Information Science to the Institute.</summary>
</bill>
