<bill session="112" type="s" number="1870" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Women's History Museum and Federal Facilities Consolidation and Efficiency Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Federal Trade Commission and National Gallery of Art Facility Consolidation, Savings, and Efficiency Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">National Women's History Museum Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Administrator of General Services to convey a parcel of real property in the District of Columbia to provide for the establishment of a National Women's History Museum and direct the Administrator of General Services to transfer administrative jurisdiction, custody, and control of the building located at 600 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, in the District of Columbia, to the National Gallery of Art, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400040"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7453"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7453-7454" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="690"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1269"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2844"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="680"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2011--Introduced.
National Women's History Museum and Federal Facilities Consolidation and Efficiency Act of 2011 - National Women's History Museum Act of 2011 - Directs the Administrator of General Services (GSA) to convey, by quitclaim deed, to the National Women's History Museum, Inc. (the Museum) specified property (commonly known as the "Cotton Annex" site) in the District of Columbia, on terms which the Administrator deems appropriate. Requires the purchase price for the property to be: (1) its market value based on its highest and best use, as determined by an independent appraisal performed under the assumption that the property does not contain any hazardous substances, waste, or pollutants requiring a response under applicable environmental laws; and (2) paid into the Federal Buildings Fund. Requires the property to be dedicated for use as a site for a national women's history museum for a 99-year period. Prohibits using federal funds to purchase the property or design and construct any facility on such property. Federal Trade Commission and National Gallery of Art Facility Consolidation, Savings, and Efficiency Act of 2011 - Requires the Administrator, not later than December 31, 2012, to transfer administrative jurisdiction, custody, and control of the building located at 600 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, in Washington, DC, to the National Gallery of Art and to name such building as the North Building of the National Gallery of Art. Requires the National Gallery of Art to pay the costs of remodeling, renovating, or reconstructing such building. Prohibits the use of appropriated funds for the initial costs of such activities. Requires the Administrator to relocate the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) employees and operations housed in such building to specified space in the leased building known as the Constitution Center located at 400 7th Street, SW, in Washington, DC. Directs the Administrator and the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to execute an occupancy agreement to assign or sublease such space.</summary>
</bill>
