<bill session="111" type="hr" number="943" updated="2013-07-19T23:04:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Federal banking regulators should, with respect to well-managed community-based depository institutions, permit appropriate capital forbearance, troubled debt restructuring accounting practices, and other time-tested measures that would allow such institutions to continue to provide for the financial vitality for our Nation's small businesses and family farms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2010-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412240" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2009-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412298" joined="2009-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412192" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412217" joined="2010-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2009--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House that all state and federal agencies which regulate community-based depository institutions should develop policies that permit such institutions that are well-managed to: (1) maintain capital temporarily at levels less than that currently required, conditioned upon regulatory approval of an appropriate plan to restore capital levels by a date certain; and (2) account temporarily for troubled debt restructuring in a manner which allows a loan to be carried on the institution's books without loss recognition if the loan is formally restructured so that the borrower can repay it, and the total future cash payments equal the loan amount on the institution's books. States that such federal and state regulatory agencies should: (1) ensure that field examiners are not inappropriately classifying loans based on judgment about currently stressed sectors apart from the ability of the loans to show likelihood of repayment based on positive cash flows, ample amounts of collateral, and other mitigating factors; and (2) include additional temporary accommodations to assist well-managed community-based depository institutions in remaining vital sources of financial strength for their communities, while maintaining needed standards to assure the continued financial integrity of those institutions and communities.</summary>
</bill>
