<bill session="113" type="sr" number="132" updated="2013-11-02T06:50:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the Department of Defense request for domestic Base Realignment and Closure authority in 2015 and 2017 is neither affordable nor feasible as of the date of agreement to this resolution and that the Department of Defense must further analyze the capability to consolidate excess overseas infrastructure and increase efficiencies by relocating missions from overseas to domestic installations prior to requesting domestic Base Realignment and Closure authority.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3262" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2013--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that the Department of Defense (DOD): (1) should not, as of the date of agreement to this resolution, be granted authority for its requested 2015 and 2017 military base realignment and closure (BRAC) rounds; (2) before being granted such authority, should achieve economic efficiencies by closing and consolidating excess overseas infrastructure and facilities and reexamining relocation opportunities of overseas missions to U.S. military installations; and (3) is unwise to request a BRAC round when the U.S. economy is struggling and negatively impacted communities are fighting to put citizens back to work.</summary>
</bill>
