<bill session="110" type="h" number="984" updated="2013-07-19T21:12:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Executive Branch Reform Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for reform in the operations of the executive branch.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400425"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2007-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400120" joined="2007-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2007-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2007-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2007-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-02-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 29 - 0.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Office of Government Ethics"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/2007--Introduced.
Executive Branch Reform Act of 2007 - Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require recording and filing by each executive branch official with the Office of Government Ethics on any significant contact made between that official and any private party relating to an official government action. Outlines the authorities and responsibilities of the Director of the Office of Government Ethics with regard to such reports. Provides for penalties and fines. Sets prohibitions on covered executive branch officials who are entering or leaving government service. Amends the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to: (1) prohibit a former federal agency contracting official from accepting compensation from a contractor as a lawyer or lobbyist of the contractor within a specified time frame; (2) prohibit former federal officials from accepting compensation from contractors if it is either a reward or if the acceptance of the compensation is inappropriate and affects the integrity of the procurement process; (3) require federal procurement officers to disclose job offers made on behalf of relatives; and (4) prohibit a federal employee who is a former employee of a contractor with the government from being personally and substantially involved with the award or administration of a contract to the employee's former employer for a specified period. Sets a prohibition on unauthorized expenditure of funds for publicity or propaganda purposes. Requires an advertisement or other communication paid for by an executive agency to disclose that such advertisement or communication is paid for by that agency. Directs each federal agency to submit to the Archivist of the United States and specified congressional committees a report describing the use of "pseudo" classification designations. Requires the Archivist to report on the use of such designations and promulgate regulations banning them. Defines "'pseudo' classification designations" as information control designations that are not defined by federal statute or Executive order relating to the classification of national security information but that are used to manage, direct, or route government information, or control its accessibility, regardless of its form or format.</summary>
</bill>
