<bill session="109" type="s" number="1267" updated="2013-07-19T20:24:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gearing Up for Academic Success Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to reauthorize the Gaining Early Awareness and Readiness for Undergraduate Programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6763-6764"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6764-6766" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2005--Introduced.
Gearing Up for Academic Success Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to reauthorize and revise Gaining Early Awareness and Readiness for Undergraduate Programs (GEAR UP). Revises fund allocation to provide, under certain conditions, for formula grants to states and competitive grants to partnerships. Requires partnerships, through a cohort approach, to provide activities designed to ensure: (1) secondary school completion and college enrollment of students at risk of dropping out; and (2) systemic changes in schools, so future cohorts of children will benefit. Requires such activities to include: (1) enrollment in college preparation curricula; (2) professional development for college preparation course instructors; and (3) curriculum development. Requires states to provide: (1) policy leadership to promote college readiness of students, especially those at risk of dropping out and those who are economically disadvantaged; and (2) services to promote coordination and information sharing among grantees. Eliminates authority for a scholarship program component and for 21st Century Scholar Certificates.</summary>
</bill>
