<bill session="111" type="h" number="434" updated="2013-07-19T23:15:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to permit access to databases maintained by the Federal Emergency Management Agency for purposes of complying with sex offender registry and notification laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-09">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-09">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Information Policy, Census, and National Archives.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO23" subcommittee="Information Policy, Census, and National Archives" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/9/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Privacy Act of 1974 to authorize the disclosure to government agencies of Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) records on assistance provided to individuals in connection with a major disaster or emergency for purposes of complying with a federal or state sex offender registry or notification law. Conditions receipt of federal funds by non-governmental organizations under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act on the organization providing assurances satisfactory to the President that it will disclose its records for the purpose of permitting a requesting jurisdiction to comply with a federal or state sex offender registry or notification law.</summary>
</bill>
