<bill session="113" type="h" number="1189" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Natural Gas Security and Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Natural Gas Act with respect to the exportation of natural gas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2013--Introduced.
American Natural Gas Security and Consumer Protection Act - Amends the Natural Gas Act to prohibit any person from exporting any natural gas from the United States to a foreign country without first having secured an order of the Secretary of Energy (DOE) authorizing such person to do so. Allows the Secretary to issue an order authorizing such exportation, upon application, if the Secretary determines that the proposed exportation will be consistent with the public interest. Requires the Secretary to issue an environmental impact statement (EIS) under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 on such an order, including by analyzing the impacts of extraction of exported natural gas on the environment in communities where the natural gas is extracted. Directs the Secretary to issue final regulations for determining whether an export of natural gas from the United States to a foreign country is in the public interest. Exempts any export authorization order from such EIS and public interest requirements if the natural gas would be exported solely to meet certain requirements of: (1) the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (regarding presidential foreign exchange transaction authorities), (2) the Trading with the Enemy Act (regarding such transaction authorities in wartime), or (3) the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (regarding the International Energy Program). Authorizes the Secretary to issue such an order upon application in such cases without modification or delay.</summary>
</bill>
