<bill session="111" type="s" number="844" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Eliminating Disparities in Diabetes Prevention Access and Care Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to prevent and treat diabetes, to promote and improve the care of individuals with diabetes, and to reduce health disparities relating to diabetes within racial and ethnic minority groups, including African-American, Hispanic American, Asian American, Native Hawaiian and Other Pacific Islander, and American Indian and Alaskan Native communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="1995"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Immunology"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2009--Introduced.
Eliminating Disparities in Diabetes Prevention Access and Care Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to provide for: (1) ongoing research and other activities with respect to pre-diabetes and diabetes in minority populations; and (2) programs to treat diabetes in minority populations. Requires the Director of NIH, through the National Center on Minority Health and Health Disparities and the National Diabetes Education Program, to provide for: (1) health care professionals' mentoring; and (2) minority health professionals' participation in diabetes-focused research programs. Requires the Director to make grants for a pipeline from high school to professional school that will increase minority representation in diabetes-focused health fields. Directs the Diabetes Mellitus Interagency Coordinating Committee to assess federal activities and programs related to diabetes in minority populations. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) conduct research on diabetes in minority populations; (2) direct the Division of Diabetes Translation to educate the public on the causes and effects of diabetes in minority populations; and (3) carry out diabetes health promotion and prevention programs for minority populations. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to educate health professionals on the causes and effects of diabetes in minority populations. Sets forth additional requirements for the Secretary related to: (1) factors that may influence health promotion, diabetes management, and prevention; (2) data collection on diabetes treatment, care, prevention, and services to the American Indian population; (3) increased participation of minority populations in clinical trials; and (4) specialized care for children with diabetes.</summary>
</bill>
