<bill session="111" type="s" number="806" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-05">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Executive Board Authorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Federal Executive Board Authorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Federal Executive Board Authorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the establishment, administration, and funding of Federal Executive Boards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2009-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4355"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4355-4356" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-07-29">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-77.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-09-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="164">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 164.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11233-11235" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11233-11234" label="text of measure as reporte in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>The committee reported substitute was withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11234" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2009-11-05" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-11-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16T14:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA03" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2736"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/5/2009--Passed Senate amended.
Federal Executive Board Authorization Act of 2009 - Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to establish Federal Executive Boards, which are defined as interagency entities established in a geographic area with a high concentration of federal employees outside the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area to strengthen the management and administration of agency activities and coordination among local federal officers to implement national initiatives in that area. Requires each Board for a geographic area to consist of a senior officer for each agency in that area. Requires the Director to: (1) consider specified factors in determining the location for establishment of such Boards, such as whether a geographic area has a strong, viable, and active Federal Executive Association and whether such Association petitions to become a Board; and (2) provide for the administration and oversight of such Boards, including by establishing staffing and communications policies and performance standards for Board staff. Requires each Board to: (1) serve as an instrument of outreach for the national headquarters of agencies relating to agency activities in the geographic area; (2) provide a forum for the exchange of information relating to programs and management methods and problems between the national headquarters of agencies and the field; (3) develop local coordinated approaches to the development and operation of programs that have common characteristics; (4) communicate management initiatives and other concerns from federal officers and employees in the Washington, D.C. area to federal officers and employees in the geographic area to achieve better mutual understanding and support; (5) develop relationships with state and local governments and nongovernmental organizations to help fulfill the roles and responsibilities of that Board; and (6) facilitate communication, collaboration, and training to prepare the federal workforce for emergencies and continuity of operations. Requires the Director to: (1) establish a fund within OPM for financing essential Board functions, into which contributions from the headquarters of each participating agency shall be deposited; (2) submit annual reports to Congress and agencies on Board program outcomes and budget matters; and (3) report to specified congressional committees on essential Board functions, staffing requirements, and staffing and operating expenses.</summary>
</bill>
