<bill session="111" type="h" number="677" updated="2013-07-19T23:17:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FAIR (Foreign Air Impact Regulation) AIR Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Clean Air Act to delay the effect of reclassifying certain nonattainment areas adjacent to an international border, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E167"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2009--Introduced.
FAIR (Foreign Air Impact Regulation) AIR Act of 2009 - Amends the Clean Air Act to delay the effective date of reclassification of a nonattainment area to a higher classification of nonattainment for failing to meet national ambient air quality standards by applicable deadlines if: (1) the area is adjacent to a foreign country; and (2) the state in which the area is located submits a claim to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) that the area would have attained the relevant standard by the attainment date but for emissions emanating from outside the United States.Prohibits such reclassification from taking effect unless: (1) the Secretary of State has entered into negotiations with the foreign country involved to develop an air quality improvement plan for the international area encompassing the nonattainment area and submitted that plan to Congress; and (2) taking such plan into consideration, the Administrator has taken appropriate action to improve air quality in the nonattainment area.</summary>
</bill>
