<bill session="113" type="hj" number="72" updated="2013-11-02T06:48:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-03T16:49:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-03T16:49:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Honoring our promise to America's veterans bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Benefits Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations for veterans benefits for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400089"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Culberson moved to suspend the rules and pass the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6082-6089" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6082" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-01T18:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 72.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="506" datetime="2013-10-01T19:45:00-04:00" where="h" result="fail" suspension="1" state="PROV_KILL:SUSPENSIONFAILED">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the resolution Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 264 - 164 (Roll no. 506).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 370 Reported to House. The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 70, H.J. Res. 71, H.J. Res. 72, H.J. Res. 73, and H.R. 3230. The resolution provides for 30 minutes of debate on each measure and provides for one motion to recommit each measure. The resolution also provides that it shall be in order at any time through the calendar day of October 6, 2013, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T13:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 370.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6200-6203" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 70, H.J. Res. 71, H.J. Res. 72, H.J. Res. 73, and H.R. 3230. The resolution provides for 30 minutes of debate on each measure and provides for one motion to recommit each measure. The resolution also provides that it shall be in order at any time through the calendar day of October 6, 2013, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T14:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 72.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed with debate on H.J. Res. 72.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6203-6210" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T15:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6207" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Duckworth moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6207-6208" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6207" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duckworth motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment, pending reservation of a point of order. The amendment would replace the underlying bill with the Senate Amendment to H.J.Res. 59.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Culberson raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Culberson stated that the provisions of the proposed amendment are not germane Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T16:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Duckworth appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6208" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T16:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Culberson moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6208-6209" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T16:36:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the appeal of the ruling of the chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 225 - 193 (Roll no. 517).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="518" datetime="2013-10-03T16:49:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 259 - 157 (Roll no. 518).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6201" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="207">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 207.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="370"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="370"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2013--Passed House without amendment.
Veterans Benefits Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 - Makes appropriations for FY2014 for veterans' benefits, specifically for entitlements and other mandatory payments whose budget authority was provided in the Military Construction and Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2013 (division E of P.L. 113-6), to continue activities at the rate to maintain program levels under current law, under the authority and conditions provided in the applicable appropriations Act for FY2013, to be continued through December 15, 2013. Allows obligations for mandatory payments due on or about the first day of any month that begins after October 2013 but not later than 30 days after December 15, 2013, to continue to be made and makes funds available for such payments. Provides amounts for "Department of Veterans Affairs--Departmental Administration--General Operating Expenses, Veterans Benefits Administration" at a specified rate for operations, subject to the authority and conditions as provided under P.L. 113-6, and makes them available to the extent and in the manner that would be provided by such Act. Makes appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under this joint resolution available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment into law of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution, (2) enactment into law of the applicable appropriations Act for FY2014 without any provision for such project or activity, or (3) December 15, 2013. Expresses the sense of Congress that this joint resolution may also be referred to as the Honoring Our Promise to America's Veterans Act.</summary>
</bill>
