<bill session="110" type="h" number="1681" updated="2013-07-19T21:18:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-11">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American National Red Cross Governance Modernization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">American National Red Cross Governance Modernization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">American National Red Cross Governance Modernization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">American National Red Cross Governance Modernization Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Congressional Charter of The American National Red Cross to modernize its governance structure, to enhance the ability of the board of governors of The American National Red Cross to support the critical mission of The American National Red Cross in the 21st century, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2007-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2007-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-03-27">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-04-16T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Foreign Affairs. H. Rept. 110-87.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-04-16T15:24:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="52">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 52.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lantos moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3429-3432" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T14:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1681.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-04-17T15:02:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3429-3431" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-04-17T15:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-04-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="119">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 119.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2007-04-23" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4863-4864" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2007-04-23">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2007-04-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2007-05-01">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2007-05-11">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2007-05-11" type="public" number="110-26">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 110-26.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="655"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="655"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate governance"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Term limits"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2007--Public Law.
American National Red Cross Governance Modernization Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) charitable organizations are an indispensable part of American society; (2) such organizations must maintain the trust of the American public by fostering effective governance and transparency; (3) the American National Red Cross (ANRC) is and will remain a federally chartered instrumentality of the United States; and (4) the ANRC should maintain appropriate communications with state regulators of charitable organizations and cooperate with such regulators.(Sec. 3) Amends the charter of the ANRC to designate the ANRC as a federally chartered instrumentality of the United States and authorize it to conduct its business and affairs as the American Red Cross in any jurisdiction and to conduct other activities consistent with its traditional purposes.(Sec. 5) Authorizes the ANRC corporation (corporation), rather than its board of directors, to prescribe policies and regulations relating to ANRC chapters. Provides for the selection of delegates to the annual meeting of the ANRC, instead of its national convention.(Sec. 6) Modifies provisions relating to the ANRC board of governors to restate the role of the board as the governing body of the corporation and to revise provisions relating to its size, composition, and relationship with management. Establishes an Advisory Council to advise, report to, and meet with the board of governors.(Sec. 7) Authorizes the corporation to adopt policies in lieu of bylaws. (Sec. 8) Defines the annual meeting of the corporation as the annual meeting of the delegates of the chapters (instead of the national convention). Designates the time and place of the annual meeting and determines the voting guidelines and requirements for such meeting. (Sec. 9) Eliminates the requirement that the number of trustees overseeing the ANRC endowment fund be nine. Grants the corporation, rather than the board of governors, the authority to prescribe policies and regulations on terms and tenure of office, accountability, and expenses of the board of trustees. (Sec. 10) Requires the corporation to submit a report to the Secretary of Defense on the activities of the corporation during the preceding fiscal year, including a complete, itemized report of all receipts and expenditures. (Sec. 11) Authorizes the Comptroller General to review the corporation's involvement in any federal program or activity. Requires the corporation to establish an Office of the Ombudsman. Requires such Office to submit an annual report to specified congressional committees on trends and systemic matters that the Office has identified as confronting the corporation.</summary>
</bill>
