<bill session="111" type="s" number="3796" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Community Health Improvement Councils Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish community health improvement councils and State health improvement technical assistance center grants.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300006"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2010--Introduced.
Community Health Improvement Councils Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a program for the creation of State Health Improvement Technical Assistance Centers and Community Health Improvement Councils to improve community health through local innovation. Defines "Community Health Improvement Council" to mean a locally driven, private, nonprofit entity that serves as the neutral convener for engaging providers and insurers and that fully engages patients and citizens in coordinating and improving the health care delivery system through community-wide education programs to promote healthier lifestyles, improve local or regional health status, clinical outcomes, and reductions in the growth in medical spending and health disparities through various approaches. Requires the Secretary to award competitive grants to five eligible entities to establish State Health Improvement Technical Assistance Centers, each of which shall: (1) establish up to four Community Health Improvement Councils; (2) provide technical assistance to such Councils; and (3) report on improvements in local and state health status, clinical outcomes, reductions in medical spending growth, and health care disparities. Requires the Secretary, in awarding grants, to give preference to entities that: (1) demonstrate the capacity to attract private sector or local government funding to ensure fiscal sustainability; (2) address significant health disparities; (3) demonstrate coordination or collaboration across governmental and nongovernmental sectors; (4) are committed to promoting full transparency of all deliberations of the Technical Assistance Centers and Community Health Improvement Councils; and (5) are independent from government and the financial self-interest of health care and purchasers stakeholders.</summary>
</bill>
