<bill session="109" type="h" number="2200" updated="2013-07-19T19:23:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prescription Drug Price Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide to the Secretary of Health and Human Services authority similar to the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to negotiate the lowest possible prices for outpatient prescription drugs, to include in the determination of best price for covered outpatient drugs under the Medicaid Program prices charged by manufacturers to certain Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400349"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2005--Introduced.
Prescription Drug Price Fairness Act - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) grant the Secretary of Health and Human Services authority similar to that of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to negotiate the lowest possible prices for outpatient prescription drugs; (2) include prices charged for covered outpatient drugs to certain Federal agencies in the determination of best price for such drugs under the Medicaid program; and (3) allow States, in entering into rebate agreements with manufacturers, to form pools to negotiate price concessions from the manufacturers for covered outpatient drugs.</summary>
</bill>
