<bill session="110" type="h" number="7045" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Plan to Advance Pancreatic Cancer Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for a Pancreatic Cancer Initiative, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400124"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2008-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Introduced.
National Plan to Advance Pancreatic Cancer Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish and implement a Pancreatic Cancer Initiative to assist in coordinating activities to address the high mortality rate associated with pancreatic cancer.Requires the Secretary to establish the Interdisciplinary Pancreatic Cancer Coordinating Committee to: (1) provide advice on overall research objectives and benchmarks for pancreatic cancer research; (2) develop and annually update a strategic plan for pancreatic cancer research awareness; and (3) conduct evaluations and make recommendations to the Secretary, the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), and the Director of the National Cancer Institute regarding the prioritization and award of NIH research grants relating to pancreatic cancer.Requires the Secretary to develop a primary care provider education program on pancreatic cancer.Requires the Director of NIH and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to develop a communication tool kit for patients and their families that focuses on specific pancreatic cancer issues relating to patient choices and patient care.Allows the Secretary to award grants to research institutions for use in developing innovative compounds or technologies for the prevention, early detection, or treatment of those cancers with five-year survival rates of less than 50%. Requires the Secretary to focus on pancreatic cancer during the initial five fiscal years of awarding such grants.Allows the Secretary to designate two additional Specialized Programs of Research Excellence focusing solely on pancreatic cancer research.</summary>
</bill>
