<bill session="111" type="s" number="3394" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strengthening Entrepreneurship for America's Veterans Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the veterans' business center program, to improve the programs for veterans of the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2010-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4087"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4087-4090" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1229"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2010--Introduced.
Strengthening Entrepreneurship for America's Veterans Act of 2010 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Associate Administrator for Veterans Business Development of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish an online mechanism to assist, and coordinate and leverage the work of, veterans' assistance providers. Requires the SBA Administrator to establish a veterans' business center program to provide financial assistance to private nonprofit organizations to conduct five-year projects for the benefit of small businesses owned and controlled by veterans. Directs each organization receiving such assistance to establish a veterans' business center to provide specific assistance to veterans, service-disabled veterans, and reservists, as well as their spouses. Sets assistance limits at not less than $150,000 or more than $200,000 per organization per fiscal year. Provides matching funds requirements. Requires the Associate Administrator to conduct an annual examination of the programs and finances of each center, and authorizes the Associate Administrator to discontinue a center's funding under appropriate circumstances. Requires the Administrator to designate at least one individual in each SBA district as a veterans business ownership representative. Directs the Comptroller General to report to: (1) the congressional veterans and small business committees regarding the ability of small businesses owned and controlled by veterans to access credit; and (2) Congress an evaluation of the effectiveness of the veterans' business center program. Requires the Administrator to report to Congress at least semiannually on appointments made to, and activities of, an interagency task force established for small businesses owned and controlled by veterans and service-disabled veterans. Repeals current grant provisions providing for the establishment and implementation of outreach programs for veterans, disabled veterans, and reservists and permits any organization previously awarded such a grant to apply for a grant renewal under the provisions of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
