<bill session="111" type="s" number="795" updated="2013-07-20T00:30:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Elder Justice Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Social Security Act to enhance the social security of the Nation by ensuring adequate public-private infrastructure and to resolve to prevent, detect, treat, intervene in, and prosecute elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2009-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2009-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4331"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2006"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2009--Introduced.
Elder Justice Act of 2009 - Amends the Social Security Act to establish an Elder Justice program under title XX (Block Grants to States for Social Services). Establishes within the Office of the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) an Elder Justice Coordinating Council (EJCC). Establishes the Advisory Board on Elder Abuse, Neglect, and Exploitation. Directs the Secretary to make grants to eligible entities to establish stationary and mobile forensic centers, to develop forensic expertise regarding, and provide services relating to, elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation. Directs the Secretary to provide incentives for individuals to train for, seek, and maintain employment providing direct care in a long-term care (LTC) facility. Directs the Secretary to make grants to LTC facilities to: (1) offer continuing training and varying levels of certification to employees who provide direct care to LTC facility residents; and (2) provide bonuses or other benefits to employees who achieve certification. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to assist LTC facilities in offsetting the costs for standardized clinical health care informatics systems designed to improve patient safety and reduce adverse events and health care complications resulting from medication errors. Directs the Secretary to ensure that HHS: (1) provides funding to state and local adult protective services services offices that investigate reports of elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation; and (2) collects and disseminates related data in coordination with the Department of Justice. Establishes a program of annual adult protective services grants to states. Directs the Secretary to make grants to eligible entities to: (1) improve the capacity of state LTC ombudsman programs to respond to and resolve abuse and neglect complaints; and (2) conduct pilot programs with state or local LTC ombudsman offices. Directs the Secretary to establish programs to provide and improve ombudsman training for national organizations and state LTC ombudsman programs. Amends part A of SSA title XI to require each individual owner, operator, employee, manager, agent, or contractor of an LTC facility receiving certain federal support to report to the Secretary and local law enforcement entities any reasonable suspicion of crimes occurring in such facility. Requires the owner or operator of such an LTC facility to notify the Secretary and the appropriate state regulatory agency of a facility's impending closure, as well as a plan for the transfer and adequate relocation of facility residents. Directs the Secretary to study and report to the EJCC and appropriate congressional committees on establishing a national nurse aide registry.</summary>
</bill>
