<bill session="112" type="h" number="2006" updated="2013-07-20T01:27:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Autism Spectrum Disorders Initiative Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a National Autism Spectrum Disorders Initiative, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2011-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1128"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
National Autism Spectrum Disorders Initiative Act of 2011 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the National Autism Spectrum Disorders Initiative in the Office of the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to improve the lives of persons with autism spectrum disorders through research focused on prevention, treatment, services, and cures. Requires the Secretary to: (1) act as the primary federal official with responsibility for overseeing all NIH research on autism spectrum disorders; (2) approve the autism spectrum disorder research strategic plan developed by the Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee and be responsible for its implementation; (3) receive directly from the President and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) all funds available for autism spectrum disorder activities of NIH; (4) allocate such funds in accordance with the strategic plan; (5) allocate amounts within 30 days after receipt, to the extent practicable; (6) have authority to reallocate up to 3% of the total amount allocated as needs change and opportunities arise; (7) plan and evaluate NIH research and other activities related to autism spectrum disorders; (8) maintain communications with all relevant federal departments and agencies to ensure the timely transmission of information concerning autism spectrum disorders; and (9) carry out this Act in consultations with the heads of NIH agencies and their advisory councils and the Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee. Terminates such provisions seven years after the date of enactment of this Act. Expands authorized research for centers of excellence for autism spectrum disorders to include translational research. Requires the Director of NIH to provide for a program under which biosamples relevant to environmental exposures that are of use in research on autism spectrum disorders are donated, collected, preserved, and made available for such research.</summary>
</bill>
