<bill session="110" type="h" number="3781" updated="2013-07-19T21:37:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Biodiesel Promotion and Quality Assurance Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Clean Air Act to promote and assure the quality of biodiesel fuel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400443" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400190" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2007-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2007-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2007-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2007-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2007-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2007-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="2007-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="2007-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2007-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1616"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/9/2007--Introduced.
Biodiesel Promotion and Quality Assurance Act of 2007 - Amends the Clean Air Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to promulgate regulations to ensure that diesel fuel sold in the United States contains the volume of biodiesel specified for 2008 through 2012. Requires the Administrator to determine the volume for 2013 and thereafter based on a review of the program. Requires at least 80% of the minimum applicable volume for each of 2008 through 2012 to be biodiesel.Requires the biodiesel fuel standards to contain compliance provisions applicable to refineries, blenders, distributors, and importers. Prohibits such standards from restricting geographic areas in which biodiesel may be used or imposing any per-gallon obligation for the use of biodiesel.Authorizes the Administrator to reduce the quantity of biodiesel required by a specified amount if market circumstances would make the price of biodiesel fuel unreasonable. Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to supersede any biodiesel mandate provided in any state or local law enacted as of January 1, 2008. Requires the Administrator to: (1) promulgate regulations to ensure that only high-quality biodiesel that is consistent with appropriate International standards is introduced into commerce; and (2) establish an inspection program to ensure that biodiesel and biodiesel blends entering commerce meet such standards. Prohibits the production of distribution of biodiesel, a biodiesel blend, or any bio-based diesel replacement that does not meet American Society of Testing and Materials standards, regardless of whether the Administrator promulgates such regulations. Requires retail diesel fuel pumps to be labeled to inform consumers of the percent of biodiesel in the biodiesel blend.</summary>
</bill>
