<bill session="109" type="s" number="764" updated="2013-07-19T20:20:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preserving Access to Affordable Drugs Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve the coordination of prescription drug coverage provided under State pharmaceutical assistance programs with the prescription drug benefit provided under the medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300028"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7487"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3487-3488" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="1572"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/2005--Introduced.
Preserving Access to Affordable Drugs Act of 2005 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to permit a State Pharmaceutical Assistance Program, at the option of the State operating it, to act as the authorized representative for any part D eligible individual residing in the State who is enrolled in the Program in order to select one or more preferred prescription drug plans to enroll such an individual, so long as the individual is afforded the authority to decline such enrollment. Revises the declaration that the coordination requirements for plans providing prescription drug coverage shall not impair or prevent a prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsor or Medicare Advantage (MA) organization from applying cost management tools (including differential payments) under its own methods of operation. Declares further that a PDP sponsor or MA organization may not require a State Pharmaceutical Assistance Program or an RX plan to apply such cost management tools when coordinating benefits. Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to repeal current requirements governing the coordination of prescription drug benefits.</summary>
</bill>
