<bill session="111" type="h" number="6361" updated="2013-07-20T00:09:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Justice Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to establish a demonstration grant program for nonprofit organizations to partner with juvenile justice agencies to monitor juvenile facilities and provide youth in the facilities and their families with increased positive engagement in the system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Family Justice Act of 2010 - Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to authorize the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to award grants to family-oriented nonprofit organizations to establish panels to monitor juvenile detention and correction facilities to provide detained youth and their family members an opportunity to participate in the development of policies, procedures, and practices that will improve outcomes for youth and promote rehabilitation and transition back into the community. Sets forth requirements for grant applications and for uses of grant funds.</summary>
</bill>
