<bill session="111" type="s" number="480" updated="2013-07-20T00:27:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Regional Economic Recovery Coordination Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Office of Regional Economic Adjustment in the Department of Commerce, to assist regions affected by sudden and severe economic dislocation by coordinating Federal, State, and local resources for economic adjustment and by providing technical assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2009--Introduced.
Regional Economic Recovery Coordination Act of 2009 - Establishes in the Department of Commerce the Office of Regional Economic Adjustment, headed by a Director, to: (1) lead, support, and coordinate a program to address economic dislocation in eligible regions (regions undergoing sudden and severe economic dislocation); (2) assist in making a specified central information clearinghouse available to states and eligible regions; (3) coordinate the federal response and provide comprehensive technical assistance to eligible regions; and (4) establish an interagency regional economic adjustment working group. Requires the Director, after notification of certain plant closings or mass employee layoffs, to certify that region as an eligible region for purposes of benefits under this Act. Authorizes a region to establish a Regional Economic and Workforce Development Coordinating Committee to, among other things: (1) ascertain the severity of the region's economic dislocation; and (2) assess the region's capacity to respond to the economic dislocation and its needs as it undertakes economic adjustment. Requires the Director to assign a federal economic recovery coordinator to each eligible region. Amends the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act to require the employer involved to notify the Secretaries of Labor and Commerce of a plant closing or layoff and the number of employees affected.</summary>
</bill>
