<bill session="113" type="h" number="357" updated="2013-11-02T06:21:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GI Bill Tuition Fairness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">GI Bill Tuition Fairness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require courses of education provided by public institutions of higher education that are approved for purposes of the educational assistance programs administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to charge veterans tuition and fees at the in-State tuition rate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400279"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412502" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412516" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412563" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412529" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412540" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412518" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412575" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412519" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412449" joined="2013-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412509" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412538" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2013-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 113-94.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-03T15:59:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="66">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 66.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="257"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2013--Reported to House amended.
GI Bill Tuition Fairness Act of 2013 - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA), for purposes of the educational assistance programs administered by the Secretary, to disapprove courses of education provided by a public educational institution that does not charge tuition and fees for veterans at the same rate that is charged for in-state residents, regardless of the veteran's state of residence. Provides for the treatment of veterans enrolled in courses at such institutions before July 1, 2015. (Sec. 4) Extends through FY2018 the authorization of appropriations for: (1) a monthly assistance allowance to disabled veterans training or competing for the Paralympic Team; and (2) grants to U.S. Paralympics, Inc. (Sec. 6) Makes eligible under VA homeless veterans reintegration program those homeless veterans who are: (1) participating in the VA supported housing program for which rental assistance is provided under the United States Housing Act of 1937, and (2) veterans who are transitioning from being incarcerated. (Sec. 7) Extends from 12 to 17 years after discharge or release from active-duty service the authorized period for veterans with service-connected disabilities to enroll in certain VA vocational training and rehabilitation programs. (Sec. 8) Reauthorizes through June 30, 2018 (under current law, the authorization expires as of June 30, 2013) certain qualifying work-study activities for individuals receiving educational assistance through the VA. (Sec. 9) Sets forth the responsibilities of each Director and Assistant Director of Veterans' Employment and Training (assigned to each state by the Secretary from among personnel within the Veterans' Employment and Training Service), including: (1) monitoring the performance of veterans' training and employment programs, with special emphasis on services to disabled veterans; (2) addressing program performance deficiencies and establishing higher performance goals; and (3) reviewing program funding and assisting with funding requests. (Sec. 10) Amends provisions concerning the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense (DOD) (employment and job training assistance and related services for members of the Armed Forces being separated from active duty and their spouses) to require such Program to include: (1) information about disability-related employment and education protections, (2) instruction in the use of educational assistance entitlements, (3) testing to determine academic readiness for post-secondary education and appropriate courses, (4) instruction on the financing of post-secondary education, and (5) information on benefits provided under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) and in other subjects determined by the Secretary concerned. Requires the VA Secretary to submit to the congressional veterans committees the results of a study to determine the feasibility of providing veterans' benefits instruction at all overseas locations where such instruction is provided through a joint contract with the Secretary of Labor. (Sec. 11) Amends the VOW to Hire Heroes Act of 2011 to extend through June 30, 2014, the veterans retraining assistance program. Directs the Secretary to submit to Congress an interim report on the retraining assistance provided under such program. (Sec. 12) Directs the Secretary to increase, as of December 1, 2013, the rates of veterans' disability compensation, additional compensation for dependents, the clothing allowance for certain disabled veterans, and dependency and indemnity compensation for surviving spouses and children. Requires each such increase to be the same percentage as the increase in benefits provided under title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act, on the same effective date. (Sec. 13) Prohibits the Secretary from paying any performance award to a VA Senior Executive Service employee during FY2014-FY2018.</summary>
</bill>
