<bill session="112" type="s" number="1452" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Main Street Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote simplification and fairness in the administration and collection of sales and use taxes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2011-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2011-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5073"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5073-5076" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2701"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax reform and tax simplification"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2011--Introduced.
Main Street Fairness Act - Grants the consent of Congress to the Streamlined Sales and Use Tax Agreement (Agreement), the multistate agreement on sales and use tax collection and administration adopted on November 12, 2002. Authorizes each state that is a party to the Agreement (member state), after 10 states (comprising at least 20% of the total population of all states imposing a sales tax) have petitioned for and have become member states, to require all remote sellers not qualifying for the small seller exception to collect and remit sales and use taxes on remote sales owed to each such member state under the terms of the Agreement. Terminates such authority if the requirements of this Act cease to be satisfied or an amendment adopted to the Agreement after the enactment of this Act is inconsistent with the provisions of this Act. Allows any person affected by the Agreement to petition the Governing Board established by the Agreement for a determination of any issue arising under the Agreement. Provides for judicial review of Governing Board determinations by the United States Court of Federal Claims and grants such Court exclusive jurisdiction over actions for judicial review. Sets forth minimum requirements for simplifying the administration of multistate sales and use taxation under the Agreement. Provides for judicial review of any civil action challenging the constitutionality of this Act by a panel of three judges of a U.S. District Court. Expresses the sense of Congress that each member state under the Agreement should work with other member states to prevent double taxation where a foreign country has imposed a transaction tax on a digital good or service.</summary>
</bill>
