<bill session="110" type="s" number="1729" updated="2013-07-19T22:35:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhanced Financial Recovery and Equitable Retirement Treatment Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend titles 18 and 28 of the United States Code to provide incentives for the prompt payments of debts owed to the United States and the victims of crime by imposing surcharges on unpaid judgments owed to the United States and to the victims of crime, to provide for offsets on amounts collected by the Department of Justice for Federal agencies, to increase the amount of special assessments imposed upon convicted persons, to establish an Enhanced Financial Recovery Fund to enhance, supplement, and improve the debt collection activities of the Department of Justice, to amend title 5, United States Code, to provide to assistant United States attorneys the same retirement benefits as are afforded to Federal law enforcement officers, and for authorized purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8698"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8698-8700" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2878"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2007--Introduced.
Enhanced Financial Recovery and Equitable Retirement Treatment Act of 2007 - Imposes surcharges for unpaid criminal monetary penalties and for unpaid balances on money judgments obtained by the United States. Increases special assessments on persons convicted of certain criminal offenses against the United States.Establishes in the Treasury the Department of Justice Enhanced Financial Recovery Fund to support Department of Justice debt collection activities.Requires assistant U.S. attorneys to be treated in the same manner as federal law enforcement officers for purposes of federal employee retirement benefit provisions.</summary>
</bill>
