<bill session="110" type="s" number="1828" updated="2013-07-19T22:36:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to conduct a study of the feasibility of increasing the consumption in the United States of certain ethanol-blended gasoline.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-07-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9619-9620"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-09-17">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer with an amendment. With written report No. 110-494.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1070">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1070.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="All terrain vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Fuel storage"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine engines"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Reported to Senate amended.
Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to study and report to Congress on the feasibility of increasing consumption in the United States of ethanol-blended gasoline with levels of ethanol of not less than 10% and not more than 40%.Requires the study to evaluate: (1) production and infrastructure constraints on increasing consumption; (2) the economic, market, and energy impacts of state and regional differences in ethanol blends and of separate and distinctly-labeled fuel storage facilities and dispensers; (3) the environmental impacts of mid-level ethanol blends on evaporative and exhaust emissions from, and on the operation, durability and performance of, on-road, off-road, and marine engines, recreational boats, vehicles, and equipment (engines); and (4) the safety impacts of mid-level ethanol blends on consumers that own and operate such engines.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
