<bill session="109" type="s" number="1358" updated="2013-07-19T20:25:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Restore Scientific Integrity to Federal Research and Policymaking Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect scientific integrity in Federal research and policymaking.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2006-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2005-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2005-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2005-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2005-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2005-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2005-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2005-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/1/2005 S7851-7852"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="839"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Censorship"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research ethics"/>
    <term name="Social science research"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2005--Introduced.
Restore Scientific Integrity to Federal Research and Policymaking Act - Prohibits a federal employee from engaging in: (1) tampering with the conduct of federally funded scientific research or analysis; (2) censorship of findings of such research or analysis; or (3) directing the dissemination of scientific information known by the directing employee to be false or misleading. Sets forth a penalty for violations of such prohibition. Includes under prohibited personnel practices the taking or failing to take, or threatening to take or failing to take, a personnel action with respect to any employee because of: (1) the development or dissemination, within the scope of employment, of scientific research or analysis that the employee reasonably believes to be accurate and valid; (2) any disclosure of information by an employee or applicant which the employee or applicant reasonably believes evidences an abuse of authority, including but not limited to, tampering with the conduct of federally funded scientific research or analysis, censoring the findings of such research or analysis, or directing the dissemination of scientific information known by the directing employee to be false or misleading. Sets forth requirements relating to federal scientific advisory committees. States that all appointments to such committees shall be made without regard to political affiliation, unless required by federal statute. Directs each federal agency to determine a peer review process that is appropriate for the agency's functions and needs. Prohibits "The Information Quality Bulletin for Peer Review", issued on December 16, 2004, from applying to any agency that has established its own peer review process. Prohibits the Office of Management and Budget from taking any action to discourage an agency from determining and establishing a peer-review process appropriate for its needs. Requires the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to provide annual reports regarding scientific integrity.</summary>
</bill>
