<bill session="111" type="h" number="3482" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Renewable Energy Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make renewable energy production a priority on certain public lands for the purpose of responsibly producing clean, affordable power for the American people.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412218"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2009--Introduced.
Renewable Energy Development Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a program for the leasing of federal lands to advance, develop, assess, install, and operate commercial renewable solar, wind, and geothermal energy systems. Requires the Secretary to: (1) identify lease sites comprised of a total of 6,400,000 acres under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in the states of Arizona, California, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, New Mexico, Nevada, Oregon, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming which are suitable for the installation and operation of solar, wind, or geothermal energy systems; and (2) incorporate renewable energy development into the relevant agency's land use and resource management plans, or equivalent plans for the identified lands. Specifies the total annual amount of acreage that is to be released for leasing under this Act from 2010 to 2019. Excludes specified federal lands from inclusion within the program. Sets forth requirements for competitive leasing sales and noncompetitive leasing of the lands to be leased. Makes any lease of lands under this Act effective for a 30-year period. Directs the Secretary to complete a programmatic environmental impact statement for the program and to publish a final regulation to implement this Act. Directs the Secretary to study: (1) barriers to additional access to federal lands for the transmission of energy produced under leases awarded under such program; and (2) the need for energy transmission corridors on public lands to address identified congestion or constraints.</summary>
</bill>
