<bill session="109" type="s" number="3552" updated="2013-07-19T20:44:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Christen O'Donnell Equestrian Helmet Safety Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to encourage and ensure the use of safe equestrian helmets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2006-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Head injuries"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2006--Introduced.
Christen O'Donnell Equestrian Helmet Safety Act of 2006 - Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to award grants to states, political subdivisions, Indian tribes and organizations, public organizations, and private nonprofit organizations for activities that encourage individuals to wear approved equestrian helmets. Requires the Secretary to report to the appropriate congressional committees on the effectiveness of such grants. Establishes an interim standard for equestrian helmets manufactured nine months after enactment of this Act pending establishment of a final standard. Directs the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to begin rulemaking proceedings for development of a final standard. Excludes such proceedings from specified laws governing the CPSC's reliance on voluntary standards, the development of consumer product safety rules, and the CPSC's regulation of consumer products in accordance with other laws. Prohibits application of judicial review provisions to any standard issued pursuant to such proceedings. Requires any failure to meet the interim standard to be treated as a violation of a consumer product safety standard promulgated under the Consumer Product Safety Act (CPSA). Requires any final standard to be considered a CPSA consumer product safety standard.</summary>
</bill>
