<bill session="113" type="h" number="3046" updated="2013-11-02T06:44:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Health Care Tax Credit Improvement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand and simplify the credit for employee health insurance expenses of small employers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
Small Business Health Care Tax Credit Improvement Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the tax credit for the health insurance expenses of small employers, to: (1) expand the eligibility of such employers for the credit by allowing them to have up to 50 full-time employees (currently, limited to no more than 25 full-time employees); (2) modify the phaseout of such credit based upon increases in the number of eligible employees and the employer's average annual wages; (3) increase the average annual wage limitation for 2013 and subsequent years; (4) repeal the requirement that employers make uniform contributions of at least 50% of each employee's premium to qualify for the tax credit; and (5) repeal the limitation on such credit based on the average premium in the small group market in the rating area in which an employee enrolls for coverage.</summary>
</bill>
