<bill session="109" type="h" number="886" updated="2013-07-19T19:12:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tariff Relief Assistance for Developing Economies Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TRADE Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To extend certain trade preferences to certain least-developed countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400226"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2006-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2005-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2006-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2006-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2006-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2006-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400420" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="2006-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="191"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Bangladesh"/>
    <term name="Bhutan"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="East Timor"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Kiribati"/>
    <term name="Laos"/>
    <term name="Maldives"/>
    <term name="Nepal"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Samoa"/>
    <term name="Solomon Islands"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Sri Lanka"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Tuvalu"/>
    <term name="Vanuatu"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2005--Introduced.
Tariff Relief Assistance for Developing Economies Act of 2005 (TRADE Act of 2005) - Authorizes the President to designate Afghanistan, Bangladesh, Bhutan, Cambodia, Kiribati, Lao People's Democratic Republic, Maldives, Nepal, Samoa, Solomon Islands, Timor-Leste (East Timor), Tuvalu, Vanuatu, Yemen, and Sri Lanka or their successor political entities as TRADE Act of 2005 beneficiary countries eligible to receive duty-free treatment for certain articles that are the growth, product, or manufacture of such countries, if after receiving the advice of the International Trade Commission (ITC) the President determines that such articles are not import-sensitive in the context of imports from such countries. Basis such designation upon eligibility requirements of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA) and theTrade Act of 1974. Prescribes the rule of origin for such articles for the duty-free treatment. Applies duty-free treatment, without any quantitative limitations, and under certain conditions, to textile and apparel articles assembled in one or more TRADE Act of 2005 beneficiary countries, apparel articles from regional fabric or yarns, and sweaters knit-to-shape from cashmere or merino wool that are imported directly into the U.S. customs territory from TRADE Act of 2005 beneficiary countries if the countries have satisfied AGOA protections against transshipment requirements. Applies duty-free treatment for apparel articles assembled in one or more TRADE Act of 2005 beneficiary countries if their assembly meets specified U.S. origin requirements. Establishes: (1) limitations on such preferential treatment; and (2) special rules for apparel articles wholly assembled in one or more TRADE Act of 2005 beneficiary countries or former beneficiary countries (or both) regardless of the country of origin of the yarn or fabric used to make such articles; and (3) applicable percentages of such benefits. Applies the AGOA surge mechanism (requiring the Secretary of Commerce to monitor imports of apparel articles from regional fabric or yarns and to make certain determinations) with respect to the preferential treatment extended to TRADE Act of 2005 beneficiary countries. Grants duty-free treatment to certain sweaters knit-to-shape from cashmere or merino wool and other specified apparel articles.</summary>
</bill>
