<bill session="113" type="h" number="1221" updated="2013-11-02T06:29:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Basel III Capital Impact Study Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Federal banking agencies to conduct an impact study on the cumulative effect of certain provisions of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act before issuing final rules amending the agencies' general risk-based capital requirements for determining risk-weighted assets as proposed in the Standardized Approach for Risk Weighted Assets Notice of Proposed Rulemaking and the Advanced Approaches Risk-based Capital Rule; Market Risk Capital Rule Notice of Proposed Rulemaking, and the Implementation of Basel III, Minimum Regulatory Capital Ratios Notice of Proposed Rulemaking issued in June 2012, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412479"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412388" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2013-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E310"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="737"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2013--Introduced.
Basel III Capital Impact Study Act - Directs the federal banking agencies (the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation [FDIC]), prior to issuing any final rule amending the agencies' general risk-based capital requirements for determining risk-weighted assets and minimum regulatory capital ratios as proposed in certain June 2012 notices of proposed rule making, to study and report regarding the impact of the approaches on the minimum regulatory capital requirements of insured depository institutions and insured depository institution holding companies. Requires the banking agencies to separately identify provisions of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (Dodd-Frank) that affect capital quality, capital levels, asset quality, and the risk management activities of insured depository institutions and insured depository holding companies and take into consideration the impact of such provisions. Specifies Dodd-Frank provisions to be included. Permits the banking agencies to solicit participation in the study from insured depository institutions and insured depository institution holding companies on a voluntary basis. Amends the International Lending Supervision Act of 1983 to revise capital adequacy requirements by directing the banking agencies to seek to ensure that any differences in rules implementing the capital standards do not: (1) give competitive advantages to any class or group of institutions unless otherwise required by federal law, or (2) undermine Dodd-Frank requirements for enhanced supervision and prudential standards.</summary>
</bill>
