<bill session="113" type="s" number="975" updated="2013-11-02T07:00:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Court-Appointed Guardian Accountability and Senior Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the inclusion of court-appointed guardianship improvement and oversight activities under the Elder Justice Act of 2009.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2013-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/2013--Introduced.
Court-Appointed Guardian Accountability and Senior Protection Act - Amends title XX (Block Grants to States for Social Services and Elder Justice) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to the highest courts of states to conduct demonstration programs that: (1) assess adult guardianship and conservatorship proceedings, including the appointment and the monitoring of the performance of court-appointed guardians and conservators; and (2) implement changes deemed necessary as a result of the assessments, such as mandating background checks for all potential guardians and conservators, and establishing systems that enable electronic filing and review of the annual accountings and other required conservatorship and guardianship filings. Requires the highest court of a state awarded such a grant to collaborate with the state's own Unit on Aging and its Adult Protective Services agency in conducting the demonstration program.</summary>
</bill>
