<bill session="111" type="s" number="3928" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commercial Seafood Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to strengthen Federal consumer product safety programs and activities with respect to commercially-marketed seafood by directing the Secretary of Commerce to coordinate with the Federal Trade Commission and other appropriate Federal agencies to strengthen and coordinate those programs and activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2010-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1370"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Commercial Seafood Consumer Protection Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) to strengthen federal activities for ensuring that commercially distributed seafood meets federal food quality and safety requirements. Directs the Secretary and other appropriate federal agencies to enter into agreements to strengthen interagency cooperation on seafood safety, labeling, and fraud, including regarding examining and testing seafood imports, inspections of foreign facilities, establishing a distribution chain tracking system, data sharing, and public outreach. Requires the Secretary, the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), and heads of other appropriate federal agencies to submit an annual report to Congress concerning the implementation of such agreements and the budget, personnel, and any additional authorities necessary to improve seafood safety and labeling and prevent seafood fraud. Directs the Secretary and the Chairman to submit to Congress a joint report on consumer protection activities, enforcement measures, and coordination efforts with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). Requires NOAA to report deceptive seafood marketing and fraud to the FTC. Directs the Secretary to increase the number of laboratories certified to Food and Drug Administration (FDA) standards. Authorizes the Secretary to increase the number and capacity of laboratories operated by NOAA involved in testing and other activities under this Act. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), subject to exceptions, to: (1) refuse imports of seafood originating from certain countries or exporters; and (2) increase the percentage of seafood tested originating from such countries. Authorizes the Secretary to send inspectors to an originating country or exporter to assess seafood practices and processes and to provide technical assistance related to U.S. requirements. Requires the development and publication of an annual list of standardized names to identify seafood at the distribution, marketing, and consumer retail stages.</summary>
</bill>
