<bill session="112" type="h" number="4344" updated="2013-07-20T01:47:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Commission on Missing Persons Assistance Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of State to assist the International Commission on Missing Persons to establish a permanent and international legal status with the immunities required for operations globally, to continue the financial support of the United States of the ICMP in their work to assist governments and other authorities in locating and identifying persons missing as a result of conflicts or natural or man-made disasters, to support the investigation of genocide and mass atrocities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2012-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2012-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2012-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2012--Introduced.
International Commission on Missing Persons Assistance Act of 2012 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the United States should support the work of the International Commission on Missing Persons (ICMP) to clarify the fate of persons missing as a result of conflict and natural and man-made disasters, (2) the United States should support the expansion of the ICMP's mandate to include assistance to governments in locating persons missing for involuntary reasons, (3) the President should enunciate a policy of assisting the ICMP in establishing a permanent and internationally recognized legal status, and (4) the Secretary of State shall make every effort to advance this proposal at the United Nations (U.N.). Directs the Secretary to report to Congress regarding such activities.</summary>
</bill>
