<bill session="112" type="s" number="3474" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Students from Worthless Degrees Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide consumer protection for students.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2012-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2012-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-08-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="6717"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2012--Introduced.
Protecting Students from Worthless Degrees Act - Makes any institution of higher education (IHE) postsecondary program designed to prepare students for a recognized occupation or profession requiring licensing or other entry pre-conditions ineligible to participate in a federal financial assistance program, unless it meets specified student consumer protection requirements. Requires each program to: (1) fully prepare students to satisfy those entry pre-conditions in the state in which the program is operated and in any state the program claims a successful program graduate will be prepared to work in the particular occupation or profession involved; (2) provide timely placement of students in required pre-licensure positions, such as internships or apprenticeships; and (3) meet specialized state accreditation requirements, or notify students if the program has not yet been fully accredited. Requires an IHE to notify out-of-state applicants as to whether or not its program satisfies the requirements of the applicant's state.</summary>
</bill>
