<bill session="109" type="h" number="3032" updated="2013-07-19T19:31:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TV Truth Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require manufacturers and retailers to provide disclosure to consumers that analog televisions will no longer receive broadcast transmissions after the public broadcast spectrum changes to digital after December 31, 2006.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400160"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2005-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Telecommunications and the Internet" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television relay systems"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2005--Introduced.
TV Truth Act of 2005 - Makes it unlawful for a manufacturer to ship in interstate commerce an analog television unless there is displayed clearly and conspicuously, as a removable label on the screen of such television, a disclosure, in both English and Spanish, stating that such analog television will no longer receive a broadcast signal without additional equipment as early as December 31, 2006, when federal law will require broadcast television transmission to change from analog to digital service (with a Federal Communications Commission (FCC) phone number for further information). Makes it unlawful for any distributor to sell at retail or rent such a television unless the distributor places adjacent to such television a sign containing such disclosure. Provides for enforcement through the Federal Trade Commission.</summary>
</bill>
