<bill session="109" type="s" number="3638" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Water Recycling and Riverside-Corona Feeder Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Inland Empire Regional Water Recycling Initiative</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to encourage the Secretary of the Interior to participate in projects to plan, design, and construct water supply projects and to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to encourage the design, planning, and construction of projects to treat impaired surface water, reclaim and reuse impaired groundwater, and provide brine disposal in the State of California.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7336-7337"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7337-7338" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-738.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="802"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="1008"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="746"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wells"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2006--Introduced.
Water Recycling and Riverside-Corona Feeder Act of 2006 - Inland Empire Regional Water Recycling Initiative - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior: (1) in cooperation with the Inland Empire Utilities Agency, to participate in the design, planning, and construction (design) of the Inland Empire regional water recycling project, California; (2) in cooperation with the Cucamonga Valley Water District, to participate in the design of the Cucamonga Valley Water District satellite recycling plants in Rancho Cucamonga to reclaim and recycle approximately two million gallons per day of domestic wastewater; (3) in cooperation with the Yucaipa Valley Water District, to participate in the design of projects to treat impaired surface water, reclaim and reuse impaired groundwater, and provide brine disposal within the Santa Ana Watershed; and (4) in cooperation with the City of Corona Water Utility, to participate in the design of, and land acquisition for, a project to reclaim and reuse wastewater, including degraded groundwaters, within and outside of the City. Limits the federal cost share of each project to 25%. Authorizes the Secretary, in cooperation with the Western Municipal Water District, to participate in a project to design the Riverside-Corona Feeder, which includes 20 groundwater wells and 28 miles of pipeline in San Bernardino and Riverside Counties, California. Limits the federal share of the project design and planning study costs.</summary>
</bill>
