<bill session="112" type="s" number="882" updated="2013-07-20T02:24:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">STOP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Trafficking of Pills Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prevent misuse, overutilization, and trafficking of prescription drugs by limiting access to such drugs for Medicare and Medicaid beneficiaries who have been identified as high-risk prescription drug users.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/2011--Introduced.
Stop Trafficking of Pills Act or STOP Act - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require state Medicaid plans to: (1) identify prescription drugs that present a high-risk of misuse or overutilization, (2) establish a dosage level for each such drug that would be deemed excessive in the absence of evidence of medical necessity, (3) identify Medicaid-eligible individuals who are either receiving a prescription drug at excessive dosage levels or who have been convicted of a drug-related offense, and (4) ensure that they are assigned to a state-established restricted recipient program. Requires a state to establish a Medicaid Lock-in Program to ensure that a high-risk prescription drug user is assigned to: (1) a single and exclusive physician for purposes of receiving any medical assistance related to a prescription drug, and (2) a single and exclusive pharmacy to receive any physician-prescribed drug. Requires a state to establish a Medicaid prescription drug restriction program to ensure that the state claims processing system does not permit a prescription drug to be dispensed to a high-risk prescription drug user more than once every 20 days. Amends part D (Miscellaneous) of SSA title XXVIII (Medicare) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a similar restricted recipient program for high-risk prescription drug users under the Medicare program.</summary>
</bill>
