<bill session="112" type="s" number="689" updated="2013-07-20T02:22:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Security Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote the oil independence of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2011--Introduced.
Energy Security Act of 2011 - Establishes in the Executive Office of the President the national energy security program to coordinate federal government activities and policies to ensure that the United States meets goals for reducing oil dependence, oil imports, and oil consumption as well as other energy policy goals. Declares it is the goal of the United States to reduce oil consumption by 2030 by an amount equal to or greater than the quantity of oil imported from outside of North America. Directs the President, in coordination with the National Energy Security Council (established by this Act) and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), to develop a national oil independence plan, which shall be updated biennially. Directs the President to review existing federal programs and authorities (including tax policies) to determine: (1) which of them could be used to accelerate reductions in oil dependence, and (2) the means to maximize such reductions. Establishes in the Executive Office of the President the National Energy Security Council.</summary>
</bill>
