<bill session="111" type="h" number="3337" updated="2013-07-19T23:42:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Post-9/11 Veterans' Job Training Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the use of entitlement under Post-9/11 Veterans Educational Assistance Program for the pursuit of apprenticeships and on-job training.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412299" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2009-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2009-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2928"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="2769"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2009--Introduced.
Post-9/11 Veterans' Job Training Act of 2009 - Amends requirements for the Post-9/11 Veterans Educational Assistance Program to entitle an eligible veteran of the Armed Forces (including eligible dependents) pursuing a full-time educational program of apprenticeship or other on-job training to a monthly benefit payment equal to: (1) 75% of the monthly benefit payment otherwise payable to such individual for each of the first six months of the program; (2) 55% of such payment for each of the second six months of the program; and (3) 35% of such payment for each of the months following the first 12 months of the program. Reduces the payment an individual receives in any month in which the individual fails to complete 120 hours of training under the program of education. Entitles an eligible veteran of the Armed Forces receiving such monthly benefit to receive also a monthly housing stipend equal to the basic allowance for housing payable for an Armed Forces member with dependents in pay grade E-5 residing in the military housing area that encompasses the ZIP code area in which the individual resides. Requires an individual's entitlement for each monthly benefit payment to be charged at the rate of: (1) 75% of a month for each of the first six months of the program; (2) 55% of a month for each of the second six months of the program; and (3) 35% of a month for each of the months following the first 12 months of the program.</summary>
</bill>
