<bill session="109" type="s" number="4038" updated="2013-07-19T20:48:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Resources, Environment, and Security Commission Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the bipartisan and independent Commission on Global Resources, Environment, and Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300086"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10738-10739"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S10739-10741" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental degradation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Population"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Introduced.
Global Resources, Environment, and Security Commission Act of 2006 - Establishes the Commission on Global Resources, Environment, and Security, a bipartisan and independent commission that will make recommendations for a coordinated, comprehensive, and long-range national policy for new and existing strategies initiated by the United States to promote global environmental security. Requires the Commission to report to the President and Congress on its findings and conclusions. Authorizes the Commission to establish a multidisciplinary science, economic, and technical advisory panel. Requires the panel to ensure that the scientific information considered by the Commission is based on the best available data. Encourages the Commission, Congress, and federal agencies to continue the dialogue about global environmental security after the Commission is terminated (30 days after the submittal of its report to Congress) and to examine institutional needs, including the formation of a new office. Requires the President to submit to Congress and agencies a report containing a statement of proposals to carry out or respond to the Commission's recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
