<bill session="109" type="h" number="4014" updated="2013-07-19T19:39:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Millennium Challenge Reauthorization Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Millennium Challenge Reauthorization Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2005-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-06-27">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13T19:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on International Relations. H. Rept. 109-563.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-07-13T19:10:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="319">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 319.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/2006--Reported to House amended.
Millennium Challenge Reauthorization Act of 2006 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 to eliminate the provision allowing appointment of an interim Chief Executive Officer of the Millennium Challenge Corporation (MCC). (Sec. 4) Extends the prohibition on funding related to abortions and involuntary sterilizations through FY2007. (Sec. 5) Revises Millennium Challenge Compact provisions to: (1) require an analysis of how the intended beneficiaries will participate in, or be impacted by, each project, and an analysis how each project will contribute to poverty reduction; (2) provide for consultation with a country's national legislature; (3) allow Compact duration to extend beyond five years (but not beyond ten) subject to a Board determination and congressional notification; and (4) allow concurrent Compacts subject to Board determination of demonstrable progress, and subsequent Compacts subject to Board determination of substantial meeting of prior Compact objectives. (Sec. 6) Requires the Board: (1) not later than 15 days prior to signing a Compact with an eligible country to provide the appropriate congressional committees with the text and a detailed summary of the Compact; and (2) to publish such summary in the Federal Register and make it and the text available on the Board website. (Sec. 7) Provides that information regarding minority staffing and minority and disadvantaged representation in procurement contracts shall be included in the annual report. (Sec. 8) Provides for minority and disadvantaged representation in the provision of MCC goods and services. (Sec. 9) Makes the funding obligation for assistance to certain candidate countries permanent. (Sec. 10) Authorizes appropriations through FY2009.</summary>
</bill>
