<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1220" updated="2013-07-19T21:01:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Honoring the lives of Dr. Victor Westphall and Mrs. Jeanne Westphall and their contributions to the Nation's veterans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR  E1058"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
    <term name="Vietnam veterans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2008--Introduced.
Recognizes the contributions made by Dr. Victor Westphall and Mrs. Jeanne Westphall to honor all veterans and memorialize the sacrifices made during the Vietnam War. Honors the memory of Dr. and Mrs. Westphall, both of whom embodied outstanding principles, courage, and service. Encourages the National Park Service of the Department of the Interior, which manages the Vietnam Veterans National Memorial, to seek collaboration and partnership with the Vietnam Veterans Memorial State Park in New Mexico, as appropriate, as a way of honoring in an enduring way Dr. and Mrs. Westphall and all Vietnam veterans for their contribution and service to the nation.</summary>
</bill>
