<bill session="111" type="h" number="5679" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">End the Stimulus Advertisement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prevent funding from the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 from being used for physical signage indicating that a project is funded by such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412314"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400242" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2010-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6403"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/2010--Introduced.
End the Stimulus Advertisement Act - Prohibits the use of funds appropriated or otherwise made available under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (ARRA) for physical signage indicating that a project is funded by such Act. States that under appropriations Acts providing funds for each of FY2011-FY2012 the total amount available for obligation for administrative expenses of an affected agency shall be the amount that would otherwise be available, reduced by 50% of the amount reported to have been expended before the enactment of this Act. Requires the head of each affected agency to report to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) a determination of the amount of funds expended before the enactment of this Act, if any, by the agency, or any grantee or other recipient of assistance from the agency, for physical signage indicating that a project was funded by the ARRA. Requires OMB to determine, and report to Congress on, the allocation of such reduction among the accounts, and programs, projects, and activities within the accounts of each affected agency. Requires the head of each affected agency to deposit each amount of the reduction in the general fund of the Treasury for purposes of deficit reduction.</summary>
</bill>
