<bill session="112" type="s" number="3439" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Wi-Net Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 40, United States Code, to direct the Administrator of General Services to install Wi-Fi hotspots and wireless neutral host systems in all Federal buildings in order to improve in-building wireless communications coverage and commercial network capacity by offloading wireless traffic onto wireline broadband networks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2012-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5385-5386"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="455"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2012--Introduced.
Federal Wi-Net Act - Directs the Administrator of General Services (GSA) to: (1) install Wi-Fi hotspots (areas where the public can access a wireless Internet connection) in all publicly accessible federal buildings constructed after enactment of this Act; (2) allow for the installation of wireless neutral host systems (small cellular communications base stations for improved cellular coverage within a building) by any eligible carriers upon request in all publicly accessible federal buildings; and (3) by December 31, 2015, retrofit all federal buildings constructed prior to enactment of this Act. Makes specified amounts available from the Federal Buildings Fund to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
