<bill session="111" type="s" number="3427" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pre-Paid Mobile Device Identification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to institute an identification requirement for the purchase of pre-paid mobile devices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2010-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2010--Introduced.
Pre-Paid Mobile Device Identification Act - Defines "authorized reseller" as any person authorized by a: (1) manufacturer to sell the manufacturer's mobile device or SIM card (subscriber identity module or equivalent data storage device); or (2) wireless carrier to sell pre-paid mobile devices or SIM cards to which the wireless carrier will provide wireless cellular service. Directs an authorized reseller before selling a pre-paid mobile device or SIM card to: (1) require the purchaser to provide the purchaser's name, address, and date of birth; (2) verify such information; and (3) record and transmit such sale information to the wireless carrier who shall keep a record of the transmission. Subjects: (1) a person who provides false information to criminal penalties; and (2) a non-complying authorized reseller or wireless carrier to civil fines. Makes it unlawful for any person who is not an authorized reseller to sell pre-paid mobile devices or SIM cards. Subjects a violator to fine, imprisonment, or both. States that if a person uses a pre-paid mobile device or SIM card obtained in violation of this Act to commit a federal criminal offense the minimum prison term for such offense required under federal statute shall be increased by one year.</summary>
</bill>
