<bill session="109" type="s" number="1195" updated="2013-07-19T20:23:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Offshore Aquaculture Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide the necessary authority to the Secretary of Commerce for the establishment and implementation of a regulatory system for offshore aquaculture in the United States Exclusive Economic Zone, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2005-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6228"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Ocean mining"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s766"/>
    <amendment number="s767"/>
    <amendment number="s768"/>
    <amendment number="s769"/>
    <amendment number="s1727"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/8/2005--Introduced.
National Offshore Aquaculture Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) to establish a site and operating permit process to make areas of the U.S. Exclusive Economic Zone available to persons to develop and operate offshore aquaculture facilities. Excludes offshore aquaculture from certain fishery conservation requirements under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) establish permit fees; and (2) modify or suspend such permits. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to aquaculture operations located on facilities subject to the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, to: (1) enforce all requirements contained in federal mineral leases and regulations issued pursuant to such Act; (2) require and enforce additional conditions necessary to protect the marine environment, property, or human life or health; and (3) issue orders to any offshore aquaculture permit holder to take appropriate action to ensure safe oil and gas or other mineral operations on such facility. Sets forth certain environmental requirements for offshore aquaculture facilities. Authorizes the Secretary to establish an integrated, multidisciplinary, scientific research and development (R&amp;D) program to further offshore aquaculture technologies compatible with the protection of marine ecosystems. Makes it unlawful for any person to: (1) falsify any information required to be reported, or any regulation or permit issued, under this Act; (2) engage in offshore aquaculture within the U.S. Exclusive Economic Zone except in full compliance with this Act; or (3) violate any provision of this Act. Sets forth civil and criminal penalties for violations of this Act. Provides for judicial review of civil penalties or permit sanctions.</summary>
</bill>
