<bill session="111" type="h" number="6245" updated="2013-07-20T00:08:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Effective Law Enforcement Through Transparent Interrogations Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to require the electronic recording of custodial interrogations in Federal criminal cases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Effective Law Enforcement Through Transparent Interrogations Act of 2010 - Amends the federal criminal code to render inadmissible as evidence in the prosecution of a federal felony all prior and subsequent statements by an individual during a custodial interrogation that are not electronically recorded, except where the recording of such statements is impracticable due to an imminent threat of bodily injury or other exigent circumstances. Requires the Attorney General to: (1) make a copy of the electronic recording of a custodial interrogation available to the individual who was subject to such interrogation; (2) identify and catalogue any such recording; and (3) preserve such recording until all related proceedings are final or the applicable statute of limitations has expired.</summary>
</bill>
