<bill session="109" type="h" number="4271" updated="2013-07-19T19:42:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Modifications to the Pima County Wastewater Management Regional Treatment System for Improved Reclaimed Water Production Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in modifications to the Pima County Wastewater Management Regional Treatment System for Improved Reclaimed Water Production.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400162"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/2005--Introduced.
Modifications to the Pima County Wastewater Management Regional Treatment System for Improved Reclaimed Water Production Act - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, in cooperation with Pima County, Arizona, to participate in the planning, design, and construction of modifications to water recycling facilities and to provide advanced treatment for production of reclaimed water for use in environmental restoration, recharge and reclaimed water projects for the towns, cities, and unincorporated areas of Pima County. Limits the federal share to 25% of the cost of the project. Prohibits the use of federal funds for project operation or maintenance.</summary>
</bill>
