<bill session="111" type="h" number="3526" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tony Cardenas Community-Based Gang Intervention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide definitions of terms and services related to community-based gang intervention to ensure that funding for such intervention is utilized in a cost-effective manner and that community-based agencies are held accountable for providing holistic, integrated intervention services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400423"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2010-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2010-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2009--Introduced.
Tony Cardenas Community-Based Gang Intervention Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States must acknowledge and address social conditions such as poverty, homelessness, inadequate educational systems, and limited economic opportunities in developing a comprehensive gang violence reduction strategy. Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to: (1) require the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to award grants to nonprofit community-based gang intervention agencies to provide services for reducing and stopping gang-related and gang-motivated violence and crime; (2) include representatives of community-based gang intervention agencies in juvenile justice and delinquency prevention advisory groups established by state plans; and (3) include community-based gang intervention and prevention activities in state and local grant programs for delinquency prevention.</summary>
</bill>
