<bill session="110" type="h" number="999" updated="2013-07-19T21:12:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the Secretary of Agriculture to release the reversionary interest of the United States on certain land in the State of Florida if encroachments and trespassing have occurred on that land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400279"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400051" joined="2007-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/2007--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, if the State of Florida notifies the Secretary that encroachments by improvements or occupation have occurred before July 13, 2006, on one or more of the parcels of real property described in this Act, to release to Florida any reversionary interest of the United States in and to any identified parcel without further federal administrative review or analysis. Bars the United States from receiving any funds as consideration for the release of the reversionary interests specified above. Requires all net proceeds from the disposition of such real property to be used by the State for the acquisition of other lands adjacent to the exterior boundaries of Blackwater River State Forest and Withlacoochee State Forest. Requires: (1) any lands so acquired to become a part of the state forest; and (2) that the acquired lands be used for public purposes. Requires the State to agree to indemnify and hold the United States harmless with regard to any boundary disputes related to any parcel released under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
