<bill session="111" type="h" number="1707" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Helping HANDS for Autism Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Helping Housing, Awareness, and Navigation Demonstration Services for Individuals With Autism Spectrum Disorders Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase housing, awareness, and navigation demonstration services (HANDS) for individuals with autism spectrum disorders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2009-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400439" joined="2009-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="706"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2009--Introduced.
Helping Housing, Awareness, and Navigation Demonstration Services for Individuals With Autism Spectrum Disorders Act of 2009 or the Helping HANDS for Autism Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a demonstration program to award grants to eligible entities to develop an autism navigator program to create a more efficient, effective, coordinated use of the health, housing, education, and social service systems for individuals with an autism spectrum disorder. Directs the Secretary to determine the functions of autism navigators, which may include: (1) case management and psychosocial assessment and care; (2) notifying individuals of autism clinical trials; (3) helping individuals overcome barriers in accessing and securing appropriate services in a timely manner; and (4) coordinating with relevant departments providing services to individuals with an autism spectrum disorder and their families. Requires a navigator program to provide centralized access for individuals with an autism spectrum disorder to multiple federal and state activities and programs related to autism spectrum disorders. Requires grantees to collect autism data and ensure confidentiality. Directs the Secretary to: (1) disseminate a standard curriculum for training first responders in assisting individuals with autism and other cognitive behavioral disabilities and their families during emergencies; and (2) award grants to states and local governments for such training. Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to provide for a program for adults with autism spectrum disorder with the goal of providing individualized housing and services.</summary>
</bill>
