<bill session="112" type="h" number="6400" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">RDOCS Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Restoring the Doctors of Our Country through Scholarships Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize grants to States for the purpose of assisting the States in operating an RDOCS program in order to provide for the increased availability of primary health care services in health professional shortage areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2012-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2012-11-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2012-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1524"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/2012--Introduced.
Restoring the Doctors of Our Country through Scholarships Act of 2012 or the RDOCS Act of 2012 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants under which states provide RDOCS scholarships, paying all costs of a student's undergraduate medical education, to provide for the increased availability of primary health care services in health professional shortage areas. Requires the scholarship recipient to agree to residency training in a primary care specialty and a five-year post-graduate period of service in a health professional shortage area. Requires that preference be given in award of scholarships to applicants enrolled in: (1) an accelerated track family-medicine program (an integrated course of study allowing completion of undergraduate medical education and graduate medical education in six years), or (2) a program that includes clinical training in rural or underserved urban communities. Sets a minimum rate at which federal funding must be matched.</summary>
</bill>
