<bill session="111" type="h" number="238" updated="2013-07-19T23:13:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Notch Baby Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide for an improved benefit computation formula for workers affected by the changes in benefit computation rules enacted in the Social Security Amendments of 1977 who attain age 65 during the 10-year period after 1981 and before 1992 (and related beneficiaries) and to provide prospectively for increases in their benefits accordingly.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400121"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2010-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/2009--Introduced.
Notch Baby Act of 2009 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act with respect to the benefit computation formula for individuals affected by the changes in benefit computation rules enacted in the Social Security Amendments of 1977 who became eligible (at age 62) for (early retirement) old-age insurance benefits after 1978 and before 1989 (and reached age 65 for full-retirement benefits after 1981 and before 1992). Sets forth a schedule of additional benefit increases for such beneficiaries (and related beneficiaries), with percentages declining from 60% to 10% keyed to the year an individual became eligible for (early retirement) benefits between 1978 and 1989.</summary>
</bill>
