<bill session="109" type="s" number="3698" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Warming Pollution Reduction Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to reduce emissions of carbon dioxide, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300057"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2006-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2006-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2006-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="2006-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8051-8052"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8052-8059" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Cogeneration of electric power and heat"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional delegations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Emissions trading"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy consumption"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fluorocarbons"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Ocean energy resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2006--Introduced.
Global Warming Pollution Reduction Act - Amends the Clean Air Act to set forth provisions concerning global warming pollution emissions. Directs the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) set milestones to reduce the aggregate net levels of emissions (authorizes EPA to establish market-based programs to achieve such reduction); (2) require each fleet of automobiles sold by a manufacturer beginning in model year 2016 to meet emission standards; (3) contract with the National Academy of Sciences to study the potential contribution of the non-highway portion of the transportation sector towards meeting the emission reduction goal; (4) require that electric generation units meet an emission standard that is not higher than the emission rate of a new combined cycle natural gas generating unit; and (5) establish a low-carbon generation trading program. Requires covered generators to provide a minimum percentage of the base quantity of electricity produced for sale from low-carbon generation. Requires EPA to: (1) establish a competitive grant program for geological disposal deployment projects; and (2) carry out a global climate change standards and processes research program. Expresses the sense of the Senate that federal funds for clean, low-carbon energy research, development, and deployment should be increased by at least 100% each year for 10 years. Directs: (1) EPA to promulgate requirements concerning the energy efficiency and peak load reduction of electricity suppliers and to establish a renewable energy credit program; (2) the Secretary of Agriculture to establish standards for accrediting certified reductions in carbon dioxide emissions through biological sequestration activities; and (3) major stationary sources to report to EPA on emissions of global warming pollutants. Requires the President to establish the Task Force on International Clean, Low Carbon Energy Cooperation. Authorizes the President to adjust, suspend, or waive any regulation promulgated pursuant to this Act in a national emergency. Requires EPA to require that gasoline contain the applicable volume of low-carbon renewable fuel. Directs EPA to require manufacturers to meet standards for new motor vehicles or engines. Requires executive agency automobiles to be as fuel-efficient as practicable. Requires: (1) the Secretary of Commerce to report on the effects of U.S. failure to adopt measures that require or result in a reduction in total emissions in accordance with the goals of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change; (2) the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to require securities issuers to inform investors of risks relating to global warming; and (3) the SEC to clarify that U.S. commitments to reduce emissions under the Framework are considered to be a material effect and that global warming constitutes a known trend. Directs federal agency environmental impact statements or analyses to evaluate the effects on, and impact of, global warming.</summary>
</bill>
