<bill session="109" type="h" number="6252" updated="2013-07-19T19:59:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Intelligence Community Audit Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reaffirm the authority of the Comptroller General to audit and evaluate the programs, activities, and financial transactions of the intelligence community, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400402"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2006-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2006-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="3968"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Covert operations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2006--Introduced.
Intelligence Community Audit Act of 2006 - Reaffirms the authority of the Comptroller General to audit and evaluate financial transactions, programs, and activities of elements of the intelligence community (those elements identified in the National Security Act of 1947) and obtain access to records for such purposes.Allows the Comptroller General to conduct an audit or evaluation of intelligence sources and methods or covert actions only upon a request of a congressional intelligence committee or the majority or minority leader of the Senate or the House of Representatives. Requires the Comptroller General to disclose the results of any such audit or evaluation only to the original requestor, the Director of National Intelligence, and the head of the relevant element of the intelligence community. Requires the Comptroller General to establish safeguards to protect the unauthorized disclosure of all classified and other sensitive information furnished to the Comptroller General in conducting an audit or evaluation.Requires elements of the intelligence community to cooperate with the Comptroller General in providing documentation and information necessary for audits and evaluations.</summary>
</bill>
