<bill session="112" type="h" number="441" updated="2013-07-20T01:14:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-24T16:21:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-10-24T16:21:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Kantishna Hills Renewable Energy Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Kantishna Hills Renewable Energy Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Kantishna Hills Renewable Energy Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Kantishna Hills Renewable Energy Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to issue permits for a microhydro project in nonwilderness areas within the boundaries of Denali National Park and Preserve, to acquire land for Denali National Park and Preserve from Doyon Tourism, Inc., and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to issue permits for microhydro projects in nonwilderness areas within the boundaries of Denali National Park and Preserve, to acquire land for Denali National Park and Preserve from Doyon Tourism, Inc., and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-06-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-07-20T12:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-158.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-07-20T12:44:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="103">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 103.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-10-24T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-24T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6990-6991" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-24T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 441.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-10-24T16:21:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6990" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-10-24T16:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-24T16:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-11-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-01-13">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman under authority of the order of the Senate of 12/17/2011 without amendment. With written report No. 112-129.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-01-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="290">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 290.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="313"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/13/2012--Reported to Senate without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on July 20, 2011. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Kantishna Hills Renewable Energy Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to issue permits for specified microhydro projects in the Kantishna Hills area within the Denali National Park and Preserve in Alaska. Defines "microhydro project" as a hydroelectric power generating facility with a maximum power generation capability of 100 kilowatts and includes any distribution or transmission lines required to serve such area. Requires the Secretary to complete, no later than 180 days after the submission of a permit application, any analysis required by the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 respecting any proposed or existing microhydro projects in such area. Directs the Secretary to exchange Park and Preserve land near or adjacent to land owned by Doyon Tourism, Inc., located at the mouth of Eureka Creek for approximately 18 acres of land owned by Doyon Tourism within the Galena patented mining claim. Instructs the Secretary to seek to complete such exchange by February 2015. Permits, if the values of the tracts proposed for exchange are determined not to be equal, an equalization of such values to be achieved by adjusting the quantity of the acreage owned by Doyon Tourism. Requires the land acquired by the Secretary to be administered as part of the Park and Preserve.</summary>
</bill>
