<bill session="110" type="hr" number="720" updated="2013-07-19T20:56:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-10-10T12:25:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-10-10T12:25:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2895) to establish the National Affordable Housing Trust Fund in the Treasury of the United States to provide for the construction, rehabilitation, and preservation of decent, safe, and affordable housing for low-income families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-09T19:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-369, by Ms. Castor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-09T19:57:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Service now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-10-09T19:58:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="132">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 132.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T11:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11410-11412" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T11:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 720.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T11:46:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 720, the Chair put the question of ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hastings (WA) objected to the voice vote based upon the absence of a quorum. The Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day. The point of no quorum is considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T11:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11412-11413" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T12:16:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 223 - 195 (Roll no. 951).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11412-11413" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2007-10-10T12:25:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="952" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 224 - 194 (Roll no. 952).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11410" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-10-10T12:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="110" type="h" number="2895"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/2007--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 2895 (National Affordable Housing Trust Fund Act of 2007).</summary>
</bill>
