<bill session="112" type="s" number="2037" updated="2013-07-20T02:34:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Older Americans Act Amendments of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reauthorize and improve the Older Americans Act of 1965, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-01-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S133-134"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-01-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/2012--Introduced.
Older Americans Act Amendments of 2012 - Revises the Older Americans Act of 1965 with respect to functions and duties of the Administration on Aging of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), particularly with respect to those with the greatest social need caused by specified noneconomic factors. Reauthorizes the Act through FY2017. Requires the Director of the Office of Long-Term Care Ombudsman Programs to recommend to the Assistant Secretary for Aging resources (including including hardware and software) needed by state Long-Term Care Ombudsmen (LTCOs) to collect and report program data through the National Ombudsman Reporting System. Directs the Assistant Secretary to award livable communities grants to eligible entities for the federal share of the cost of assisting communities in preparing for the aging of the population through specified activities. Grants states the option to use certain grant funds to provide disease prevention and health promotion services directly, including clinical preventive services. Directs the Assistant Secretary to award grants: (1) to a national organization to establish a National Resource Center on Livable Communities for All Ages; and (2) to carry out projects to support and promote modern multipurpose senior center models which yield multiservice, multigenerational centers for older individuals, their families, and others to gain needed skills, resources, and connections for continuum of care and quality of life. Requires each grantee under the Older American community service employment program to place at least 50% of its project participants in positions with organizations that assist older adults or with duties that positively impact their lives. Revises the prohibition against contracting by state LTCO programs with public agencies or nonprofit private organizations to carry out LTCO programs in any case in which there is an organizational conflict of interest unless such conflict has been identified, disclosed, and remedied by certain actions. Requires a state agency to provide the services of a state legal services developer, who shall promote the development and operation of an integrated legal assistance delivery system.</summary>
</bill>
