<bill session="110" type="h" number="487" updated="2013-07-19T21:08:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-07T15:30:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-05-07T15:30:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Amendments Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Amendments Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Amendments Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Act to provide compensation to members of the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe for damage resulting from the Oahe Dam and Reservoir Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400443"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E114-115"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-19">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Unanimous Consent .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-05-07T14:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-128.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-05-07T15:00:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="77">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 77.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-05-07T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Napolitano moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-07T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4502-4505" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-07T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 487.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-05-07T15:30:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4503-4504" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-05-07T15:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2007--Passed House without amendment.
Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Amendments Act of 2007 - Amends the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Act to make member landowners eligible for the additional financial compensation provided to the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe for the acquisition by the federal government of 104,492 acres of land of the Tribe and member landowners for the Oahe Dam and Reservoir project. Defines "member landowner" as a member of the Tribe (or an heir of such a member) that owned land on the Cheyenne River Sioux Reservation that was acquired by the United States for the Oahe Dam and Reservoir Project of the Pick-Sloan Missouri River Basin program. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to make five annual deposits into the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribal Recovery Trust Fund. Rewrites requirements concerning the investment of the Trust Fund. Requires the investment of separate principal and interest accounts within such Fund. Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury: (1) to annually review with the Tribe the results of the investment activities and financial status of the Fund; and (2) if investing the Fund pursuant to such requirements is not practicable or would result in adverse consequences, to modify those requirements to the least extent necessary. Authorizes the plan prepared for the use of payments to the Tribe to provide for payment of additional compensation to member landowners. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to assist the Tribe in claims processing by providing any record requested to identify the heirs of member landowners within 90 days after receiving a request. Extinguishes all monetary claims of a member landowner or an heir of a member landowner against the United States for the taking by the United States of land or property of the Tribe for the Oahe Dam and Reservoir Project upon acceptance by such member landowner or heir of any payment by the Tribe for damages resulting from the taking.</summary>
</bill>
