<bill session="110" type="s" number="2927" updated="2013-07-19T22:46:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Government Oil Acquisition Financial Accountability and Consumer Relief Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to increase the supply and lower the cost of petroleum by temporarily suspending the acquisition of petroleum for the Strategic Petroleum Reserve and to amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to include additional acquisition requirements for the Reserve.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2008-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2008-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2008--Introduced.
Government Oil Acquisition Financial Accountability and Consumer Relief Act of 2008 - Instructs the Secretary of Energy to suspend petroleum acquisition for the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR). Authorizes the Secretary to resume petroleum acquisition for the SPR not earlier than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary notifies Congress that for the most recent consecutive four-week period: (1) the weighted average price of retail, regular, all formulations gasoline in the United States is $2.50 or less per gallon; or (2) the weighted average price of retail, No. 2 diesel in the United States is $2.75 or less per gallon. Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to require that acquisitions made for the SPR reflect a steady monthly dollar value of oil.Instructs the Secretary to include at least 10% heavy crude oil in making any crude oil acquisitions for the SPR.</summary>
</bill>
