<bill session="112" type="h" number="6230" updated="2013-07-20T02:03:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Grow Your Own Teacher Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a Federal "Grow Your Own Teacher" program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2012--Introduced.
Grow Your Own Teacher Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to establish a Grow Your Own Teacher program making competitive grants to eligible entities to train and employ certain individuals in hard-to-staff schools or teaching positions. Defines an "eligible entity" as a consortium consisting of a local educational agency (LEA) that receives school improvement funds under part A of title I of the Act and an institution of higher education that offers a state-accredited teacher certificate program. Requires the grant to be used to: (1) train certain individuals who received a high school diploma from a participating LEA to be teachers, including by having them observe and work with a veteran teacher in a classroom for at least one year; (2) employ such individuals in hard-to-staff schools and teaching positions in such LEA, with priority given to teaching positions in mathematics, science, special education, world languages, and English as a second language; and (3) employ such individuals in a manner that reduces the divergence between the racial diversity of teachers and of students. Authorizes the Secretary to forgive the student loans incurred by training program participants who have been employed as teachers in hard-to-staff schools or teaching positions.</summary>
</bill>
