<bill session="109" type="s" number="991" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Pension Fairness and Full Disclosure Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to limit the availability of benefits under an employer's nonqualified deferred compensation plans in the event that any of the employer's defined benefit pension plans are subjected to a distress or PBGC termination in connection with bankruptcy reorganization or a conversion to a cash balance plan, to provide appropriate funding restrictions in connection with the maintenance of nonqualified deferred compensation plans, and to provide for appropriate disclosure with respect to nonqualified deferred compensation plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2005-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2005-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2005-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2005-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2005-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4876"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2233"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Defined benefit pension plans"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Pension trust guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2005--Introduced.
Pension Fairness and Full Disclosure Act of 2005 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to establish a termination fairness standard that limits availability of benefits under an employer's nonqualified deferred compensation plans if such employer's defined benefit pension plan is subjected to: (1) a termination based on bankruptcy reorganization; or (2) a conversion to a cash balance plan. Prohibits funding nonqualified deferred compensation plans while maintaining underfunded defined benefit plans. Imposes penalties on funding nonqualified deferred compensation plans: (1) in the event of a pension plan termination based on bankruptcy reorganization or of a conversion to a cash balance plan; or (2) while maintaining underfunded defined benefit plans. Requires disclosure with respect to nonqualified deferred compensation plans.</summary>
</bill>
