<bill session="110" type="h" number="5829" updated="2013-07-19T21:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Public Housing Asset Management Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the Operating Fund for public housing of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412186"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2008-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3521"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6216"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing management"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Welfare work participation"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2008--Introduced.
Public Housing Asset Management Improvement Act of 2008 - Prohibits the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development from imposing restrictions or limitations on the amount of management and related fees for a public housing project which the public housing agency (PHA) determines reasonable, unless such restriction or limitation: (1) is determined pursuant to a negotiated rulemaking convened by the Secretary no earlier than April 1, 2009, with representatives from interested parties; and (2) is effective only on or after January 1, 2011. Allows any PHA that owns or operates fewer than 500 public housing units under the United States Housing Act of 1937 to elect to be exempt from asset management requirements imposed by the Secretary. Prohibits the Secretary from imposing any requirement, regulation, or guideline relating to asset management that restricts or limits in any way the use by PHAs of amounts for Capital Fund assistance for costs of any PHA central office. Requires the Secretary to ensure that PHAs encourage the reasonable efforts of resident tenant organizations to represent their members and of tenants to organize. Makes illegal immigrants ineligible for financial assistance under this Act. Prohibits the Secretary from accepting as reasonable any management or related fees for enforcing a dwelling lease or other similar agreement that requires the registration of or prohibits the possession of firearms by an individual for personal protection or for sport, if the possession is not prohibited, or the registration is not required, by existing law. Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to convert current community service requirements (and related exemptions) for adult residents of public housing projects to make them optional at the discretion of a PHA. Amends the Anti-Drug Abuse Act of 1988 to authorize appropriations for FY2009-FY2011. Expands the scope of eligible activities that may be conducted under public and assisted housing drug elimination programs.</summary>
</bill>
