<bill session="111" type="s" number="2900" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gas Turbine Efficiency Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Gas Turbine Efficiency Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a research, development, and technology demonstration program to improve the efficiency of gas turbines used in combined cycle and simple cycle power generation systems.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2010-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2010-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2010-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Energy. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-699.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 111-315.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="601">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 601.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG01" subcommittee="Energy" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3029"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2010--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Gas Turbine Efficiency Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to carry out a research, development, and technology demonstration program to improve the efficiency of gas turbines used in power generation systems and to identify the technologies that will lead to gas turbine combined cycle efficiency of 65% or simple cycle efficiency of 50%. Requires the program to: (1) support first-of-a-kind engineering and detailed gas turbine design for megawatt-scale and utility-scale electric power generation; (2) include technology demonstration through component testing, subscale testing, and full scale testing in existing fleets; (3) include field demonstrations of the developed technology elements to demonstrate technical and economic feasibility; and (4) assess overall combined cycle and simple cycle system performance. Delineates as the goals of the program: (1) in phase I, to develop the conceptual design of, and to develop and demonstrate the technology required for, advanced high efficiency gas turbines that can achieve at least 62% combined cycle efficiency or 47% simple cycle efficiency on a lower heating value basis; and (2) in phase II, to develop the conceptual design for advanced high efficiency gas turbines that can achieve at least 65% combined cycle efficiency or 50% simple cycle efficiency on a lower heating value basis. Directs the Secretary, in selecting program proposals, to emphasize the extent to which the proposal will: (1) stimulate the creation or increased retention of jobs in the United States; and (2) promote and enhance U.S. technology leadership. Requires awards of financial assistance to be made on a competitive basis with an emphasis on technical merit. Authorizes appropriations for FY2011-FY2014.</summary>
</bill>
