<bill session="111" type="s" number="2798" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to reduce the risk of catastrophic wildfire through the facilitation of insect and disease infestation treatment of National Forest System and adjacent land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2010-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2009-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11496-11497, S11498-11499"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11497-11499" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-566.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-313.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="599">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 599.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4398"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2010 - (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to identify high-risk areas within the National Forest System in the states of Alaska, Arizona, California, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, New Mexico, Oregon, South Dakota, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming (the affected states). Defines "high-risk area" to mean a road, trail, or other area that poses a high risk to public health or safety due to hazard trees resulting from landscape-scale tree mortality caused by an insect or disease epidemic. Requires the Secretary to develop educational materials describing the risk posed by hazard trees in high-risk areas and the measures that can be taken by the public in avoiding or reducing such risk. Directs the Secretary to identify insect or disease epidemic areas within the National Forest System in the affected states and to include with such information an estimate of the annual mortality caused by the epidemic and a projection of future tree mortality resulting from such epidemic. Requires the information identified pursuant to this section to be made available to affected communities, fire departments, and the public. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into contracts or provide financial assistance through cooperative agreements to help in the collection, development, monitoring, and distribution of such information and materials. (Sec. 5) Authorizes the Secretary to assist state and local governments, Indian tribes, private landowners, and other persons from an insect or disease epidemic area within the National Forest System in an affected state with the collection, harvest, storage, and transportation of eligible material to a biomass conversion facility in accordance with the Business Crop Assistance Program. Authorizes the Secretary to make payments to owners of nonindustrial private forest land in affected states to carry out emergency measures to restore their land after an insect or disease infestation. Directs the Secretary to carry out authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects in affected states on National Forest System land. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior to enter into good neighbor agreements with governors to coordinate the procurement and implementation of authorized restoration services. Defines a "good neighbor agreement" as a nonfunding master cooperative agreement between the Secretary and a governor or a memorandum of agreement or understanding between the Secretary and a governor. Requires contracts and subcontracts for authorized restoration services under this section to be in compliance with small business assistance and protection provisions. Terminates the authority of the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements and contracts under this section on September 30, 2019, and prohibits the termination date of such an agreement from extending beyond September 30, 2020. Repeals separate authorities for cooperative services on National Forest System lands in Colorado and Utah. (Sec. 7) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
