<bill session="112" type="h" number="4366" updated="2013-07-20T01:47:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Project Ready STEM Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award grants for science, technology, engineering, and math education programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412327"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2012-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2012-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2012-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E595"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/17/2012--Introduced.
Project Ready STEM Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to award grants to national intermediaries and, through them, subgrants to their community-based affiliates to operate after school, summer, and weekend programs that focus on science, technology, engineering, and math (STEM) education. Defines a "national intermediary" as a national private nonprofit organization that has: (1) a network comprising community-based affiliates in at least 50 urban communities, (2) expertise in overseeing programs to help middle and secondary school students succeed, and (3) operated in at least 25 states continuously for at least 20 years. Requires the STEM programs to primarily serve students who are traditionally underrepresented in STEM field careers, and include project-based learning opportunities and individualized instruction. Directs each subgrantee to collaborate with an institution of higher education in providing such services. Requires grantees to direct at least: (1) 50% of their grant to community-based affiliates that are successfully operating STEM programs so that they can expand them to reach more students traditionally underrepresented in STEM field careers, and (2) 25% of their grant to the development of STEM programs by community-based affiliates not currently operating any.</summary>
</bill>
