<bill session="110" type="h" number="3009" updated="2013-07-19T21:30:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Market Transparency Reporting of United States Transactions Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance transparency of trading in over-the-counter derivatives in natural gas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400628"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2007-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-25">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commodity Futures Trading Com.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG16" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities and Risk Management" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Commodity exchanges"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Derivative securities"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Swaps (Finance)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2007--Introduced.
Market Transparency Reporting of United States Transactions Act of 2007 - Amends the Commodity Exchange Act to define "included natural gas transaction" as a contract, agreement, or transaction in natural gas that is entered into: (1) in reliance on the provisions regarding either excluded swap transactions or the legal certainty for certain transaction in exempt commodities; or (2) by use of a domestic technology or software providing direct access to a foreign board of trade. (Thus places natural gas transactions within the jurisdiction of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC).) Prescribes recordkeeping and disclosure requirements governing natural gas in swap transactions, positions, inventories and commitments otherwise excluded from CFTC jurisdiction ("over-the-counter transactions"). Requires the CFTC to: (1) establish a reporting system regarding large positions in included natural gas transactions; (2) publish on a regular basis the information reported to it regarding such transactions; and (3) promulgate rules or regulations to implement this Act. Requires the CFTC reporting system to include aggregate reportable positions held by commercial and noncommercial persons.Increases civil money penalties for violations of this Act. Revises criminal penalties.</summary>
</bill>
