<bill session="109" type="s" number="258" updated="2013-07-19T20:15:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Training and Research in Urology Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to enhance research, training, and health information dissemination with respect to urologic diseases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2005-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="2005-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2005-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2005-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2005-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="2005-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S887-888"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S888-889" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="944"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Urology"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2005--Introduced.
Training and Research in Urology Act of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to separate the research and training on urologic diseases from that of kidney and hematologic diseases. Replaces the Division Director for Kidney, Urologic, and Hematologic Diseases in the National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases with a Division Director for Urologic Diseases and a Division Director for Kidney and Hematologic Diseases. Requires the Director of the Institute to: (1) give particular attention to supporting research and training programs geared to the needs of urology residents and fellows; and (2) submit to Congress a national urologic research plan and review such plan every three years. Replaces the National Kidney and Urologic Diseases Data System, the National Kidney and Urologic Diseases Information Clearinghouse, and the National Kidney and Urologic Diseases Advisory Board with separate data systems, information clearinghouses, and advisory boards for kidney diseases and urologic diseases. Replaces the Kidney, Urologic, and Hematologic Diseases Interagency Coordinating Committee and the Institute's advisory panel subcommittee on kidney, urologic, and hematologic diseases with separate coordinating committees and subcommittees for: (1) kidney and hematologic diseases; and (2) urologic diseases. Requires at least 15 of the centers developed for research in kidney and urologic diseases under the Public Health Service Act to focus exclusively on urologic diseases. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a loan repayment program for urology research.</summary>
</bill>
