<bill session="111" type="s" number="946" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Critical Electric Infrastructure Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to provide additional legal authorities to adequately protect the critical electric infrastructure against cyber attack, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2195"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2009--Introduced.
Critical Electric Infrastructure Protection Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, working with other national security and intelligence agencies, to conduct an investigation to determine if the security of federally owned programmable electronic devices and communication networks (including hardware, software, and data) essential to the operation of critical electric infrastructure have been compromised. Amends the Federal Power Act to direct the Secretary to make ongoing assessments and provide periodic reports with respect to cyber vulnerabilities and cyber threats to critical infrastructure, including critical electric infrastructure and advanced metering infrastructure. Directs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to establish mandatory interim measures to protect against known cyber vulnerabilities or threats to the operation of the critical electric infrastructure in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
