<bill session="111" type="s" number="3838" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to appropriate funds for the final settlement of lawsuits against the Federal Government for discrimination against Black Farmers and to provide relief for discrimination in a credit program of the Department of Agriculture under the Equal Credit Opportunity Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2010-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2010--Introduced.
Appropriates funds to the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to carry out the Settlement Agreement (dated February 18, 2010, between plaintiffs and the Secretary to resolve claims that were raised or that could have been raised in the cases consolidated in In re Black Farmers Discrimination Litigation, including Pigford claims) if the Agreement is approved by a court order that is or becomes final and nonappealable. States that: (1) such funds are in addition to certain Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) funds and shall be available only after the CCC funds are fully obligated; and (2) if the Agreement is not approved the CCC funds shall be the sole funding for Pigford claims. Permits an eligible complaint alleging discrimination in violation of the Equal Credit Opportunity Act involving a USDA credit program to file a civil action or request administrative review as provided for by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
