<bill session="113" type="h" number="435" updated="2013-11-02T06:22:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Enlistment Opportunity Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize the enlistment in the Armed Forces of additional persons who are residing in the United States and to lawfully admit for permanent residence certain enlistees who are not citizens or other nationals of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412505" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412533" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2013-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412509" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412515" joined="2013-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2013-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-29">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-29">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration And Border Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/29/2013--Introduced.
Military Enlistment Opportunity Act of 2013 - Amends citizenship and residency qualifications for enlistment in the armed forces to permit enlistment of additional persons who: (1) have resided continuously in a lawful status in the United States for at least two years, or (2) possess an employment authorization document issued by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services under requirements of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) policy entitled Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals. Requires authorized enlistees who are not citizens or other nationals of the United States or lawfully admitted for permanent residence to be adjusted to the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence under an exception to specified provisions of Immigration and Nationality Act. (Such enlistees need not establish that they entered the United States prior to January 1, 1972, or comply with other specified requirements.) Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to rescind such adjusted status if the person is separated from the armed forces under other than honorable conditions before the person served for a period or periods aggregating five years.</summary>
</bill>
