<bill session="110" type="h" number="5336" updated="2013-07-19T21:50:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Brownfields Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to authorize funding for brownfields revitalization activities and State response programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2008-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-12">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Brownfields"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/2008--Introduced.
Brownfields Reauthorization Act of 2008 - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to: (1) require the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Inspector General's report to Congress on the management of the brownfields program to be submitted every four years; and (2) extend the authorization of appropriations for such program and for state response programs through FY2012. Includes among the criteria used to rank brownfield grant applications the extent to which the grant would implement green building standards, including the use of energy efficient building standards. Amends the Superfund Amendments and Reauthorization Act of 1986 to authorize grants to be made for the training and education of workers who are or may be engaged in activities related to: (1) brownfields site characterization, assessment, or remediation; or (2) emergency response, rescue, recovery, or cleanup in connection with a natural or intentional disaster. Authorizes funding for worker training and education grants for FY2008-FY2012.</summary>
</bill>
