<bill session="112" type="s" number="657" updated="2013-07-20T02:22:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Blue Alert Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">National Blue Alert Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to encourage, enhance, and integrate Blue Alert plans throughout the United States in order to disseminate information when a law enforcement officer is seriously injured or killed in the line of duty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2011-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2011-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1898-1899"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-09-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="160">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 160.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="365"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="365"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/2011--Reported to Senate amended.
National Blue Alert Act of 2011 - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) establish a national Blue Alert communications network within the Department of Justice (DOJ) to disseminate information when a law enforcement officer is seriously injured or killed in the line of duty, and (2) assign an existing DOJ officer to act as the national coordinator of such network. Sets forth the duties of the national coordinator, including: (1) providing assistance to states and local governments that are using Blue Alert plans; (2) establishing voluntary guidelines for states and local governments to use in developing such plans; (3) developing protocols for efforts to apprehend suspects that address activities during the period between the initial notification of a law enforcement agency that a suspect has not been apprehended and the time of apprehension of the suspect, or when the law enforcement agency involved determines that the Blue Alert is no longer effective; (4) working with states to ensure appropriate regional coordination of various elements of the network; (5) establishing an advisory group to assist states, local governments, law enforcement agencies, and other entities in initiating, facilitating, and promoting Blue Alert plans; (6) acting as the nationwide point of contact for the development of the network and regional coordination of Blue Alerts; and (7) determining which procedures and practices for notifying law enforcement and the public when a law enforcement officer is killed or seriously injured are effective and do not require the expenditure of additional resources to implement. Prohibits the national coordinator from: (1) lobbying any officer of a state regarding the funding or implementation of a Blue Alert plan, or (2) hosting a conference focused solely on the Blue Alert program that requires the expenditure of federal funds. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act to: (1) authorize public safety and community policing grants to be used to assist states in developing and enhancing programs and activities in support of a Blue Alert plan and communications network, and (2) authorize appropriations for such purpose.</summary>
</bill>
