<bill session="109" type="h" number="514" updated="2013-07-19T19:08:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Armed Forces Voluntary Immunization and Health Justice Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the Department of Defense from requiring members of the Armed Forces to receive the anthrax and smallpox immunizations without their consent, to correct the records of servicemembers previously punished for refusing to take these vaccines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2005-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2005-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400375" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2005-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-02">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-02">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Anthrax"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Insubordination"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Smallpox"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/2005--Introduced.
Armed Forces Voluntary Immunization and Health Justice Act of 2005 - Prohibits requiring a member of the Armed Forces to participate in either of the smallpox or anthrax vaccine immunization programs of the Department of Defense. Permits administering either vaccine to any such member without the informed consent of the member. Requires the correction of the records of servicemembers previously punished for refusing to take either vaccine. Requires the Secretary of Defense to assess the current threat of an anthrax or smallpox attack on members of the Armed Forces and report the results. Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) carry out an ongoing assessment of the adverse health effects being reported by members and former members of the Armed Forces with respect to the smallpox and anthrax vaccines administered by the Department of Defense; and (2) prepare an estimate of the future cost to the Department of Veterans Affairs to treat those adverse health effects, if determined to be service-connected. Requires the President to establish a National Center for Military Deployment Health Research to coordinate and synthesize research efforts by Federal departments and agencies relating to the health effects of military deployments on members of the Armed Forces, including members of the reserve components.</summary>
</bill>
