<bill session="112" type="s" number="1437" updated="2013-07-20T02:28:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Communities of Color Teenage Pregnancy Prevention Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out programs to provide youth in racial or ethnic minority or immigrant communities the information and skills needed to reduce teenage pregnancies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5019-5020"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2678"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2011--Introduced.
Communities of Color Teenage Pregnancy Prevention Act of 2011 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants for programs to provide youth in racial or ethnic minority or immigrant communities the information and skills needed to avoid teen pregnancy and develop healthy relationships. Allows up to 10% of amounts made available for this Act to be allotted for a rigorous, independent evaluation of grant activities. Requires the Secretary to award grants for multimedia campaigns to provide public education and increase public awareness regarding teenage pregnancy and related social and emotional issues. Requires the Director of the Center for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to make grants for research on teen pregnancy, dating violence, and healthy relationships among racial or ethnic minority or immigrant communities. Requires the Secretary to direct the interagency adolescent health workgroup within the Office of Adolescent Health to include teen dating violence prevention and healthy teen relationship strategies in the work of such group, with a particular focus among racial or ethnic minority or immigrant communities, in consultation with the Federal Interagency Workgroup on Teen Dating Violence chaired by the Department of Justice (DOJ).</summary>
</bill>
