<bill session="112" type="h" number="1454" updated="2013-07-20T01:22:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Congressional Pay Accountability Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the salaries of Members of Congress to be held in escrow if all regular appropriation bills for a fiscal year have not been enacted by the beginning of the fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2011-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-08">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-08">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/2011--Introduced.
Congressional Pay Accountability Act of 2011 - Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, if all of the regular appropriation bills for a fiscal year do not become law before the beginning of that fiscal year, to: (1) deposit all payments otherwise required to be made for the compensation of Members of Congress in an escrow account, and (2) release them to the Members only upon the enactment of all such bills. Requires a 25% reduction in a Member's annual rate of pay for pay periods occurring during any Congress if all of the regular appropriation bills for the fiscal year in which that Congress begins do not become law before the first day of such Congress.</summary>
</bill>
