<bill session="111" type="s" number="3204" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Measuring and Evaluating Trends for Reliability, Integrity, and Continued Success (METRICS) Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Education to award grants to improve access to, sharing of, and use of, education data to improve student outcomes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5024"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/2010--Introduced.
Measuring and Evaluating Trends for Reliability, Integrity, and Continued Success (METRICS) Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to states to improve access to, and the sharing and use of, education data to improve student outcomes. Requires state grantees to have or be in the process of implementing integrated statewide education longitudinal data systems, which link individual students' early childhood, elementary, secondary, and postsecondary education and workforce data over time. Requires the use of grant funds to: (1) expand the ability of the data systems to link such data and do so across state agencies; (2) improve opportunities to access, analyze, and use data from such systems; and (3) build the capacity of teachers, leaders, parents, students, researchers, and the public to use longitudinal data for effective decision-making. Gives grant priority to states that propose to coordinate their efforts with local educational agencies (LEAs) or other states. Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive grants to high-need LEAs to develop and implement a comprehensive plan for using data to improve teaching, learning, and student outcomes. Requires such plan to include strategies to: (1) provide teachers, leaders, parents, students, researchers, and the public with access to student education data in a manner that respects student and teacher privacy; (2) coordinate with state efforts to build integrated statewide longitudinal data systems; (3) regularly analyze and share student education data with school personnel, parents, and students; (4) train teachers and school leaders to use such data effectively; (5) ensure that source data used at the local level is consistent with source data used to report indicators as required by state or federal law; and (6) provide training that addresses the use of data collection software, privacy policies, data integrity issues, report planning, and processes.</summary>
</bill>
