<bill session="110" type="s" number="36" updated="2013-07-19T22:20:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act to establish a biofuels promotion program to promote sustainable production of biofuels and biomass, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2007-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Alternative crops"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy crops"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Sustainable agriculture"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2007--Introduced.
Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a biofuels innovation program which shall: (1) encourage production of dedicated energy crops in a sustainable manner that protects the soil, air, water, and wildlife; (2) provide financial and technical assistance to owners and operators of eligible cropland to produce energy crops and crop mixes to support development and expansion of crop use for biofuels, power or heat generation to supplement or replace nonbiobased energy sources, and biobased products to supplement or replace non-biobased products; (3) establish biofuels innovation program project areas; and (4) provide financial and technical assistance to owners and operators for harvesting, storing, and transporting cellulosic material. Extends (and increases for FY2008-FY2010) authorization of appropriations for research, extension, and educational programs on biobased energy technologies and products.</summary>
</bill>
