<bill session="112" type="h" number="3978" updated="2013-07-20T01:44:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">EASY Voting Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Equal Access to Support Youth Voting Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the dissemination of false information for the purpose of discouraging a student of an institution of higher education from registering to vote or voting in an election for Federal office, to require States which require individuals to present a photo identification as a condition of voting in elections for Federal office to accept a photo identification presented by a student which is issued by the school the student attends, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2012-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-08">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/8/2012--Introduced.
Equal Access to Support Youth Voting Act or EASY Voting Act - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit the dissemination of false information with the intent of discouraging students who attend an institution of higher education (IHE) from voting or registering to vote in a federal election. Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require state and local election officials to accept a current and valid student photo identification issued by the IHE the student attends as a current and valid photo identification when such identification is required to obtain a ballot or vote in a federal election.</summary>
</bill>
