<bill session="111" type="s" number="1601" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the release of water from the marketable yield pool of water stored in the Ruedi Reservoir for the benefit of endangered fish habitat in the Colorado River, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9006"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9006-9007" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5362"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3387"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/2009--Introduced.
Requires the release of 5,412.5 acre-feet of water from the marketable yield pool (the portion of the regulatory capacity that is dedicated to marketing purposes) of water stored in the Ruedi Reservoir (a component of the Fryingpan-Arkansas Project of the Bureau of Land Management [BLM] in western Colorado) for the benefit of endangered fish habitat in the Colorado River for FY2013 and each fiscal year thereafter, at the request of the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service. Requires such release during the late summer months to enhance low water flows in areas that comprise the endangered fish habitat in the Colorado River, unless otherwise requested by the Director. Provides that the release shall satisfy 50% of the obligation of certain water users to provide 10,825 acre-feet of water, as described in the document entitled "Final Programmatic Biological Opinion for Bureau of Reclamation's Operations and Depletions, Other Depletions, and Funding and Implementation of Recovery Program Actions in the Upper Colorado River above the Confluence with the Gunnison River." Makes this Act effective on the date on which the Secretary of the Interior complies with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 regarding such release.</summary>
</bill>
