<bill session="111" type="h" number="5981" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-11">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase the flexibility of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development with respect to the amount of premiums charged for FHA single family housing mortgage insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T10:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Frank (MA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T10:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6468-6469" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T10:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5981.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-07-30T10:07:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6468-6469" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T10:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-04">
      <text>Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6741" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-08-04" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2010-08-04">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-08-11">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-08-11" type="public" number="111-229">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-229.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/11/2010--Public Law.
Amends the National Housing Act with respect to requirements for the insurance of mortgages secured by a one- to four-family dwelling which are obligations of the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund. (Sec. 1) Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish and collect annual premium payments of up to 1.5% of the remaining insured principal balance on such a dwelling. (Currently the Secretary is required to establish and collect annual premium payments of up to .5% of the remaining insured principal balance.) Authorizes an annual premium of up to 1.55% of the remaining insured principal balance of any 30-year mortgage on such a dwelling involving an original principal obligation greater than 95% percent of such value. (Currently, an annual premium of up to 0.55% of the remaining insured principal balance on such a mortgage is required.) Authorizes the Secretary to adjust the amount of any initial or annual premium through notice published in the Federal Register or mortgagee letter, which shall establish the effective date of any such adjustment. (Sec. 2) Directs the Assistant Secretary of HUD who is the Federal Housing Commissioner to appear before specified congressional committees within 270 days after the enactment of this Act to discuss the finances, including premiums, of the Federal Housing Administration (FHA).</summary>
</bill>
