<bill session="110" type="h" number="6093" updated="2013-07-19T21:57:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Carmelo Rodriguez Military Medical Accountability Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 171 of title 28, United States Code, to allow members of the Armed Forces to sue the United States for damages for certain injuries caused by improper medical care and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400178"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2008--Introduced.
Carmelo Rodriguez Military Medical Accountability Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Tort Claims Act to allow claims for damages to be brought against the United States for personal injury or death of a member of the Armed Forces arising out of a negligent or wrongful act or omission in the performance of medical, dental, or related health care functions that: (1) takes place other than in the context of combat; and (2) is provided by persons acting within the scope of their office or employment by or at the direction of the Armed Forces, whether inside or outside the United States. Provides for a reduction of claims under this Act by the present value of other benefits attributable to such death or injury received by the member and by that member's estate, survivors, and beneficiaries pursuant to other federal law.</summary>
</bill>
