<bill session="109" type="h" number="4438" updated="2013-07-19T19:43:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gulf Coast Recovery Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Gulf Coast Recovery Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish special rules with respect to certain disaster assistance provided for Hurricane Katrina and Hurricane Rita.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409888"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400662" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400634" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400635" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2005-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2005-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-12-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-22T17:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 109-364.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-12-22T17:25:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="195">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 195.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local budgets"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State budgets"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/22/2005--Reported to House without amendment.
Gulf Coast Recovery Act of 2005 - Authorizes the President to provide assistance under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (the Stafford Act) to reimburse an eligible state or local government 75% of the eligible expenses incurred between January 1 and June 30, 2006, for base pay and overtime expenses of employees who provide essential government services for response and recovery operations with respect Hurricanes Katrina and Rita on or after August 29, 2005.Amends the Community Disaster Loan Act of 2005 to limit a disaster loan to 50% of a local government's operating budget for the fiscal year in which the disaster occurs. Sets at 100% the federal share of assistance for debris removal under the Stafford Act with respect to such hurricanes.Requires the President to contribute at least 75% of the cost of hazard mitigation measures approved under the Stafford Act in the one-year period following enactment of this Act with respect to such hurricanes.Amends the Stafford Act to double from 7.5% to 15% of the estimated aggregate amount of federal disaster relief grants to be made with respect to a major disaster the limit on the total amount of contributions the President may make for cost-effective hazard mitigation measures in the disaster area. Extends unemployment assistance in the case of an eligible individual affected by the hurricane disasters. Requires the President to make such assistance available for 52 weeks after the date of the disaster declaration. Requires the amount of such assistance for a week of unemployment, beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, to be at least 50% of the national average weekly unemployment benefit provided to an individual as of the date of the disaster declaration. Amends the Stafford Act to require the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to make grants to state and local governments to: (1) purchase or improve commercially available interoperable communications equipment; (2) purchase mobile equipment to generate emergency power; and (3) train first responders and emergency personnel on how to best use such equipment effectively. Authorizes appropriations for FY2006-FY2008.</summary>
</bill>
