<bill session="111" type="s" number="901" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sustainable Revenue for Oregon Counties Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Oregon Task Force on Sustainable Revenue for Counties, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4760-4761"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4761-4763" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/2009--Introduced.
Sustainable Revenue for Oregon Counties Act of 2009 - Establishes the Oregon Task Force on Sustainable Revenue for Counties to consider and review concepts for the establishment of a long-term revenue source for counties in Oregon that have historically received federal funds. Directs the Task Force, in conducting the consideration and review, to consider: (1) revenue sources proposed by relevant legislation or administrative actions; (2) payments based on timber harvests, including thinning to restore forest health, carried out at sustainable levels; (3) payments based on the revenues each county could have received through property taxation if the land owned by the federal government was privately held and subject to a property tax; (4) revenue based on a portion of the proceeds from sales of material collected from public land in Oregon for the production of biomass electricity or cellulosic liquid transportation fuels, user fees for recreational activities on such land, payments for increases in carbon sequestration, and land exchanges or transfers that could provide compensation for nontaxable federal land in the counties; (5) local revenue sources that could be used to reduce or eliminate reliance of the counties on federal funds; (6) federal payments made by the government to the counties, including specified guaranteed payments; and (7) any other revenue source appropriate for review. Requires the Task Force to hold hearings on the establishment of a sustainable, long-term revenue source for the counties.</summary>
</bill>
