<bill session="111" type="h" number="4119" updated="2013-07-19T23:49:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the construction of the Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System in the State of Montana and a portion of McKenzie County, North Dakota, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400335"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="637"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Missouri River"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2009--Introduced.
Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a cooperative agreement to provide federal assistance for the planning, design, and construction of the Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System for specified counties in Montana and North Dakota. Lists agreement requirements. Limits the federal share of planning, design, and construction of the System to 75% of the total cost. Delineates the components of System facilities for which federal funds may be expended and the System's service area. Limits the obligation of funds for construction. Provides that any cost relating to the System's operation, maintenance, or replacement shall not be a federal responsibility and shall be paid by the System. Directs the Administrator of the Western Area Power Administration to make available to the System a quantity of power required, up to one and a half megawatt capacity, to meet the System's pumping and incidental operation requirements between May 1 and October 31 of each year from the water intake facilities and through all pumping stations, water treatment facilities, reservoirs, storage tanks, and pipelines up to the point of delivery of water by the water supply system to all storage reservoirs and tanks and each entity that distributes water at retail to individual users. Makes the System eligible to receive power only if it operates on a nonprofit basis and is constructed pursuant to the agreement. Sets forth provisions regarding the purchase of additional power and the Authority's responsibility for power charges, non-federal delivery costs, and non-federal transmission and distribution system delivery and service arrangements. Directs the Authority to develop a water conservation plan containing a description of water conservation objectives and measures and a schedule for carrying out such measures. Requires the plan to be designed to ensure that users of water provided by the System use the best practical technology and management techniques to conserve water.</summary>
</bill>
