<bill session="111" type="s" number="1280" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">TARP Recipient Ownership Trust Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to delegate management authority over troubled assets purchased under the Troubled Asset Relief Program, to require the establishment of a trust to manage assets of certain designated TARP recipients, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2009-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2009-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6727"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6727-6728" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2009--Introduced.
TARP Recipient Ownership Trust Act of 2009 - Amends Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA) to authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to delegate to a private entity management authority with respect to any entity assisted under the Act. Prohibits any expenditure of funds under the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) until the Secretary transfers all voting, nonvoting, and common equity in any designated TARP recipient to a limited liability company, to be held and managed in trust on behalf of U.S. taxpayers. Requires the trustees to liquidate the trust, including the assets it holds, by December 24, 2011, unless the trustees report to Congress that liquidation would not maximize profitability of the company and the return on investment to the taxpayer.</summary>
</bill>
