<bill session="112" type="h" number="103" updated="2013-07-20T01:11:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care Choices for Seniors Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Social Security Act to improve choices available to Medicare eligible seniors by permitting them to elect (instead of regular Medicare benefits) to receive a voucher for a health savings account, for premiums for a high deductible health insurance plan, or both and by suspending Medicare late enrollment penalties between ages 65 and 70.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2011-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2011-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2011-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2011-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400315" joined="2011-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2011-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2011-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2011-01-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
Health Care Choices for Seniors Act - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivor's and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a procedure under which an individual otherwise entitled to benefits under part A (Hospital Insurance) of SSA title XVIII (Medicare) may waive such entitlement and be automatically enrolled in the Medicare Alternative Voucher Program (MAV Program). Directs the Secretary to establish the MAV Program, under which a voucher may be used as a contribution into a health savings account and for the payment of enrollment premiums under a high deductible health plan. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the amount of the itemized deduction for health savings accounts by the amount of the MAV that is contributed to an individual's health savings account. Suspends Medicare late enrollment penalties for an individual between ages 65 and 70.</summary>
</bill>
