<bill session="110" type="s" number="268" updated="2013-07-19T22:22:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ice Age Floods National Geologic Trail Designation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Ice Age Floods National Geologic Trail Designation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to designate the Ice Age Floods National Geologic Trail, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2008-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-01-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2007-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-01-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-01-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-01-31">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-02-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-15.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-02-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="40">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 40.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="450"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="450"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Ice Age Floods National Geologic Trail Designation Act - Designates the Ice Age Floods National Geologic Trail, a trail from Missoula, Montana to the Pacific Ocean, to provide for the public appreciation, understanding, and enjoyment of the nationally significant natural and cultural features of the Ice Age Floods and to promote efforts to interpret and educate along the pathways of the floods. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, to administer the Trail in accordance with this Act. Prohibits the Trail, except as provided in this Act, from being considered a unit of the National Park System (NPS). Allows the Secretary, in order to improve management of the Trail and coordinate Trail activities with other public agencies and private entities, to establish and operate a Trail management office at a central location within the vicinity of the Trail. Requires the Secretary to prepare a cooperative management and interpretation plan for the Trail. Authorizes the Secretary to plan, design, and construct interpretive facilities for sites associated with the Trail if the facilities are constructed in partnership with state, local, tribal, or nonprofit entities and are consistent with the cooperative management and interpretation plan. Allows the Secretary, in order to facilitate the development of coordinated interpretation, education, resource stewardship, visitor facility development and operation, and scientific research associated with the Trail and to promote more efficient administration of the sites associated with the Trail, to enter into cooperative management agreements with appropriate officials in the states of Montana, Idaho, Washington, and Oregon in accordance with the authority provided for units of the NPS. States that, for purposes of such authority only, the Trail be considered an NPS unit. Permits the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with public or private entities to carry out this Act. Specifies the effect of this Act on private property rights. Declares that designation of the Trail does not create any liability for, or affect any liability under any law of, any private property owner with respect to any person injured on the private property. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
