<bill session="111" type="h" number="3273" updated="2013-07-19T23:41:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ensuring One Level of Aviation Safety Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the implementation of certain recommendations of the National Transportation Safety Board, to require the establishment of national standards with respect to flight requirements for pilots, to require the development of fatigue management plans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412291" joined="2009-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2009-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="1284"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1284"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2009--Introduced.
Ensuring One Level of Aviation Safety Act of 2009 - Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to: (1) implement certain aviation safety recommendations of the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB); and (2) notify Congress, within 180 days after the NTSB provides the Administrator with a safety recommendation, of determinations with respect to future and pending NTSB recommendations. Directs the Administrator to: (1) submit to Congress a plan that contains a process for each air carrier to certify to the FAA that it has received an airworthiness directive or other FAA issued order, including a plan for ensuring air carrier compliance with such directives and orders; and (2) perform, at least annually, random, unannounced, onsite inspections of regional air carriers to ensure their compliance with FAA safety standards. Requires the Administrator to: (1) issue a final rule with respect to the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking published in the Federal Register on January 12, 2009, regarding training programs for flight crewmembers and aircraft dispatchers; (2) revise federal aviation safety regulations to increase the minimum number of hours of flight experience required for pilots to conduct flight operations; (3) prescribe regulations to limit the number of hours allowed for pilots to address pilot fatigue problems as well as to provide guidance to air carriers to develop, and submit to the FAA, fatigue management plans; and (4) submit to Congress a plan for overseeing federally-certified pilot training schools. Requires an air carrier, before allowing an individual to begin service as a pilot, to request and receive from the FAA records pertaining to any failed attempt of the individual to pass a practical test required to obtain a certificate or type rating under federal regulations.</summary>
</bill>
