<bill session="109" type="s" number="1600" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Digital Translator and Low-Power Television Transition Assistance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to ensure full access to digital television in areas served by low-power television, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2005-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9520"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Introduced.
Digital Translator and Low-Power Television Transition Assistance Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to extend the deadline for conversion of translator stations and low-power analog television stations to advanced (digital) television services from the current transition period ending on December 31, 2006, to the period ending four years thereafter. Establishes in the Treasury the Low-Power Digital Television Transition Trust Fund, funded by proceeds from the federal auction of certain electromagnetic spectrum frequencies, for the making of grants to licensees of low-power television stations, state and local governments, and community organizations to: (1) upgrade low-power television translator stations from analog to digital in eligible rural communities and other areas served by low-power television stations; and (2) extend digital television broadcast signals to unserved households located in such communities and areas. Requires a report from the Federal Communications Commission to specified congressional committees on the status of low-power television and translator stations. Directs the FCC to report semiannually to such committees on the status of international cooperation with Canada and Mexico with respect to the Digital Television table of allotments.</summary>
</bill>
