<bill session="112" type="s" number="1118" updated="2013-07-20T02:26:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FEMA Common Sense and Cost Effectiveness Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the construction and maintenance of levees on property acquired under hazard mitigation grant programs of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412494"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2011--Introduced.
FEMA Common Sense and Cost Effectiveness Act of 2011 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act and the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to authorize the construction and maintenance of levees on property acquired under the Federal Emergency Management Agency's (FEMA's) hazard mitigation grant programs, including: (1) a levee that is federally owned and operated; (2) a permanent levee that is federally constructed and nonfederally operated and maintained; (3) a levee that is federally constructed as a nonpermanent levee, that a nonfederal entity desires to operate and maintain as a permanent levee, and the owners of which are participating in, or, in a specified period after the date on which the levee is constructed, will begin participating in, the emergency response to natural disasters program; and (4) a nonfederal levee the owners of which are participating in the program. Authorizes an application to construct or maintain a levee on acquired lands to be denied if the levee poses a significant threat of harm to downstream communities.</summary>
</bill>
