<bill session="111" type="h" number="3804" updated="2013-07-19T23:46:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-07T13:28:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-07T13:28:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Park Service Authorities and Corrections Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Park Service Authorities and Corrections Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Park Service Authorities and Corrections Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">National Park Service Authorities and Corrections Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical corrections to various Acts affecting the National Park Service, to extend, amend, or establish certain National Park Service authorities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412319"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07T13:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-360, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07T13:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07T13:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Oversight and Government discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-12-07T13:23:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="212">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 212.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07T13:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07T13:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13537-13540" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07T13:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3804.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-12-07T13:28:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13537-13539" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07T13:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 111-276.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-08-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="546">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 546.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Reported to Senate without amendment.
National Park Service Authorities and Corrections Act of 2009 - Title I: National Park Service Authorizations - (Sec. 101) Extends the National Park Service Advisory Board and the National Park Service Concessions Management Advisory Board until December 31, 2019. (Sec. 103) Revises specified current penalty provisions applicable to the National Park System to provide for the uniform application throughout the System of specified penalty provisions of the National Park Service Organic Act and the federal criminal code. (Sec. 104) Increases the amount that may be appropriated in any one year for the National Park Service (NPS) Volunteers-In-Parks Program. Title II: Pearl Harbor Ticketing - (Sec. 202) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, in managing the World War II Valor in the Pacific National Monument, to enter into an agreement with the organizations authorized to administer a Pearl Harbor historic site in Hawaii with respect to visitor access and the sale of tickets. Instructs the Secretary, with respect to any such agreement, to: (1) require the organization administering or managing a Pearl Harbor historic site to pay to the Secretary a fee to recover administrative costs associated with the use of the visitor center within the Pearl Harbor Naval Complex within the Monument for public access and ticket sales, the proceeds of which shall remain available for use by the NPS at the Monument; and (2) ensure the limited liability of the United States arising from the admission of the public through the visitor center to such a site and the sale or issuance of any tickets to such site. Prohibits the Secretary, under this title, from: (1) regulating or approving rates for admission to an attraction within a Pearl Harbor historic site; (2) regulating or managing visitor services of such historic sites within the Complex, other than at those sites managed by the NPS as part of the Monument; or (3) charging an entrance fee for admission to the Monument. (Sec. 203) Prohibits anything in this title from authorizing the Secretary or any organization that administers or manages a Pearl Harbor historic site to take any action in derogation of the preservation and protection of the values and resources of the Monument. Title III: Changes to National Park Units - (Sec. 301) Provides for the transfer of the administrative jurisdiction of specified land within the George Washington Memorial Parkway and the Turner-Fairbank Highway Research Center. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to restrict the use of specified acreage within the boundary of the Parkway that is immediately adjacent to part of the Research Center's north perimeter fence by prohibiting the storage, construction, or installation of any item that may obstruct the view from the Research Center into the Parkway. Provides for the transfer of administrative jurisdiction to occur without reimbursement or consideration. Requires NPS and the Federal Highway Administration (FHA) to comply with all terms and conditions of a certain Agreement with regard to the transfer of administrative jurisdiction, management, and maintenance of the lands discussed in such Agreement. Instructs the Secretary to allow the Research Center access to the land the Secretary restricts for maintenance purposes. Bars the pruning or removal of trees which are six inches or more in diameter without the advance permission of the Secretary. Requires the use of any pesticide to be approved by the Secretary prior to its application. Requires the inclusion of: (1) the land transferred to the Secretary in the boundaries of the Parkway and to be administered by the NPS as part of the Parkway; and (2) the land transferred to the Secretary of Transportation in the boundary of the Research Center and to be removed from the Parkway's boundary. Requires the land designated for restricted use to be maintained by the Research Center. (Sec. 302) Revises provisions regarding the removal of snow and ice around federal buildings in the District of Columbia. Requires federal agencies (under current law, the Director of the NPS) to remove snow, sleet, and ice from around such buildings. Requires such snow, sleet, or ice removal to occur within a reasonable time period after snow or sleet ceases to fall or after ice has accumulated. Permits delegation of all such duties to another governmental or nongovernmental entity through a lease, contract, or other comparable arrangement. (Sec. 303) Redesignates the Martin Luther King, Junior, National Historic Site in Georgia as the Martin Luther King, Jr. National Historical Park. (Sec. 304) Adjusts the boundary of the Lava Beds National Monument in California. Title IV: Technical Corrections - Makes technical and conforming amendments to specified acts relating to public lands.</summary>
</bill>
