<bill session="111" type="h" number="714" updated="2013-07-19T23:18:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-10-08">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to lease certain lands in Virgin Islands National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400073"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-23T15:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-23T15:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1622-1623" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-23T15:30:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 714.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-02-23T15:38:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1622" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-02-23T15:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments. With written report No. 111-146.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="296">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 296.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2010-05-13" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3761-3762" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3762" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-05-14">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Christensen moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7008" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments to H.R. 714.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-09-28T12:54:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7008" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T12:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-09-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-10-08">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-10-08" type="public" number="111-261">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-261.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/2010--Public Law.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, if the long-term benefit to the Virgin Islands National Park would be greater by entering into a lease than by authorizing a concession contract, to enter into a lease with the owner of the retained use estate for the operation and management of the Caneel Bay resort on the island in the Park. Allows the Secretary to acquire associated property. Sets forth the terms and conditions for the lease authorized by this Act, including provisions ensuring protection of the natural, cultural, and historic features of the resort and associated property, consistent with the laws and policies applicable to property managed by the National Park Service (NPS). Instructs the Secretary, in determining the fair market value rental of the lease, to take into consideration: (1) the value of any associated property conveyed; and (2) the value, if any, of the relinquished term of the retained use estate. Makes rental amounts paid to the United States under the lease available for visitor services and resource protection within the Virgin Islands National Park. Requires the Secretary to submit a proposed lease to Congress at least 60 days before the award of the lease. Prohibits the extension or renewal of a lease entered into under this Act. Requires, upon the termination of such a lease, that if the Secretary determines the continuation of commercial services at the resort to be appropriate, such services shall be provided in accordance with the National Park Service Concessions Management Improvement Act of 1998. Requires the owner of the retained use estate to terminate, extinguish, and relinquish to the Secretary all rights under the retained use estate and transfer, without consideration, ownership of improvements on the retained use estate to the NPS. Requires an appraisal that is agreed to by the Secretary and the owner to determine the value, if any, of the relinquished term of the retained use estate, to be conducted in accordance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
