<bill session="109" type="h" number="3177" updated="2013-07-19T19:32:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Lobbying Reform bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Lobby Gift Ban Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit registered lobbyists from making gifts to Members of Congress and to congressional employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2006-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2006-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Politicians' families"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/2005--Introduced.
Lobby Gift Ban Act of 2005 - Prohibits a registered lobbyist from knowingly making a gift to a Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of Congress, with the exception of certain: (1) lawful political fundraising activities; (2) gifts from relatives; (3) employee benefits; (4) informational materials; (5) items of nominal value; (6) gifts on a personal basis, under specified circumstances; (7) outside business or employment activities provided to his or her spouse; (8) opportunities and benefits unrelated to congressional employment; and (9) foods or refreshments of nominal value offered other than as part of a meal. Considers a gift to a family member of a Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of Congress, or a gift to any other individual based on that individual's relationship with the Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee, to be a prohibited gift if it was given because of the individual's official position. Imposes a civil fine of $50,000 for violation of this Act, depending on the extent and gravity of the violation. Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner from accepting a gift from a registered lobbyist prohibited by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
