<bill session="111" type="h" number="3027" updated="2013-07-19T23:39:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Predisaster Hazard Mitigation Enhancement Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to establish a grant program for predisaster hazard mitigation enhancement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400402"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2009-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2009-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2009--Introduced.
Predisaster Hazard Mitigation Enhancement Program Act of 2009 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize: (1) the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to make grants on a competitive basis to states and other jurisdictions to assist predisaster hazard mitigation strategies; and (2) the use of technical and financial assistance under such Act to support state programs that provide grants to low income homeowners for wind and flood inspections of their principal residences and for implementation of hazard mitigation improvements.. Limits the use of grants to assist predisaster hazard mitigation improvements to: (1) residential property valued up to $250,000; (2) small business property valued up to $500,000; and (3) residential rental property valued up to the product of the number of rental units in such property and $250,000. Prohibits grants from being used for projects located in the Coastal Barrier Resources System. Directs the Administrator to arrange with the National Academy of Sciences or a similar organization to examine methods to coordinate the functions of man-made and natural storm buffers.</summary>
</bill>
