<bill session="112" type="s" number="800" updated="2013-07-20T02:23:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Routes to School Program Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users to reauthorize and improve the safe routes to school program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2011-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2011-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2011-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/2011--Introduced.
Safe Routes to School Program Reauthorization Act - Amends the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU) to reauthorize appropriations for FY2012-FY2016 for the safe routes to school program. Revises program requirements to specify children kindergarten through 12th grade as the ones to be benefited by the program. Revises criteria used to determine state apportionment of program funds. Includes projects for other nonmotorized modes of transportation besides walking and bicycling as noninfrastructure-related projects. Authorizes states to set-aside up to 10% of apportioned funds for infrastructure improvements that create safe routes to bus stops located outside of the vicinity of schools. Requires each state that receives an apportionment to carry out an assessment of the economic and geographical distribution of funding to ensure that low-income schools are adequately able to access such funds. Defines "low-income school" to mean a school in which 65% or more of students qualify for a free or reduced price lunch under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act. Requires each state receiving an apportionment for a fiscal year to use a sufficient amount of it to fund a full-time position of coordinator for the state safe routes to school program. Prescribes requirements for the treatment of noninfrastructure and infrastructure projects. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) develop and implement a comprehensive plan for evaluating the effectiveness of safe routes to school, and (2) make grants to an experienced national nonprofit organization to operate a national safe routes to school clearinghouse.</summary>
</bill>
