<bill session="110" type="hr" number="447" updated="2013-07-19T20:54:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Condemning the recent convictions and sentencing of Vietnamese pro-democracy activists, expressing concern over the future of the United States-Vietnam relationship, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2007-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2007-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2007-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2008-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412192" joined="2008-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2007-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2007-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1166"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2007--Introduced.
Condemns the convictions and sentencing of Tran Quoc Hien, Huynh Nguyen Dao, Nguyen Bac Truyen, Le Nguyen Sang, Nguyen Van Dai, and Le Thi Cong Nhan and the continued detention of Le Quoc Quan, Tran Thuy Trang, and Truong Quoc Huy by the government of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam. Calls for their release and the dropping of all criminal charges, and for the release of all other political and religious prisoners in Vietnam. Expresses concern over the future of the U.S.-Vietnam relationship unless Vietnam demonstrates progress towards democracy and respect for human rights and religious freedom. Urges the President to use the upcoming visit of the President of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam to the United States as an opportunity to publicly call for progress towards democracy and respect for human rights and religious freedom in Vietnam.</summary>
</bill>
