<bill session="111" type="s" number="3854" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Honest Services Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to expand the definition of scheme or artifice to defraud with respect to mail and wire fraud.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7631"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7631-7632" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6391"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/2010--Introduced.
Honest Services Restoration Act - Amends the federal criminal code to expand the definition of "scheme or artifice to defraud," for purposes of fraud offenses, to include: (1) a scheme or artifice by a public official to engage in undisclosed self-dealing; or (2) a scheme or artifice by officers and directors to engage in undisclosed private self-dealing. Defines "undisclosed self-dealing" to mean: (1) performing an official act to benefit or further a financial interest of the public official, a spouse or minor child, a general partner, a business or organization in which the public official is serving as an employee, officer, director, trustee, or general partner, or an individual, business, or organization with whom the public official is negotiating for, or has any arrangement concerning, prospective employment or financial compensation; and (2) knowingly falsifying, concealing, covering up, or failing to disclose material information regarding a financial interest as required by law. Defines "undisclosed private self-dealing" to mean: (1) performing an act which causes or is intended to cause harm to the employer of the officer or director and which is undertaken to benefit or further by an actual or intended value of $5,000 or more a financial interest of the officer or director, a spouse or minor child, a general partner, another business or organization in which the officer or director is serving as an employee, officer, director, trustee, or general partner, or an individual, business, or organization with whom the officer or director is negotiating for, or has any arrangement concerning, prospective employment or financial compensation; and (2) knowingly falsifying, concealing, covering up, or failing to disclose material information regarding a financial interest as required by law.</summary>
</bill>
