<bill session="109" type="h" number="5717" updated="2013-07-19T19:54:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Education Assessment Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to clarify Federal requirements under that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400222"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2006-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2006-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2006-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1343"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Education Reform" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rating of teachers"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2006--Introduced.
Education Assessment Technical Corrections Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Act of 1965 to except teachers in hard to staff areas from the requirement that all teachers teaching in core academic subjects within a state be highly qualified not later than the end of the 2005-2006 school year. Requires teachers in hard to staff areas, instead, to satisfy at least 80% of the requirements to be highly qualified by the end of the 2006-2007 school year, and satisfy all of them by the end of the following school year. Revises requirements for assessments of student groups in measuring the adequate yearly progress of the state, and of all public schools and local educational agencies (LEAs) in the state, toward enabling all public elementary school and secondary school students to meet the state's student academic achievement standards. Provides that a student group which has failed to meet or exceed achievement standards may satisfy assessment requirements if it met such standards in the immediately preceding year. Authorizes the testing of disabled students at their instructional level, rather than grade level, provided they show progress in accordance with individualized education programs. Permits states to change the method of counting students who are in more than one group. Revises the sanctions for schools which fail an assessment by reason of a group of no more than four students from designation as needing improvement to mandatory redirection of funds to the needs of such group. Requires the Secretary of Education to make recommendations to Congress for increasing the percentage of limited English proficient students and disabled students who meet or exceed state academic achievement standards.</summary>
</bill>
