<bill session="110" type="s" number="1749" updated="2013-07-19T22:35:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Crime Victims' Rights Rules Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure to provide adequate protection to the rights of crime victims, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300062"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8745-8748"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Depositions"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Pleas (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Right to counsel"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Speedy trial"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Trials"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2007--Introduced.
Crime Victims' Rights Rules Act of 2007 - Expresses the sense of Congress with respect to ensuring that the rights and standing of crime victims are accounted for in the federal criminal justice system.Amends the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure to allow for the involvement of crime victims in the various phases of the criminal justice process, including: (1) the initial court appearance of a defendant; (2) the preliminary hearing; (3) the pretrial conference; (4) transfers of trial venues; and (5) revocations or modifications of probation or supervised release. Sets forth requirements for giving notice to crime victims of criminal proceedings and their right to participate in such proceedings.Requires a court to consider the views of crime victims before accepting a plea of guilty or nolo contendere. Permits a crime victim to attend any public deposition taken in a criminal proceeding.Prohibits documents containing personal or confidential information about a crime victim from being subpoenaed without giving the victim notice and an opportunity to be heard.Grants crime victims the right to: (1) attend any public court proceeding, subject to certain court-imposed restrictions; and (2) address the court regarding any decisions to release a defendant or dismiss a criminal case.Authorizes a court to appoint counsel to assist crime victims in exercising their rights.Requires a court to protect crime victims against unreasonable delay in criminal proceedings.Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to amend its sentencing guidelines, policy statements, and official commentary to ensure that crime victims have meaningful participation in the sentencing process.</summary>
</bill>
