<bill session="110" type="h" number="6928" updated="2013-07-19T22:04:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">After School Partnerships Improve Results in Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">ASPIRE</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To award grants to improve after-school interdisciplinary education programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2008-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2008-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Career education"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Geography"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Physical education and training"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Service learning"/>
    <term name="Social sciences"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student activities"/>
    <term name="Student transportation"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2008--Introduced.
After School Partnerships Improve Results in Education Act or ASPIRE - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive matching grants to partnerships, composed of a state or local educational agency and at least one college or nonprofit, community, tribal, business, labor, or career technical student organization, for the development of national model after-school interdisciplinary education programs for secondary school students. Directs the Secretary to allot grants to states for matching subgrants to other partnerships, composed of such entities, for the development of after-school interdisciplinary education programs for secondary school students. Gives grant and subgrant priority to programs targeting a high percentage of impoverished, struggling, or rural students and their families. Requires each partnership grantee and subgrantee to include in its program: (1) at least one activity involving mathematics and science education, language arts, writing, and reading, or history, geography, or social studies; and (2) at least one activity involving career technical education, business and entrepreneurial education, health and wellness, the environment and conservation, or arts and music education. Allows program activities to take place after school, before school, or at any other time that the school is not in session. Directs the Secretary to carry out national activities, such as providing technical assistance to grantees and subgrantees, and conducting a national evaluation of such programs.</summary>
</bill>
