<bill session="113" type="s" number="719" updated="2013-11-02T06:58:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lyme and Tick-Borne Disease Prevention, Education, and Research Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the expansion of Federal efforts concerning the prevention, education, treatment, and research activities related to Lyme and other tick-borne diseases, including the establishment of a Tick-Borne Diseases Advisory Committee.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2013-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="610"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="611"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2013--Introduced.
Lyme and Tick-Borne Disease Prevention, Education, and Research Act of 2013 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish the Tick-Borne Diseases Advisory Committee. Requires the Committee to advise the Secretary and the Assistant Secretary for Health regarding the manner in which such officials can: (1) ensure interagency coordination and communication and minimize overlap regarding efforts to address tick-borne diseases; (2) identify opportunities to coordinate efforts with other federal agencies and private organizations addressing such diseases; (3) ensure interagency coordination and communication with constituency groups; (4) ensure that a broad spectrum of scientific viewpoints are represented in public heath policy decisions and that information disseminated to the public and physicians is balanced; and (5) advise relevant federal agencies on priorities related to Lyme and other tick-borne diseases. Directs the Committee to regularly review published public and private treatment guidelines and evaluate such guidelines for effective representation of a wide variety of views. Requires the Secretary, acting as appropriate through various federal officials, to provide for the coordination of all federal programs and activities related to Lyme and other tick-borne diseases and the conduct or support of specified activities, including: (1) developing sensitive and accurate diagnostic tools and tests, (2) improving the efficient utilization of diagnostic testing currently available, (3) surveillance and reporting of Lyme and other tick-borne diseases, (4) providing and promoting access to a clearinghouse of information on such diseases, (5) increasing public education related to such diseases, (6) creating a physician education program to educate health professionals on the latest research and diversity of treatment options for Lyme disease, (7) establishing epidemiological research objectives, and (8) determining the effectiveness of different treatment modalities.</summary>
</bill>
