<bill session="112" type="h" number="6200" updated="2013-07-20T02:03:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safety And Fraud Enforcement for Seafood Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen Federal consumer protection and product traceability with respect to commercially marketed seafood, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2012-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2012-11-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2012-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2012-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412447" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2012-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2012-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2012-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2012-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2012-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1327-1328"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, Ways and Means, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG29" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2012--Introduced.
Safety And Fraud Enforcement for Seafood Act - Requires the Secretaries of Commerce and Health and Human Services (HHS) to execute a memorandum of understanding to improve interagency cooperation on seafood safety, building upon any prior agreement, including those under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act. Includes in such a memorandum processes concerning efficient use of inspection personnel, intergovernmental cooperation, use of data, monitoring of substances used in fish farming, and prescreening of imported seafood by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). Establishes the following coordination requirements: (1) development of a process to expedite the importation of seafood from foreign countries and exporters that consistently adhere to the highest standards for seafood safety, (2) use of the national sea grant college program for outreach activities, and (3) collection of information to prevent seafood fraud. Defines "seafood fraud" as the mislabeling or misrepresentation of seafood in violation of this Act or other applicable federal laws and regulations. Provides standards for refusal of admission of imported seafood based upon findings of failure to meet controls of existing fishery product regulations, the use of treatments or feed containing substances not approved for use by U.S. aquaculturists, or a level of any substance above the maximum deemed safe for consumption by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Provides procedures for import certifications and allowance of individual shipments in certain cases. Includes, in fishery management plan data required to be submitted in the course of fish processing, information that accompanies seafood (including by labeling) through final sale concerning market and species names, production method, catch or aquaculture area, and weight, number, or product transformation. Requires a public website to list exporters of seafood to the United States and track violations. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to increase the number of shipments inspected for seafood fraud, prevent the percentage of seafood shipments inspected from declining in a subsequent year, and ensure that inspections for fraud prevention also collect seafood safety information. Allows civil actions by states for seafood fraud violations. Requires the Secretaries to report to Congress biennially on seafood safety and seafood fraud prevention measures.</summary>
</bill>
