<bill session="111" type="s" number="1081" updated="2013-07-20T00:33:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit the release of enemy combatants into the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2009-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2009--Introduced.
Defines "covered individual" as any individual who: (1) has been determined by a Combatant Status Review Tribunal to be an enemy combatant or is awaiting the determination of such a tribunal; (2) is in U.S. custody at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba; and (3) is not a U.S. citizen or an alien admitted for permanent residence. Prohibits: (1) a court from ordering a covered individual's release into the United States; and (2) the Secretary of State from issuing any visa and the Secretary of Homeland Security from admitting or providing any type of status to a covered individual that permits such individual's entry or admission into the United States. States that a covered individual who is no longer held as an enemy combatant shall be: (1) released into the Secretary of Homeland Security's custody for expeditious transfer to such individual's country of nationality or to another country; and (2) housed separately from aliens detained as enemy combatants in a manner consistent with the safety of U.S. personnel.</summary>
</bill>
