<bill session="111" type="h" number="6003" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the establishment of the National Fab Lab Network to build out a network of community based, networked Fabrication Laboratories across the United States to foster a new generation with scientific and engineering skills and to provide a work force capable of producing world class individualized and traditional manufactured goods.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2010-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Introduced.
National Fab Lab Network Act of 2010 - Establishes the National Fab Lab Network (NFLN), as a non-profit entity, to facilitate the construction of a network of connected labs. Defines "Fab Lab" or "Fabrication Laboratory" to mean a facility containing a variety of manufacturing and other fabrication tools operable by digital input as well as the software and computers required to design and operate those tools. States that these labs serve a broad range of purposes, but each allow for how members of the local community, businesses, and academic or educational purposes can be pursued with the lab's resources. Authorizes and empowers the NFLN to receive real or personal property and to hold it absolutely or in trust, and to invest, reinvest, and manage it, and to apply such property and the income arising therefrom to the objects of its creation and according to the instructions of its donors. Sets forth the functions of the NFLN. Requires the NFLN to: (1) facilitate the construction of a new type of information and digital fabrication infrastructure; and (2) promote the goals of greater science, technology, engineering, and math (STEM) education, workforce development in manufacturing and product design, increased innovation in the private sector, as well as scientific and academic discovery through the use of distributed digital fabrication tools. Permits acceptance by the NFLN of donations from private individuals, corporations, government agencies, or other organizations.</summary>
</bill>
