<bill session="112" type="h" number="6561" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Teachers and First Responders Back to Work Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Education to make grants to States to hire teachers and prevent layoffs, to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to make grants to hire firefighters and prevent layoffs, and to direct the Attorney General to make grants to hire law enforcement officers and prevent layoffs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1723"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2012--Introduced.
Teachers and First Responders Back to Work Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Education to make grants to states to prevent teacher layoffs and support the creation of additional jobs in early childhood, elementary, and secondary public education in the 2012-2013 and 2013-2014 school years. Directs the Secretary to allocate grant funds based on each state's: (1) population of individuals aged 5 through 17 relative to all other states, and (2) total population relative to all other states. Sets forth application requirements, including assurances with respect to maintenance of state support for early childhood, elementary, and secondary education at no less than FY2011 levels. Requires a state to: (1) reserve 10% of grant funds for awards to state-funded early learning programs; and (2) allocate remaining funds to local educational agencies (LEAs) based on each LEA's enrollment, and the amount of funds received by the LEA for basic programs under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, relative to the enrollment of and amounts received by all other LEAs in the state. Requires early learning programs and LEAs to use such funds only to pay compensation, benefits, and other expenses necessary to retain existing employees, recall or rehire former employees, or hire new employees to provide early childhood, elementary, or secondary educational and related services. Directs: (1) the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to make competitive grants to hire, rehire, and retain firefighters pursuant to the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 and to maintain resources for fire departments; and (2) the Attorney General to make competitive grants to hire, rehire, and retain career law enforcement officers pursuant to the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968. Authorizes additional appropriations for FY2012-FY2013 for such grants.</summary>
</bill>
