<bill session="110" type="h" number="6162" updated="2013-07-19T21:57:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area and Dominguez Canyon Wilderness Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area and the Dominguez Canyon Wilderness Area.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400620"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2008-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3065"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Stream conservation"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2008--Introduced.
Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area and Dominguez Canyon Wilderness Area Act - Establishes the Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area in Colorado to conserve and protect the unique and nationally important values of certain public land in Mesa, Montrose, and Delta Counties and the water resources of area streams that are necessary to support aquatic, riparian, and terrestrial species and communities.Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) develop a comprehensive management plan for the long-range protection and management of the Conservation Area; and (2) establish the Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area Advisory Council to advise the Secretary on the preparation and implementation of the management plan.Designates certain lands in Mesa, Montrose, and Delta Counties as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System, to be known as the Dominguez Canyon Wilderness Area.</summary>
</bill>
