<bill session="113" type="h" number="2174" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Long Island Sound Restoration and Stewardship Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend and reauthorize certain provisions relating to Long Island Sound restoration and stewardship.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2013-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412560" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2013-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1080"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1080"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Long Island Sound"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Long Island Sound Restoration and Stewardship Act - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to expand the duties of the Office of Management Conference of the Long Island Sound Study by requiring the Office to: (1) conduct or commission studies to strengthen the implementation of the Comprehensive Conservation and Management Plan for the Long Island Sound, including studies on environmental impacts on the Sound watershed and studies on planning initiatives for the Sound that identify the areas that are most suitable for various types of activities in order to reduce conflicts among uses, reduce environmental impacts, facilitate compatible uses, or preserve critical ecosystem services to meet economic, environmental, security, or social objectives; (2) develop and implement strategies to increase public education and awareness with respect to the ecological health and water quality conditions of the Sound; (3) make publicly available on the Internet information relating to the environmental quality of the Sound; and (4) monitor the progress made toward meeting the identified goals, actions, and schedules of the Plan. Limits the federal share for grants for projects and studies which will help implement the Plan, other than citizen involvement and citizen involvement grants, to 60%. Requires the Office's Director to submit a report that includes: (1) an assessment of the progress made by the Office and the Long Island Sound states in implementing the plan, (2) an assessment of the key ecological attributes that reflect the health of the ecosystem of the Sound watershed, (3) a description of any substantive modifications to the Plan made during the preceding two years, (4) recommendations to improve progress in restoring and protecting the Sound watershed, (5) priority actions for implementation of the Plan for the next two years, and (6) a description of the means by which federal funding and actions will be coordinated with the actions of the Long Island Sound states and other entities. Requires the President to submit, together with the annual U.S. budget, information regarding each federal agency involved in the protection and restoration of the Sound watershed. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency Act (EPA) to coordinate the actions of federal agencies that impact water quality in the Sound watershed to improve the water quality and living resources of the watershed. Requires a federal agency that owns or occupies real property, or carries out activities, within the Sound watershed to: (1) participate in regional and subwatershed planning, protection, and restoration activities with respect to the watershed; and (2) ensure that the property and activities carried out by the agency are consistent with the Plan. Amends the Long Island Sound Stewardship Act of 2006 to terminate the Long Island Sound Stewardship Advisory Committee on December 31, 2018 (currently 2011). Extends reporting requirements by requiring the Advisory Committee to submit to the Administrator and the decision making body of the Long Island Sound Study Management Conference an annual report through FY2018 on stewardship sites. Makes the amendments to such Act become effective on October 1, 2011. Extends through FY2018 the authorization of appropriations to the Administrator for the implementation of the Management Conference of the Long Island Sound Study, the Long Island Sound Stewardship Act of 2006, the Long Island Sound Grants, and Long Island Sound Stewardship Grants.</summary>
</bill>
