<bill session="111" type="h" number="4025" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for justice and compensation for United States citizens taken hostage by Iran, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2009-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/4/2009--Introduced.
States that: (1) it is U.S. policy to seek justice for U.S. victims of terrorism and to hold terrorists and their state-sponsors accountable for their actions; and (2) U.S. law regarding victims of terrorism supersedes the Algiers Accords and any other agreement with Iran stemming from the holding of U.S. hostages in Iran from November 1979 through January 1981. Abrogates and deems not applicable any provision of the Algiers Accords, entered into with Iran on January 19, 1981, that purports to prohibit a U.S. citizen from prosecuting any claim relating to such hostage taking in any U.S. court or to limit the jurisdiction of any U.S. court with respect to such matter. Requires the President to direct payments as provided for by this Act to a common fund to be established and administered by certified class representatives for U.S. citizens who were hostages in Iran.</summary>
</bill>
