<bill session="113" type="s" number="220" updated="2013-11-02T06:54:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Citrus Disease Research and Development Trust Fund Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create a Citrus Disease Research and Developing Trust Fund to support research on diseases impacting the citrus industry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="853"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2013--Introduced.
Citrus Disease Research and Development Trust Fund Act of 2013 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to establish the Citrus Disease Research and Development Trust Fund, consisting of revenues from duties paid on imported citrus or citrus products, to support scientific research, technical assistance, and development activities to combat both domestic and invasive citrus diseases and pests harming the United States. Establishes the Citrus Disease Research and Development Trust Fund Advisory Board. Makes Fund amounts available to the Secretary of Agriculture to develop a coordinated program of research and product development relating to: (1) scientific research of both domestic and invasive diseases and pests afflicting the citrus industry; and (2) support for the dissemination and commercialization of relevant information, techniques, and technologies discovered through Fund research or other research projects intended to solve problems caused by citrus production diseases and invasive pests. Requires the President to notify certain congressional committees before entering into a trade agreement that could result in a decrease in the amount of: (1) duties paid on imported citrus or citrus products, and (2) funds transferred into the Fund. Prescribes a formula for required estimated tax payments otherwise due in each of the quarters of 2018 from corporations with assets of at least $1 billion. Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (COBRA) to extend certain customs users fees for the processing of merchandise entered into the United States between October 23, 2021, and November 6, 2021, and other specified customs users fees for merchandise entered between October 30, 2021, and November 13, 2021.</summary>
</bill>
