<bill session="111" type="h" number="4303" updated="2013-07-19T23:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stand with the Iranian People Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance United States sanctions against Iran by targeting Iranian governmental officials, prohibiting Federal procurement contracts with persons that provide censorship or surveillance technology to the Government of Iran, providing humanitarian and people-to-people assistance to the Iranian people, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400645" joined="2010-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2009-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2010-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2010-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="2010-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Oversight and Government Reform, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-14">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-14">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-14">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-14">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/14/2009--Introduced.
Stand with the Iranian People Act - Directs the Secretary of State to deny issuance of a visa and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to deny U.S. admission to any government official of Iran who is credibly alleged to have ordered, acquiesced to, or participated in human rights abuses against the people of Iran. Authorizes the Secretary of State to waive such ban if in the U.S. national interest. Prohibits the head of an executive agency from entering into or renewing a contract for the procurement of goods or services with a person or entity that provides censorship or surveillance technology to the government of Iran. Authorizes the Secretary concerned to waive such prohibition if in the U.S. national interest. States that the establishment and carrying out of operations by U.S. nonprofit organizations in Iran for the direct provision of specified humanitarian and people-to-people assistance may not be prohibited or restricted. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to require such an organization to notify the Department of the Treasury up to 14 days in advance of commencing operations in Iran. Excludes from such provision an organization that provides services or conducts transactions with any organization or entity that appears on the Department of the Treasury's Specially Designated Nationals List (a list of organizations and individuals that are restricted from doing business with the United States or U.S companies or individuals).</summary>
</bill>
