<bill session="111" type="h" number="3894" updated="2013-07-19T23:47:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize a community-based overweight and obesity prevention program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412273"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/21/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a community-based overweight and obesity prevention program under which the Secretary shall award grants to, or enter into contracts with, eligible entities to plan and implement evidence-based programs for the prevention of overweight and obesity among children and their families through improved nutrition and increased physical activity. Sets the period of a grant or contract at five years, subject to renewal. Requires an entity, to be eligible, to be a community partnership that demonstrates community support. Authorizes the Secretary to award a grant or contract to only an entity that: (1) demonstrates that it will establish a steering committee to provide input on the assessment of, and improvements to, the entity's program and has conducted or will conduct an assessment of the overweight and obesity problem in its community; (2) agrees to provide non-federal amounts equal to $1 for each $9 provided; and (3) demonstrates that it will maintain its previous level of spending for funded activities. Directs the Secretary to give preference to entities that will: (1) serve communities with high levels of overweight and obesity and related chronic diseases; and (2) plan or implement activities for the prevention of overweight and obesity in school or workplace settings.</summary>
</bill>
