<bill session="111" type="s" number="1328" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Shasta-Trinity National Forest Administrative Jurisdiction Transfer Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the exchange of administrative jurisdiction over certain Federal land between the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6945"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6945" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-223.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="689"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2009--Introduced.
Shasta-Trinity National Forest Administrative Jurisdiction Transfer Act - Transfers the administrative jurisdiction over specified federal land in the Shasta-Trinity National Forest in California from the Chief of the Forest Service to the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM). Subjects such land to the laws, including regulations, applicable to the land administered by the Director. Excludes land within the Shasta Dam Reclamation Zone from such transfer of administrative jurisdiction and continues the administration of such land by the Secretary of the Interior acting through the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation. Transfers the administrative jurisdiction over specified federal land in California administered by the Director from the the Director to the Chief. Subjects the land to the laws, including regulations, applicable to National Forest System land. Withdraws such land from the public domain and reserves it for administration as part of the Shasta-Trinity National Forest. Requires the Chief and the Director, with respect to the transfer of their lands, to identify any known sites concerning hazardous substances and to provide notice of any sites identified to the federal agency head to which the land is being transferred.</summary>
</bill>
