<bill session="113" type="h" number="1337" updated="2013-11-02T06:30:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Palestinian Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To restrict funds for the Palestinian Authority, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412526"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412508" joined="2013-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412431" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2013-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Gaza Strip"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="West Bank"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2013--Introduced.
Palestinian Accountability Act - Prohibits any U.S. government document from referring to the areas controlled by the Palestinian Authority (PA) as Palestine until the Secretary of State certifies to Congress that the PA: (1) does not inappropriately influence elections in PA-contolled areas; (2) is promoting human rights and ending government corruption; (3) has taken steps to dismantle terrorist infrastructures and arrest terrorists, control Palestinian security organizations, and end the incitement to violence and hatred in the Palestinian media, educational institutions, and mosques; (4) has ceased to participate in any boycott of Israel; (5) works with Israel to implement the Performance-Based Roadmap to a Permanent Two-State Solution to the Israeli-Palestinian Conflict of 2003 (the Roadmap to Peace); (6) recognizes Israel's right to exist as a Jewish state; and (7) has excluded Hamas from participating in a unity government or has required Hamas to publicly support such requirements. Prohibits certain Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 funds from being made available to the PA unless: (1) a U.S. nongovernmental or private entity audits the PA budget and the Secretary submits the audit to Congress, and (2) the Secretary certifies to Congress that the PA meets specified requirements. Prohibits funds from being obligated or expended for U.S. contributions to the United Nations (U.N.) if a Palestinian state is recognized as a U.N. member state unless the Secretary certifies to Congress that the PA meets specified requirements. Prohibits funds from from being obligated or expended for U.S. contributions to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA) unless: (1) a U.S. nongovernmental or private entity audits the UNRWA budget and the Secretary submits the audit to Congress, and (2) the Secretary certifies to Congress that UNRWA meets specified requirements.</summary>
</bill>
