<bill session="111" type="h" number="2046" updated="2013-07-19T23:30:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Bottle Recycling Climate Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require a refund value for certain beverage containers, and to provide resources for State pollution prevention and recycling programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2009-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E934-935"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/2009--Introduced.
Bottle Recycling Climate Protection Act of 2009 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit retailers and distributors from selling beverages in containers that do not display a statement of a refund value of five cents. Defines "beverage" as an alcoholic or non-alcoholic, carbonated or uncarbonated liquid that is intended for human consumption. Requires: (1) distributors to collect the refund value for each beverage sold to retailers by a deposit initiator; and (2) retailers to collect the refund value for each beverage sold to consumers. Requires: (1) retailers to pay the refund on returned unbroken containers of brands sold for up to a specified number of containers per day based on the square footage of the retailer's space (excluding any container contaminated by a hazardous waste); and (2) distributors to pay the refund on returned containers of brands sold, plus at least three cents per container for handling costs. Directs each deposit initiator to pay to a state, quarterly, unclaimed refund amounts, which shall be available to the state for programs designed to reduce greenhouse gas emissions. Prohibits distributors and retailers from intentionally disposing of containers subject to this Act or any metal, glass, or plastic from such containers (other than the top or seal) in landfills or solid waste disposal facilities. Exempts states that have implemented laws requiring beverage container deposits or that have demonstrated achievement of specified recycling, reuse, or recovery rates for beverage containers. Prohibits states or political subdivisions that impose taxes on the sale of beverage containers from imposing any tax on the amount attributable to the refund value of such containers. Provides for the adjustment for inflation of the refund amounts at ten-year intervals. Prescribes civil penalties for violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
