<bill session="111" type="h" number="4027" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Taxpayer and Western Area Power Administration Firm Power Customer Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Hoover Power Plant Act of 1984 to ensure that project beneficiaries are solely responsible for repaying the costs of Western Area Power Administration power transmission and delivery projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2009-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2726"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/5/2009--Introduced.
American Taxpayer and Western Area Power Administration Firm Power Customer Protection Act - Amends the Hoover Power Plant Act of 1984, as amended by the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, regarding the borrowing authority of the Western Area Power Administration. Repeals the mandatory forgiveness of: (1) remaining balances owed to the Treasury at the end of a project's useful life; and (2) funds expended to study projects that are not constructed. Requires the Administrator of Western Area Power Administration to certify, prior to committing funds for any power transmission and delivery project in which it participates, that appropriate agreements have been executed to ensure that project beneficiaries will be solely responsible for repaying the entire capital and operational costs of the project.</summary>
</bill>
