<bill session="111" type="h" number="553" updated="2013-07-19T23:16:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-10-07">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Reducing Over-Classification Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Reducing Over-Classification Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Reducing Over-Classification Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Reducing Over-Classification Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Reducing Over-Classification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to develop a strategy to prevent the over-classification of homeland security and other information and to promote the sharing of unclassified homeland security and other information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400166"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E100"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03T15:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Thompson (MS) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03T15:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H893-898" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03T15:49:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 553.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-02-03T16:21:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H893-894" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03T16:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-200.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-05-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="413">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 413.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7554-7556" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7554-7556" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2010-09-27" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T17:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Harman moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7075-7077" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T17:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 553.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-09-28T17:46:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7075-7076" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T17:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-09-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-10-07">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-10-07" type="public" number="111-258">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-258.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4661"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/7/2010--Public Law.
Reducing Over-Classification Act - (Sec. 4) Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (HSA) to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to designate a Classified Information Advisory Officer to develop and disseminate educational materials and to develop and administer training programs to assist state, local, and tribal governments (including law enforcement agencies) and private sector entities: (1) in developing plans and policies to respond to requests related to classified information without communicating such information to individuals who lack appropriate security clearances: (2) regarding the appropriate procedures for challenging classification designations of information received by personnel of such entities; and (3) on the means by which such personnel may apply for security clearances. Directs such Officer to inform the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis on policies and procedures that could facilitate the sharing of classified information with such personnel. (Sec. 5) Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to require the Director of National Intelligence to establish: (1) guidance to standardize formats for classified and unclassified intelligence products for purposes of promoting the sharing of such products; and (2) policies and procedures requiring the increased use, including portion markings, of the classification of portions of information within one intelligence product. Amends HSA to: (1) include among the responsibilities of the Secretary relating to intelligence and analysis and infrastructure protection, to integrate relevant information, analysis, and vulnerability assessments in order to prepare finished intelligence and information products in both classified and unclassified formats whenever reasonably expected to be of benefit to a state, local, or tribal government or a private sector entity; and (2) require the state, local, and tribal homeland security and law enforcement officers and intelligence analysts assigned by the Interagency Threat Assessment and Coordination Group (ITACG) Detail to work in the National Counterterrorism Center to make recommendations to the Secretary for the further dissemination of intelligence products that could likely inform or improve the security of such a government or entity. Requires the Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the National Conterterrorism Center and the ITACG Advisory Council, to: (1) compile an annual assessment of ITACG Detail's performance, including summaries of customer feedback, in preparing, disseminating, and requesting the dissemination of intelligence products intended for state, local, and tribal government and private sector entities; (2) provide such assessment to the program manager for the information sharing environment for use in the annual report on ITACG progress. Requires such report to include an assessment of whether the ITACG detailees have appropriate access to all relevant information as required. (Sec. 6) Permits the President or the head of an agency with an officer or employee who is authorized to make original or derivative classification decisions, in making certain cash incentive awards, to consider such officer's or employee's consistent and proper classification of information. Requires the inspector general of each such agency, in consultation with the Information Security Oversight Office, to carry out at least two evaluations of that agency or components thereof to: (1) assess whether applicable classification policies, procedures, rules, and regulations have been adopted, followed, and effectively administered; and (2) identify policies, procedures, rules, regulations, or management practices that may be contributing to persistent misclassification of material. Requires each first evaluation to be completed by September 30, 2013, and each second evaluation to be completed by September 30, 2016. Requires each inspector general to: (1) submit a report on each such evaluation to specified congressional committees, the agency head, and the Director of the Information Security Oversight Office; and (2) coordinate with other inspectors general and with the Information Security Oversight Office to ensure that evaluations follow a consistent methodology that allows for cross-agency comparisons. (Sec. 7) Directs the head of each executive agency, in accordance with Executive Order 13526, to require: (1) annual training for each employee who has original classification authority; and (2) training at least every two years for employees who perform derivative classification or are responsible for analysis, dissemination, preparation, production, receipt, publication, or otherwise communication of classified information. Requires such training to: (1) educate the employee regarding the guidance established under the National Security Act of 1947 regarding the formatting of finished intelligence products, the proper use of classification markings, and incentives and penalties related to the proper classification of intelligence information; and (2) serve as a prerequisite for obtaining and maintaining original classification authority or derivatively classifying information. Directs each agency head to ensure that the training is conducted efficiently and in conjunction with any other required security, intelligence, or other training programs to reduce the associated costs and administrative burdens.</summary>
</bill>
