<bill session="113" type="h" number="1544" updated="2013-11-02T06:32:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National High Performance Passenger Rail Transportation-Oriented Development Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote transportation-oriented development and encourage dedicated revenue sources for urban and regional rail corridor development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400318"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2013-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E448"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/2013--Introduced.
National High Performance Passenger Rail Transportation-Oriented Development Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to establish an initiative to promote intercity and urban passenger rail operations and transportation-oriented development by creating rail projects qualified for federal incentives for communities to encourage dedicated revenue sources for urban and regional rail corridor development. Authorizes the Secretary to designate up to four qualified pilot projects. Amends the Railroad Revitalization and Regulatory Reform Act of 1976 to direct the Secretary to provide direct loans and loan guarantees for qualified rail projects. Authorizes the Secretary to make secured loans, loan guarantees, or lines of credit for such projects. Directs the Secretary to provide technical assistance to: (1) state, local, or regional authorities to identify transportation-oriented development opportunities; (2) states, localities, and regions outside the Northeast Corridor to establish regional authorities and identify existing and potential stations within the region to maximize development and commercial revenue generation to support financially the development of a high performance intercity or urban rail passenger corridor; and (3) states and local or regional entities along the Northeast Corridor to establish a Northeast Corridor Transportation-Oriented Development Working Group and identify Northeast Corridor existing and potential stations to maximize development and commercial revenue generation to support financially the creation of a true high-speed rail corridor in the Northeast Corridor.</summary>
</bill>
