<bill session="112" type="h" number="4261" updated="2013-07-20T01:46:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">REVAMP with Community Colleges Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Revamping the Education of our Veterans to Align Manufacturing through Partnerships with Community Colleges Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of Labor to establish a competitive grant program for community colleges to train veterans for local jobs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2012--Introduced.
Revamping the Education of our Veterans to Align Manufacturing through Partnerships with Community Colleges Act of 2012 or REVAMP with Community Colleges Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Labor to award grants to community colleges to: (1) analyze the demand for trained employees in their locality and the skills possessed by veterans who receive federal educational assistance and seek local employment, (2) provide those veterans with training that addresses local demand for trained employees, and (3) facilitate the establishment of an advisory board to provide guidance to the training program and assist trained veterans in their pursuit of local employment. Requires the advisory board to be composed of local business representatives and an employee from the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA).</summary>
</bill>
