<bill session="113" type="h" number="1090" updated="2013-11-02T06:28:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Elementary Educator STEM Content Coach Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an Elementary Educator Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM) Content Coach program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400185"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2013-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2013--Introduced.
Elementary Educator STEM Content Coach Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to award grants to states and, through them, subgrants to partnerships between local educational agencies and public or nonprofit organizations to carry out professional development training programs for elementary school teachers that have at least three years of classroom teaching experience and exhibit content knowledge in the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) fields. Refers to those teachers as STEM Coaches. Requires grant applicants to have adopted college- and career-ready standards in the STEM disciplines. Requires public or nonprofit subgrantees to have expertise in developing or implementing before school, after school, summer learning, or expanded learning time activities for students. Requires the professional development training programs to: (1) give STEM Coaches a deep understanding of the principles and concepts of the STEM disciplines; (2) create enthusiasm for the STEM disciplines; (3) provide opportunities for collaboration and teacher mentoring among STEM Coaches and between STEM Coaches and other teachers; and (4) allow STEM Coaches to connect student learning in the STEM disciplines to real-life applications, to out of school programs, and across the curriculum. Directs the Secretary to plan a national evaluation of the professional development training program for STEM Coaches.</summary>
</bill>
