<bill session="109" type="h" number="285" updated="2013-07-19T19:06:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Homeland Security Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance cybersecurity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400404"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2005-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2005-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2005-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2005-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Management, Integration, and Oversight.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Security, infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-20">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on Management, Integration, and Oversight Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSHM09" subcommittee="Management, Integration, and Oversight" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication systems"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/2005--Introduced.
Department of Homeland Security Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2005 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish in the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) Directorate for Information Analysis and Infrastructure Protection a National Cybersecurity Office, headed by an Assistant Secretary for Cybersecurity, who shall assist the Secretary of Homeland Security in promoting cybersecurity for the Nation. Grants the Assistant Secretary primary authority within DHS for all cybersecurity-related critical infrastructure programs of DHS. Includes among the responsibilities of the Assistant Secretary to: (1) establish and manage a national cybersecurity response system, a national cybersecurity threat and vulnerability reduction program, a national cybersecurity awareness and training program, a government cybersecurity program, and a national security and international cybersecurity cooperation program; (2) coordinate specified activities with the private sector and with other directorates and offices within DHS; (3) develop processes for information sharing with the private sector; (4) consult with the Secret Service's Electronic Crimes Task Force on private sector outreach and information activities and with the Office for Domestic Preparedness to ensure that realistic cybersecurity scenarios are incorporated into tabletop and recovery exercises; and (5) consult and coordinate with other Federal agencies on cybersecurity-related programs, policies, and operations and with other relevant Federal agencies and within DHS on security of digital control systems. Grants the Assistant Secretary primary authority within DHS over the National Communications System.</summary>
</bill>
