<bill session="112" type="h" number="6503" updated="2013-07-20T02:06:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Fuels Innovation Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To promote the development of renewable energy on certain Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400570"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5991"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="6154"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1775"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2012--Introduced.
Clean Fuels Innovation Act of 2012 - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) complete the Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement (EIS) for Solar Energy Development in Six Southwestern States in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) to analyze the potential impacts of the development of renewable energy on public land and any land use plans, and (2) amend such land use plans as determined appropriate. Establishes similar requirements for the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) with respect to National Forest System land. Requires the Secretary of Interior to establish a renewable energy leasing pilot program under which lease sales of certain sites are conducted on covered lands administered by the Secretary to carry out renewable energy projects. Requires the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to jointly determine whether or not to expand the pilot program to all covered lands. Defines "covered land" to mean land that is public land or National Forest System land and not excluded from the development of renewable energy under federal law. Establishes the Renewable Energy Resource Conservation Fund to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior for mitigating the impacts of renewable energy on federal land and carrying out any activity authorized under the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965, with the exception of the acquisition of land, water, or interests therein. Requires the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to submit a report that: (1) identifies locations on certain military installations in the United States that could be developed for renewable energy production, and (2) describes the administration of the development of commercial-scale renewable energy projects on such installations. Requires the Secretary of Defense to publish a notice of intent to prepare an EIS to support the development of renewable energy on the locations identified. Requires the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to determine the feasibility of carrying out a mitigation banking program on federal lands administered by the Secretaries to offset the impacts of renewable energy on such lands.</summary>
</bill>
