<bill session="110" type="h" number="6778" updated="2013-07-19T22:03:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ex-Offenders Voting Rights Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To secure the Federal voting rights of certain qualified ex-offenders who have served their sentences.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="818"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="7136"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3640"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2008--Introduced.
Ex-Offenders Voting Rights Act of 2008 - Declares that the right of a U.S. citizen to vote in any election for federal office shall not be denied or abridged because that individual has been convicted of a criminal offense unless, at the time of the election, such individual is serving a felony sentence in a correctional institution or facility. Requires the chief correctional officer of each state to inform convicted felons within 30 days after their release of their right to vote in elections for federal office and the date of the next election in which they are eligible to vote. Provides for enforcement and remedies for violations of this Act. Specifies that: (1) nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit a state from enacting any state law that affords the right to vote in any election for federal office on terms less restrictive than those terms established by this Act; and (2) the rights and remedies established by this Act shall be in addition to all other rights and remedies provided by law, and shall not supersede, restrict, or limit the application of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 or the National Voter Registration Act of 1993.</summary>
</bill>
