<bill session="111" type="h" number="2364" updated="2013-07-19T23:33:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 211(o) of the Clean Air Act to change the definition of renewable biomass in the renewable fuel program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412300" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2009-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Clean Air Act to include within the definition of "renewable biomass" for purposes of renewable fuel program provisions materials, pre-commercial thinnings, or removed invasive species from National Forest System land and public lands that: (1) are byproducts of preventative treatments; (2) are removed to reduce hazardous fuels, to reduce or contain disease or insect infestation, or to restore ecosystem health; (3) would not otherwise be used for higher-value products; (4) are not from components of the national Wilderness Preservation System, Wilderness Study Areas, Inventoried Roadless Areas or unroaded acres of at least 5,000 acres, old growth or mature forest stands, components of the National Landscape Conservation System, National Monuments, National Conservation Areas, Designated Primitive Areas, or Wild and Scenic Rivers corridors; (5) are harvested in environmentally sustainable quantities; and (6) are harvested in accordance with federal and state law and applicable land management plans.</summary>
</bill>
