<bill session="111" type="h" number="2199" updated="2013-07-19T23:31:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Workers From Imminent Dangers Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to authorize the Secretary of Labor to prevent employee exposure to imminent dangers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2009--Introduced.
Protecting Workers From Imminent Dangers Act of 2009 - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to require the Department of Labor to: (1) inform employers and employees and their representatives when a condition or practice in a place of employment is such that an imminent danger to safety or health exists that could reasonably be expected to cause death, serious physical harm, or permanent impairment of the health or functional capacity of employees if not corrected immediately or before the danger can be eliminated through prescribed enforcement procedures; and (2) request that the condition or practice be corrected immediately or that employees be immediately removed from exposure to such danger. Requires the Department, if an employer refuses to comply with such request, to immediately issue an order requiring the employer to cause all persons to be withdrawn from, and to be prohibited from entering, such area until the Department determines that such imminent danger and the conditions or practices which caused it no longer exist. Declares that such an order shall not preclude issuing a citation or proposing a penalty for a violation under such Act. Prohibits the Department from preventing: (1) the entry or continued activity of employees whose presence is necessary to avoid, correct, or remove such imminent danger or to maintain the capacity of a continuous process operation to resume normal operations without a complete cessation of operations; and (2) a necessary cessation of operations from being accomplished in a safe and orderly manner. Prohibits persons from discharging or discriminating against an employee for the refusal to perform a duty that has been identified by an order as the source of an imminent danger. Sets forth penalties for violations.</summary>
</bill>
