<bill session="109" type="s" number="1921" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Savings for Working Families Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote freedom, fairness, and economic opportunity by repealing the income tax and other taxes, abolishing the Internal Revenue Service, and replacing such taxes with a national sales tax and a business tax.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2005-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="25"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="25"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Inheritance tax"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax simplification"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/26/2005--Introduced.
Repeals: (1) the income tax, including the tax on capital gains and the alternative minimum tax; (2) estate, gift, and generation-skipping transfer taxes; and (3) the Financing of Presidential Election Campaigns provisions. Imposes a sales tax of 8.4% on the use or consumption of taxable property or services, to be administered and collected by the states. Allows certain credits against such tax for, among other things, business use conversion, export sales, bad debt, insurance proceeds, and previously taxed property. Grants a family consumption allowance for certain low-income families. Repeals the corporate income tax and related provisions. Imposes a business tax of 8.4% of the annual gross profit on the sale of taxable property and services in the United States by a business entity. Defines "gross profits" as the taxable receipts of a business entity over the allowable deductible amounts for such entity, including the cost of business purchases and loss carryover deductions. Sets forth rules for the taxation of income from the non-exempt business activities of governmental entities. Revises the tax treatment of charitable and other nonprofit organizations. Imposes a tax of 8.4% of the customs value of all property brought into the United States for consumption, use, or warehousing. Revises tax administration provisions, including registration, accounting, penalty, and taxpayer rights provisions. Prohibits funding of the Internal Revenue Service after FY2010. Savings for Working Families Act of 2005 - Allows certain low-income individuals to establish individual development accounts (IDAs) to accumulate assets for, among other things, higher education expenses, first-time home purchases, and business capitalization or expansion costs. Provides for federal matching funds to certain financial institutions for investment in IDAs.</summary>
</bill>
