<bill session="111" type="h" number="6404" updated="2013-07-20T00:10:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Breast Density and Mammography Reporting Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require that every mammography report delivered to a patient after a mammography examination, as required by section 354 of the Public Health Service Act (commonly referred to as the "Mammography Quality Standards Act of 1992"), contain a summary of the patient's breast density and a statement concerning the benefit of supplementary screening tests for patients with dense breast tissue, where such additional evaluations are recommended by a patient's interpreting physician.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2010-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2010-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2010-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2010-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2010--Introduced.
Breast Density and Mammography Reporting Act of 2010 - Amends the Mammography Quality Standards Act of 1992 to include within the standards to assure the safety and accuracy of mammography the requirement that: (1) facilities that perform mammograms provide the patient with a summary of the report of the mamography results that includes information regarding the patient's individual measure of breast density based on the Breast Imaging Reporting and Data System established by the American College of Radiology and used by the National Cancer Institute, or as specified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) based upon new scientific knowledge, technological advances, or other updated medical procedures where the use of such screening developments is consistent with the practice of medical experts in the field; (2) the summary convey to the patient his or her increased risk of developing breast cancer based on that person's individual measure of breast density analyzed by the patient's interpreting physician; and (3) the report include a notice to the patient stating that he or she might benefit from supplementary screening tests for expanded detection if his or her mammogram demonstrates dense breast tissue, that a report of the mammography results has been sent to his or her treating physician's office, and and the patient should contact that physician regarding any questions or concerns about the report.</summary>
</bill>
