<bill session="113" type="s" number="1398" updated="2013-11-02T07:04:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Real Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal Government to expedite the sale of underutilized Federal real property.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1382"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1486"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2013--Introduced.
Federal Real Property Asset Management Reform Act of 2013 - States that the purpose of this Act is to increase the efficiency and effectiveness of the federal government in managing real property by: (1) requiring federal agencies to maintain an up-to-date inventory of real property, (2) establishing a Federal Real Property Council to develop guidance on and ensure the implementation of strategies for better managing federal real property, and (3) authorizing a pilot program to expedite the disposal of surplus real property. Requires each federal agency to: (1) maintain adequate inventory controls and accountability systems for real property under its control, (2) develop current and future workforce projections to assess the need of the federal workforce regarding the use of real property, (3) continuously survey real property under its control to identify excess and underutilized property and other real property suitable for colocation or consolidation with other agencies and facilities, (4) establish goals to reduce excess and underutilized federal property, (5) assess leased space to identify space that is not fully used or occupied, and (6) conduct an inventory and make an assessment of real property under its control. Requires the Postmaster General to annually identify a list of postal properties with space available for use by federal agencies. Establishes a Federal Real Property Council to: (1) develop guidance and ensure implementation of an efficient and effective real property management strategy, (2) identify opportunities to better manage real property assets, and (3) reduce the costs of managing real property. Requires agencies with independent leasing authority to submit to the Council a list of all their leases, including operating leases. Requires the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish and maintain a single, comprehensive, and descriptive database of real property under the custody and control of all federal agencies Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to establish a pilot program to dispose of, by sale, transfer, or other means of disposal, any surplus property. Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to report on such pilot program. Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to make grants to private nonprofit organizations to purchase real property to assist the homeless.</summary>
</bill>
