<bill session="113" type="h" number="2729" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Assistance Eligibility Verification Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title IV of the Social Security Act to provide for information comparisons for USDA Housing Assistance programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400004"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2013-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2013--Introduced.
Housing Assistance Eligibility Verification Act of 2013 - Amends part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) of title IV of the Social Act to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to furnish to the Secretary of Health and Human Service (HHS) information in the Federal Parent Locator Service (FPLS) and other USDA sources for comparison with information in the National Directory of New Hires, in order to obtain information in the Directory with respect to individuals (including tenants) who are applying for or participating in any housing program under the Housing Act that extends financial assistance, through the Farmers Home Administration, to owners of farms and other real estate, among other such parties. Requires USDA to seek information, and make information disclosures, only to the extent necessary to verify an individual's employment and income. Requires the Secretary of HHS to: (1) compare information in the National Directory with information provided by USDA about such individuals; and (2) disclose to USDA, in turn, National Directory information about them. Authorizes USDA to use the information resulting from a data match to: (1) verify the employment and income of such individuals; and (2) analyze such information after the removal of personal identifiers. Sets forth rules for the types of disclosures permitted and conditions on disclosure. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to apply to farm housing programs under the Housing Act of 1949 the requirement that the Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary of the Treasury disclose return information on earned, retirement, and unearned income to federal, state, and local agencies administering certain programs under the Social Security Act, the Food Stamp Act of 1977, or veterans programs, or certain housing assistance programs.</summary>
</bill>
