<bill session="113" type="h" number="3230" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-03T13:59:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-03T13:59:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pay Our Guard and Reserve Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Pay Our Guard and Reserve Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations during a Government shutdown to provide pay and allowances to members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces who perform inactive-duty training during such period.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400340"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2013-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412538" joined="2013-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 370 Reported to House. The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 70, H.J. Res. 71, H.J. Res. 72, H.J. Res. 73, and H.R. 3230. The resolution provides for 30 minutes of debate on each measure and provides for one motion to recommit each measure. The resolution also provides that it shall be in order at any time through the calendar day of October 6, 2013, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 370 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T12:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 370.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6193-6200" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T12:42:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 70, H.J. Res. 71, H.J. Res. 72, H.J. Res. 73, and H.R. 3230. The resolution provides for 30 minutes of debate on each measure and provides for one motion to recommit each measure. The resolution also provides that it shall be in order at any time through the calendar day of October 6, 2013, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T12:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on H.R. 3230.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T13:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6198" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T13:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Enyart moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6198-6199" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6198" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Enyart motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment, pending reservation of a point of order. The amendment would replace the underlying bill with the Senate Amendment to H.J.Res. 59.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T13:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (FL) raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Young stated that the amendment was not germane to the underlying bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T13:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Enyart moved to appeal of the ruling of the chair.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6199" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T13:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (FL) moved to table the motion to appeal of the ruling of the chair</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6199" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T13:50:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the appeal of the ruling of the chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 194 (Roll no. 515).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="516" datetime="2013-10-03T13:59:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 265 - 160 (Roll no. 516).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6193" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03T13:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="206">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 206.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="370"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3214"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/3/2013--Passed House without amendment.
Pay Our Guard and Reserve Act - Makes appropriations for FY2014, for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for FY2014 are not in effect, for pay and allowances to members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces who perform inactive-duty training during FY2014. Makes such appropriations, funds, and authority granted by this Act available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment of an appropriation for any purpose for which amounts are made available by this Act, (2) enactment of the applicable regular or continuing appropriations resolution or other Act without any appropriation for such purpose, or (3) January 1, 2015.</summary>
</bill>
