<bill session="110" type="s" number="1493" updated="2013-07-19T22:33:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Advanced Information and Communications Technology Research Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote innovation and basic research in advanced information and communications technologies that will enhance or facilitate the availability and affordability of advanced communications services to all Americans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6862"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6862-6863" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2007--Introduced.
Advanced Information and Communications Technology Research Act - Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) and the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to develop a plan to increase sharing of spectrum between federal and nonfederal government users and establish a implementation pilot program. Requires the director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to establish the Telecommunications Standards and Technology Acceleration Research Program to support and promote innovation in the United States through high-risk, high-reward telecommunications research. Requires the director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to establish a program of basic research in advanced information and communications technologies focused on enhancing or facilitating the availability and affordability of advanced communications services to all Americans. Requires related grants.</summary>
</bill>
