<bill session="110" type="h" number="7245" updated="2013-07-19T22:07:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Election Software Disclosure Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to prohibit the use in any election for Federal office of any election-dedicated voting system technology which has not been certified for use in the election by the State which will administer the election and to establish the standards under which such technology and information regarding the technology may be disclosed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/2008--Introduced.
Election Software Disclosure Act of 2008 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to prohibit a voting system used in a state in a federal election from containing or using any election-dedicated voting system technology: (1) which has not been certified by the state for such use; and (2) which has not been deposited with the appropriate state and local election officials to be held in escrow and disclosed in accordance with this Act. Requires a state or local election official with whom an election-dedicated voting system technology has been deposited to: (1) hold it in escrow; and (2) disclose information regarding it to a qualified person who has entered into a nondisclosure agreement meeting certain requirements with respect to the technology, or if state law requires such disclosure.</summary>
</bill>
