<bill session="111" type="s" number="3883" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Effective STEM Teaching and Learning Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend part B of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to promote effective STEM teaching and learning.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Effective STEM Teaching and Learning Act of 2010 - Replaces the Mathematics and Science Partnership program under part B of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 with a program providing competitive grants to states to improve preschool through grade 12 education in: (1) mathematics or science, or both; and (2) at the state's discretion, technology or engineering, or both. Requires state grantees to use: (1) up to 20% their grant for certain state-level science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) activities, including the development, implementation, or improvement of a comprehensive state STEM plan; and (2) the bulk of their grant for competitive subgrants to high-need local educational agencies (LEAs), partnerships between such LEAs and institutions of higher education or nonprofit organizations, or educational service agencies proposing to serve such LEAs. Directs subgrantees to use the subgrants to implement high-quality, evidence-based, comprehensive, and coherent STEM programs in high-need schools that include: (1) high-quality professional development for teachers and school leaders; (2) high-quality curriculum and instructional materials that are aligned with state standards; (3) coherent, high-quality assessment systems that are aligned with state standards and assessments, and used to improve instruction and student interventions; and (4) program monitoring. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to reserve a portion of part B funds to award competitive, capacity-building grants to states that do not receive a STEM improvement grant under part B.</summary>
</bill>
