<bill session="113" type="s" number="1023" updated="2013-11-05T04:46:42-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Investment in American Jobs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, to conduct an interagency review of and report on ways to increase the competitiveness of the United States in attracting foreign investment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2013-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2052"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2013--Introduced.
Global Investment in American Jobs Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) U.S. ability to attract foreign direct investment is directly linked to U.S. long-term economic prosperity, global competitiveness, and security; (2) it should be mindful of the potential impact upon the U.S. ability to attract foreign direct investment when evaluating proposed legislation; (3) it is a top national priority to enhance U.S. competitiveness, prosperity, and security by removing unnecessary barriers to foreign direct investment and the U.S. jobs it creates and promoting policies to ensure the United States remains the premier global destination in which to invest, hire, innovate, and manufacture products; (4) maintaining the U.S. commitment to open investment policy encourages other countries to do the same and enables the United States to open new markets abroad for U.S. companies and their products; and (5) U.S. policies regarding foreign direct investment should reflect national security interests and should not disadvantage domestic investors or companies. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to conduct an interagency review of the U.S. global competitiveness in attracting foreign direct investment and report to Congress recommendations for making the United States more competitive in attracting foreign direct investment without undermining fundamental domestic labor, consumer, or environmental protections.</summary>
</bill>
