<bill session="113" type="s" number="1219" updated="2013-11-02T07:02:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians Water Rights Settlement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians Water Rights Settlement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-10">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2508"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2013--Introduced.
Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians Water Rights Settlement Act - Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms the Pechanga Settlement Agreement, entered into by the Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians, the Rancho California Water District (RCWD), the Eastern Municipal Water District (EMWD), and the United States. Ratifies, confirms, and declares valid the Tribal Water Right which shall be held in trust by the United States on behalf of the Band and its allottees. States that the Band shall: (1) have the authority to use, allocate, and lease the Tribal Water Right; and (2) enact a Pechanga Water Code. Authorizes the waiver of claims by the Band and the United States regarding: (1) Santa Margarita River Watershed water rights, (2) subsidence damage to lands within the Reservation, and (3) the negotiation or execution of the Pechanga Settlement Agreement or this Act. Requires the Band and the United States to waive such claims against the RCWD and EMWD. Establishes in the Treasury the Pechanga Settlement Fund. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to use amounts from designated accounts of that Fund to fulfill the Band's obligations under the Recycled Water Infrastructure Agreement and the ESAA Capacity Agreement, both entered into by the Band, RCWD, and United States. (The ESSA Capacity Agreement deals with the delivery of potable water that the Band receives from the EMWD and the Metropolitan Water District of Southern California pursuant to an Extension of Service Area Agreement with those entities.) Repeals this Act and voids any related agreements on the later of May 1, 2030, or the day after an alternative date agreed to by the Band and the Secretary, if the Secretary does not publish a statement of findings required under this Act by April 30, 2030. Returns any appropriations and unobligated amounts to the general fund of the Treasury.</summary>
</bill>
