<bill session="112" type="s" number="3309" updated="2013-07-20T02:45:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeless Veterans Assistance Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the assistance provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs to homeless veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4241-4242"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4242-4243" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-668.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2012--Introduced.
Homeless Veterans Assistance Improvement Act of 2012 - Requires public or private nonprofit entities that receive grants under the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) comprehensive service programs for homeless veterans to agree to meet the physical, privacy, safety, and security needs of such veterans. Requires at least 1% of VA financial assistance provided for supportive services for very low-income veteran families in permanent housing to be used for legal services to assist such families with issues that interfere with their ability to obtain or retain housing or supportive services. Allows services for which a homeless veteran receives a grant under the comprehensive service programs to include furnishing care for a dependent. Directs (under current law, authorizes) the VA Secretary to make per diem homeless veterans assistance payments to certain entities that meet the supportive services criteria, but also furnish assistance to individuals who are not veterans. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants for the operational expenses of a service center established for homeless veterans. Revises VA authority to provide dental care to veterans receiving certain other assistance through the VA to include those veterans receiving assistance under the United States Housing Act of 1937. Extends permanently the VA comprehensive service programs for homeless veterans. Extends temporarily various VA authorities and programs affecting homeless veterans.</summary>
</bill>
