<bill session="109" type="s" number="568" updated="2013-07-19T20:18:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Insurance Budgeting Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Truth in Budgeting and Social Security Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to balance the budget and protect the Social Security Trust Fund surpluses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2005-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2422-2424"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biennial budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget reconciliation"/>
    <term name="Budget resolutions"/>
    <term name="Capital budgets"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="Economic forecasting"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Federal budget process"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fiscal year"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="House Appropriations"/>
    <term name="House Budget"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Senate Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Senate Budget"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2005--Introduced.
Truth in Budgeting and Social Security Protection Act of 2005 - Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) (BBEDC) to extend discretionary spending caps and pay-as-you-go (PAYGO) requirements. Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (CBA) to prescribe authority and criteria for designation of emergency requirements, as well as points of order against such a designation. Amends BBEDC to extend indefinitely certain budget enforcement mechanisms of discretionary spending limits (caps). Amends CBA to require: (1) proposed legislation to contain a projection by the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) of the cost of debt servicing for measures; (2) conference reports to contain amounts allocated to the Committee on Appropriations subcommittees; and (3) the CBO to report on proposed legislation or conference reports by any committee that contain cost riders that are likely to increase the cost path of a measure. Requires the President to report to specified congressional committees in January of each year on the fiscal exposures of the Federal Government and their implications for long-term financial health. Federal Insurance Budgeting Act of 2005 - Requires that, starting FY 2008, the President's budget submission to Congress be based upon the risk-assumed cost of Federal insurance programs for accrual budgeting purposes. Amends cost requirements of Federal insurance programs. Requires agencies responsible for Federal insurance programs to develop models to estimate their risk-assumed cost by year. Amends CBA to revise the Federal and congressional budget processes by establishing a two-year budgeting and appropriations cycle and timetable. Defines the budget biennium as the two consecutive fiscal years beginning on October 1 of any odd-numbered year. Establishes the Commission on Federal Budget Concepts.</summary>
</bill>
