<bill session="110" type="h" number="4062" updated="2013-07-19T21:39:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Accountability for Nuclear Waste Storage Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to require commercial nuclear power plant operators to transfer spent nuclear fuel from the spent nuclear fuel pools of the operators into spent nuclear fuel dry casks at independent spent fuel storage installations of the operators that are licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, to convey to the Secretary of Energy title to all such transferred spent nuclear fuel, to provide for the transfer to the Secretary of the independent spent fuel storage installation operating responsibility of each plant together with the license granted by the Commission for the installation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2007-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2007-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400324" joined="2008-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="784"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/2007--Introduced.
Federal Accountability for Nuclear Waste Storage Act of 2007 - Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to require commercial nuclear power plant operators to transfer, within six years after enactment of this Act, spent nuclear fuel from spent nuclear fuel pools into spent nuclear fuel dry casks at an independent spent fuel storage facility generally licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) and located at the power reactor site.Directs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) make grants to compensate a contractor for expenses incurred in carrying out such transfer; and (2) accept conveyance of title to a spent nuclear fuel dry cask (including its contents) from the contractor following certification of compliance by the NRC. States that conveyance of title confers upon the Secretary full responsibility for the possession, stewardship, maintenance, monitoring, and ultimate disposition of all transferred spent nuclear fuel. Authorizes the Secretary to contract with the holder of an NRC operating license for power reactors located on or adjacent to the spent nuclear fuel dry cask for the performance of such tasks.</summary>
</bill>
