<bill session="112" type="h" number="3624" updated="2013-07-20T01:41:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Student Loan Default Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Education to enter into voluntary, flexible agreements with certain guaranty agencies to provide delinquency prevention and default aversion services for borrowers and potential borrowers of Federal Direct Loans under the Higher Education Act of 1965, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400274"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2012-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="2012-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2012-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2012-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2012-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2012-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2011--Introduced.
Student Loan Default Prevention Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education, upon the request of an eligible guaranty agency, to enter into or revise a voluntary, flexible agreement with that agency to provide services to borrowers and potential borrowers of Federal Family Education Loans (FFELs) or Direct Loans (DLs). Treats guaranty agencies as eligible to participate in such agreements if they have extensive and relevant experience and demonstrated effectiveness in providing such services. Authorizes those guaranty agencies to provide services that include: (1) delinquency prevention and default aversion activities, (2) collecting defaulted loans, (3) monitoring institutions that participate in the DL program, (4) training financial aid officials, and (5) informational outreach to schools and students that supports access to higher education and financial literacy. Requires the Secretary to pay fees to such agencies that are cost neutral and take into account the savings projected from the provision of such services.</summary>
</bill>
