<bill session="110" type="s" number="2551" updated="2013-07-19T22:43:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nuclear Waste Policy Amendments Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the safe development of a repository at the Yucca Mountain site in the State of Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2008-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2008-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2008-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2008-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2008-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2008-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2008-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S285-286"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2008--Introduced.
Nuclear Waste Policy Amendments Act of 2008 - Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to revise administrative procedures, including those used by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) at the Yucca Mountain site, for applications: (1) for a construction authorization; (2) to amend a construction authorization to receive and possess spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste; and (3) to close a repository permanently.Revises administrative procedures for infrastructure activities conducted by the Secretary of Energy at the Yucca Mountain site.States that, in any environmental impact statement regarding a repository for spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste, the NRC need not consider any action related to construction or operation of a rail transport system for transporting spent nuclear fuel or high-level radioactive waste to the repository.Expresses the nature of the Secretary's obligation to develop a repository in accordance with the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 for purposes of an NRC determination on whether to grant, amend, or renew any license for a civilian nuclear power reactor or high-level radioactive waste or spent fuel storage or treatment facility. Declares that the Secretary's obligation provides sufficient and independent grounds for any further NRC findings of reasonable assurances that spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste would be disposed of safely and in a timely manner. Declares that no consideration of the environmental impact of the storage of spent nuclear fuel or high-level radioactive waste on the site of the civilian nuclear power reactor or high-level radioactive waste or spent fuel storage or treatment facility for the period following the term of the license shall be required in any environmental analysis prepared in connection with a license to construct or operate the facility.Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to issue, administer, and enforce air quality permits or requirements affecting activities subject to this Act.Applies requirements for expedited authorizations to the conduct of infrastructure activities.Exempts from certain requirements of the Solid Waste Disposal Act for disposal or management of solid waste or hazardous waste any material that is: (1) transported or stored in NRC-certified containers; or (2) located at the Yucca Mountain site for disposal if it is managed or disposed of in compliance with an NRC license. Prescribes requirements for contracts for the acceptance of title, subsequent transportation, and disposal of waste or spent fuel from new civilian nuclear power reactors.</summary>
</bill>
