<bill session="109" type="hr" number="728" updated="2013-07-19T19:00:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require preapproval of privately-funded travel and the inclusion of such travel information on the public website of the Office of the Clerk of the House of Representatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2006-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="2006-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2006-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional publicity"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="House Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/2006--Introduced.
Amends rule XXV (Limitations on Outside Earned Income and Acceptance of Gifts) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require a Member, officer, or employee of the House, before taking a privately-funded trip, to provide the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct with the trip's complete itinerary and estimated expenses, together with an explanation of its purpose and relationship to official duties. Requires the Committee to make a determination that the proposed trip (including the itinerary and estimated expenses) complies with all applicable House rules. Requires such individual to provide the actual itinerary and actual expenses to the Committee within 15 days after completion of the trip (not counting Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays). Requires the Committee, within 45 days after receipt of such information, to verify compliance with the itinerary and expenses it preapproved and report to the Clerk of the House. Requires the Clerk of the House, within 10 days after receipt, to post on the Clerk's public Internet site any information submitted about a privately-funded trip, including the advance authorizations, disclosures of reimbursement, the itinerary, and expenses. Keeps the information available on the website until the individual no longer serves as a Member, officer, or employee of the House.</summary>
</bill>
