<bill session="112" type="h" number="5713" updated="2013-07-20T01:59:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Talk Before You Toll Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century to ensure that the highest priority consideration is given to local comments when selecting a toll pilot project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400616"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2012-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400280" joined="2012-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2012-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/2012--Introduced.
Talk Before You Toll Act of 2012 - Amends the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century (TEA-21) to revise the Interstate System (IS) reconstruction and rehabilitation pilot program. Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to permit states to collect tolls on highways, bridges, or tunnels for reconstructing and rehabilitating IS highway corridors only if the state has solicited, received, and published on its website public comments approving or disapproving the toll facility, including comments on its economic and environmental impact. Directs the Secretary, upon a state's application for a facility, to meet monthly with local transportation representatives and consumer advocacy groups to discuss their views and recommendations for any modifications to a state's plan for a proposed toll facility. Requires a state to hold at least one public meeting to review the specifics of its final facility management plan and solicit public comment. Requires the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) to: (1) publish on its website all comments and suggestions received by the state regarding the proposed toll facility, and (2) consider them before making a final determination on a state's application.</summary>
</bill>
