<bill session="111" type="h" number="861" updated="2013-07-19T23:19:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Strategic Targeted American Recovery and Transition Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">American Recovery and Reinvestment Tax Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making supplemental appropriations for job creation, school repair and modernization, and tax reduction for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2009, and for other stimulative purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412300"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="598"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="679"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="336"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="350"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2009--Introduced.
Strategic Targeted American Recovery and Transition Act - Designates: (1) each amount in this Act as an emergency requirement, necessary to meet certain emergency needs in accordance with the FY2008-FY2009 congressional budget resolutions; and (2) as an emergency for Pay-As-You-Go (PAYGO) principles. Establishes use-it-or-lose-it requirements for grantees. Requires them to enter into contracts or other binding commitments within one year after enactment of this Act, or within nine months after the grant is awarded, whichever is later, to make use of 100% of such funds. Requires agency recovery or deobligation and redistribution of uncommitted funds. Makes all funds appropriated by this Act available for obligation through FY2010, unless expressly provided otherwise. Makes additional appropriations to specified federal agency and departmental Offices of Inspector General. Appropriates additional amounts to the Government Accountability Office (GAO). Prohibits the use of funds for a project for the construction, alteration, maintenance, or repair of a public building or public work unless all of the iron and steel used in the project is domestic, except in certain circumstances. Requires publication on the website Recovery.gov of: (1) all federal agency plans for using funds made available in this Act; and (2) all federal, state, or local agency public notices regarding funds obligated to particular infrastructure investments. Prescribes review and reporting requirements for inspectors general of federal departments or executive agencies, the GAO, and the Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers. Establishes the Recovery Act Accountability and Transparency Board to: (1) coordinate and conduct oversight of federal spending under this Act to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse; and (2) establish the Recovery.gov website. Places limitations on the length of certain noncompetitive contracts. Grants the Comptroller General and the Offices of Inspector General access to certain contractors' or subcontractors' records or employees. Prohibits reprisals against state and local government and contractor whistleblowers. Makes supplemental appropriations for FY2009 to: (1) the Department of Labor (DOL), Employment and Training Administration; (2) the Department of Education; and (3) the Department of Transportation (DOT). American Recovery and Reinvestment Tax Act of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase: (1) to 45% the rate of the earned income tax credit in 2009 or 2010 for taxpayers with three or more qualifying children; (2) the threshold amount for the phase-out of such credit for married couples filing jointly; and (3) the refundable portion of the child tax credit in 2009 and 2010. Extends for one year the 50% bonus depreciation allowance for specified types of depreciable property and through 2009 the increased expensing allowance ($125,000) for depreciable business assets. Allows a work opportunity tax credit for unemployed veterans and disconnected youth (certain youth who are not regularly employed or attending school) hired in 2009 or 2010. Repeals the requirement that federal, state, and local governmental entities withhold 3% of payments to contractors who provide goods and services to such entities.</summary>
</bill>
