<bill session="109" type="h" number="4684" updated="2013-07-19T19:45:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to provide for an increase in the amount of awards under the first and second phases of the Small Business Innovation Research program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400084"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-01">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Technology, and Standards.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Environment, Technology, and Standards" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Industrial research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2006--Introduced.
Amends the Small Business Act relating to the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Program (a program under which a portion of a federal agency's research or research and development funds are reserved for award to small businesses) to require certain program directives issued for the general conduct of SBIR programs within the federal government to provide, among other things, that an agency may increase to specified levels amounts awarded in the first and second phases of the SBIR Program. Requires such amounts be adjusted once every five years to reflect economic adjustments and programmatic considerations.</summary>
</bill>
