<bill session="109" type="h" number="1705" updated="2013-07-19T19:19:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a program to support deployment of idle reduction and energy conservation technologies for heavy-duty vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400368"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2005-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-19">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="6"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air conditioning"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Weights and measures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/19/2005--Introduced.
Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) review and update mobile source air emission models to determine whether they accurately reflect the emissions resulting from long-duration idling of heavy-duty vehicles and other vehicles and engines; (2) review emission reductions achieved by the use of idle reduction technology; and (3) complete such revisions of EPA regulations and guidance as the Administrator determines to be appropriate. Instructs the Administrator to establish a program to support deployment of idle reduction and energy conservation technologies, giving priority to deployment based on the costs and beneficial effects on air quality and ability to lessen the emission of criteria air pollutants. Directs the Administrator to commence a study to analyze all locations at which heavy-duty vehicles stop for long-duration idling. States that in order to promote reduction of fuel use and emissions because of engine idling, the maximum gross vehicle weight limit and the axle weight limit for any heavy-duty vehicle equipped with an idle reduction technology shall be increased by a quantity necessary to compensate for the additional weight of the idle reduction system.</summary>
</bill>
