<bill session="109" type="s" number="3605" updated="2013-07-19T20:44:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Great Lakes Migratory Bird Research and Management Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enable the Great Lakes Fishery Commission to investigate the effects of migratory birds on sustained productivity of stocks of fish of common concern in the Great Lakes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2006-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6791"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="5089"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2006--Introduced.
Great Lakes Migratory Bird Research and Management Act - Amends the Great Lakes Fishery Act of 1956 to authorize the Great Lakes Fishery Commission to carry out activities relating to the investigation of migratory bird depredation on commercial and sport fisheries in the Great Lakes. Amends the Migratory Bird Treaty Act to require the Secretary of the Interior, on the request of the Great Lakes Fishery Commission, to issue a permit to a cooperating federal, state, or tribal agency of the United States, or federal, provincial, or first nation agency of Canada that is signatory to a Memorandum of Understanding with the Great Lakes Fishery Commission to manage and take migratory birds for the purpose of controlling migratory bird depredation on commercial fisheries and sport fisheries in the Great Lakes.</summary>
</bill>
