<bill session="110" type="s" number="1016" updated="2013-07-19T22:29:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Solar Opportunity and Local Access Rights Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to promote energy independence and self-sufficiency by providing for the use of net metering by certain small electric energy generation systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="2848"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Homeowners' associations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Solar access rights"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/28/2007--Introduced.
Solar Opportunity and Local Access Rights Act - Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to require each state regulatory authority with ratemaking authority, and each nonregulated electric utility, to conduct a hearing, and on the basis of such hearing, adopt a net metering standard. Requires retail electric suppliers to offer to arrange to make net metering available to retail customers on a first-come-first-served basis. Prescribes implementation requirements regarding: (1) net energy measurement; (2) billing practices; (3) ownership of credits; (4) safety and performance standards; and (5) determination of compliance. Directs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to publish model interconnection standards, according to specified requirements, for the physical connection between local distribution systems and qualified generation units and qualified electric generation units that do not exceed 20,000 kilowatts of capacity. Requires states to adopt such model standards, subject to FERC approval. Prohibits a state or nonregulated utility from adopting or enforcing any standard or requirement concerning net metering or interconnection that restricts access to the electric power transmission or local distribution system by qualified generators beyond those established under this Act. Allows states to adopt or enforce additional incentives or requirements to encourage qualified generation and net metering, including any that afford: (1) greater access to the electric power transmission and local distribution systems by qualified generators; or (2) greater compensation or credit for electricity generated by qualified generators. Amends federal law governing administrative services for public buildings and properties to authorize a contract for renewable energy for a maximum period of 30 years. Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to issue regulations to prohibit: (1) excessive fees for solar energy systems building permits; and (2) any restriction impairing the ability of the owner or lessee of a one-family residential structure to install or use a solar energy system on such property. Directs the Secretary to issue regulations also requiring that the application for approval of such a system: (1) be processed and approved in the same manner as an application for approval of an architectural modification to the property; and (2) not be willfully avoided or delayed.</summary>
</bill>
