<bill session="111" type="s" number="1205" updated="2013-07-20T00:34:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to exempt guides for hire and other operators of uninspected vessels on Lake Texoma from Coast Guard and other regulations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2009-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6266"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6266" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Other Legislative Involvement"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2717"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2717"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2009--Introduced.
Exempts residents or nonresidents who assist, accompany, transport, guide, or aid persons in the taking of fish for monetary or other consideration on Lake Texoma (located on the border between Texas and Oklahoma): (1) who are licensed by the state in which they are operating from any related requirement established or administered by the Coast Guard; and (2) who are licensed by the Coast Guard from state regulation so long as the Coast Guard license remains valid. Prohibits an individual with a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariners document and serving under the authority of such license, certificate, or document on a vessel that is required to have a vessel security plan from entering an area designated as a secure area in such a plan unless the individual has (or is accompanied by an individual who has) a biometric transportation security card issued by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating. (Current law contains the same prohibition, but without referring to serving under the authority of such license, certificate, or document.) Removes a provision prohibiting an individual engaged on a towing vessel that pushes, pulls, or hauls alongside a tank vessel from entering a secured area without having (or without being accompanied by an individual who has) such a card.</summary>
</bill>
