<bill session="111" type="h" number="1776" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Quality FIRST (From Incentives, Reporting, Standards, and Technology) Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to expand the development of quality measures for inpatient hospital services, to implement a performance-based payment methodology for the provision of such services under the Medicare Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412234" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2009-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2009-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412289" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412299" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2009--Introduced.
Quality FIRST (From Incentives, Reporting, Standards, and Technology) Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make performance-based payments each fiscal year to hospitals that provide high quality inpatient hospital services to inpatients entitled to benefits under Medicare part A (Hospital Insurance). Requires the Secretary to select appropriate evidence-based, statistically valid, and sufficiently field tested quality measures of care furnished by hospitals in inpatient settings for evaluating hospital performance. Requires a utilization and quality control peer review organization to give priority of quality improvement assistance to low-performing hospitals. Directs the Secretary to establish a program under which a hospital seeking to improve the quality of inpatient hospital services based on the results of a performance evaluation may apply to the Secretary to receive quality improvement assistance from a private quality organization with expertise in supporting inpatient service quality improvement.</summary>
</bill>
