<bill session="111" type="h" number="5851" updated="2013-07-20T00:05:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30T17:11:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-30T17:11:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Offshore Oil and Gas Worker Whistleblower Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Offshore Oil and Gas Worker Whistleblower Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide whistleblower protections to certain workers in the offshore oil and gas industry.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2010-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T00:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1574 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3534 and H.R. 5851. General debate for H.R. 3534 shall be one hour and forty minutes. After general debate, the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. And, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in Part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying the resolution. Notwithstanding clause 11 of rule XVIII, no amendment to that amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed in Part B of the report of the Committee on Rules. The rule also makes in order</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T11:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1574 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1574.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6486-6492" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3534 and H.R. 5851. General debate for H.R. 3534 shall be one hour. After general debate, the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. And, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in Part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying the resolution. Notwithstanding clause 11 of rule XVIII, no amendment to that amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed in Part B of the report of the Committee on Rules. The rule also makes in order H.R. 5851. General debate for H.R. 5851 shall be limited to one hour and the bill is closed to amendments, with the exception of the amendment printed in part C of the report which is considered adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T12:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 5851.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T13:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6492" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T13:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 2c of rule 19, the Chair postponed further proccedings on H.R. 5851 until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6552-6555" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T16:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Kline (MN) moved to recommit with instructions to Education and Labor.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6552-6554" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6552" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T16:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kline (MN) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House with an amendment to insert a new section in the bill entitled "Whistleblower Protection for Certain Offshore Workers."</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T17:04:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 171 - 234 (Roll no. 505).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6553-6554" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-07-30T17:11:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="506" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 315 - 93 (Roll no. 506).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6486-6487" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T17:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T17:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 5851.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T17:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1574, the text of H.R. 5851, as passed by the House, was appended as new matter at the end of H.R. 3534.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30T17:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1574, H.R. 5851 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="111" type="hr" number="1574"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="1574"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5749"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h765"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/30/2010--Passed House without amendment.
Offshore Oil and Gas Worker Whistleblower Protection Act of 2010 - (Sec. 2) Prohibits an employer from discharging, discriminating, against, or engaging in retaliatory actions against specified employees who: (1) report to a government official any violation or unsafe condition under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act; (2) testify or participate in a proceeding concerning such violation; (3) reported an illness, injury, or unsafe condition related to the employer's activities to the employer or a state or federal government official; (4) refused to perform duties, or exercised stop work authority, based upon a good faith belief that performing such duties could result in injury to or impairment of the health of the covered employee or other employees, or cause an oil spill to the environment; or (5) objected to, or refused to participate in any activity, policy, practice, or assigned task that the employee reasonably believed to be in violation of such Act. Sets forth complaint filing procedures with the Secretary of Labor regarding such retaliation. Requires the Secretary to investigate and determine whether there is reasonable cause to believe that the complaint has merit and notify in writing the complainant and the employer regarding the Secretary's findings. Authorizes a civil action to require compliance with this Act. Requires employers to: (1) post a notice approved by the Secretary of Labor explaining employee rights and remedies under this Act in a conspicuous location in the place of employment where employees frequent; (2) provide training to employees about their rights under this Act within 30 days of employment, and at least once annually; and (3) provide employees with a card containing a toll free telephone number at the Department of Labor to get information or file a complaint. Directs the Secretary of Labor, within 30 days after enactment of this Act, to designate agency officials to receive, investigate, and adjudicate complaints concerning violations under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
