<bill session="109" type="s" number="1807" updated="2013-07-19T20:29:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Hurricane Relief and Reconstruction Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide assistance for small businesses damaged by Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2005-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2005-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2005-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2005-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2006-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="2005-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2005-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10799-10801"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-30">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cooperative societies"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Propane"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/2005--Introduced.
Small Business Hurricane Relief and Reconstruction Act of 2005 - Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to make loans of up to $10 million aggregate to a nonprofit organization located or operating in a disaster area (as designated by the President as a result of Hurricane Katrina or Rita) or providing services to persons who have evacuated from a disaster area. Defers disaster loan payments to the later of one year after the date of enactment of this Act or one year from the date of issuance of the loan (but allows the Administrator to extend such deferral until two years after either date). Authorizes the refinancing of any loan or business debt related to such disasters that was outstanding on August 24, 2005. Authorizes the Administrator to make loans to small businesses or cooperatives that demonstrate a direct adverse economic impact caused by either Hurricane Katrina or Rita. Authorizes the Administrator to make loans to small businesses that have or are likely to suffer substantial economic injury on or after August 24, 2005, as the result of a significant increase in the price of heating oil, natural gas, propane, or kerosene. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to authorize such loans for farms that are also a small business and that suffer substantial economic injury after such date as the result of a significant increase in energy or input costs. Authorizes the Administrator to: (1) make supplemental emergency loans to small businesses located anywhere in the United States that are directly adversely affected by Hurricane Katrina or Rita; and (2) guarantee timely payment on any debentures issued by small business development companies after Hurricane Katrina or Rita. Increases authorized funding for small business loan programs. Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of Commerce for grants to state government agencies in Louisiana, Alabama, Mississippi, Texas, and Florida, for relief from damages caused by Hurricane Katrina or Rita. Authorizes appropriations to the SBA for specified small business development and counseling activities. Directs or authorizes the Administrator, with respect to small businesses affected by Hurricane Katrina or Rita, to: (1) establish a contracting outreach and technical assistance program; (2) provide performance bonding; and (3) increase the goal of participation in federal prime contracts and subcontracts.</summary>
</bill>
