<bill session="110" type="s" number="2599" updated="2013-07-19T22:43:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Spouse Education and Employment Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide enhanced education and employment opportunities for military spouses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2008-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home offices"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Telecommuting"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2008--Introduced.
Military Spouse Education and Employment Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to include spouses of members of the Armed Forces on extended active duty (more than 90 days or for an indefinite period) and eligible teleworking military spouses (teleworking spouses whose wages are expected to equal or exceed 150% of U.S. median annual earnings) as members of a targeted group for purposes of the work opportunity tax credit. Includes the wife or husband of a member serving on extended active duty within the federal veterans' employment preference. Allows members who have completed two terms of service and have reenlisted for a third term to transfer a portion of their entitlement to basic educational assistance under the Montgomery GI Bill. (Current law allows such transfer for members with critical military skills.) Requires studies on: (1) the development of an education grant program for training military spouses in health care and early childhood development careers; and (2) creating work opportunities for undergraduate- and graduate-educated military spouses during the active-duty service of their spouses.</summary>
</bill>
