<bill session="109" type="s" number="200" updated="2013-07-19T20:15:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area in the State of Georgia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300021"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2005-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S606"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-02-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment. With written report No. 109-3.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-02-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="10">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 10.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2099"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="203"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Mountains"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2005--Reported to Senate amended.
Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area Act - (Sec. 4) Establishes the Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area in Georgia. Designates the Arabia Mountain Heritage Area Alliance as the Area's management entity. (Sec. 5) Requires the Alliance to develop and submit a management plan for the Heritage Area to the Secretary of the Interior for approval that incorporates an integrated and cooperative approach to protect, interpret, and enhance the resources of the Area. Provides for such plan to be based upon the preferred concept in the document entitled "Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area Feasibility Study", dated February 28, 2001. Prohibits the Secretary from providing any additional funding under this Act until a management plan is submitted. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical and financial assistance to the Area for the development and implementation of the management plan. (Sec. 8) Specifies the effect of this Act on certain authorities for occupational safety, conservation, and environmental regulations and land use regulations. (Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations. Limits: (1) the funding that may be used in any fiscal year to $1,000,000; and (2) the Federal share of the cost of any project or activity carried out using funds made available under this Act to 50 percent. (Sec. 10) Terminates the authority of the Secretary to make grants or provide assistance under this Act on September 30, 2016.</summary>
</bill>
