<bill session="112" type="h" number="4471" updated="2013-07-20T01:48:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gasoline Regulations Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Gasoline Regulations Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require analyses of the cumulative impacts of certain rules and actions of the Environmental Protection Agency that impact gasoline, diesel fuel, and natural gas prices, jobs, and the economy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400431"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2012-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2012-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412458" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2012-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412280" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2012-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412393" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2012-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400392" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2012-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2012-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held Prior to Introduction.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 28 - 13.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-06-06T19:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 112-519.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-06-06T19:40:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="366">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 366.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4480"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3445"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/2012--Reported to House without amendment.
Gasoline Regulations Act of 2012 - Requires the President to establish the Transportation Fuels Regulatory Committee to analyze and report, for each of 2016 and 2020, on the cumulative impacts of certain covered rules and actions under the Clean Air Act, including the impacts on gasoline, diesel fuel, and natural gas prices, operating costs, consumers, regional economies, U.S. competitiveness, small businesses, employment, labor markets, public health, and state, local, and tribal governments. Designates as "covered rules": (1) the rule entitled "Control of Air Pollution From New Motor Vehicles: Tier 3 Motor Vehicle Emission and Fuel Standards"; (2) any rule proposed after March 15, 2012, establishing or revising a standard of performance or emission standard for new stationary sources or hazardous air pollutants that is applicable to petroleum refineries; (3) any rule proposed after March 15, 2012, for implementation of the Renewable Fuel Program under the Clean Air Act; (4) the rules entitled "National Ambient Air Quality Standards for Ozone" and "Reconsideration of the 2008 Ozone Primary and Secondary National Ambient Air Quality Standards" and any subsequent rule revising or supplementing the national ambient air quality standards for ozone; and (5) any successor or substantially similar rules. Defines a "covered action" as any action affecting facilities involved in the production, transportation, or distribution of gasoline, diesel fuel, or natural gas taken on or after January 1, 2009, by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), a state or local government, or a permitting agency as a result of the application of provisions of the Clean Air Act relating to operating permits or the prevention of significant deterioration of air quality to an air pollutant that is identified as a greenhouse gas in the rule entitled "Endangerment and Cause or Contribute Findings for Greenhouse Gases Under Section 202(a) of the Clean Air Act." Prohibits the Administrator from finalizing the following rules until at least six months after the Committee submits its final report: (1) "Control of Air Pollution From New Motor Vehicles: Tier 3 Motor Vehicle Emission and Fuel Standards" and any successor or substantially similar rule; (2) any rule proposed after March 15, 2012, establishing or revising a performance or emission standard for new stationary sources or hazardous air pollutants that is applicable to petroleum refineries; and (3) any rule revising or supplementing the national ambient air quality standards for ozone under the Clean Air Act. Requires the EPA Administrator to consider feasibility and cost in revising or supplementing any such standards for ozone.</summary>
</bill>
