<bill session="112" type="h" number="1256" updated="2013-07-20T01:21:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Physician Payment Transparency and Assessment Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require the use of analytic contractors in identifying and analyzing misvalued physician services under the Medicare physician fee schedule and an annual review of potentially misvalued codes under that fee schedule.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2011-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2011-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2011-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E569"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2011--Introduced.
Medicare Physician Payment Transparency and Assessment Act of 2011 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to identify physician services annually (currently, periodically) as being potentially misvalued using specified criteria. Authorizes the Secretary to use existing processes to receive recommendations on the review and appropriate adjustment of potentially misvalued physician services, but only to the extent consistent with the use of analytic contractors. Requires the Secretary of HHS to use analytic contractors to identify, and analyze services identified as being, potentially misvalued physician services, and perform related tasks as currently authorized.</summary>
</bill>
