<bill session="111" type="h" number="5096" updated="2013-07-19T23:58:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Diverse Teachers Recruitment Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to make grants for recruiting, training, and retaining individuals from underrepresented groups as teachers at public elementary and secondary schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E612"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3891"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/2010--Introduced.
Diverse Teachers Recruitment Act of 2010 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award competitive matching grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) or nonprofits, educational service agencies, institutions of higher education, or states that enter into partnerships with such LEAs, for recruiting, training, and retaining individuals from underrepresented groups as public elementary and secondary school teachers. Gives priority to LEAs that serve the most high-need schools and those that serve schools with the highest percentages of minorities in their student bodies. Requires the Secretary to evaluate the success of the grantees and compile a database of best practices for recruiting, training, and retaining individuals from underrepresented groups as public elementary and secondary school teachers.</summary>
</bill>
