<bill session="109" type="h" number="4087" updated="2013-07-19T19:40:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Court, Offender Supervision, Parole, and Public Defender Employees Equity Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit nonjudicial employees of the District of Columbia courts, employees transferred to the Pretrial Services, Parole, Adult Probation, and Offender Supervision Trustee, and employees of the District of Columbia Public Defender Service to have periods of service performed prior to the enactment of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 included as part of the years of service used to determine the time at which such employees are eligible to retire under chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="2005-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2126"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional pensions"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Disability retirement"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/19/2005--Introduced.
District of Columbia Court, Offender Supervision, Parole, and Public Defender Employees Equity Act of 2005 - Entitles any individual serving as a federal or congressional employee or a Member of Congress who performed qualifying District of Columbia service (certain service as a D.C. court nonjudicial employee, certain service performed by an individual as an employee of an entity of the DC government whose functions were transferred to the Pretrial Services, Parole, Adult Supervision, and Offender Supervision Trustee under the Balanced Budget Act of 1997, and certain service performed by an individual as an employee of the DC Public Defender Service) to have such service included in calculating such individual's creditable service under the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS), but only for purposes of specified sections of FERS. Requires the Office of Personnel Management to accept the certification of the appropriate personnel official of the government of the District of Columbia concerning whether an individual performed qualifying District of Columbia service and the length of the period of such service such individual performed.</summary>
</bill>
