<bill session="113" type="h" number="2379" updated="2013-11-02T06:39:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Qualified Mortgage Loan Originator Transitional Authority Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 to permit a transitional period of 90 days for completion of requirements for qualified registered mortgage loan originators.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2013-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="2013-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2013-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/2013--Introduced.
Qualified Mortgage Loan Originator Transitional Authority Act of 2013 - Amends the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Listening Act of 2008 with respect to the prohibition against an individual's engaging in the business of a loan originator without first obtaining (and maintaining annually) a registration as a registered loan originator or a license and registration as a state-licensed loan originator, as well as obtaining a unique identifier. Authorizes certain individuals who are qualified registered loan originators under the Truth in Lending Act, however, to act as a loan originator, during a 90-day period following submission of background check materials, under the supervision of a state-licensed firm that engages in loan origination. Terminates the individual's authority to act as a loan originator upon the end of such 90-day period.</summary>
</bill>
