<bill session="110" type="h" number="1276" updated="2013-07-19T21:14:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Soboba Band of Luiseno Indians Settlement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To approve, ratify, and confirm the settlement agreement entered into to resolve claims by the Soboba Band of Luiseno Indians relating to alleged interences with the water resources of the Tribe, to authorize and direct the Secretary of the Interior to execute and perform the Settlement Agreement and related waivers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2007-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2007-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2007-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="2007-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="4841"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sewerage"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/2007--Introduced.
Soboba Band of Luiseno Indians Settlement Act - Approves, ratifies, and confirms the Settlement Agreement entered into by the Soboba Band of Luiseno Indians (the Tribe) relating to alleged interferences with the water resources of the Tribe's reservation. Declares that the United States consents to be made a party to the lawsuit Soboba Band of Luiseno Indians v. Metropolitan Water District of Southern California No. 00-04208 GAF (MANx) pending in the U.S. District Court for the Central District of California, for the purpose of entering the judgment and decree attached to the Settlement Agreement as Exhibit H. Authorizes and directs the Secretary of the Interior (or the Secretary's designee) to execute and implement the Settlement Agreement and any amendments approved by the parties to the Agreement to make it consistent with this Act. Establishes the: (1) San Jacinto Basin Restoration Fund for costs associated with constructing and maintaining the part of the basin recharge project necessary to accommodate supplemental imported water deliveries; and (2) Soboba Band of Luiseno Indians Water Development Fund for costs associated with constructing and maintaining water-related development projects. Provides for waivers and releases of specified claims made by the Tribe. Sets forth rules concerning the Tribe's use of water under the Settlement Agreement. Requires the United States, as trustee for the Tribe, and the Tribe to make available up to 98 acres of the Tribe's reservation land for habitat conservation related to the part of the basin recharge project described above.</summary>
</bill>
