<bill session="109" type="h" number="3540" updated="2013-07-19T19:35:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gun Show Loophole Closing Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require criminal background checks on all firearms transactions occurring at events that provide a venue for the sale, offer for sale, transfer, or exchange of firearms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2006-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2005-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2006-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2005--Introduced.
Gun Show Loophole Closing Act of 2005 - Amends the federal criminal code to provide for regulation of firearms transfers at special firearms events (events at which 75 or more firearms are offered or exhibited for sale, exchange, or transfer if one or more of the firearms has been shipped or transported in, or otherwise affects, interstate or foreign commerce, excluding an offer or exhibit of firearms: (1) by an individual, from that individual's personal collection, at that individual's private residence, if the individual is not required to be licensed; and (2) at events conducted and attended by permanent or annual dues paying members of private, not-for-profit organizations whose primary purpose is owning and maintaining real property for hunting activities). Prohibits any person from operating a special firearms event without notifying the Attorney General. Sets forth: (1) responsibilities of special firearms events operators and of firearms licensees and transferors other than licensees at such events, including with regard to criminal background checks; (2) special firearms event license application requirements; and (3) penalties for violation of this Act. Authorizes a state to apply to the Attorney General for, and sets forth criteria for, certification of the 24-hour verification authority of that state with respect to criminal background checks. Increases penalties for: (1) serious record keeping violations by licensees; and (2) violations of criminal background check requirements.</summary>
</bill>
