<bill session="111" type="s" number="1347" updated="2013-07-20T00:35:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Carmelo Rodriguez Military Medical Accountability Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 171 of title 28, United States Code, to allow members of the Armed Forces to sue the United States for damages for certain injuries caused by improper medical care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1478"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2009--Introduced.
Carmelo Rodriguez Military Medical Accountability Act of 2009 - Amends the Federal Tort Claims Act to allow claims for damages to be brought against the United States for personal injury or death of a member of the Armed Forces arising out of a negligent or wrongful act or omission in the performance of medical, dental, or related health care functions that is provided by persons acting within the scope of their office or employment by or at the direction of the government, whether inside or outside the United States. Prohibits a claim under this Act from being reduced by the amount of any benefit received under a Servicemember's Group Life Insurance policy. Makes this Act inapplicable to any claim arising out of the combatant activities of the Armed Forces during the time of armed conflict.</summary>
</bill>
