<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1024" updated="2013-07-19T23:04:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-01-27T12:08:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-01-27T12:08:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing support for designation of January as Poverty in America Awareness Month.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2010-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2010-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-26T15:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McDermott moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-26T15:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H350-353" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-26T15:28:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1024.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-26T15:42:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-27T12:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H400" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-01-27T12:08:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="21" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 387 - 18 (Roll no. 21).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 1/26/2010 H351" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-01-27T12:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/27/2010--Passed House without amendment.
Supports the designation of Poverty in America Awareness Month. Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) eradicating poverty in the United States should be the goal for all people in the United States; (2) the severe economic downturn has highlighted the need to ensure that the nation's most vulnerable individuals and families are able to meet their most fundamental needs during a time of financial crisis; and (3) Congress should recommit itself to helping individuals and families facing economic hardship receive the assistance they need and deserve in moving towards greater economic security through programs under title IV (Grants to States for Aid and Services to Needy Families with Children and for Child-welfare Services) of the Social Security Act and other related programs.</summary>
</bill>
