<bill session="111" type="h" number="5640" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Rape Kit Database Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a National Rape Kit Database.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400426"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2010--Introduced.
National Rape Kit Database Act - Requires the Attorney General to: (1) establish a publicly available database on information on rape kits collected by federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies; and (2) provide technical assistance to such agencies to enable participation in the database. Defines "rape kit" to mean a sexual assault forensics evidence collection kit. Requires certain information to be included in such database by law enforcement agencies and laboratories with respect to a rape kit, including: (1) the date of the action constituting the basis for the collection of the rape kit; (2) the city or locality where such action occurred; (3) the date of the entry into the database; (4) the entity that has possession of the rape kit; and (5) the processing status of the rape kit and whether the statute of limitations has expired (for a backlogged case). Prohibits the disclosure in a rape kit of the personally identifiable information of a sexual assault victim (e.g., name, address, or contact information). Denies grant funds under the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 and the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program to states that fail to comply with the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
