<bill session="111" type="s" number="3272" updated="2013-07-20T00:55:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Close the Revolving Door Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide greater controls and restrictions on revolving door lobbying.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2010-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2259"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2010--Introduced.
Close the Revolving Door Act of 2010 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose a permanent ban (currently, a two-year ban) on lobbying contacts by any former Member of Congress or elected officer of the Senate or the House of Representatives with any Member, officer, or employee of either house of Congress or any employee of any other legislative office. Provides for a six-year lobbying ban (currently, a one-year ban) on former congressional staff. Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to: (1) require the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives to maintain a joint Internet website for the disclosure of lobbying activity called "lobbyist.gov;" (2) require a substantial lobbying entity (defined as an incorporated entity that employs more than three federally-registered lobbyists during a filing period) to file annually with the Secretary and Clerk a list of any employee or contractor who is a former Member of Congress or congressional staff person who made at least $100,000 in any one year, who worked for a total of four years or more in that capacity, or who had a job title that contained the terms Chief of Staff, Legislative or Staff Director, Counsel, Professional Staff Member, Communications Director, or Press Secretary; (3) require the Secretary and the Clerk to provide a copy of the filings of substantial lobbying entities to the U.S. Attorney for the District of Columbia; and (4) increase from $200,000 to $500,000 the civil penalty for intentional failure to correct a defective filing of lobbying activity. Prohibits any person who is a registered lobbyist or an agent of a foreign principal, within six years after leaving such position, from being hired by a Member or committee of either house of Congress with whom that lobbyist or agent has had substantial lobbying contact, subject to a waiver based on a compelling national need. Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit: (1) a political committee from making any expenditure or reimbursement for noncommercial air travel by a candidate for federal office; and (2) a lobbyist from making any contribution of U.S. or foreign currency to or for the benefit of any candidate for federal office.</summary>
</bill>
