<bill session="111" type="s" number="3395" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Renewable Energy Market Access Program Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide cost-sharing assistance to improve access to the markets of foreign countries for energy efficiency products and renewable energy products exported by small- and medium-sized businesses in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2010-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4090-4091"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4091-4092" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2010--Introduced.
Renewable Energy Market Access Program Act - Directs the Under Secretary for International Trade of the Department of Commerce to establish and carry out a program to provide cost-sharing assistance to nonprofit trade associations in the United States or state or regional organizations that promote the exportation and sale of energy efficiency products or renewable energy products to: (1) improve access to the markets of foreign countries for energy efficiency products and renewable energy products exported by small- and medium-sized U.S. businesses; and (2) assist such businesses in obtaining services and other assistance, including from the Department of Commerce and other federal agencies, with respect to exporting such products.</summary>
</bill>
