<bill session="109" type="h" number="5205" updated="2013-07-19T19:50:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transportation Empowerment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To empower States with authority for most taxing and spending for highway programs and mass transit programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400016" joined="2006-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="s" number="2512"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2512"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Highway planning"/>
    <term name="Highway use tax"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Limited access highways"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Toll roads"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2006--Introduced.
Transportation Empowerment Act - Authorizes appropriations, for FY2010-FY2014, out of the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) for the interstate maintenance program, emergency relief, interstate bridge program, the Federal lands highways program, highway safety programs, surface transportation research, and certain administrative expenses. Authorizes a state, upon determining that excess funds have been made available, to transfer the excess funds to, and use such funds for, any surface transportation purpose (including mass transit and rail) in the state. Revises requirements regarding state apportionments under the interstate maintenance component for resurfacing, restoring, rehabilitating, and reconstructing the Interstate System. Prohibits restricting a State's ability, as part of any highway improvement project, to: (1) impose and collect a toll on any highway in the State that is part of the Interstate System; (2) use revenue from such a toll for any purpose that the State determines to be appropriate; or (3) have toll revenue credited toward a non-federal cost share required for receipt of federal funds. Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to: (1) extend, for five years, the availability of HTF funds for certain authorized expenditures; (2) set a core programs financing rate for gasoline, special motor fuels, kerosene, and diesel fuel; (3) establish in the HTF an Infrastructure Special Assistance Fund; and (4) provide for the return of excess tax receipts to states for transportation purposes. Grants consent to states to enter into interstate compacts to establish infrastructure banks to promote investment in the construction of surface transportation projects. Amends the IRC to reduce taxes on gasoline, diesel fuel, kerosene, and special fuels funding the HTF.</summary>
</bill>
