<bill session="112" type="h" number="4398" updated="2013-07-20T01:48:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Racial Profiling Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide grants to States in order to prevent racial profiling.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E573"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/2012--Introduced.
Racial Profiling Prevention Act - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to make a grant to a state that: (1) has enacted and is enforcing a law that prohibits a state or local law enforcement officer from using the race or ethnicity (racial profiling) of the driver or passengers in making routine or spontaneous law enforcement decisions, such as ordinary traffic stops on federal-aid highways; and (2) allows and maintains public inspection statistical information for each motor vehicle stop made by a law enforcement officer on a federal-aid highway regarding the race and ethnicity of the driver and any passengers. Requires grant-receiving states to provide assurances to the Secretary that they are undertaking activities to comply with such requirements. Requires a state to use such grants for the costs of: (1) collecting, maintaining, and evaluating the results of data on traffic stops; and (2) activities to comply with the requirements of this Act. Declares that nothing in this Act shall alter the manner in which a state or local law enforcement officer considers race or ethnicity whenever there is trustworthy information that links persons of a particular race or ethnicity to an identified criminal incident, scheme, or organization.</summary>
</bill>
