<bill session="112" type="h" number="6038" updated="2013-07-20T02:02:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Global Conservation Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To strengthen the role of the United States in the international community of nations in conserving natural resources to further global prosperity and security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400640"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400638" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400442" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412452" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2012-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2012-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2012-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3356"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2012--Introduced.
Global Conservation Act of 2012 - Requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to audit, and report to Congress on, existing U.S. international conservation policies and programs to determine the extent to which such programs are: (1) addressing natural resource challenges to ensure healthy and sustainable supplies of water, wildlife, fish, forests, plants, and other critical resources; (2) advancing U.S. foreign policy priorities in areas such as security, democratization, sustainable food production, and clean water; (3) enhancing economic and wildlife conservation benefits derived from properly managed international hunting and angling tourism; (4) addressing poaching, illegal logging, fishing, and wildlife trafficking; and (5) establishing more effective policies and processes for executive branch agencies engaged in international conservation. Directs the President: (1) to establish the Interagency Working Group on Global Conservation; and (2) through such Working Group, to establish the International Conservation Strategy to strengthen the capacity of the United States to collaborate with other countries, international organizations, the private sector, and private voluntary organizations to conserve natural resources and enhance biodiversity. Requires the Strategy to provide a comprehensive plan of action that identifies specific and measurable benchmarks, goals, and time frames. Requires the Working Group to ensure that the Strategy is appropriate to local needs and conditions and incorporates the views of partner countries. Establishes the Global Conservation Public Advisory Board to: (1) advise the Working Group on matters related to U.S. international conservation policies and programs and the implementation of the Strategy; and (2) ensure that the best scientific, policy, economic security, and business expertise are reflected in U.S. international conservation strategies and policies. Prohibits any provision in this Act from being construed as restricting, limiting, or otherwise impairing: (1) properly managed recreational hunting and angling, or (2) the ability of any foreign jurisdiction or authority to authorize regulated programs supporting wildlife for local consumption and commercialization. Urges the President to work with foreign assistance donor countries to: (1) develop a comprehensive international conservation assistance strategy consistent with the United States International Conservation Strategy, (2) identify multilateral mechanisms to coordinate international action, and (3) agree on a timetable for achieving the goals of the United States International Conservation Strategy.</summary>
</bill>
