<bill session="111" type="s" number="1724" updated="2013-07-20T00:39:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fighting Real Estate Fraud Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a competitive grant program in the Department of Justice to be administered by the Bureau of Justice Assistance which shall assist local criminal prosecutor's offices in investigating and prosecuting crimes of real estate fraud.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2009--Introduced.
Fighting Real Estate Fraud Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Attorney General to make grants on a competitive basis through the Bureau of Justice Assistance of the Department of Justice (DOJ) to states, local governments, and Indian tribal governments to assist prosecutors in investigating and prosecuting real estate fraud. Defines "real estate fraud" to include crimes involving purposeful misrepresentations, forgeries, omissions to general applications, tax returns, financial statements, appraisals and valuations, verifications of deposit and employment, escrow and closing documents, credit reports, and any actions that may defraud a secured creditor. Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress on the effectiveness of the grant program in investigating and prosecuting real estate fraud.</summary>
</bill>
