<bill session="111" type="s" number="3163" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Meat Safety and Accountability Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act to require tracing of meat and meat food products that are adulterated or contaminated by enteric foodborne pathogens to the source of the adulteration or contamination.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/2010--Introduced.
Meat Safety and Accountability Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act to require the Secretary to implement sampling protocols to enable Food Safety and Inspection Service personnel to rapidly trace potential adulteration and contamination of meat and meat food products by enteric foodborne pathogens to possible preceding adulteration and contamination sources, including preparation, packaging, and slaughtering establishments, to determine the original contamination source. Requires, if a meat or meat food product sample tests positive for enteric foodborne pathogen contamination, a trace to identify: (1) adulteration and contamination sites, including preparation, packaging, and slaughtering establishments; and (2) the original adulteration or contamination source. Requires, if a raw ground meat sample tests positive for enteric foodborne pathogen contamination at a preparation, packaging, or slaughtering establishment, subsequent daily sampling at the establishment and any supplying establishments for at least 15 consecutive days after the date on which the adulterated or contaminated sample is collected.</summary>
</bill>
