<bill session="109" type="hc" number="312" updated="2013-07-19T20:04:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-15T21:46:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-15T21:46:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Urging the Government of the Russian Federation to withdraw or modify proposed legislation that would have the effect of severely restricting the establishment, operations, and activities of domestic and foreign nongovernmental organizations in the Russian Federation.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">Urging the Government of the Russian Federation to withdraw the first draft of the proposed legislation as passed in its first reading in the State Duma that would have the effect of severely restricting the establishment, operations, and activities of domestic, international, and foreign nongovernmental organizations in the Russian Federation, or to modify the proposed legislation to entirely remove these restrictions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400167" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2005-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400260" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400423" joined="2005-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T22:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T22:04:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11621-11624" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T22:04:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 312.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T22:19:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T21:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11858-11859" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-12-15T21:46:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="641" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 405 - 15 (Roll no. 641).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/14/2005 H11621" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T21:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T21:46:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="sc" number="70"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="sr" number="339"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2005--Passed House amended.
Urges: (1) the government of the Russian Federation to withdraw the first draft of the proposed legislation that would restrict the establishment and activities of domestic, international, and foreign nongovernmental organizations in the Russian Federation, or to modify the proposed legislation to remove such restrictions; and (2) in the event that the first draft of such proposed legislation is not withdrawn, the State Duma and the Federation Council of the Federal Assembly to amend the legislation to ensure the establishment and autonomous operations of such nongovernmental organizations in accordance with the practices universally adopted by democracies, including the provisions regarding foreign assistance.</summary>
</bill>
