<bill session="111" type="s" number="3520" updated="2013-07-20T00:57:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Unemployment Insurance Extension Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for an extension of unemployment insurance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5246-5247, S5248-5249, S5250, S5252, S5253, S5256"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4213"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5618"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5647"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6419"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6556"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3551"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3706"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3981"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3990"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2010--Introduced.
Unemployment Insurance Extension Act of 2010 - Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 with respect to the state-established individual emergency unemployment compensation account (EUCA). Extends the final date for entering a federal-state agreement under the Emergency Unemployment Compensation (EUC) program through December 31, 2010. Postpones the termination of the program until May 31, 2011. Amends the Assistance for Unemployed Workers and Struggling Families Act to extend through December 31, 2010: (1) federal-state agreements increasing regular unemployment compensation payments to individuals; and (2) requirements that federal payments to states cover 100% of EUC. Amends the Unemployment Compensation Extension Act of 2008 to exempt weeks of unemployment between enactment of this Act and May 31, 2011, from the prohibition in the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 against federal matching payments to a state for the first week in an individual's eligibility period for which extended compensation or sharable regular compensation is paid if the state law provides for payment of regular compensation to an individual for his or her first week of otherwise compensable unemployment. (Thus allows temporary federal matching for the first week of extended benefits for states with no waiting period.)</summary>
</bill>
