<bill session="111" type="s" number="1621" updated="2013-07-20T00:38:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Thermal Energy Efficiency Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve thermal energy efficiency and use, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2009-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9020-9021"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/2009--Introduced.
Thermal Energy Efficiency Act of 2009 - Establishes in the Treasury a Thermal Energy Efficiency Fund. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) allocate to the Fund 2% of the quantity of emission allowances established for any of calendar years 2012-2050 under any program for the regulation of greenhouse gas emissions that is established by federal law; (2) auction all of the emission allowances allocated to the Fund for a calendar year; and (3) deposit all proceeds of such auctions into the Fund. Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE), for each calendar year during which such a program is in effect, to use amounts in the Fund to make competitive grants to eligible entities (including state and local governments, commercial or industrial entities, and federal agencies) to carry out qualifying district energy, combined heat and power, or recoverable waste energy projects. Establishes as a goal of the United States to meet 20% or more of total U.S. electrical power capacity through combined heat and power by calendar year 2030.</summary>
</bill>
