<bill session="113" type="h" number="1768" updated="2013-11-02T06:33:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accountability Review Board Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Diplomatic Security Act to require certain notifications to Congress of Accountability Review Boards of the Department of State, avoid conflicts of interest of the members of such Boards, require actions with respect to reports from such Boards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400348"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412547" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412531" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412508" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412553" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2013-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412540" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412569" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412528" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2013-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412525" joined="2013-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/2013--Introduced.
Accountability Review Board Reform Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the effectiveness of Accountability Review Boards would be improved by increasing their independence from the Department of State. Amends the Omnibus Diplomatic Security and Antiterrorism Act regarding congressional notification of an Accountability Review Board's convening to include: (1) notification of the Chairman of the House Committee on Foreign Affairs; and (2) disclosure of any individual employed at a grade not lower than FS-3 or GS-14 or any political appointee who is hired, assigned, or detailed to assist the Board. Revises the appointment of the five Board members to provide that two members shall be appointed by the Secretary, two by the Chairperson of the Council of Inspectors General of Integrity and Efficiency, and one by the Director of National Intelligence. States that to the maximum extent practicable individuals assisting a Board shall be employees of the Department's Office of the Inspector General. Prohibits an individual who has a personal or professional relationship with someone expected to be investigated from serving as a Board member or staffer. Defines "conflict of interest" for such purposes. Authorizes a Board to accept any evidence determined by a Board member to be relevant and material to an investigation. States that the Federal Rules of Evidence shall not apply to the Board. Requires that a Board report and related recommendations be submitted to Congress, in addition to the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
