<bill session="111" type="s" number="3482" updated="2013-07-20T00:56:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Solar Energy Pilot Leasing Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the development of solar pilot project areas on public land in Lincoln County, Nevada.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4856"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4856-4857" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="5508"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2010--Introduced.
American Solar Energy Pilot Leasing Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to: (1) designate specified federal land in Nevada under the administrative jurisdiction of BLM that is identified as a solar development zone as a solar pilot project area; (2) conduct lease sales and issue leases for commercial solar energy development on such land; and (3) include work requirements and mandatory milestones to ensure that diligent development is carried out under such a lease and to reduce speculative behavior. Prohibits (with exceptions) new easements, special-use permits, or rights-of-way on such land from the date of enactment of this Act until the date of the issuance of a lease for such land. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish the duration of leases issued; (2) include provisions in such a lease requiring the lease holder to furnish a reclamation bond or other form of security and to restore the land or conduct mitigation activities upon completion of authorized activities; (3) establish and ensure compliance with best management practices to ensure the sound, efficient, and environmentally responsible development of solar resources on the land in a manner that would minimize and mitigate impacts to habitat and ecosystem function; and (4) establish royalties, fees, rentals, bonuses, and any other appropriate payments to ensure a fair return to the United States for any lease issued. Sets forth provisions governing royalty rates and proceeds distribution. Establishes in the Treasury a Renewable Energy Mitigation and Fish and Wildlife Fund, which shall be available to the Secretary for providing amounts to states or other interested parties for mitigating impacts of renewable energy on public land and carrying out activities authorized under the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965. Directs the Secretary: (1) within Lincoln County, Nevada, to give highest priority consideration to implementation of the solar lease sales provided for under this Act; and (2) to evaluate other solar development proposals in the County not provided for under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
