<bill session="109" type="h" number="6270" updated="2013-07-19T19:59:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">California Desert and Mountain Heritage Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate certain Federal lands in Riverside County, California, as wilderness, to designate certain river segments in Riverside County as a wild, scenic, or recreational river, to adjust the boundary of the Santa Rosa and San Jacinto Mountains National Monument, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400039"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-04">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2006--Introduced.
California Desert and Mountain Heritage Act - Designates as wilderness: (1) certain Bureau of Land Management (BLM) lands in the Cleveland National Forest, to be part of the Agua Tibia Wilderness; (2) specified lands in the San Bernardino National Forest to be known as the Cahuilla Mountain Wilderness and the South Fork San Jacinto Wilderness and as part of the Santa Rosa Wilderness; (3) certain BLM land in Riverside County, California, to be known as the Beauty Mountain Wilderness; and (4) certain land in Joshua Tree National Park, to be part of the Joshua Tree Wilderness. Designates certain lands in the Joshua Tree National Park as potential wilderness. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to manage such land as wilderness until it is incorporated into the Joshua Tree Wilderness (effective when the Secretary publishes notice that all uses of the land prohibited by the Wilderness Act have ceased or that sufficient inholdings have been acquired to establish a manageable wilderness unit). Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate as wild, scenic, or recreational rivers specified segments of the North Fork San Jacinto River, Fuller Mill Creek, Palm Canyon Creek, and Bautista Creek in California. Amends the Santa Rosa and San Jacinto Mountains National Monument Act of 2000 to include additional lands within the boundaries of the Santa Rosa and San Jacinto Mountains National Monument.</summary>
</bill>
