<bill session="109" type="h" number="4593" updated="2013-07-19T19:44:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To advance the deadline for energy use metering in Federal buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400155"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="2006-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2580-2581"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2005--Introduced.
Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to require, by October 1, 2012, all federal buildings, for the purposes of efficient use of energy and reduction in the cost of energy (currently, electricity) used in such buildings, to be metered. Requires agencies to use, to the maximum extent practicable, advanced meters or advanced metering devices for electricity, primary fuels, including natural gas and petroleum-based fuels, steam, and chilled water (currently, electricity, primary fuels, including natural gas and petroleum-based fuels, steam, and chilled water are not specified), that provide data at least daily and that measure at least hourly consumption of electricity in the federal buildings of the agency. Requires that, by October 1, 2008, metering meeting the above requirements shall apply to: (1) buildings on which construction commenced after the date of enactment of this Act; (2) existing buildings with more than 100,000 square feet of enclosed space; and (3) existing buildings that use large amounts of energy per square foot such as process energy facilities, health care facilities, and data centers.</summary>
</bill>
