<bill session="112" type="h" number="3684" updated="2013-07-20T01:42:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Commuter Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Surface Transportation and Uniform Relocation Assistance Act of 1987 to authorize the Secretary of Transportation to permit Federal regulation and review of tolls and toll increases on certain surface transportation facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412451"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412452" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412393" joined="2011-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412499" joined="2012-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="2006"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="2006"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2011--Introduced.
Commuter Protection Act - Amends the Surface Transportation and Uniform Relocation Assistance Act of 1987 to expand the requirement that certain bridge tolls be just and reasonable to all bridges or tunnels constructed on a federal-aid highway. (Current law applies the just and reasonable toll requirement only to bridges constructed under the Bridge Act of 1906, the General Bridge Act of 1946, or the International Bridge Act of 1972.) Requires that tolls for all such bridges and tunnels be subject to review and regulation by the Secretary of Transportation (DOT), upon complaint or the initiative of the Secretary, including with respect to increases in the amount of tolls. Directs the Secretary to promulgate regulations to define, determine, and, when appropriate, prescribe just and reasonable toll rates. Requires that such regulations: (1) establish an administrative complaint process for aggrieved persons to challenge such determinations or toll rate increases on bridges or tunnels, (2) authorize the Secretary or an administrative law judge to conduct investigations and hold formal hearings on such complaints, and (3) permit complainants to seek judicial review of a final administrative determination in a U.S. district court. Directs the Comptroller General to: (1) evaluate the use of tolls by interstate authorities to maintain and improve surface transportation facilities, and (2) make recommendations to increase transparency and accountability of the funding decisions by those authorities.</summary>
</bill>
