<bill session="112" type="sr" number="424" updated="2013-07-20T02:14:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution condemning the mass atrocities committed by the Government of Syria and supporting the right of the people of Syria to be safe and to defend themselves.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2012-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2012-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2502-2503" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/2012--Introduced.
Condemns the mass atrocities and severe human rights abuses being perpetrated against the Syrian people by Bashar al-Assad and his followers. Recognizes the right of the Syrian people to defend themselves against the violence being conducted by the Assad regime and supports calls by Arab leaders to provide the Syrian people with the means to defend themselves. Urges the President to take all necessary precautions to ensure that support for the Syrian opposition does not benefit individuals in Syria who are aligned with al Qaeda or who have committed human rights abuses. Affirms that the establishment of safe havens would be an important step to save Syrian lives and calls on the President to consult with regional allies on whether, how, and where to create such safe havens. Urges the President, as part of an international effort to hold senior Syrian officials accountable for mass atrocities, to gather information about such mass atrocities. Commends the establishment of the Friends of the Syrian People Contact Group and other international diplomatic efforts to end the violence and support a peaceful transition to democracy and the removal of Bashar al-Assad from power.</summary>
</bill>
