<bill session="110" type="h" number="7110" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-26T18:41:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-26T18:41:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Job Creation and Unemployment Relief Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making supplemental appropriations for job creation and preservation, infrastructure investment, and economic and energy assistance for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400300"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1507 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 7110 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1507 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T17:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1507.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10075-10088" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T17:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 7110 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T17:31:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 7110.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10087" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-09-26T18:41:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="660" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 264 - 158 (Roll no. 660).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10075-10081" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26T18:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-11-17">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-11-18">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1124 under authority of the order of the Senate of 11/17/2008.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="110" type="hr" number="1507"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="3604"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Air conditioning"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Architecture and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Asbestos"/>
    <term name="Bicycles"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Charter schools"/>
    <term name="Civil engineering"/>
    <term name="Class size"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Electric batteries"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fungi"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Green products"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Iron"/>
    <term name="Iron and steel industry"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Lighting"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Palau Islands"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Polychlorinated biphenyls"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public schools"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Steel"/>
    <term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation rates"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1177"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/26/2008--Passed House without amendment.
Job Creation and Unemployment Relief Act of 2008 - Title I: Infrastructure Investments - Chapter I: Transportation - Makes supplemental appropriations for FY2009 for infrastructure investments to the Department of Transportation (DOT) for: (1) the Federal Aviation Administration, grants-in-aid for airports; (2) Federal Highway Administration, highway infrastructure investment; (3) Federal Railroad Administration, capital and debt service grants to the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (AMTRAK); (4) Federal Transit Administration, transit capital assistance and transit energy assistance grants. Chapter 2: Clean Water - Makes supplemental appropriations for FY2009 for clean water to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), state and tribal assistance grants. Chapter 3: Flood Control and Water Resources - Makes supplemental appropriations for FY2009 for flood control and water resources to: (1) the Department of Defense (DOD) - Civil for the Department of the Army Corps of Engineers; and (2) the Department of the Interior, Bureau of Reclamation. Chapter 4: 21st Century Green High-Performing Public School Facilities - Makes supplemental FY2009 appropriations to the Department of Education for school modernization, renovation, and repair (for 21st century green high-performing public school facilities). (Sec. 1401) Requires the Secretary of Education to make grants to states for the modernization, renovation, or repair of public schools, including public charter schools, to make them safe, healthy, high-performing, and technologically up-to-date. Allocates grant funds among states on the basis of the relative portion of school improvement funds provided to local educational agencies (LEAs) in each state under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Reserves 1% of the grant funds for assistance to outlying areas and Indian schools. Requires states to reallocate such grant funds to LEAs on the basis of each LEA's share of school improvement funds received by LEAs in the state for the previous fiscal year. Prohibits LEAs from using this Act's grants: (1) for maintenance costs, stadiums, or facilities used primarily for events for which the public is charged admission; or (2) to supplant funds otherwise available for school modernization, renovation, repair, and construction efforts. Prohibits States from considering LEAs' receipt of this Act's grants in determining their eligibility for state aid or the amount of state aid they receive. Requires grantees' contracting procedures for school modernization, renovation, repair, and construction to ensure the maximum number of qualified bidders through full and open competition. Requires the iron and steel used in projects funded under this Act to have been produced in this country, subject to specified exceptions. Requires all laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors in the performance of work assisted under this Act to be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar work in the locality. Directs LEA grantees to use at least 25% of grant funds for public school modernization, renovation, repairs, or construction that meet Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED) green building rating standards, Energy Star standards, Collaborative for High Performance Schools (CHPS) criteria, Green Building Initiative environmental design and rating standards (Green Globes), or equivalent standards adopted by the entities that have jurisdiction over such LEAs. Requires the Secretary to provide outreach and technical assistance to states and LEAs concerning the best practices in school modernization, renovation, repair, and construction. Chapter 5: Housing - Makes supplemental appropriations for FY2009 for public and Indian housing to the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), the Public Housing Capital Fund. Chapter 6: Energy Development - Makes supplemental appropriations for FY2009 to the Department of Energy (DOE) for: (1) energy efficiency and renewable energy; (2) electricity delivery and energy reliability; and (3) the advanced battery loan guarantee program account. Title II: Unemployment Compensation and Job Training - Chapter 1: Extension of Unemployment Compensation - (Sec. 2101) Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 to increase the alternative amounts required for first-tier benefits in state emergency unemployment compensation accounts. Requires the amount to be equal to the lesser of: (1) 80% (currently, 50%) of the total amount of regular compensation (including dependents' allowances) payable to the individual during the individual's benefit year; or (2) 20 (currently, 13) times the individual's average weekly benefit amount for the benefit year. (Sec. 2102) Sets forth a special rule for second-tier benefits (identical to the current benefits for first-tier benefits without the increases under this chapter. Prescribes circumstances under which a state shall be considered to be in an extended unemployment benefit period. Limits any individual's emergency unemployment compensation account to only one augmentation under this chapter. (Sec. 2103) Prohibits any additional augmentation for any account exhausted after March 31, 2009. Prohibits any compensation under this chapter for any week beginning after August 27, 2009. Chapter 2: Job Training - Makes supplemental appropriations for FY2009 to the Department of Labor (DOL), Employment and Training Administration for: (1) job training and employment services; and (2) state unemployment insurance and employment service operations. Title III: Temporary Increase in Medicaid Matching Rate - (Sec. 3001) Prescribes a temporary increase in the federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act. Requires substitution of the FY2008 FMAP for the FY2009 FMAP if the former is greater than the latter. Requires, similarly, substitution of the the FY2009 FMAP for the FY2010 FMAP if the former is greater than the latter, but only for the portion of the first calendar quarter in FY2010 before December 1, 2009. Makes for each state for FY2009 and the portion of FY2010 up to December 1, 2009: (1) a general 1% increase in the FMAP; and (2) a general 4% increase in the cap on Medicaid payments to Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa. Requires specified further percentage point increases in the FMAP per calendar quarter for each state that meets certain qualifying criteria, including: (1) reduced employment in the state; (2) a specified increase in food stamp or Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program participation; and (3) a specified increase in the housing foreclosure rate. Specifies circumstances that would make a state ineligible for such increases. (Sec. 3002) Prescribes an adjustment in the computation of the Medicaid FMAP to disregard significantly disproportionate employer pension and insurance fund contributions in a state, as calculated according to a specified formula. Title IV: Temporary Increase in Food Assistance - (Sec. 4001) Revises the formula for calculating the value of certain benefits determined under the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 and consolidated block grants for Puerto Rico and American Samoa, using 105% of the June 2008 value of the thrifty food plan. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to make specified funds available for the costs of associated state administrative expenses. Makes necessary appropriations. Title V: General Provisions - (Sec. 5001) Entitles this entire Act the Job Creation and Unemployment Relief Act of 2008. (Sec. 5002) Prohibits the use of any funds made available in this Act to employ unlawful aliens in violation of the Immigration and Nationality Act. (Sec. 5003) Designates each amount in each title of this Act as an emergency requirement, necessary to meet emergency needs. (Sec. 5004) Declares that each amount in this Act, unless otherwise expressly provided, is made available in addition to amounts otherwise available for FY2009.</summary>
</bill>
