<bill session="109" type="s" number="563" updated="2013-07-19T20:18:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Driver Licensing and Education Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Driver Licensing and Education Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve driver licensing and education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2005-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2262-2266"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2269" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Driver education"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/2005--Introduced.
Driver Licensing and Education Improvement Act of 2005 - Amends Federal transportation law to establish the National Driver Licensing and Education Improvement Program in the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration. Requires the Program, among other things, to provide States with services for coordinating State motor vehicle driver education and licensing programs. Amends Federal highway law to direct the Secretary of Transportation to provide grants to States to: (1) improve motor vehicle driver education programs; and (2) establish and improve the administration of graduated licensing systems. Directs the Secretary to conduct a study to determine whether the establishment and imposition of nationwide minimum standards of motor vehicle driver education would improve national highway traffic safety or the performance and legal compliance of novice drivers. Modifies eligibility requirements for grants for support of alcohol-impaired driving countermeasures to require a multiple-stage graduated licensing system for young drivers that: (1) authorizes the issuance of an initial license or learner's permit to a driver on or after the driver's 16th birthday; (2) prohibits a person under age 21 with a blood alcohol concentration of .02 percent or greater from operating a motor vehicle; (3) provides for a learning stage and an intermediate stage of at least six months each; (4) limits the numbers of passengers under the age of 18 years old; (5) limits nighttime driving, and (6) applies special penalties for violations of system restrictions and of other State motor vehicle laws.</summary>
</bill>
