<bill session="111" type="s" number="3140" updated="2013-07-20T00:53:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Biosecurity and Vaccine Development Improvement Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to grant the Secretary of Health and Human Services authority to design, construct, and operate facilities for the purpose of developing and producing biological products in order to meet critical national needs for such biological products, in response to potential bioterrorist attacks or naturally occurring pathogens.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2010-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1751-1752"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2010--Introduced.
Biosecurity and Vaccine Development Improvement Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to design, construct, and operate facilities to develop and produce biological products to meet critical national needs in response to potential bioterrorist attacks or naturally occurring pathogens for which private industry has not devoted adequate development effort or has not produced adequate stocks of such biological products. Requires the Secretary to ensure that there is competition. Allows the Secretary to: (1) establish a public-private partnership to design, construct, own, and operate such a facility; and (2) use the authority to enter into other transactions under the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority to establish such a facility.</summary>
</bill>
