<bill session="110" type="s" number="3184" updated="2013-07-19T22:49:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Empowering Teaching and Learning Through Education Portals Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to make grants to States to implement statewide portal initiatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6022"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-06-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6023-6024" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Corporate philanthropy"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Educational television"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2008--Introduced.
Empowering Teaching and Learning Through Education Portals Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award matching grants to states to implement or maintain education portal initiatives that include collecting and making available: (1) high quality resources (including data, tools, and digital media content) for teachers, students, and parents, that support public education from Head Start through graduate school; and (2) resources for ongoing and sustainable teacher training in the use of education technology at such educational levels. Allows teachers, students, and parents to contribute resources to their state portal, which is to be accessible statewide. Permits states to use funds available to them under part A (Teacher and Principal Training and Recruiting Fund) of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to maintain such initiatives after their receipt of this Act's funding ends. Requires the Secretary to hold a conference, at least biennially, for state advisory panels on education portal initiatives to share information on best practices. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) count corporate contributions to such initiatives separately from other corporate contributions in applying charitable contribution deductibility limits; and (2) allow corporate deductions for contributions to such initiatives to reach 50% of a corporation's taxable income.</summary>
</bill>
