<bill session="109" type="s" number="527" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PLEA Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protect Law Enforcement Armor Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to protect the Nation's law enforcement officers by banning the Five-seveN Pistol and 5.7 x 28mm SS190 and SS192 cartridges, testing handguns and ammunition for capability to penetrate body armor, and prohibiting the manufacture, importation, sale, or purchase of such handguns or ammunition by civilians.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2006-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2005-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2040"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2040-2041" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="1136"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2005--Introduced.
Protect Law Enforcement Armor Act or PLEA Act - Amends the Federal criminal code to expand the definition of "armor piercing ammunition" to include a projectile that: (1) may be used in a handgun; and (2) the Attorney General determines to be capable of penetrating body armor. Directs the Attorney General to promulgate standards for the uniform testing of projectiles against Body Armor Exemplar (i.e., body armor that the Attorney General determines meets minimum standards for the protection of law enforcement officers), taking into account variations in performance related to the type of handgun used, the length of the barrel, the amount and kind of powder used to propel the projectile, and the projectile's design. Prohibits the manufacture, sale, possession, or transfer of the Fabrique Nationale Herstall Five-SeveN Pistol, 5.7 x 28mm SS190 and SS192 cartridges, or any other handgun that uses armor piercing ammunition, except: (1) where manufactured and sold exclusively to U.S. military, law enforcement, or intelligence agencies; and (2) by a licensed manufacturer or contractor for the purpose of examining and testing to determine whether such prohibition applies.</summary>
</bill>
