<bill session="112" type="s" number="2153" updated="2013-07-20T02:35:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-03-05">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to apply the countervailing duty provisions of the Tariff Act of 1930 to nonmarket economy countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2012-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2012-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2012-03-05" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1375-1376" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1375-1376" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>See also H.R. 4105.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4105"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="4105"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4105"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2012--Introduced.
Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 regarding the imposition of countervailing duties on imports into the United States from a country subsidizing, directly or indirectly, the manufacture, production, or export of merchandise which materially injures a U.S. industry or threatens to. Declares that merchandise on which countervailing duties must be imposed includes merchandise from a nonmarket country, unless the administering authority cannot identify and measure subsidies provided by the government of the nonmarket economy country (or a public entity within its territory) because the economy of that country is essentially composed of a single entity. Requires the administering authority to reduce the antidumping duty on a class or kind of merchandise from a nonmarket economy country in cases where: (1) such country (or a public entity within its territory) has provided the merchandise with a countervailable subsidy (other than an export subsidy); (2) the subsidy has reduced the average price of imports of that class or kind of merchandise during the relevant period; and (3) the extent to which the subsidy, in combination with the use of normal value, has increased the weighted average dumping margin for such merchandise can be reasonably estimated. Requires the administering authority, in such cases, to reduce the antidumping duty by the amount of the increase in the weighted average dumping margin estimated (but not by more than the portion of the countervailing duty rate attributable to the countervailable subsidy).</summary>
</bill>
