<bill session="110" type="h" number="3522" updated="2013-07-19T21:34:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-27">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ratify a conveyance of a portion of the Jicarilla Apache Reservation to Rio Arriba County, State of New Mexico, pursuant to the settlement of litigation between the Jicarilla Apache Nation and Rio Arriba County, State of New Mexico, to authorize issuance of a patent for said lands, and to change the exterior boundary of the Jicarilla Apache Reservation accordingly, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2008-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-09-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1847-1848"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-04-29T14:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-610.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-04-29T14:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="380">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 380.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-04-29T14:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rahall moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-29T14:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2770-2771" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-29T14:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3522.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2008-04-29T14:16:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2770" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-04-29T14:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2008-05-01" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3727" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2008-05-01">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2008-05-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2008-05-19">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2008-05-27">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2008-05-27" type="public" number="110-236">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 110-236.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/2008--Public Law.
Ratifies and approves the Jicarilla Apache Nation's quitclaim deed for the Settlement Lands to Rio Arriba County, New Mexico, but such ratification and approval shall be effective only upon satisfaction of the following conditions: (1) that the Board of Commissioners of the Rio Arriba County, New Mexico, has enacted a resolution permanently abandoning a specified disputed county road and has submitted a copy of that resolution to the Secretary of the Interior; and (2) that the Jicarilla Apache Nation has executed a quitclaim deed to Rio Arriba County for specified settlement lands subject to the exceptions identified in the Settlement Agreement and has submitted a copy of such deed to the Secretary. Makes such ratification and approval effective only as of the date that the Secretary publishes findings in the Federal Register that the conditions have been met.Requires the Secretary, following publication of the findings, to issue to the County a patent for the Settlement lands. Subjects the patent to all valid existing rights of third parties, including but not limited to easements of record. Requires that the patent include a specified perpetual restrictive covenant running with the Settlement Lands for the benefit of the lands comprising the Jicarilla Apache Reservation adjacent to the Settlement Lands. Provides that the lands conveyed to the County in such patent shall cease to be a part of the Jicarilla Apache Reservation and the exterior boundary of the Reservation shall be deemed relocated accordingly.</summary>
</bill>
