<bill session="109" type="h" number="4002" updated="2013-07-19T19:39:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Nursing Home Emergency Assistance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure that a private for-profit nursing home affected by a major disaster receives the same reimbursement as a public nursing home affected by a major disaster.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400311"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2033"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/2005--Introduced.
Nursing Home Emergency Assistance Act - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to allow the President to provide reimbursement to private for-profit nursing homes for damages and expenses from a major disaster or declared emergency. Requires that such nursing homes: (1) be located within 30 miles of the disaster or emergency; and (2) have acted during the disaster or emergency in accordance with any relevant requirements applicable to private nonprofit nursing homes seeking reimbursement. Limits the amount of reimbursement to not greater than the amount available under such Act to a public or private nonprofit nursing home for similar damages or expenses after a disaster or emergency.</summary>
</bill>
