<bill session="111" type="s" number="2765" updated="2013-07-20T00:50:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Health Information Technology Financing Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to authorize loan guarantees for health information technology.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2010-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11349"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3014"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="3854"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/2009--Introduced.
Small Business Health Information Technology Financing Act of 2009 - Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to guarantee up to 90% of the amount of a loan, up to specified loan amounts, to a small business health professional to be used for the acquisition and installation of health information technology for the professional's medical practice. Defines the term "health information technology" to mean computer hardware, software, and related technology that supports the meaningful electronic health record use requirements of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act and is purchased by an eligible professional to aid in the provision of health care, including electronic medical records, but excludes information technology whose sole use is financial management, maintenance of inventory of basic supplies, or appointment scheduling.</summary>
</bill>
