<bill session="112" type="h" number="2567" updated="2013-07-20T01:32:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal First Offender Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide for deferred sentencing and the possibility of dismissal for drug offenders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412306"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2011-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2011-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2011-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2011-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2011-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2011-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2011-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2011--Introduced.
Federal First Offender Improvement Act of 2011 - Amends the federal criminal code to extend the pre-judgment probation and expungement procedures for simple possession of a controlled substance under the Controlled Substances Act to individuals who are convicted under such Act of drug trafficking or of attempting or conspiring to commit a drug offense. Sets forth requirements for granting pre-judgment probation for drug trafficking or of attempting or conspiring to commit a drug offense, including that: (1) the offender did not use violence or credible threats of violence or possess a firearm or other dangerous weapon (or induce another participant to do so) while committing the offense; (2) the offense did not result in death or serious injury to any person; (3) the offender was not an organizer, leader, manager, or supervisor of others in the offense and was not engaged in a continuing criminal enterprise; and (4) the offender has not been previously convicted of a crime of violence or other offense punishable by a prison term of more than one year. Provides for a period of such probation of up to two years. Revises the requirement for pre-judgment probation for simple possession to having not been previously convicted of a crime of violence or other offense punishable by a term of imprisonment for more than one year. Eliminates the requirement that an offender seeking expungement of a record of a disposition be less than 21 years old at the time of the offense.</summary>
</bill>
