<bill session="110" type="h" number="5958" updated="2013-07-19T21:55:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeowner Opportunity Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make permanent the increases made by the Economic Stimulus Act of 2008 in the loan limits for the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, and the FHA.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2008-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400039" joined="2008-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412011" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400139" joined="2008-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="2008-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412222" joined="2008-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400277" joined="2008-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400321" joined="2008-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2008-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage banks"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2008--Introduced.
Homeowner Opportunity Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act, and the National Housing Act to make permanent certain increases in the maximum original principal obligation of a mortgage that may be purchased by the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac). Expresses the sense of the Congress to encourage Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to securitize mortgages acquired under the increased conforming loan limits to the extent that such securitizations do not impose additional costs for mortgages originated, purchased, or securitized under the existing limits, or interfere with the goal of adding liquidity to the market. Amends the National Housing Act to: (1) increase the mortgage loan limit for mortgage insurance in high-cost areas; and (2) direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to publish the median house prices and mortgage principal obligation limits for all areas each year.</summary>
</bill>
