<bill session="112" type="h" number="1237" updated="2013-07-20T01:21:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-23T15:38:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-07-23T15:38:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a land exchange with the Trinity Public Utilities District of Trinity County, California, involving the transfer of land to the Bureau of Land Management and the Six Rivers National Forest in exchange for National Forest System land in the Shasta-Trinity National Forest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-05-30T17:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-500.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-05-30T17:43:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="353">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 353.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-07-23T15:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-23T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5083-5085" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-23T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1237.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2012-07-23T15:38:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5083-5084" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-07-23T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2012--Passed House amended.
Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), if the Trinity Public Utilities District of Trinity County, California, conveys to the Secretary of Agriculture the Van Duzen parcel within the Six Rivers National Forest and if the District conveys to the Secretary of the Interior the Sky Ranch parcel adjacent to public land administered by the Redding Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to convey land in the Shasta-Trinity National Forest near the Weaverville Airport to the District. Requires, regarding the value of the Van Duzen and Sky Ranch parcels, that: (1) if such value is less than that of the land conveyed to the Utilities District any cash equalization payments received by the Secretaries shall be deposited in the Treasury, and (2) if such value is greater, no cash equalization payment may be made to the District and the acreage of the land involved may be adjusted to equalize the value of the exchange. Instructs that the exact acreage and legal description of the lands to be exchanged be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Secretary concerned. Makes the District responsible for the survey costs and reasonable administrative costs related to the exchange. Requires the land acquired by the USDA Secretary to be added to and administered as part of the Six Rivers National Forest and the land acquired by the Secretary of the Interior to be administered as public land by the Redding Field Office. Directs the USDA Secretary to complete the conveyance of the System land within one year of the date on which the District offers to make such conveyances.</summary>
</bill>
