<bill session="112" type="h" number="1525" updated="2013-07-20T01:23:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">All-STAR Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">All Students Achieving through Reform Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide high-quality public charter school options for students by enabling such public charter schools to expand and replicate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400024" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2011-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2011-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="809"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2011--Introduced.
All Students Achieving through Reform Act of 2011 or All-STAR Act of 2011 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to direct the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to certain eligible entities and, through them, subgrants to successful public charter schools to allow such schools to expand or replicate to serve additional students. Lists, as eligible grantees, state and local educational agencies, authorized public chartering agencies, and tax-exempt organizations that have successfully supported the replication and expansion of such schools. Sets forth the attributes that are to give such entities grant priority, including their serving or planning to serve a large percentage of low-income students from public schools with low-graduation rates or schools identified as needing improvement, corrective action, or restructuring under the ESEA. Authorizes grantees to use up to 25% of a grant to establish a reserve account to assist them in acquiring and developing new facilities for successful public charter schools through: (1) credit enhancement initiatives, (2) the establishment of revolving loan funds, (3) direct spending or financing, or (4) partnerships with community development or other mission-based financial institutions. Directs the Secretary to conduct an independent, comprehensive, and scientifically sound evaluation of the effect this Act's initiatives have on student achievement and other areas, as determined by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
