<bill session="113" type="h" number="2690" updated="2013-11-02T06:41:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Innovate to Deliver Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the long-term profitability of the United States Postal Service through enhanced innovation, operational flexibility, workforce realignment, and regulatory relief.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412517" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412595" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2013-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="961"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Postal Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2013--Introduced.
Innovate to Deliver Act of 2013 - Establishes in the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) the position of Chief Innovation Officer, who shall manage the development and implementation of innovative postal and nonpostal products and services. Requires: (1) the Postmaster General, not later than 12 months after the designation of a Chief Innovation Officer, to submit to Congress a comprehensive strategy for maximizing revenues through innovative postal and nonpostal products and services; and (2) the Comptroller General (GAO) to study and report on the implementation of the USPS innovation strategy. Authorizes USPS to: provide nonpostal services (e.g., check-cashing services, warehousing, public internet access services) that use the processing, transportation, delivery, retail network, technology, or other resources of USPS in a manner consistent with the public interest; conduct market tests of experimental products with total anticipated revenues of up to $50 million (currently, $10 million); ship distilled spirits, wine, or malt beverages consistent with state laws: invest excess moneys of the Competitive Product Fund; engage in a reduction in force (RIF) except when prevented by a collective bargaining agreement; enter into intra-service agreements with other agencies to furnish to each other property and services; treat similar or related agreements between USPS and its postal users (Negotiated Service Agreements) as a single product; and seek expedited processing for time-sensitive advisory opinions from the Postal Regulatory Commission (PRC). Requires the PRC, in establishing a system for regulating USPS rates and classes for market-dominant products, to: (1) require that each class or type of mail service cover its direct and indirect costs, and (2) take into account the value to USPS of having pricing flexibility. Repeals the requirement for uniform postal rates for books, films, and other materials. Requires the USPS Board of Governors to: (1) ensure that rates and fees charged by USPS cover its total costs for FY2014 and each subsequent fiscal year, and (2) submit to Congress an itemized report for each fiscal year describing all travel and reimbursable business travel expenses paid to each Governor. Requires each PRC Commissioner to submit a similar itemized report for each fiscal year. Imposes limits on the compensation, including bonuses, and fringe benefits of USPS officers and employees, with exceptions for officers or employees in very senior executive positions. Requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to: (1) revise the formula for determining USPS contributions to the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS), and (2) use excess FERS contributions to pay existing USPS operating and pension liabilities. Expresses the sense of Congress that USPS use its available authority to provide early retirement or separation to eligible USPS employees. Allows USPS employees to take service credits instead of separation payments. Allows USPS and PRC employees to contribute their voluntary separation incentive payments to Thrift Savings Fund accounts. Modifies the prepayment schedule for the Postal Retiree Health Benefits Fund to: (1) amortize health care liabilities over a 40-year period, (2) reduce the prefunding requirement to 80% of actuarial liabilities, and (3) suspend the commencement of payments to the Fund until FY2017. Requires the Comptroller General to report on the workforce reduction or realignment method used by USPS to align its workforce with its needs. Requires the Postmaster General to submit detailed reports to Congress on plans to close or suspend USPS retail or processing facilities. Extends the process for closing or consolidating a post office to postal stations and branches. Authorizes the PRC to change classes of mail using specified criteria and notification requirements.</summary>
</bill>
