<bill session="110" type="s" number="1347" updated="2013-07-19T22:31:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-05">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Omnibus Indian Advancement Act to modify the date as of which certain tribal land of the Lytton Rancheria of California is deemed to be held in trust and to provide for the conduct of certain activities on the land.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5873-5874"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5874" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-10-26">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Dorgan without amendment. With written report No. 110-208.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-10-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="452">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 452.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30">
      <text>Star Print ordered on the report.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2007-11-05" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13937" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S13937" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06T10:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/5/2007--Passed Senate without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)Amends the Omnibus Indian Advancement Act to repeal the declaration that specified land accepted by the Secretary of the Interior for the benefit of the Lytton Rancheria in California shall be deemed to have been held in trust and part of the reservation of the Rancheria prior to October 17, 1988. (The date on the recorded deed is October 16, 2000.) Allows the Lytton Rancheria to conduct activities for class II gaming on the land taken into trust.Prohibits the Lytton Rancheria from expanding the exterior physical measurements of any facility on the Rancheria in use for class II gaming activities.States that, for class III gaming purposes, the land taken into trust shall be treated, for purposes of provisions relating to gaming on lands acquired in trust after October 17, 1988, as if the land was acquired on October 9, 2003, the date on which the Secretary took it into trust.</summary>
</bill>
