<bill session="111" type="h" number="3533" updated="2013-07-19T23:43:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Consumer Product Safety Act to clarify and ensure the effective implementation of certain children's product safety provisions added by the Consumer Product Safety Improvement Act of 2008.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400052"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/2009--Introduced.
Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to require the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC), by regulation, to: (1) initiate a program by which a manufacturer or private labeler of a toy or durable nursery product shall label a product as complying with third party testing requirements; and (2) base certification labeling requirements for toys and durable infant and toddler products, at minimum, upon specified product safety design analysis and testing standards (including randomness and frequency standards). Repeals the general product conformity certification requirements of the Act. Delays until August 14, 2010, the effective date of requirements that a manufacturer place permanent, distinguishing marks on a children's product and its packaging that enable the manufacturer to ascertain the product's specific source and the ultimate purchaser to ascertain its production date, location, and cohort information.</summary>
</bill>
