<bill session="111" type="s" number="3954" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Air Cargo Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve air cargo security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-11-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="6410"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2010--Introduced.
Air Cargo Security Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a system for the screening and inspecting of all cargo transported in domestic and foreign all-cargo aircraft, including in intrastate air transportation, to ensure the security of such aircraft. Requires such systems to meet minimum standards that ensure equipment, technology, procedures, or personnel used for screening cargo provide a level of security commensurate with the security level for screening passenger checked baggage. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a system for regularly screening and inspecting shipments of cargo transported in air transportation, including intrastate air transportation, at shipping facilities to ensure that appropriate security controls, systems, and protocols are observed; and (2) enter into arrangements with civil aviation authorities of foreign countries to ensure the regular screening and inspecting at shipping facilities in such countries of such cargo transported by air to the United States. Authorizes the Secretary to increase the number of air cargo inspectors to carry out such screenings and inspections. Directs the Secretary to establish a training and evaluation program for all individuals who handle air cargo to ensure that such cargo is properly handled and safeguarded from security breaches.</summary>
</bill>
