<bill session="110" type="s" number="1985" updated="2013-07-19T22:37:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Capital Access for Senior Homeowners Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve access of senior homeowners to capital.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300003"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cooperative housing"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Home equity conversion"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2007--Introduced.
Capital Access for Senior Homeowners Act of 2007 - Amends the National Housing Act with respect to insurance of home equity conversion mortgages for elderly homeowners. Repeals the 275,000 cap on the aggregate number of such mortgages insured under the Act. Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to insure a home equity conversion mortgage when the primary purpose of such mortgage is to enable an elderly mortgagor to purchase a one- to four-family dwelling in which the mortgagor will occupy or occupies one of the units. Extends the meaning of mortgage which may be insured to: (1) a first or subordinate mortgage or lien on all stock allocated to a dwelling unit in a residential cooperative housing corporation; or (2) a first mortgage or first lien on a leasehold under certain related leases. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress on the costs and availability of credit under the home equity conversion mortgages for elderly homeowners program.</summary>
</bill>
