<bill session="110" type="s" number="3322" updated="2013-07-19T22:50:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Midwestern Disaster Tax Relief Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide tax relief for the victims of severe storms, tornados, and flooding in the Midwest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2008-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7167-7169" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="6587"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Textbooks"/>
    <term name="Tornadoes"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5254"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/23/2008--Introduced.
Midwestern Disaster Tax Relief Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide tax benefits to individuals affected by presidentially-declared natural disasters (i.e., severe storms, tornadoes, or flooding) in the states of Arkansas, Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Michigan, Minnesota, Missouri, Nebraska, and Wisconsin on or after May 20, 2008, and before August 1, 2008 (Midwestern disaster area).Makes specified provisions of the Internal Revenue Code, which currently apply only to residents of the Gulf Opportunity Zone and the Hurricane Katrina disaster area, applicable to the Midwestern disaster area, including: (1) tax-exempt bond financing, the low-income housing tax credit, accelerated depreciation and increased expensing of business assets, an increase in the rehabilitation tax credit, extended carryback of net operating losses, and investment in tax credit bonds; (2) increased tax deductions for tuition and related educational expenses; (3) expensing of environmental remediation costs and demolition and cleanup costs; (4) tax incentives for employer-provided housing; (5) tax-free withdrawals from retirement accounts and recontributions for home purchases; (6) employer tax credits for retention of employees; (7) suspension of limitations on tax deductions for charitable contributions and personal casualty losses; (8) mortgage revenue bonds for owner-occupied residences; (9) tax exemptions for cancellation of indebtedness; and (10) nonrecognition of gain for homes and businesses destroyed in a disaster. Allows taxpayers in the Midwestern disaster area who claimed a tax deduction for a casualty loss to a principal residence and later received a grant under any federal or state program for reimbursement of such loss to file an amended tax return, without incurring tax penalties.Extends through 2009 the additional tax exemption for housing displaced individuals in the Midwestern disaster area. Excludes from gross income, through December 31, 2008, reimbursements to volunteers in the Midwestern disaster area for the use of a personal vehicle for charitable work. Increases the standard mileage rate for the charitable use of personal vehicles.Extends through 2009 the enhanced tax deduction for charitable contributions of food inventories and of book inventories to public schools. Requires tax-exempt charitable organizations to provide the Secretary of the Treasury with specified information, on an annual basis, relating to their disaster relief activities.</summary>
</bill>
