<bill session="109" type="h" number="5411" updated="2013-07-19T19:52:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-06-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a demonstration program to facilitate landscape restoration programs within certain units of the National Park System established by law to preserve and interpret resources associated with American history, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-586.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-07-20T19:08:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="337">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 337.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Insect control"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military parks"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2006--Reported to House without amendment.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, to carry out a demonstration program that provides that receipts from timber sales shall be retained for expenditure within units of the National Park System from which the timber is removed as part of an approved plan for the restoration or protection of park resources or values. Instructs the Secretary to permit each of the existing 24 National Battlefields, National Battlefield Parks, National Military Parks, and National Battlefield Sites to participate in the demonstration program if the unit has in place a general management plan, cultural landscape plan, or other resources management plan approved pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 that identifies specific timber for removal for purposes of cultural or historic landscape restoration or fuel load reduction. Requires each unit selected to participate in the demonstration program to retain receipts from the sale or disposal of timber removed. Provides for such receipts to be available for expenditure for within a unit for the following purposes only: (1) landscape restoration; (2) interpretive services; (3) eradication of disease, insects, or invasive species; or (4) fuel load reduction. Requires the Secretary to submit: (1) a report containing a specific timeline for timber removal in each of the units authorized to participate in the demonstration program; and (2) a report containing the results of such demonstration program, including any resource or other impacts, positive or negative, on each participating unit. Sunsets the authority granted to the Secretary to carry out the demonstration program four years after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
