<bill session="110" type="s" number="1151" updated="2013-07-19T22:30:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Care for Hybrids Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide incentives to the auto industry to accelerate efforts to develop more energy-efficient vehicles to lessen dependence on oil.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-04-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1920"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Industrial buildings"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax shelters"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/2007--Introduced.
Health Care for Hybrids Act - Requires the Secretaries of Energy, Health and Human Services, Transportation, and the Treasury to establish a task force to create a program to reimburse certain domestic automobile manufacturers for a portion (up to 10%) of the annual health care coverage costs for their retired employees. Requires such manufacturers to invest at least 50% of their health care cost savings in petroleum fuel reduction technologies, including alternative or flexible fuel vehicles and hybrids, and in the retraining of workers and retooling of manufacturing plants. Terminates such program on December 31, 2017. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) define economic substance for purposes of evaluating tax shelter transactions; (2) impose penalties for understatements of tax liability resulting from transactions lacking in economic substance; and (3) deny a tax deduction for interest assessed on underpayments of tax resulting from transactions lacking in economic substance.</summary>
</bill>
