<bill session="109" type="s" number="514" updated="2013-07-19T20:17:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Appalachian Development Highway System Completion Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to complete construction of the 13-State Appalachian development highway system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2023-2025"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Appalachia"/>
    <term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2005--Introduced.
Appalachian Development Highway System Completion Act of 2005 - Authorizes appropriations out of the Highway Trust Fund (other than the Mass Transit Account) for the Appalachian development highway system program for each of FY 2005 through 2010. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to apportion such funds among the States based on the latest available cost-to-complete estimate for the system, prepared by the Appalachian Regional Commission. Authorizes a State, upon notice to the Secretary, to lend any amount of contract or obligation authority available to it pursuant to the apportionment to any other State that is eligible for such an apportionment for use for eligible activities with respect to the system. Provides that whenever an apportionment is made, the Secretary shall deduct an amount (not to exceed two-fifths of one percent of the sums made available) determined to be appropriate to administer provisions concerning the program and to make transfers to the Commission to pay the costs of administrative activities associated with the system. Removes the system from minimum guarantee provisions under Federal highway law.</summary>
</bill>
