<bill session="112" type="s" number="1881" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAFE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safeguarding America's Future and Environment Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish an integrated Federal program to respond to ongoing and expected impacts of climate variability and change by protecting, restoring, and conserving the natural resources of the United States and to maximize government efficiency and reduce costs, in cooperation with State, local, and tribal governments and other entities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2012-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/2011--Introduced.
Safeguarding America's Future and Environment Act or the SAFE Act - Requires the President to establish an interagency Natural Resources Climate Change Adaptation Panel to: (1) develop and implement a Natural Resources Climate Change Adaptation Strategy to protect, restore, and conserve natural resources so that such resources become more resilient, adapt to, and withstand the impacts of climate variability and change; and (2) review and revise such strategy every five years. Requires each agency represented on such panel to integrate the elements of such strategy that relate to conservation, restoration, and management of natural resources into agency plans, environmental reviews, and programs. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to establish a National Climate Change and Wildlife Science Center within the United States Geological Survey (USGS) to assess and develop scientific information, tools, strategies, and techniques to be used to address the impacts of climate variability and change on natural resources. Requires the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the Interior to establish a Science Advisory Board to advise such Panel on the state of the science regarding such impacts and strategies and mechanisms for natural resources adaptation. Requires each agency with representation on such panel to: (1) submit to the President a natural resources adaptation plan to address such impacts and implement such plan upon approval by the President, and (2) review such plan every five years. Requires states, in order to be eligible to receive funding under this Act, to submit to the Secretary of the Interior and, as applicable, the Secretary of Commerce for review and approval a state natural resources adaptation plan that details efforts to address impacts of climate change on natural resources and coastal areas.</summary>
</bill>
