<bill session="111" type="h" number="5878" updated="2013-07-20T00:05:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Economic Fair Treatment and Job Creation Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make funds and tax benefits available to assist job creation and workforce diversification in the golf industry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400075"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2010--Introduced.
Economic Fair Treatment and Job Creation Act of 2010 - Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to revise the prohibition against the use by any state or local government or private entity of funds made available in that Act for any golf course to prohibit such use for any golf course: (1) which is private; and (2) to the extent such funds are not for job creation and workforce diversification relating to such golf course. Requires any entity that uses such funds for a golf course to: (1) submit to the Comptroller General a report which describes baseline data on existing jobs and diversity of the golf course and related businesses and provides detailed information on jobs created; and (2) institute a diversity plan for the golf course and related businesses and establish objective conduct for recruiting women, members of racial and ethnic minority groups, and individuals with disabilities for entry, mid-management, and senior executive positions. Requires the Comptroller General to report on the use of any funds for golf courses as a result of this Act. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to remove commercial golf courses from property for which specified Gulf Opportunity Zone tax benefits are not available.</summary>
</bill>
