<bill session="109" type="s" number="1443" updated="2013-07-19T20:26:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to permit athletes to receive nonimmigrant alien status under certain conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2005-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8668-8669"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3821"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2005--Introduced.
Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to enlarge the scope of P-1 (athletes and entertainers) nonimmigrant visas to include: (1) a professional athlete; (2) a person who performs as an athlete, coach, or part of a team that is located in the United States and is a member of certain amateur foreign leagues or associations from which a significant number of individuals are drafted by major sports leagues or their minor league affiliates; and (2) a professional or amateur athlete who performs individually or as part of a group in a theatrical ice skating production coming to the United States in a specific ice skating production or tour. (Currently such provision is limited to athletes performing at an "internationally recognized level of performance.") Eliminates consultation requirements applicable to the Secretary of Homeland Security's approval of such visas. Requires the Secretary to permit a petition to seek P-1 classification for multiple alien athletes. Prohibits additional fees for such petitions. Requires the Secretary to allow athletes or their employers to seek admission for such athletes under other than P-1 provisions of the Act.</summary>
</bill>
