<bill session="111" type="h" number="514" updated="2013-07-19T23:16:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Responsible Subprime Lending Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that certain amendments made by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to Regulation Z to prohibit certain unfair, abusive or deceptive home mortgage lending practices and restricts certain other mortgage practice shall take effect as a matter of law and a new effective date, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400144"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/14/2009--Introduced.
Responsible Subprime Lending Act - States that certain revisions added as a final rule by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Board) to regulation Z relating to Truth in Lending, shall apply as a matter of law to covered loans for which the creditor receives an application after the end of the 30-day period beginning on the enactment of this Act (except for the final rules on advertising, escrows, and loan servicing). States that certain final rules on escrows shall be effective for covered loans for which the creditor receives an application on or after October 1, 2009, but for such loans [sic] secured by manufactured housing on or after April 1, 2010. Directs the Board to issue a final rule as soon as possible without regard to statutory notice and comment procedures to make certain revisions in accordance with the effective dates provided under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
