<bill session="113" type="h" number="1382" updated="2013-11-02T06:30:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Coast Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Commerce, through the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, to establish a constituent-driven program that collects priority coastal geospatial data and supports an information platform capable of efficiently integrating coastal data with decision support tools, training, and best practices to inform and improve local, State, regional, and Federal capacities to manage the coastal region.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400349"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2013-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2013--Introduced.
Digital Coast Act of 2013 - Defines "Digital Coast" as a constituent-driven effort led by the Secretary of Commerce, through the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), to provide an enabling platform integrating geospatial data, decision support tools, training, and best practices to address coastal and emergency management issues and enhance coastal economies and ecosystem services by helping communities with cost-effective and participatory solutions. Directs NOAA to establish and implement the Digital Coast to: (1) collect data concerning coastal elevations, land use and cover, habitat and submerged aquatic vegetation, parcels, planimetrics, socioeconomics, and human use; and (2) integrate other data sources for the broadest measure of coastal resource management constituents and applications. Directs NOAA to: (1) make such data and resulting products accessible via the Digital Coast and other related Internet technologies, (2) provide training on decision support tools developed under this Act, (3) document data to Federal Geographic Data Committee standards, and (4) archive the raw data at appropriate NOAA or federal data centers. Requires coordination and data sharing with states, U.S. territories, local governments, nongovernmental entities, and other federal efforts. Requires the establishment of NOAA Coastal Services Centers to facilitate the development of products and services addressing the needs of local, state, and regional entities involved with coastal and ocean decisionmaking and to lead development and maintenance of the Digital Coast.</summary>
</bill>
