<bill session="112" type="s" number="352" updated="2013-07-20T02:19:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Energy Independence and Security Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the exploration, leasing, development, production, and economically feasible and prudent transportation of oil and gas in and from the Coastal Plain in Alaska.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2011-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S749-751"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1682"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="3407"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2011--Introduced.
American Energy Independence and Security Act of 2011 - Authorizes the exploration, leasing, development, production, and transportation of oil and gas in and from the Coastal Plain in Alaska. Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a competitive oil and gas leasing program for oil and gas exploration, development, and production in the Coastal Plain. Amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act to repeal the prohibition against production of oil and gas from Arctic National Wildlife Refuge. States that, in connection with specified environmental protection laws, the Secretary shall not be required to: (1) identify nonleasing alternative courses of action, or (2) analyze the environmental effects of those actions. Authorizes the Secretary to designate not more than 45,000 acres of the Coastal Plain as a special area (including the Sadlerochit Spring area).Prohibits surface occupancy of land comprising the special area if the Secretary leases all or a portion of such special area for oil and gas exploration and development.Authorizes the Secretary to lease all or a portion of a special area under terms that permit the use of horizontal drilling technology from sites on leases located outside the special area (directional drilling). Sets forth procedures for lease sales and lease grants. Prohibits the Secretary from closing land within the Coastal Plain to oil and gas leasing, exploration, or development, except in accordance with this Act. Sets forth procedures for: (1) Coastal Plain environmental protection, (2) expedited judicial review, (3) rights-of-way and easements, and (4) local government impact aid and community service assistance, including Alaska establishment of a Coastal Plain Local Government Impact Aid Assistance Fund. Prescribes a revenue allocation scheme derived from adjusted bonus, rental, and royalty receipts from federal oil and gas leasing and operations authorized under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
