<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1568" updated="2013-07-19T23:09:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29T13:46:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-29T13:46:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5893) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to create jobs through increased investment in infrastructure, to eliminate loopholes which encourage companies to move operations offshore, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T20:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-577, by Mr. Hastings (FL).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28T20:14:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI are waived. The resolution waives clause 6(a) of rule XIII against any resolution reported from the Rules Committee through the calendar day of Sunday, August 1, 2010 (same day filing).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-07-28T20:15:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="227">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 227.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29T11:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6297-6306" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29T11:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1568.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29T12:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6306" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29T12:50:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1568, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Foxx demanded the yeas and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29T13:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6308-6309" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2010-07-29T13:46:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="486" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 233 - 182 (Roll no. 486).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6297" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29T13:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="111" type="h" number="5893"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2010--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5893) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to create jobs through increased investment in infrastructure, to eliminate loopholes which encourage companies to move operations offshore.</summary>
</bill>
