<bill session="111" type="s" number="4030" updated="2013-07-20T01:01:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to establish a community-supported agriculture promotion program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/2010--Introduced.
Amends the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to carry out a program, to be known as the Community-Supported Agriculture Promotion Program, to promote community-supported agriculture (CSA). Defines the term "CSA" to mean a farm operated in a manner consistent with community-supported agriculture, as defined by the Secretary. States that the purposes of the program are to: (1) increase domestic consumption of agricultural commodities by improving and expanding, or assisting in the improvement or expansion of, domestic CSA programs; (2) aid in the development of new CSA programs; and (3) increase participation in CSA in low-income areas or food deserts. Makes nonprofit corporations, agricultural cooperatives, producer networks, local governments, and public benefit corporations eligible to receive grants under the program. Directs the Secretary to establish criteria and guidelines for the submission, evaluation, and funding of proposed projects under the program.</summary>
</bill>
