<bill session="109" type="h" number="5849" updated="2013-07-19T19:56:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Illegal Transshipments Enforcement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase the fine and prison term for textile transshipment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400172"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Embezzlement"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2006--Introduced.
Illegal Transshipments Enforcement Act of 2006 - Amends the federal criminal code to repeal the requirement of specific intent to convert to personal use from the prohibition against theft or fraudulent acquisition of goods or chattels in an interstate or foreign shipment of cargo. Adds to the list of vehicles or facilities involved any trailer, air cargo container, intermodal container, trailer, container freight station, warehouse, or freight consolidation facility. Increases from one to three years the prison term for any such felony involving less than $1,000. States that goods and chattel shall be construed to be moving as an interstate or foreign shipment at all points between the point of origin and the final destination (as evidenced by the waybill or other shipping document of the shipment), regardless of any temporary stop while awaiting transshipment or otherwise. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and make appropriate changes to the federal sentencing guidelines based upon the amendments to the crime of cargo theft made by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
