<bill session="109" type="s" number="1498" updated="2013-07-19T20:26:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain water distribution facilities to the Northern Colorado Water Conservancy District.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300003"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2005-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8960"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-273.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="3443"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2005--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to convey the St. Vrain Supply Canal, the Boulder Creek Supply Canal that extends from the St. Vrain River to Boulder Creek, and the South Platte Supply Canal, all of which are facilities of the Colorado-Big Thompson Project located in the counties of Larimer, Boulder, and Weld, Colorado, to the Northern Colorado Water Conservancy District. Provides that the District shall not be required to provide additional consideration for this conveyance. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer from the reclamation fund in the Treasury to the Secretary specified funds, which shall be derived from amounts collected by the Western Area Power Administration for the sale of electricity from the Loveland Area Projects. Directs the Secretary: (1) if the transferred water distribution facilities have not been conveyed to the District within one year after this Act's enactment, to submit to specified congressional committees a report that describes the reasons for the failure to convey such facilities and the schedule for completing the transfer as soon as practicable; and (2) to provide annual reports until the date on which such facilities are conveyed.</summary>
</bill>
