<bill session="113" type="h" number="180" updated="2013-11-02T06:20:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-14T18:54:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-05-14T18:54:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Blue Alert Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">National Blue Alert Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage, enhance, and integrate Blue Alert plans throughout the United States in order to disseminate information when a law enforcement officer is seriously injured or killed in the line of duty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412451"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2013-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2013-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412532" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2013-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2013-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412297" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2013-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2013-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2013-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-06">
      <text>Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-14T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 113-54.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-14T16:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="32">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 32.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-14T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-14T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2579-2582" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-14T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 180.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-14T17:16:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-14T18:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2586-2587" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="144" datetime="2013-05-14T18:54:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 406 - 2 (Roll no. 144).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2579-2580" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-05-14T18:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="357"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="357"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2013--Passed House amended.
National Blue Alert Act of 2013 - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) establish a national Blue Alert communications network within the Department of Justice (DOJ) to disseminate information when a law enforcement officer is seriously injured or killed in the line of duty, in coordination with federal, state, and local Blue Alert plans; and (2) assign an existing DOJ officer to act as the national coordinator of the Blue Alert communications network. Sets forth the duties of the national coordinator, including: (1) providing assistance to states and local governments that are using Blue Alert plans; (2) establishing voluntary guidelines for states and local governments to use in developing such plans; (3) developing protocols for efforts to apprehend suspects; (4) working with states to ensure appropriate regional coordination of various elements of the network; (5) establishing an advisory group to assist states, local governments, law enforcement agencies, and other entities in initiating, facilitating, and promoting Blue Alert plans; (6) acting as the nationwide point of contact for the development of the network and the regional coordination of Blue Alerts through the network; and (7) determining what procedures and practices are in use for notifying law enforcement and the public when a law enforcement officer is killed or seriously injured in the line of duty and which of the procedures and practices are effective and do not require the expenditure of additional resources to implement. Requires the guidelines to: (1) provide that appropriate information relating to a Blue Alert is disseminated to officials of law enforcement, public health, and other agencies; and (2) provide mechanisms that ensure that Blue Alerts comply with all applicable federal, state, and local privacy laws and regulations and include standards that specifically provide for the protection of the civil liberties of law enforcement officers and their families. Prohibits the coordinator from: (1) performing any official travel for the sole purpose of carrying out the duties of the coordinator, (2) lobbying any officer of a state regarding the funding or implementation of a Blue Alert plan, or (3) hosting a conference focused solely on the Blue Alert program that requires the expenditure of federal funds. Directs the coordinator to annually submit a report on the coordinator's activities and the effectiveness and status of the Blue Alert plans that are in effect or being developed.</summary>
</bill>
