<bill session="111" type="sr" number="403" updated="2013-07-20T00:19:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that Umar Farouk Abdulmutallab should be tried by a military tribunal rather than by a civilian court.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2010-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2010-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2010-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2010-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2010-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2010-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S396" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2010--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) foreign terrorists should not be afforded the same rights as U.S. citizens under the Constitution; (2) foreign terrorist enemy combatants should be tried in military tribunals; (3) to the extent that foreign terrorists are prosecuted in civilian courts, they should be thoroughly interrogated for information necessary to protect the United States before they are provided with a lawyer and informed of their right to remain silent; and (4) the Attorney General should consult with specified intelligence officials, congressional leaders, or the President before unilaterally deciding to terminate the interrogation of a key intelligence source and provide a terrorist enemy with the rights of U.S. citizens under the Constitution. Expresses the sense of the Senate with respect to the interrogation and prosecution of Umar Farouk Abdulmutallab.</summary>
</bill>
