<bill session="109" type="s" number="2984" updated="2013-07-19T20:39:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FILL UP Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Future Investment to Lessen Long-term Use of Petroleum Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require certain profitable oil companies to expend 1 percent of recent quarterly profits to install E-85 fuel pumps in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2006--Introduced.
Future Investment to Lessen Long-term Use of Petroleum Act, or the FILL UP Act - Sets forth investment requirements for a company that: (1) produces, refines, distributes, or sells petroleum products in the United States; and (2) reported at least $1 billion in net income, for all domestic and international operations, to the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) for the first quarter of 2006. Requires each such company to expend not less than 1% of its total reported profits for the first quarter of 2006 to install infrastructure to dispense E-85 fuel or other alternative fuels at domestic gasoline service stations. Sets a three-year deadline to complete installation of such infrastructure. Directs the Secretary of Energy to ensure compliance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
