<bill session="112" type="h" number="3498" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tutoring for Students Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for high-quality academic tutoring for low-income students, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2012-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2012-02-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="1570"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2011--Introduced.
Tutoring for Students Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to require states to: (1) reserve 10% of the school improvement funds they receive under part A of title I of the ESEA; and (2) reallocate 97% of the reserved funds to local educational agencies (LEAs) to provide, or arrange for the provision of, high-quality academic tutoring to impoverished students. Requires states to determine which of their LEAs will participate in the program, but requires the inclusion of their lowest performing LEAs. Allocates the reserve funds among participating LEAs in proportion to their respective share of school improvement funds. Requires states to develop processes for selecting, evaluating, and, if necessary, removing providers of academic tutoring. Requires providers to have a record of increasing student academic achievement and a capacity to do so in a manner that is consistent with the applicable LEA's instructional program and state academic content and achievement standards. Removes providers that fail for two consecutive years to improve the academic proficiency of impoverished students. Requires states to maintain an updated list of approved providers, by school district, from which parents may choose. Requires providers of academic tutoring to keep parents and LEAs apprised of a student's progress, and employ tutors that meet state-determined qualifications. Directs the Secretary of Education to conduct a national evaluation to determine the value of such tutoring and document best practices.</summary>
</bill>
