<bill session="111" type="h" number="5675" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Border and Homeland Security Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve border security and to increase prosecutions and penalties for illegal entry into the United States, to prevent and combat the smuggling of weapons of mass destruction into the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400141"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Natural Resources, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/2010--Introduced.
National Border and Homeland Security Act of 2010 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to give state criminal alien assistance program (SCAAP) funding priority to: (1) northern or southern border states; or (2) state political subdivisions having one of the four largest populations of unlawfully present aliens for the preceding fiscal year. Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) (Secretary) to complete the required 700 mile southwest border fencing by December 31, 2012. Amends the Secure Fence Act of 2006 to direct the Secretary to achieve operational control over U.S. international land and maritime borders by December 31, 2012. Directs the Secretary to: (1) increase the number of full-time, active-duty Border Patrol agents; (2) increase the number of Customs and Border Protection officers at U.S. ports of entry; and (3) ensure the implementaion of the automated entry and exit control system for aliens entering the United States at ports of entry (US-Visit) by December 31, 2011. Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) from impeding border security-related activities by the Secretary on U.S. public lands. Sets forth activities that may be taken to increase the number of Operation Streamline prosecutions by the following U.S. district courts: (1) the District of Arizona; (2) the District of New Mexico (3) the Southern District of California (4) the Southern District of Texas; and (5) the Western District of Texas. Increases criminal penalties for improper U.S. entry by an alien. Excludes minimum mandatory prison penalties for an alien who: (1) is under 18 years old; (2) is a parent traveling with a child under 18 years old; or (3) has a life-threatening health condition. Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office (of DHS), in protecting the United States from a nuclear, fissile material, or radiological attack, to consider potential smuggling routes in land border areas between ports of entry, railcars entering the United States from Canada or Mexico, and private aircraft or small vessels. Directs the Secretary to procure the number of next generation portable radiation detectors (PRD) and radioactive isotope identification devices (RIID) required by the Border Patrol along the southern and northern U.S. borders by July 1, 2011. Authorizes appropriations for port security grants. Directs the Secretary to develop and implement a strategic plan to detect and interdict biological and chemical weapons entering the United States.</summary>
</bill>
