<bill session="112" type="s" number="1743" updated="2013-07-20T02:31:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Learn to Earn Reemployment Training Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to consolidate certain Federal job training programs into a State-administered, market-delivered block grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412384"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-10-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/2011--Introduced.
Learn to Earn Reemployment Training Improvement Act of 2011 - Establishes the Learn to Earn program to facilitate the reemployment of individuals receiving emergency unemployment compensation (EUC claimants) under title IV of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to analyze federal job training programs and recommend to Congress their termination or consolidation sufficient to result in total savings of at least $100 million per fiscal year. Prescribes legislative procedures for consideration in both chambers of proposed legislative language (job training bill) for program terminations or consolidations. Directs the Secretary to make certain allotments (out of funds saved from program terminations and consolidations) to states with approved state plans to establish State Learn to Earn programs to increase reemployment opportunities for EUC claimants by providing them with short-term work experience placements with eligible employers. Prescribes program requirements. Requires a State Learn to Earn program to give participants emergency unemployment compensation (including augmented wages, if necessary) for work performed. Authorizes a program also to provide supportive services to a participant, such as transportation, child care, and dependent care.</summary>
</bill>
