<bill session="112" type="h" number="2322" updated="2013-07-20T01:30:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Burt Lake Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians Reaffirmation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reaffirm and clarify the Federal relationship of the Burt Lake Band as a distinct federally recognized Indian Tribe, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412436"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2011-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2011--Introduced.
Burt Lake Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians Reaffirmation Act - Reaffirms federal recognition and the rights and privileges of the Burt Lake Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians in Cheboygan County, Michigan. Extends to the Band eligibility for all federal services and benefits available to other federally recognized Indian tribes. Designates the service area for the delivery of federal services to the Band and to other Indians in the area of Cheboygan County, Michigan.Directs the Secretary of the Interior to acquire land in Cheboygan County, Michigan, and in other geographic areas and to hold such lands in trust for the benefit of the Band. Sets forth criteria and evidentiary requirements for determining the initial membership of the Band. Requires the Band to provide a copy of its base roll to the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs within one year of this Act's enactment. Provides that the initial constitution of the Band shall be the constitution submitted by the Band to the Office of Federal Acknowledgment on May 2, 2005.</summary>
</bill>
