<bill session="109" type="h" number="5067" updated="2013-07-19T19:49:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Border Security and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish operational control over the international land and maritime borders of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400006" joined="2006-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2006-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400637" joined="2006-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Unconventional Threats and Capabilities.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS26" subcommittee="Terrorism, Unconventional Threats and Capabilities" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4312"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Cameras"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Central America"/>
    <term name="Central Americans"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Computer matching"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Dogs"/>
    <term name="Drone aircraft"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Fissionable materials"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Government aircraft"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military civic action"/>
    <term name="Military surveillance"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Police communication systems"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Prison alternatives"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Radar"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Right of asylum"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/2006--Introduced.
Border Security and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2006 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) take all appropriate actions, including development of a national border strategy, to maintain operational control over the U.S. international land and maritime borders; (2) report on cross-border security agreements with Mexico and Canada; (3) provide for biometric data enhancements; (4) report on the One Face at the Border Initiative; (5) implement a secure communications plan for Border Patrol and border security use; (6) increase Border Patrol agents, port of entry inspection personnel, and canine detection teams; and (7) report on the airspace security mission's impact on the National Capital Region. Directs the Secretary to reimburse (up to prior-to-damage value) property owners for costs associated with repairing damages to the property owners' private infrastructure constructed on a U.S. government right-of-way delineating the international land border when such damages are the result of unlawful entry of aliens. Directs the Secretary to establish at least one Border Patrol unit for the U.S. Virgin Islands by September 30, 2006. Directs the Secretary to report to the Committee on Homeland Security respecting DHS progress in tracking Central American gangs across the U.S.-Mexico border. Directs the Secretary to compile specified health care-related data respecting unauthorized aliens taken into U.S. custody. Directs the Secretary to deploy radiation detection portal monitors at all U.S. ports of entry and facilities within one year of enactment of this Act. Directs the Secretary: (1) and the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to develop a plan to increase the availability of DOD surveillance equipment along the U.S. international land and maritime borders; (2) to assess border security vulnerabilities on Department of Interior land directly adjacent to the U.S. border; (3) to conduct a border security threat assessment and information sharing exercise; and (4) to establish the Border Security Advisory Committee. Authorizes the Secretary to permit a state, local government, or Indian tribe to use specified federal funds for border security activities usually performed by a federal agency but which, pursuant to an agreement, are being performed by state, local, or tribal government. Directs the Secretary to establish a university-based Center for Excellence for Border Security. Requires mandatory detention of an alien apprehended illegally seeking to enter the United States at a U.S. port of entry or land or maritime border as of October 1, 2006, unless such alien is: (1) paroled into the United States for humanitarian or public benefit reasons; or (2) is permitted to withdraw an application for admission and immediately departs from the United States. Provides that during the period 60 days after enactment of this Act and prior to October 1, 2006, an apprehended alien may be released with notice to appear only if: (1) the Secretary determines that the alien is not a national security risk; and (2) the alien provides a bond of not less than $5,000. Directs the Secretary, subject to appropriations, to fully utilize: (1) all Department of Homeland Security (DHS) bed space; and (2) all other options to cost effectively increase detention capacity. Denies admission to the nationals of a country that refuses or delays acceptance of its nationals ordered removed from the United States. Directs the Secretary to place an alien (other than from Mexico or Canada) who has not been admitted or paroled into expedited removal if apprehended within 100 miles of the border and within 14 days of unauthorized entry. Directs the Secretary to take specified actions to ensure coordination of DHS border security efforts. Establishes in DHS an Office of Air and Marine Operations whose primary mission shall be to prevent the entry of terrorists, other unlawful aliens, instruments of terrorism, narcotics, and other contraband into the United States, and whose secondary mission shall be to assist other agencies with such protective functions. Directs the Office to operate and maintain the Air and Marine Operations Center in Riverside, California, or other designated facility. Directs the Secretary to transfer to United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement all functions of the Customs Patrol Officers unit operating on the Tohono O'odham Indian reservation (the "Shadow Wolves" unit). Authorizes the Secretary to establish within United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement additional Customs Patrol units to operate on Indian lands.</summary>
</bill>
