<bill session="112" type="h" number="1890" updated="2013-07-20T01:26:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAFER Drilling Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Save America from Environmentally Reckless Drilling Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to require, as a condition and term of any exploration plan or development and production plan submitted under that Act, that the applicant for the plan must submit an oil spill containment and clean-up plan capable of handling a worst-case scenario oil spill, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412254"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2011--Introduced.
Save America from Environmentally Reckless Drilling Act or SAFER Drilling Act - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to require, as a condition and term of any exploration plan or any development and production plan, that the applicant submit and implement an oil spill containment and cleanup plan (to be approved by the Secretary and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency [EPA]) capable of handling a worst-case scenario oil spill. Describes required plan contents. Allows approval by the Administrator only if the applicant has demonstrated adequate technology, organization, resources, and capacity both to contain and to prevent shoreline contamination by a significant proportion of a worst-case spill, and to provide for long-term cleanup and remediation of the marine and coastal environments. Authorizes cancellation of a lease (without compensation) upon failure of the lease holder to submit an exploration plan or development and production plan in accordance with this Act or to implement an approved oil spill containment and cleanup plan.</summary>
</bill>
