<bill session="110" type="h" number="6518" updated="2013-07-19T22:00:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Justice Integrity Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To increase public confidence in the justice system and address any unwarranted racial and ethnic disparities in the criminal process.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="s" number="3245"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in criminal justice administration"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2008--Introduced.
Justice Integrity Act of 2008 - Requires the Attorney General to: (1) establish a pilot program in 10 U.S. districts to promote fairness and the perception of fairness in the federal criminal justice system and to determine whether legislation is required; and (2) designate a U.S. attorney in each of the districts to implement a plan for carrying out such pilot program.Requires each U.S. attorney designated to implement a pilot program to appoint an advisory group consisting of judges, prosecutors, defense attorneys, and other individuals and entities who play an important role in the criminal justice system. Requires each advisory group to: (1) collect and analyze data on the race and ethnicity of defendants at each stage of a criminal proceeding; (2) seek to determine causes of racial and ethnic disparities in the criminal justice process; and (3) submit to the U.S. attorney a report and proposed plan for addressing such disparities. Requires each U.S. attorney to annually evaluate the efficacy of a plan submitted by an advisory group. Requires the Attorney General to: (1) prepare a comprehensive report on all advisory group plans and submit such report and plans to Congress; and (2) exercise continuing oversight of the criminal justice system to reduce unwarranted racial and ethnic disparities and improve such system.</summary>
</bill>
