<bill session="110" type="s" number="2427" updated="2013-07-19T22:42:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">OPEN Government Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Openness Promotes Effectiveness in our National Government Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to promote accessibility, accountability, and openness in Government by strengthening section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Freedom of Information Act), and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2007-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-12-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14853-14854"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-12-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14854-14855" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1309"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="1326"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="849"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2488"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consent decrees"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Journalism"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Position classification"/>
    <term name="Promotions"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Reporters and reporting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/6/2007--Introduced.
Openness Promotes Effectiveness in our National Government Act of 2007 or the OPEN Government Act of 2007 - Amends Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) provisions to define "representative of the news media" and "news," specify examples of news-media entities, and provide that a freelance journalist shall be regarded as working for a news-media entity if the journalist can demonstrate a solid basis for expecting publication through that entity.Provides that, for purposes of recovery of attorney fees and other litigation costs under FOIA, a complainant has substantially prevailed if the complainant has obtained relief through either: (1) a judicial order or an enforceable written agreement or consent decree; or (2) a voluntary or unilateral change in position by the agency, provided that the complainant's claim is not insubstantial. Requires attorney fees to be paid only from appropriations of an agency against which a claim or judgment has been rendered.Directs the Attorney General to notify the Special Counsel of and report on civil actions taken for arbitrary and capricious rejections of requests for agency records.Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) the tolling of the time limit within which agencies determine whether to comply with a request for records; and (2) refunding search fees if an agency fails to comply with time limits. Requires each agency to make available its FOIA Public Liaison to assist in resolving requester disputes.Requires agencies to establish: (1) a system to assign an individual tracking number for each FOIA request that will take longer than ten days to process; and (2) a telephone line or Internet service to provide information on the status of requests.Revises certain reporting requirements relating to FOIA requests and agency responses. Establishes the Office of Government Information Services within the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) to: (1) review agency compliance with FOIA policies; (2) recommend policy changes; and (3) offer mediation services between FOIA requesters and administrative agencies as a non-exclusive alternative to litigation. Requires each agency to designate a Chief FOIA Officer and at least one FOIA Public Liaison.Requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to report on personnel policies related to FOIA.</summary>
</bill>
