<bill session="112" type="s" number="1610" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cement Sector Regulatory Relief Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide additional time for the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate achievable standards for cement manufacturing facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2012-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2011-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2011-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2011-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2250"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2681"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1650"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1786"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="1971"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/2011--Introduced.
Cement Regulatory Relief Act of 2011 - Provides that the following rules shall have no force or effect and shall be treated as though they had never taken effect: (1) the National Emission Standards for Hazardous Air Pollutants from the Portland Cement Manufacturing Industry and Standards of Performance for Portland Cement Plants; and (2) the Standards of Performance for New Stationary Sources and Emission Guidelines for Existing Sources: Commercial and Industrial Solid Waste Incineration Units, and the rule entitled "Identification of Non-Hazardous Secondary Materials that are Solid Waste," to the extent that such rules apply to the Portland cement manufacturing industry and Portland cement plants. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), in lieu of such rules, to promulgate within 15 months (or such later date as may be determined by the Administrator) regulations for the Portland cement manufacturing industry and Portland cement plants subject to such rules, that: (1) establish maximum achievable control technology standards, performance standards, and other requirements for hazardous air pollutants or solid waste combustion under the Clean Air Act; and (2) identify nonhazardous secondary materials that, when used as fuels in combustion units of that industry and those plants, qualify as solid waste under the Solid Waste Disposal Act for purposes of determining the extent to which such combustion units are required to meet emission standards for such pollutants under such Act or the Clean Air Act. Requires the Administrator, after considering the costs of achieving emission reductions, non-air quality health and environmental impacts and energy requirements, feasibility of implementation, the availability of equipment, suppliers, and labor, and potential net employment impacts, to establish dates for compliance with standards and requirements under such regulations no earlier than five years after the effective date of the regulation. Sets forth guidelines for such rules and regulations, including requiring the Administrator to: (1) ensure that emission standards for existing and new sources can be met under actual operating conditions consistently and concurrently with emission standards for all other air pollutants covered by regulations applicable to the source category, and (2) impose the least burdensome regulatory alternative for each regulation promulgated.</summary>
</bill>
