<bill session="110" type="s" number="1890" updated="2013-07-19T22:36:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Flood Insurance Choice Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to allow individuals to opt-out of the National Flood Insurance Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300069"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/2007--Introduced.
Flood Insurance Choice Act of 2007 - Amends the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 to permit an individual homeowner not to purchase property flood insurance, even for property in a special flood hazard area, if he or she submits certain written certifications to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and the state, community, or local official responsible for zoning and building codes. Declares that such homeowner shall not be required to comply with certain base flood elevation requirements. Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, with respect to land use controls, financial assistance and mitigation assistance, to shield from penalties for non-compliance those areas that have complied with its requirements but where individuals have opted out pursuant to this Act. Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to deny assistance for individuals who have opted-out of the flood insurance program.</summary>
</bill>
