<bill session="109" type="h" number="2715" updated="2013-07-19T19:28:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Stop Self-Authorized Secret Searches Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish reasonable procedural protections for the use of national security letters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400289"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2005-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2005-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400305" joined="2005-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2005-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2005-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2005-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2005-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="737"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2005--Introduced.
Stop Self-Authorized Secret Searches Act - Amends the federal criminal code, the Right to Financial Privacy Act, and Fair Credit Reporting Act to require that there be specific and articulable facts giving reason to believe that the person to whom records pertain is a foreign power or agent for Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) access to such records for foreign intelligence and international terrorism investigations. Prohibits a request for subscriber information or financial or business records from: (1) containing any requirement that would be held unreasonable if contained in a subpoena issued by a U.S. court in aid of a grand jury investigation of espionage or international terrorism; or (2) requiring the production of documentary evidence that would be privileged from disclosure if demanded by such a subpoena. Prohibits an electronic communication service provider, a financial institution, or a consumer reporting agency from disclosing that the FBI has sought access to telephone records for 90 days after receipt of such request, with exceptions (current law places no limits on nondisclosure). Authorizes the court to issue an ex parte order prohibiting disclosure for an additional period upon determining that there is reason to believe that disclosure sought by a government agency will result in: (1) endangering the life or physical safety of any person; (2) flight from prosecution; (3) destruction of or tampering with evidence; (4) intimidation of potential witnesses; or (5) otherwise seriously endangering U.S. national security by alerting a target, a target's associates, or the foreign power of which the target is an agent, of the government's interest in the target. Sets forth provisions governing: (1) judicial review of requests for and disclosure or nondisclosure of information; and (2) use and disclosure of acquired information by federal officers, including requirements for advanced authorization by the Attorney General for its use in a criminal proceeding, advance notice to the aggrieved party of its use in a trial, hearing, or other government proceeding, and the right of such party to move to suppress evidence obtained.</summary>
</bill>
