<bill session="109" type="hr" number="424" updated="2013-07-19T18:58:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To congratulate the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Discovery crew of Commander Eileen Collins, Pilot Jim Kelly, Mission Specialist Charlie Camarda, Mission Specialist Wendy Lawrence, Mission Specialist Soichi Noguchi, Mission Specialist Steve Robinson, and Mission Specialist Andy Thomas on the successful completion of their 14 day test flight to the International Space Station for the first step of the Vision for Space Exploration, begun from the Kennedy Space Center, Florida, on July 26, 2005, and completed at Edwards Air Force Base, California, on August 9, 2005. This historical mission represented a great step forward into the new beginning of the Second Space Age.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="441"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Astronauts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space shuttles"/>
    <term name="Space stations"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/6/2005--Introduced.
Commends the following individuals who comprised the crew of National Aeronautics and Space Administration Space Shuttle Discovery STS Flight 114: Commander Eileen Collins, pilot Colonel Jim Kelly, and mission specialists Charlie Camarda, Wendy Lawrence, Soichi Noguchi of Japan, Steve Robinson, and Andy Thomas.</summary>
</bill>
