<bill session="112" type="s" number="251" updated="2013-07-20T02:18:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit the provision of Federal funds to State and local governments for payment of obligations, to prohibit the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System from financially assisting State and local governments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2011-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2011-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2011-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2011-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2011-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2011-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2011-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400105" joined="2011-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2011-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2011-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2011-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2011-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2011-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2011-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2011-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="184"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/2011--Introduced.
Prohibits the use of federal funds to purchase or guarantee obligations of, issue lines of credit to, or provide direct or indirect grants-and-aid to any state, municipal, local, or county government which, on or after January 26, 2011, has defaulted on its obligations, is at risk of defaulting, or is likely to default, without such federal assistance. Prohibits the Secretary of the Treasury from using, directly or indirectly, general fund revenues or borrowed funds to purchase or guarantee any asset or obligation of any such state, municipal, local, or county government. Prohibits the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System from: (1) providing or extending to, or authorizing with respect to, such a state, municipal, local, or county government, or other entity with taxing authority or bonding authority, any funds, loan guarantees, credits, or any other financial instrument or other authority, including bond purchases; or (2) otherwise assisting such a government entity under any Board authority. Waives the application of this Act for federal assistance provided in response to a natural disaster.</summary>
</bill>
