<bill session="113" type="h" number="3289" updated="2013-11-02T06:46:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide funds during the lapse of appropriations for the payment of military death gratuities and funeral and related transportation and housing expenses through the transfer of unobligated amounts in the Health Insurance Reform Implementation Fund.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400221"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hj" number="91"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3274"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/2013--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), during any period for which interim or full-year appropriations for FY2014 are not in effect for payment of military death gratuities and funeral and related transportation and housing expenses, to transfer, from unobligated amounts in the Health Insurance Reform Implementation Fund established by the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 (P.L. 111-152), to the Secretary of Defense (DOD) sufficient funds to provide the following benefits on behalf of members of the Armed Forces who die during such period: payment of death gratuities to certain survivors of deceased military service members, including for the death of members on active duty or inactive duty training, the death of members after discharge or release from duty or training, members and employees dying outside the United States while assigned to intelligence duties, and other eligible survivors; payment of authorized funeral and burial expenses, including authorized funeral travel and travel related to the dignified transfer of remains and unit memorial services; and temporary continuation of a basic allowance of housing for certain dependents of members dying on active duty.</summary>
</bill>
