<bill session="111" type="s" number="1565" updated="2013-07-20T00:37:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Better Health in the Arctic Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve Arctic health.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8685-8687"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2009--Introduced.
Better Health in the Arctic Act - Directs the Arctic Research Commission, in collaboration with federal health agencies, to prepare and submit to Congress a two-year study to examine the science base, gaps in knowledge, and strategies for the prevention and treatment of mental, behavioral, and physical health problems faced by populations in the Arctic, with a focus on Alaska. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH): (1) in collaboration with other governmental agencies and private and nonprofit entities involved in Arctic health issues, to develop a national Arctic health science policy; and (2) in developing the policy, to review and take into consideration the National Arctic Health Science Policy developed by the American Public Health Association Task Force in 1984. Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish a Desk for Arctic Health within the Office of the Director's Division of Program Coordination, Planning, and Strategic Initiatives, which shall: (1) work with the Interagency Arctic Research Policy Committee to ensure adequate health representation from federal agencies; (2) collaborate and consult with governmental entities and U.S. nongovernmental organizations involved in Arctic health issues; and (3) collaborate with the Canadian Institutes of Health Research on indigenous Arctic people health issues. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to establish a program at CDC's National Center of Environmental Health to foster advances and help provide technical support in the field of Arctic health impact assessments.</summary>
</bill>
