<bill session="112" type="s" number="1634" updated="2013-07-20T02:30:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the approval and disapproval of programs of education for purposes of educational benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2011-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-09-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-567.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2011--Introduced.
Amends federal provisions concerning the approval of state programs of education for purposes of the use of veterans' educational assistance provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to repeal the constructive approval of: (1) an accredited standard college degree program offered at a public or not-for-profit educational institution that is accredited by an agency or association recognized by the Secretary of Education, or (2) a program leading to a secondary school diploma offered by a secondary school approved in that state. Repeals the authority of the VA Secretary to: (1) approve accredited programs offered by proprietary for-profit educational institutions, or (2) disapprove courses which fail to meet state approving agency requirements.</summary>
</bill>
