<bill session="109" type="s" number="2755" updated="2013-07-19T20:37:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy PRICE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Production, Refining, Infrastructure, Conservation and Efficiency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance the energy production, refining, infrastructure, conservation and efficiency capabilities of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300097"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8353"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animal behavior"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Automobile engines"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum engineering"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Synthetic fuel"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2006--Introduced.
Energy Production, Refining, Infrastructure, Conservation and Efficiency Act, or the Energy PRICE Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish and implement a competitive leasing program for the exploration, development, and production of the oil and gas resources of the Coastal Plain (Arctic National Wildlife Refuge, ANWR). Establishes in the Treasury the Coastal Plain Local Government Impact Aid Assistance Fund. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to create an enhanced tax credit for oil recovery projects using qualified carbon dioxide in a method involving flooding or injection. Amends Armed Forces procurement law to extend to cap at 25 years the multiyear contract authority of the Department of Defense to procure fuel derived from coal, oil shale, and tar sands. Instructs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), upon request of a state or Indian tribe, to enter into an refinery permitting agreement to streamline the permit process for the construction and operation of a refinery. Amends the Clean Air Act to: (1) hold a state harmless and not require it to revise its implementation plan to account for the emissions from a waiver granted by the Administrator; and (2) revise boutique fuel requirements. Directs the EPA Administrator to: (1) conduct a research and demonstration program to evaluate the air quality benefits of ultra-clean Fischer-Tropsch transportation fuel, including diesel and jet fuel; and (2) evaluate the use of such fuel to reduce engine exhaust emissions. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) provide for full expensing of qualified refinery property; (2) treat certain oil and gas pipelines as five-year property for depreciation purposes; and (3) except tax-exempt financing of energy transportation infrastructure from the private business use test. Amends the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users to repeal the prohibition against demolition of the Brightman Street Bridge (Massachusetts) and the requirement of its maintenance as an emergency service route. Amends federal transportation law to revise the considerations the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) must take into account when deciding maximum feasible average fuel economy standards. Directs the Secretary to issue new regulations setting forth increased average fuel economy standards for passenger automobiles. Requires the Administrator of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to solicit applications for grants under the EPA Natural Gas STAR Program to pay the federal share of project costs for reduction of methane emissions in the oil and gas industries.</summary>
</bill>
