<bill session="110" type="h" number="3079" updated="2013-07-19T21:30:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-12-11T12:28:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-12-11T12:28:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Northern Mariana Islands Covenant Implementation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Northern Mariana Islands Delegate Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Northern Mariana Islands Delegate Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Northern Mariana Islands Immigration, Security, and Labor Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Northern Mariana Islands Delegate Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Northern Mariana Islands Immigration, Security, and Labor Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Joint Resolution Approving the Covenant to Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend the joint resolution that approved the covenant establishing the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2007-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-07">
      <text>Subcommittee on Insular Affairs Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-11-07">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-12-04T19:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-469, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-04">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than Dec. 11, 2007 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(k), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-11T12:05:00-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Christensen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-11T12:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15219-15227" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-11T12:06:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3079.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2007-12-11T12:28:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H15219-15224" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-12-11T12:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-11T12:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-324.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="676">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 676.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="1634"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="s" number="2739"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-territorial relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2007--Passed House amended.
Title I: Northern Mariana Islands Immigration, Security, and Labor Act - Northern Mariana Islands Immigration, Security, and Labor Act - (Sec. 103) Extends U.S. immigration laws, as defined by the Immigration and Nationality Act, to the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands (CNMI), subject to a transition period through December 31, 2013. Sets forth provisions respecting: (1) numerical limitations for nonimmigrant workers (parallel provisions for Guam and the CNMI); (2) nonimmigrant investors and nonimmigrant workers; and (3) removal. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to report to Congress respecting nonresident guestworkers in the CNMI. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for CNMI nonimmigrant visitor visa waivers (as currently provided for Guam) for stays of up to 45 days (current law provides for 15-day stays) in Guam or the CNMI. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) to monitor such admissions and suspend the entry of nationals from a country whose nationals have created an unacceptable number of program violations or pose security or law enforcement risks. Provides that a person: (1) seeking U.S. entry from the CNMI shall be processed under existing immigration authority regarding entry from Guam, Puerto Rico, and the U.S. Virgin Islands; and (2) denied admission shall be immediately removed. Authorizes: (1) additional countries to be added to such visa waiver program; (2) creation of additional Guam or CNMI-only nonimmigrant visas; and (3) the Attorney General, the Secretary, and the Secretary of Labor to establish CNMI immigration operations offices. Directs the President and the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to report to Congress respecting the transition program. Authorizes the Governor of CNMI to report to the President respecting the program. States that the CNMI government shall: (1) not permit an increase in the number of alien workers in the CNMI as of the date of enactment of this Act; and (2) administer its non-refoulement protection program in accordance with its September 2003 agreement with the Department of the Interior. Exempts hospitals in Guam, the CNMI, and the U.S. Virgin Islands from certain nurse admissions requirements. (Sec. 104) Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Northern Mariana Islands Delegate Act - Northern Mariana Islands Delegate Act - (Sec. 202) States that: (1) the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands shall be represented in the U.S. Congress by the Resident Representative to the United States (authorized by the Covenant to Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in Political Union With the United States of America); and (2) the Resident Representative shall be a nonvoting Delegate to the House of Representatives and elected as provided for by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
