<bill session="111" type="h" number="2770" updated="2013-07-19T23:36:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-27T14:41:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-07-27T14:41:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Nonprofit Research and Education Corporations Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Veterans Nonprofit Research and Education Corporations Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Veterans Nonprofit Research and Education Corporations Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to modify and update provisions of law relating to nonprofit research and education corporations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2009-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2009-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2009-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2009-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1359"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-07-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23T20:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 111-225.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-07-23T20:46:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="123">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 123.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Filner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8819-8822" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2770.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-07-27T14:41:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8820-8821" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2722"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="252"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2009--Passed House amended.
Veterans Nonprofit Research and Education Corporations Enhancement Act of 2009 - (Sec. 2) Amends federal provisions concerning the establishment at Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) medical facilities of nonprofit research and education corporations (NRECs) to allow an NREC to facilitate the conduct of research or education, or both, at more than one VA medical center. States that such an NREC shall be known as a multi-medical center research corporation (MCRC). Allows an NREC to act as a MCRC if: (1) the NREC board of directors approve a resolution permitting that NREC to act as a MCRC; and (2) the Secretary of Veterans Affairs approves the resolution. Requires each NREC and MCRC (corporation) to be established in accordance with the nonprofit corporation laws of the state in which the VA medical center which it supports is located. States that neither such corporation shall be considered to be owned by, or an agent or instrumentality of, the United States. (Sec. 3) Restates the purposes of the corporations, including with respect to their role in: (1) providing a flexible funding mechanism; and (2) residencies or similar programs. (Sec. 4) Modifies the composition of corporation boards of directors. Revises requirements concerning non-VA members of boards of directors of NRECs and MCRCs to: (1) state a minimum number who are not officers or employees of the federal government; and (2) expand the required areas of experience or expertise. Allows a corporation executive director to be an employee of the VA. Removes financial relationship restrictions from conflict of interest standards applicable to directors. (Sec. 5) Increases authorized corporate powers of the corporations to include entering into contracts and setting fees for education and training facilitated through a corporation. (Sec. 7) Revises annual report procedures to modify the thresholds for the obtaining of audits and require submission of an Internal Revenue Service return form applicable to organizations exempt from income tax. Revises conflict of interest policies applicable to directors, officers, and employees of a corporation to apply the policy adopted by the corporation (under current law, they are subject to federal laws and regulations applicable to federal employees). Revises requirements for a report to Congress to increase the threshold for providing information identifying payees of the corporation.</summary>
</bill>
