<bill session="111" type="h" number="3370" updated="2013-07-19T23:42:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Vessel Repair Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit qualified withdrawals from a capital construction fund account for the maintenance or repair of United States-flag vessels provided that the maintenance or repair is performed within the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2009-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2009--Introduced.
Vessel Repair Enhancement Act of 2009 - Expands, for capital construction fund provisions, the definition of "qualified vessel" to include: (1) a vessel documented under U.S. laws and maintained or repaired in a privately owned shipyard in the United States; and (2) any floating dry dock and related shipyard infrastructure (including marine railways) located in the United States and used to build, maintain, or repair U.S.-documented vessels. Amends federal merchant marine law and the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow capital construction funds to be used for maintenance or repair of vessels documented under the laws of the United States; (2) establish the order of withdrawal for purposes of the tax treatment of qualified withdrawals from such funds; and (3) disallow a basis reduction for maintenance or repair withdrawals.</summary>
</bill>
