<bill session="111" type="h" number="6562" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Residential Housing Recovery Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To revitalize home ownership by establishing a shared equity appreciation homeownership pilot program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400048"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/2010--Introduced.
American Residential Housing Recovery Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to carry out a shared equity appreciation financing pilot program to analyze the effectiveness of shared equity financing methods that stimulate the flow of private equity capital into the housing sector, while mitigating risk to borrowers. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for private investment in shared equity appreciation contracts. Amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to: (1) treat shared equity appreciation contracts as a consumer financial product; and (2) provide for regulatory oversight of shared equity appreciation contracts by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</summary>
</bill>
