<bill session="112" type="s" number="1017" updated="2013-07-20T02:25:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Disabled Veteran Caregiver Housing Assistance Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to increase assistance for disabled veterans who are temporarily residing in housing owned by a family member, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-08">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="117"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2011--Introduced.
Disabled Veteran Caregiver Housing Assistance Act of 2011 - Increases the amount of assistance authorized to be provided by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) for permanent and total service-disabled veterans who are temporarily residing in housing owned by a family member from: (1) $14,000 to $28,000, in the case of the acquisition of housing with special features; and (2) $2,000 to $5,000, in the case of adaptations to a current residence. Directs the Secretary to adjust such amounts annually based on the residential home cost-of-construction index. Removes a provision that prohibits providing such assistance after December 31, 2011. Expands the eligibility for specially adapted housing assistance provided by the Secretary for veterans with certain vision impairments. Removes certain limitations on the aggregate amount of assistance available for adapting and acquiring such housing for individuals residing temporarily in housing owned by a family member.</summary>
</bill>
