<bill session="111" type="h" number="1699" updated="2013-07-19T23:27:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patient Access to Critical Lab Tests Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require that certain complex diagnostic laboratory tests performed by an independent laboratory after a hospital outpatient encounter or inpatient stay during which the specimen involved was collected shall be treated as services for which payment may be made directly to the laboratory under part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="1220"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2009--Introduced.
Patient Access to Critical Lab Tests Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) where practical, Medicare regulations and policies should be written to promote development of and access to certain highly specialized laboratory tests; and (2) certain Medicare regulations should be revised to permit laboratories furnishing such tests to bill for and be paid directly by Medicare for furnishing them. Declares that, whenever a laboratory performs a covered complex diagnostic laboratory test, with respect to a specimen collected from an individual during a period in which the individual is a hospital patient, if the test is performed after such period, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall treat such test, for purposes of making direct payment to the laboratory, as if the specimen had been collected by the laboratory directly. Defines "covered complex diagnostic laboratory test" as: (1) an analysis of DNA, RNA, chromosomes, proteins, or metabolites that detects genotypes, mutations, chromosomal changes, biochemical changes, cell response, or gene expression or is a cancer chemotherapy sensitivity assay, with certain exceptions; (2) a diagnostic X-ray or other diagnostic test; (3) one developed and performed by a laboratory independent of the hospital in which the specimen involved was collected, and not under any arrangements with such hospital; and (4) one not furnished by such hospital, directly or under any arrangements made by it.</summary>
</bill>
