<bill session="111" type="sr" number="276" updated="2013-07-20T00:18:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-21">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution designating September 22, 2009, as "National Falls Prevention Awareness Day".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412328" joined="2009-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2009-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2009-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2009-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-09-21" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9615" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9615" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9591" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="sr" number="633"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/21/2009--Passed Senate without amendment.
Designates September 22, 2009, as National Falls Prevention Awareness Day. Commends the Falls Free Coalition Advocacy Work Group and the 22 state falls coalitions for their efforts to work together to increase education and awareness about the prevention of falls among older adults. Encourages: (1) businesses, individuals, governments, the public health community, and health care providers to work together to promote the awareness of and reduce the incidence of falls among older people in the United States; (2) state health departments to use their leadership to reduce injuries and injury-related health care costs by collaborating with colleagues, organizations, and individuals to reduce falls among older adults; and (3) experts in the field of fall prevention to share best practices. Urges the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to continue developing and evaluating interventions to prevent falls among older adults that can be used in effective community-based fall prevention programs.</summary>
</bill>
