<bill session="110" type="h" number="6619" updated="2013-07-19T22:01:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Savings for the Uninsured on Rx Expenses (SURE) Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a drug discount program for individuals without prescription drug coverage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400642"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2008--Introduced.
Savings for the Uninsured on Rx Expenses (SURE) Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a prescription drug discount card program modeled on the Medicare drug discount card program to provide access to prescription drug discounts for eligible individuals. Defines as "eligible" an individual who: (1) is a U.S. citizen, national, or alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence; (2) is not eligible for outpatient prescription drug coverage; and (3) is not eligible to enroll for prescription drug coverage under part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act. Applies the Medicare drug discount card program requirements related to enrollment and card features, with certain exceptions. Requires a prescription drug card sponsor to disseminate information concerning the use of health savings accounts to cover the costs of prescriptions drugs for which discounts are provided. Directs the Secretary to require that sponsors demonstrate that they have a marketing plan to effectively reach out to eligible individuals. Disallows judicial review of a determination not to endorse a prescription drug discount card program or not to enter into a contract with a sponsor.</summary>
</bill>
