<bill session="111" type="h" number="5250" updated="2013-07-19T23:59:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Election Assistance Commission to make an election administration improvement payment to the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands under title I of the Help America Vote Act of 2002, to treat the Commonwealth as a State for the other purposes of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412312"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2010--Introduced.
Directs the Election Assistance Commission to make a single payment to the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in an amount equal to the aggregate amount of the payments which would have been made to the Commonwealth under title I of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 for election administration improvement activities if: (1) the Commonwealth had been treated as a state at the time payments were made under such title to other states; and (2) the Commonwealth had been subject to the same minimum payment amounts applicable to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, and the United States Virgin Islands. Directs the Commonwealth to use such payment to carry out the same election administration improvement activities for which states received similar payments under the Help America Vote Act of 2002. Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to treat the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands as a state.</summary>
</bill>
