<bill session="109" type="h" number="3798" updated="2013-07-19T19:37:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Military Family Assistance Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 37, United States Code, to provide the Secretary of Defense with the authority to make temporary, emergency adjustments in the monthly rates of the basic allowance for housing and the cost-of-living allowance for members of the uniformed services in response to sudden increases in energy and gasoline prices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400157"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Public utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2005--Introduced.
Military Family Assistance Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to make an emergency adjustment in the rates of the basic allowance for housing in a particular military housing area in response to a sudden increase in energy costs resulting from higher charges for utilities or other causes. Allows such increase to remain in effect for up to six months. Requires the Secretary to notify Congress of such an adjustment and the reasons for such adjustment. Authorizes the Secretary to make an emergency adjustment in the cost-of-living allowance and establish temporary high cost areas during a fiscal year in response to a sudden increase in gasoline prices in an area. Provides the same six-month limitation and congressional notification requirement.</summary>
</bill>
