<bill session="112" type="s" number="54" updated="2013-07-20T02:17:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Supporting Child Maltreatment Prevention Efforts in Community Health Centers Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to implement demonstration projects at federally qualified community health centers to promote universal access to family centered, evidence-based behavior health interventions that prevent child maltreatment and promote family well-being by addressing parenting practices and skills for families from diverse socioeconomic, cultural, racial, ethnic, and other backgrounds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5841"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/2011--Introduced.
Supporting Child Maltreatment Prevention Efforts in Community Health Centers Act of 2011 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the National Center for Injury Prevention and Control of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to award grants to eligible federally qualified health centers to fund a minimum of 10 demonstration projects to promote: (1) universal access to family centered, evidence-based interventions that prevent child maltreatment by addressing parenting practices and skills; and (2) behavioral health and family well-being for families from diverse socioeconomic, cultural, racial, and ethnic backgrounds, including by addressing issues related to sexual orientation and individuals with disabilities. Sets forth permitted uses of grant funds, including to: (1) adapt and implement evidence-based parenting skills training programs for caregivers from all backgrounds who use the health center for health care and child well-visits; (2) adapt instruments and screen caregivers for child maltreatment risk factors such as depression, substance abuse, and intimate partner violence; and (3) provide access to mental health services to caregivers screened positive for child maltreatment risk factors. Requires the Secretary to award a contract for the provision of technical assistance, project coordination, and training for health care professionals for grantees under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
