<bill session="111" type="h" number="3980" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-10-12">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Redundancy Elimination and Enhanced Performance for Preparedness Grants Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Redundancy Elimination and Enhanced Performance for Preparedness Grants Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Redundancy Elimination and Enhanced Performance for Preparedness Grants Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Redundancy Elimination and Enhanced Performance for Preparedness Grants Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Redundancy Elimination and Enhanced Performance for Preparedness Grants Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Redundancy Elimination and Enhanced Performance for Preparedness Grants Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for identifying and eliminating redundant reporting requirements and developing meaningful performance metrics for homeland security preparedness grants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400657"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2009-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-03">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-11-17">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-12-01T18:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 111-346.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-12-01T18:41:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="199">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 199.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T13:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Cuellar moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T13:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13411-13413" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T13:16:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3980.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T13:22:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T17:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13427" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2009-12-02T17:09:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="922" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 414 - 0 (Roll no. 922).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H13411-13412" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-12-02T17:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-291.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="566">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 566.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2010-09-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7364-7365" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7364-7365" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cuellar moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7073-7075" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 3980.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2010-09-28T17:36:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7073-7074" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T17:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2010-09-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2010-10-12">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2010-10-12" type="public" number="111-271">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 111-271.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSHM12" subcommittee="Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/2010--Public Law.
Redundancy Elimination and Enhanced Performance for Preparedness Grants Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to submit to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 90 days after this Act's enactment a report that includes: (1) an assessment of redundant reporting requirements imposed by the Administrator on state, local, and tribal governments in connection with the awarding of covered grants; (2) a plan for eliminating any redundant and unnecessary reporting requirements identified; and (3) a plan for promptly developing a set of quantifiable performance measures and metrics to assess the effectiveness of the programs under which the grants are awarded. Defines "covered grants" as homeland security preparedness grants awarded under the Urban Area Security Initiative and the State Homeland Security Grant Program and other grants specified by the Administrator.Requires the Administrator to submit to such committees within one year after such report is required and every two years thereafter a grants management report that includes: (1) the status of efforts to eliminate such redundant and unnecessary reporting requirements; (2) the status of efforts to develop quantifiable performance measures and metrics; and (3) a performance assessment of each covered grant program.Directs the Administrator to: (1) enter into a contract for the National Academy of Public Administration to assist the Administrator in studying, developing, and implementing performance measures and metrics to assess the effectiveness of Department of Homeland Security (DHS) grants and the programs under which covered grants are awarded; and (2) report on the study's findings and recommendations within one year after such contract is awarded.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
