<bill session="109" type="s" number="2912" updated="2013-07-19T20:38:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Great Lakes Coordination and Oversight Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Great Lakes Coordination and Oversight Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish the Great Lakes Interagency Task Force, to establish the Great Lakes Regional Collaboration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2006-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2006-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2006-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2006-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-05-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe with an amendment. With written report No. 109-338.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="618">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 618.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2006--Reported to Senate amended.
Great Lakes Coordination and Oversight Act of 2006 - Establishes the Great Lakes Interagency Task Force, as created by Executive Order 13340, within the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). Establishes the Great Lakes Regional Collaboration, which shall draft a strategy every three years to describe the health of the Great Lakes and to identify Great Lakes restoration goals. Requires the the Collaboration's Executive Committee to: (1) establish a process for communicating with Collaboration members; (2) work with the Collaboration to develop its strategy; (3) develop a list of goals, identify the level of government that is best able to achieve them, hold semiannual public meetings to discuss them, and receive input relating to them from stakeholder groups; (4) submit to Congress and the Task Force a biennial report on progress in carrying out the restoration and meeting the Collaboration's goals and recommendations and on contributions made by Great Lakes states, municipal partners, and Great Lakes Tribes; and (5) ensure that the Collaboration has balanced representation of stakeholder groups and that its strategy is coordinated with the activities of the Lake Chaplain Basin Program. Adds as duties of the Task Force to: (1) ensure that implementation of its programs is coordinated, effective, and cost-efficient; (2) submit to Congress a biennial report that describes the Collaboration's activities; (3) establish a regular means of communication with the Collaboration's Executive Committee to exchange information and recommendations for action; and (4) ensure that its activities are coordinated with Lake Chaplain Basin Program activities. Requires the Administrator of the EPA to evaluate each committee of which the Administrator is a member and office within EPA's jurisdiction that oversees a Great Lakes program to identify overlapping duties and to develop recommendations to improve the efficiency of those committees and offices.</summary>
</bill>
