<bill session="112" type="h" number="3559" updated="2013-07-20T01:40:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Insurance Data Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit the Federal Insurance Office of the Department of the Treasury and other financial regulators from collecting data directly from an insurance company.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412461"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2012-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412484" joined="2012-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2012-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-16">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity Prior to Introduction.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Prior to referral, consideration and markup held by the Subcommitte on Insurance, Housing, and Community Opportunity. Forwarded favorably by a yea and nay vote of 7-5 by the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings, Markup" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG16" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities and Risk Management" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2011--Introduced.
Insurance Data Protection Act - Repeals the subpoena and enforcement powers of the Director of the Federal Insurance Office in the Department of the Treasury. Declares that the sharing of any nonpublicly available data with or by the Office among other federal agencies, the state insurance regulators and their collective agents, or other entities does not affect any federal or state confidentiality privilege arising under federal or state law to which such data or information is otherwise subject. Amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to exempt an insurance company from the subpoena powers of the Director of the Office of Financial Research in the Treasury. Prescribes the treatment of data collected by financial regulators from a nonbank financial company that is an insurance company, including confidentiality procedures and agency disclosure requirements.</summary>
</bill>
