<bill session="111" type="s" number="1089" updated="2013-07-20T00:33:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to facilitate the export of United States agricultural commodities and products to Cuba as authorized by the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000, to establish an agricultural export promotion program with respect to Cuba, to remove impediments to the export to Cuba of medical devices and medicines, to allow travel to Cuba by United States citizens and legal residents, to establish an agricultural export promotion program with respect to Cuba, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2009-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2009-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2009-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5704"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="1531"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4645"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3112"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2009--Introduced.
Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2009 - Prohibits the President from restricting direct transfers from a Cuban depository institution to a U.S. depository institution in payment for a product or agricultural commodity authorized for sale under the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to provide information and technical assistance to U.S. agricultural producers, cooperative organizations, or state agencies to promote U.S. agricultural exports products to Cuba. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase the airport ticket tax for transportation between the United States and Cuba by $1; and (2) establish in the Treasury the Agricultural Export Promotion Trust Fund. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State should issue temporary entry visas to Cuban nationals whose itinerary documents an intent to conduct activities, including phytosanitary inspections, relating to the purchase of U.S. agricultural commodities or products. Amends the Democracy Act of 1992 to repeal the requirement for onsite verification of certain medical exports to Cuba. Prohibits the President from regulating or prohibiting travel to or from Cuba by U.S. citizens or legal residents, or any of the transactions incident to such travel. States that: (1) any regulation restricting or prohibiting such travel shall have no effect; and (2) such prohibition shall not apply in time of war or armed hostilities between the United States and Cuba, or of imminent danger to the public health or the physical safety of U.S. citizens or legal residents. Amends the Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 to repeal the prohibition on enforcement of rights to certain U.S. intellectual properties and such properties' transfer.</summary>
</bill>
