<bill session="109" type="s" number="742" updated="2013-07-19T20:19:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Preservation of Antibiotics for Medical Treatment Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to preserve the effectiveness of medically important antibiotics used in the treatment of human and animal diseases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2005-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2005-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2005-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2005-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3407-3408"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="2562"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Antibiotics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drug resistance in microorganisms"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family farms"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Medicated feeds"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Small farms"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/2005--Introduced.
Preservation of Antibiotics for Medical Treatment Act of 2005 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to deny an application for a new animal drug that is a critical antimicrobial animal drug unless the applicant demonstrates that there is a reasonably certainty of no harm to human health due to the development of antimicrobial resistance attributable to the nontherapeutic use of the drug. Defines "critical antimicrobial animal drug" as a drug intended for use in food-producing animals that contains specified antibiotics or other drugs used in humans to treat or prevent disease or infection caused by microorganisms. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to withdraw approval of a nontherapeutic use of such drugs in food-producing animals two years after the date of enactment of this Act unless certain safety requirements are met. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to make payments to livestock or poultry producers to defray the costs of reducing the use of such drugs, with priority given to family-owned or small farms and ranches. Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to award grants to colleges and universities to establish programs to phase out the nontherapeutic use of such drugs in livestock or poultry. Requires the manufacturer of such a drug or an animal feed for food-producing animals containing such a drug to report sales information to the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</summary>
</bill>
