<bill session="109" type="s" number="1320" updated="2013-07-19T20:25:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Multilateral Debt Relief Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide multilateral debt cancellation for Heavily Indebted Poor Countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300020" joined="2005-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2005-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400621" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="2005-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7525-7526"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-06-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="3191"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Debt agreements"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2005--Introduced.
Multilateral Debt Relief Act of 2005 - Authorizes: (1) the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. executive director of each international financial institution (the World Bank, the International Monetary Fund, the Inter-American Development Bank, the African Development Bank, and the African Development Fund) to reach an agreement among the shareholders to permanently cancel 100 percent of the debts owed to each such institution by an eligible country (as defined by this Act); and (2) appropriations for the U.S. contribution to such agreement if other members of the international financial institutions contribute funds for such purpose. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary should pursue additional bilateral and multilateral debt relief for each country eligible for International Development Association grants. Amends the International Development Association Act to authorize, and authorize appropriations for, the U.S. Governor of the Association to contribute necessary sums to the fourteenth replenishment of the Association. Amends the African Development Fund Act to authorize, and authorize appropriations for, The U.S. Governor of the Fund to contribute necessary sums to the tenth replenishment of the Fund. Authorizes appropriations to fulfill U.S. commitments to the Enhanced HIPC Initiative (as defined by this Act).</summary>
</bill>
