<bill session="111" type="h" number="5961" updated="2013-07-20T00:06:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medical-Legal Partnership for Health Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a demonstration project to award grants to, and enter into contracts with, medical-legal partnerships to assist patients and their families to navigate health-related programs and activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412228" joined="2010-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3668"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2010--Introduced.
Medical-Legal Partnership for Health Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a nationwide demonstration project to: (1) award matching grants or enter into contracts with medical-legal partnerships to assist patients and their families in navigating health-related programs and activities; and (2) evaluate the effectiveness of such partnerships. Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance to grantees to support the establishment and sustainability of medical-legal partnerships. Requires amounts received under this Act to be used to achieve one or more of the following goals: (1) enhancing access to health care services; (2) improving health outcomes for low-income individuals; (3) reducing health disparities among health disparities populations; (4) enhancing wellness and prevention of chronic conditions and other health problems; (5) reducing cost of care to the health care system; (6) addressing the social determinants of health; and (7) addressing situational factors that contribute to poor health, such as poor housing. Prohibits funds under this Act from being used: (1) for any medical malpractice action or proceeding; (2) to provide any state or local public benefit to an alien who is not a qualified alien or a nonimmigrant under the Immigration and Nationality Act or an alien who is paroled into the United States under such Act for less than one year; or (3) to provide legal assistance with respect to any proceeding or litigation which seeks to procure an abortion or to compel any individual or institution to perform or assist in the performance of an abortion. Requires the Secretary to study and report to Congress on the results of such project.</summary>
</bill>
