<bill session="113" type="s" number="1087" updated="2013-11-02T07:01:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Education Through Technology Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to award grants to encourage State educational agencies, local educational agencies, and schools to utilize technology to improve student achievement and college and career readiness, the skills of teachers and school leaders, and the efficiency and productivity of education systems at all levels.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2013-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="521"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/2013--Introduced.
Enhancing Education Through Technology Act of 2013 - Replaces part D (Enhancing Education Through Technology) of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) with a new part D (Achievement Through Technology and Innovation). Directs the Secretary of Education (under new subpart 1 [Technology Readiness and Access] of part D) to award matching grants to states and, through them, subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to strengthen state and local technological infrastructure and professional development that supports digital learning. Allocates grant funds among states in proportion to each state's share of school improvement funds under part A of title I of the ESEA. Requires states to use at least 90% of their grant to award subgrants to LEAs. Requires LEAs to use: (1) at least 40% of those funds to support the acquisition of technology that addresses their technology infrastructure and access needs, and (2) at least 35% of those funds for professional development for digital learning. Allows states to form purchasing consortia with other states, and allows LEAs to form purchasing consortia with other LEAs, to carry out grant and subgrant activities, including the purchase of technology. Directs the Secretary (under new subpart 2 [Technology for Tomorrow Fund] of part D) to award renewable, competitive grants to eligible partnerships to improve student achievement, academic growth, and college-and-career readiness through the use of technology and digital learning. Defines an "eligible partnership" as a partnership that includes at least one high-need LEA and at least one state, LEA or educational service agency, institution of higher education, nonprofit or community-based organization, or business or for-profit organization. Requires partnerships to use their grants to carry out activities that utilize technology and digital learning to: (1) promote personalized, individualized instruction; (2) improve teacher and school leader preparation, professional development, knowledge, skills, practice, and professional capacity; (3) ensure all students equitable access to high-quality curriculum, instruction, assessments, technology, and digital learning; and (4) improve educational efficiency and productivity. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish partnership performance measures, (2) contract with an outside entity to evaluate the grant program and identify effective practices for improving student outcomes, (3) disseminate and provide technical assistance to LEAs and states on best practices in utilizing technology and digital learning for student advancement, and (4) ensure that the Department of Education applies those best practices to other innovation fund programs.</summary>
</bill>
