<bill session="110" type="s" number="2994" updated="2013-07-19T22:47:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Great Lakes Legacy Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Great Lakes Legacy Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to provide for the remediation of sediment contamination in areas of concern.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2008-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-05-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 110-488.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1059">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1059.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sedimentation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Great Lakes Legacy Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to include among activities that the Great Lakes National Program Office is authorized to carry out for the remediation of sediment contamination in areas of concern: (1) demonstration or pilot projects that use innovative approaches, technologies, or techniques for the remediation of sediment contamination; and (2) activities to restore aquatic habitat after remediation. Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to provide additional consideration to projects that are funded by potentially responsible parties (individuals or entities that may be liable under federal or state environmental remediation laws with respect to a project carried out under such Act) and determined to be of greater environmental significance than competing proposals. Revises provisions concerning the nonfederal share of the costs of such projects. Authorizes the Administrator, Acting through the Program Office, to enter into agreements with nonfederal sponsors to implement projects under which such sponsors may pay in advance their share of the project costs and receive reimbursement for such costs from the Administrator. Requires the Administrator to implement a public information and participation program relating to the remediation of contaminated sediment in areas of concern in the United States.Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2013 for: (1) such remediation; (2) the public information and participation program; and (3) research on the development and use of innovative approaches, technologies, and techniques for such remediation.</summary>
</bill>
