<bill session="113" type="h" number="2518" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Truth in Spending Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the long-term fiscal accountability of direct spending legislation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412421"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2013-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2013-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2401"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2013--Introduced.
Truth in Spending Act of 2013 - Requires the President's annual budget request to Congress to include the most recent reports of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) regarding the difference between the actual costs and the estimated costs of direct spending legislation, including proposed legislative language, if any, in such reports. Requires OMB to submit annually for inclusion in the President's budget request reports (with follow-up reports every five fiscal years) on the total estimated cost and total actual cost of direct spending legislation for the then budget year and four outyears. Requires the President, within seven days after receiving an OMB report, to submit proposed legislative language, if any, set forth in the report to both chambers. Prescribes the procedure for fast track consideration of the legislation in both chambers. Prohibits the budgetary effects of such legislation from being entered on either PAYGO scorecard under the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</summary>
</bill>
