<bill session="112" type="h" number="6449" updated="2013-07-20T02:05:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Air Travelers' Bill of Rights Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish an air travelers' bill of rights, to implement those rights, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412424" joined="2012-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Transportation Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="112" type="s" number="3302"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2012--Introduced.
Air Travelers' Bill of Rights Act of 2012 - Directs the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration [TSA]) to: (1) establish an air travelers' bill of rights for air passengers screened at primary airports, and (2) post it on the TSA website and display signs and distribute brochures listing such rights to passengers before they are screened. Requires the air travelers' bill of rights to include, at a minimum, that a passenger has the right to: (1) presumed innocence before, during, and after screening; (2) be screened expeditiously if verified by the TSA as a low-risk or frequent traveler; (3) decline to be screened by a device that uses backscatter x-rays; (4) freedom from searches and screening procedures not implemented for cause or suspicion; (5) be screened by a method other than a pat-down; (6) accompany minor children through the screening process; (7) privacy of any image of the passenger generated during the screening process; and (8) peacefully express his or her concerns of mistreatment during the screening process to the supervisor of the individual conducting the screening. Transfers from the Under Secretary of Transportation for Security (DOT) to the Assistant Secretary the authority to approve any application of an airport operator to have the screening of passengers and property at an airport be carried out by the screening personnel of a qualified private screening company (security screening opt-out program). Requires the Assistant Secretary to approve all such applications. Directs the Assistant Secretary to take necessary actions to expand TSA's expedited screening initiative (PreCheck program). Directs the Assistant Secretary to increase the number of canines from the TSA's National Explosives Detection Canine Team Program, placed at commercial service airports with more than 2.5 million passenger boardings each year, to a number sufficient to ensure at least one canine team can be tasked exclusively for screening passengers. Prohibits the use of random computer-generated screening of air passengers at commercial service airports. Directs the Assistant Secretary to prescribe regulations to: (1) limit the screening of passengers through use of pat-downs; and (2) ensure that the screening of passengers wearing a prosthetic limb, a breast pump, adult diapers, a wheelchair, an insulin pump, or any other medical device is done in a private area out of view of other passengers if requested. Requires termination of any TSA or private security screener who commits a gross violation of the privacy of a passenger in a manner not supported by TSA policy. Amends the Support Anti-terrorism by Fostering Effective Technologies Act of 2002 to exclude from its liability protections against claims arising out of, or resulting from, an act of terrorism the manufacturers of advanced imaging technology or any technology developed or acquired after enactment of this Act for the screening of passengers. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to take all appropriate actions to implement any elements of the air travelers' bill of rights that are not currently included in TSA policies and practices. Directs the Assistant Secretary to provide a Passenger Privacy Protection Award to an eligible airport and individual for improving the privacy of passengers at airports each year. Prescribes requirements for the distribution of unclaimed money recovered at airport security checkpoints.</summary>
</bill>
