<bill session="113" type="h" number="1892" updated="2013-11-02T06:34:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unlocking Technology Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 1201 of title 17, United States Code, to require the infringement of a copyright for a violation of such section, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400245"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412503" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2013--Introduced.
Unlocking Technology Act of 2013 - Amends the prohibition under federal copyright law on the circumvention of a technological measure that controls access to a copyright-protected work to require that such prohibition apply only to circumventions carried out in order to infringe or facilitate infringement of a protected work. Declares that it shall not be a violation to: (1) circumvent a technological measure if the purpose is to engage in a use that is not an infringement of federal copyright law; or (2) use, manufacture, import, offer to the public, provide, or otherwise traffic in any technology, product, service, device, component, or part primarily designed or produced to facilitate noninfringing uses of protected works by circumventing a technological measure that effectively controls access to such work, unless the intent is to infringe or facilitate infringement of a copyright. Declares that it is not an infringement to copy or adapt the software or firmware of a user-purchased mobile communications device for the sole purpose of enabling the device to connect to a wireless communications network if: (1) the copying or adapting is initiated by, or with the consent of, the owner of that device or the owner's agent; (2) the owner or agent is in legal possession of the device; and (3) the owner has the consent of, or an agreement with, the authorized operator of such wireless communications network to make use of its network. (Thus allowing the "unlocking" of mobile devices without requiring an owner to obtain the consent of the initial carrier network before switching to a new carrier.) Directs the President to ensure that applicable bilateral and multilateral trade agreements are modified to be consistent with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
