<bill session="111" type="h" number="3099" updated="2013-07-19T23:39:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Travelers Bill of Rights Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require a site operator of an international travel Web site to provide information on its Web site to consumers regarding the potential health and safety risks associated with overseas vacation destinations marketed on its Web site.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412279" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2009-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2009--Introduced.
International Travelers Bill of Rights Act of 2009 - Defines "site operator" as an individual or entity that operates a website providing access to international travel services, including an overseas vacation destination or a third party that operates a website offering international travel services. Requires a site operator to provide information in a clear and conspicuous way on its website regarding the health and safety risks of overseas vacation destinations marketed on the site, including the onsite health and safety services available and, if those services are not available 24 hours a day, the hours the services are available, if known. Requires a site operator to: (1) establish a process under which an overseas vacation destination will be suspended from its website as a result of consumer complaints regarding poor medical care, unsafe or unsanitary facilities, or other health-related issues; and (2) make all such complaints publicly available on its website. Allows an operator to modify complaints at the request of the complainant and to remove offensive language and personal identification. Treats a violation as an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under the Federal Trade Commission Act.</summary>
</bill>
