<bill session="113" type="s" number="854" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEM Education for the Global Economy Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve student academic achievement in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/25/2013--Introduced.
STEM Education for the Global Economy Act of 2013 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to replace the Mathematics and Science Partnerships program with a STEM Education program. Directs the Secretary of Education to implement that program by allotting formula grants to states and, through them, awarding competitive subgrants to high-need local educational agencies (LEAs) or educational service agencies serving such LEAs to improve preschool and elementary and secondary school science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) education. Allots such grants to states pursuant to a formula that takes into account each state's share of elementary and secondary school students and each state's share of such students who are impoverished. Directs the Secretary to use program appropriations that exceed a specified amount in a fiscal year to award STEM education grants to states on a competitive basis. Authorizes the Secretary to award capacity-building grants to states to help them qualify for competitive grants. Requires subgrants to be used for activities that include: (1) recruiting, supporting, evaluating, and training STEM teachers; (2) developing and improving high-quality STEM curricula and instructional supports to improve student achievement in those subjects; and (3) integrating STEM instruction with instruction in reading, English language arts, or other academic subjects. Authorizes states to require subgrantees to obtain a commitment from one or more outside partners to match, from nonfederal funds, a portion of the subgrant funds. Directs the Secretary to award to partnerships between states or LEAs and outside entities experienced in improving the effectiveness or retention of STEM teachers competitive grants to establish and operate STEM master teacher corps programs. Requires the partnerships to: (1) select a group of highly-rated STEM teachers to serve as corps members in high-need schools; (2) provide corps members with instructional leadership responsibilities, research-based training, and a salary supplement; and (3) build a community of practice among corps members. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, to establish performance metrics and use those metrics to evaluate this Act's programs and identify best practices to improve STEM instruction.</summary>
</bill>
