<bill session="110" type="s" number="3524" updated="2013-07-19T22:52:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeland Security and Law Enforcement Improvements Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to improve the Office for State and Local Law Enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9034-9035"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9035-9036" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2008--Introduced.
Homeland Security and Law Enforcement Improvements Act of 2008 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to reassign to the Office of the Secretary of Homeland Security the Office for State and Local Law Enforcement (Office). Establishes within the Office: (1) the Law Enforcement Information Sharing Resource Center to provide technical assistance relating to information sharing and intelligence; (2) the Foreign Liaison Officers Against Terrorism Program; and (3) the Commercial Equipment Direct Assistance Program to make counterterrorism technology, equipment, and information available to local law enforcement agencies. Directs the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security for State and Local Law Enforcement to establish a National Law Enforcement Deployment Team Program to respond to the threat or occurrence of a natural or man-made incident.Authorizes the Assistant Secretary to make grants to states and local governments for law enforcement terrorism prevention activities.</summary>
</bill>
