<bill session="109" type="h" number="5963" updated="2013-07-19T19:57:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Close the Revolving Door Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To modify certain post-employment restrictions with respect to officers and employees of the Department of Homeland Security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2006-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2006-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2006-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2006-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2006-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2006-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2006-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2006--Introduced.
Close the Revolving Door Act - Amends the federal criminal code to specify that the one-year post-employment prohibition against certain senior executive agency personnel making communications or appearances to influence the agency in which such person served within the year before their service terminated shall apply to former Department of Homeland Security (DHS) employees who served in DHS at any time during the year before their service terminated. Prohibits DHS or any agency thereof from requesting a waiver of such restriction. Prohibits any agency, bureau, or other entity of DHS from being designated as a separate agency or bureau for purposes of such prohibition. Makes certain post-employment restrictions on former executive branch officers and employees applicable to persons who make a communication or appearance on behalf of a former DHS officer or employee.</summary>
</bill>
