<bill session="109" type="s" number="538" updated="2013-07-19T20:18:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Professionals Substance Abuse Education Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to educate health professionals concerning substance use disorders and addiction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2162"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2162-2164" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="1789"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Dentists"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug addiction"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marriage counseling"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medication abuse"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Physicians' assistants"/>
    <term name="Psychologists"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/7/2005--Introduced.
Health Professionals Substance Abuse Education Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide support and continue grants to specified organizations to train health professionals to: (1) recognize substance abuse in their patients or patients' family members; (2) intervene, treat, or refer for treatment those individuals who are affected by substance abuse; (3) identify and assist children of substance abusing parents; (4) serve as advocates and resources for community-based substance abuse prevention programs; and (5) address the non-therapeutic use of prescription medications. Directs the Secretary to: (1) encourage community colleges and other academic institutes to offer academic credit for classes offered by the Addiction Technology Transfer Centers; (2) conduct a process and outcome evaluation of the programs and activities carried out under this Act; and (3) establish and administer a substance abuse faculty fellowship program. Requires the Secretary to establish centers of excellence at U.S. medical centers or universities to: (1) initiate, promote, and implement training, research, and clinical activities related to targeted issues or special areas of focus; and (2) provide opportunities for interdisciplinary collaboration in curriculum development, course development, clinical practice, research and translation of research into practice, and policy analysis and formulation.</summary>
</bill>
