<bill session="109" type="s" number="347" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Advance Directives Improvement and Education Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act and title III of the Public Health Service Act to improve access to information about individuals' health care operations and legal rights for care near the end of life, to promote advance care planning and decisionmaking so that individuals' wishes are known should they become unable to speak for themselves, to engage health care providers in disseminating information about and assisting in the preparation of advance directives, which include living wills and durable powers of attorney for health care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2005-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2005-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2005-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2005-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300028" joined="2005-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2005-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2005-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300068" joined="2005-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2005-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2005-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2005-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1274-1275"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1275-1277" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="2058"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="570"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Living wills"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Pain"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Power of attorney"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Terminal care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2005--Introduced.
Advance Directives Improvement and Education Act of 2005 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, to provide for Medicare coverage of end-of-life planning consultations. Requires a service provider, Medicare Advantage organization, or prepaid or eligible organization to give effect to an advance directive executed outside the State in which it is presented, even one that does not appear to meet the formalities of execution, form, or language required by the State in which it is presented, to the same extent as such provider or organization would give effect to an advanced directive that meets such requirements. Permits a provider or organization to decline to honor such a directive if the provider or organization can reasonably demonstrate that it is not an authentic expression of the individual's wishes concerning his or her health care. Makes such advance directive requirements applicable under Medicaid, title XIX of the Social Security Act. Amends the Public Health Service Act to provide for grant programs to increase awareness of advance directive planning issues. Directs the Secretary to conduct a national public education campaign to: (1) raise public awareness of the importance of planning for care near the end of life; (2) improve the public's understanding of the various situations in which individuals may find themselves if they become unable to express their health care wishes; (3) explain the need for readily available legal documents that express an individual's wishes, through advance directives (including living wills, comfort care orders, and durable powers of attorney for health care); and (4) educate the public about the availability of hospice care and palliative care. Directs the Secretary to provide for the establishment of a national, toll-free, information clearinghouse as well as clearinghouses that the public may access to find out about State-specific information regarding advance directive and end-of-life decisions. Requires General Accounting Office studies and reports on end-of-life planning issues.</summary>
</bill>
