<bill session="111" type="s" number="1559" updated="2013-07-20T00:37:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">NATO-Western Balkans Support Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to consolidate democracy and security in the Western Balkans by supporting the Governments and people of Bosnia and Herzegovina and Montenegro in reaching their goal of eventual NATO membership, and to welcome further NATO partnership with the Republic of Serbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2009-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2009-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2009-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2009-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Montenegro"/>
    <term name="Serbia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2009--Introduced.
NATO-Western Balkans Support Act of 2009 - States that Congress supports the commitment to further enlargement of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to include Bosnia and Herzegovina and Montenegro. Expresses the sense of Congress that the existing position of political advisor within the NATO Mission in Sarajevo should be filled by an ambassadorial-level U.S. diplomat as senior civilian representative to the NATO Mission in Sarajevo. Deems Bosnia and Herzegovina and Montenegro as eligible to receive assistance under the NATO Participation Act of 1994. States that such designation: (1) is in addition to the designation of Poland, Hungary, the Czech Republic, and Slovenia pursuant to the NATO Enlargement Facilitation Act of 1996, the designation of Romania, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, and Bulgaria pursuant to the European Security Act of 1998, and the designation of Slovakia pursuant to the Gerald B. H. Solomon Freedom Consolidation Act of 2002, and the designation of the Republic of Albania, the Republic of Croatia, Georgia, the Republic of Macedonia (FYROM), and Ukraine pursuant to the NATO Freedom Consolidation Act of 2007 as eligible to receive assistance under the NATO Participation Act of 1994; and (2) shall not preclude the designation by the President of other countries as eligible to receive assistance under the NATO Participation Act of 1994. Authorizes FY2010 appropriations under the Arms Export Control Act for assistance to Bosnia and Herzegovina and Montenegro.</summary>
</bill>
