<bill session="111" type="s" number="577" updated="2013-07-20T00:28:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Immigration Fraud Prevention Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to provide penalties for individuals who engage in schemes to defraud aliens and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2009-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3075"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3075-3076" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="1992"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2009--Introduced.
Immigration Fraud Prevention Act of 2009 - Amends the federal criminal code to subject a person to fine, imprisonment, or both, who: (1) willfully and knowingly executes a scheme in connection with any federal immigration law-related matter to defraud a person, or to obtain money or anything else of value from a person by means of false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises; or (2) willfully, knowingly, and falsely represents that such person is an attorney or an accredited representative in any federal immigration law-related matter. Directs the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) use the Executive Office of Immigration Review to investigate such immigration fraud crimes; and (2) educate immigrant communities about who may provide legal services and representation in immigration proceedings. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require that: (1) aliens in removal proceedings be provided with a description of who may represent them, including notice that immigration consultants, visa consultants, and other unauthorized individuals may not provide such representation; and (2) the Attorney General provide for lists of persons who are prohibited from providing representation in immigration proceedings.</summary>
</bill>
