<bill session="111" type="h" number="4709" updated="2013-07-19T23:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">E 2 for Innovation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Engineering Education for Innovation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To award planning grants and implementation grants to State educational agencies to enable the State educational agencies to complete comprehensive planning to carry out activities designed to integrate engineering education into K-12 instruction and curriculum and to provide evaluation grants to measure efficacy of K-12 engineering education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412319"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412257" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2010-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412188" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412204" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2010-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2010-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2010-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400437" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="3043"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2010--Introduced.
Engineering Education for Innovation Act or E 2 for Innovation Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award planning grants and matching implementation grants to states to integrate engineering education into kindergarten through grade 12 (K-12) instruction and curricula. Requires each state that desires an implementation grant to develop quantifiable benchmarks for activities supported by such grants and submit them to the Secretary for approval. Requires states to use implementation grants to: (1) establish assessment tools and challenging academic content and achievement standards for engineering education; (2) develop or obtain effective engineering education curricula; (3) develop or improve engineering teacher training programs; (4) recruit qualified engineering teachers for needy schools; (5) facilitate distance learning and online education in engineering; and (6) invest in after-school engineering education programs. Directs the Institute of Education Sciences to support engineering education research and an evaluation of this Act's grant programs. Requires the Secretary to use the evaluation's findings to provide information to the public and technical assistance to states on best practices and promising innovations in K-12 engineering education.</summary>
</bill>
