<bill session="113" type="h" number="2276" updated="2013-11-02T06:38:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Virgin Valley Tourism and Lake Mead Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote economic development and to preserve the Lake Mead Area in Clark County, Nevada, in order to conserve, protect, and enhance the cultural, archaeological, natural, wilderness, scientific, geological, historical, biological, wildlife, educational, and scenic resources of the area, to designate wilderness areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412559"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2013-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1744"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1054"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/6/2013--Introduced.
Virgin Valley Tourism and Lake Mead Preservation Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to establish a visitor center and field office in Mesquite, Nevada, to: (1) serve visitors; and (2) assist in fulfilling the purposes of the Lake Mead National Recreation Area, the Grand Canyon-Parashant National Monument, and the Gold Butte National Conservation Area established by this Act. Requires completion of a study regarding local renewable energy development. Amends the Mesquite Lands Act of 1986 to require proceeds from sales of parcels of public lands in Mesquite, Nevada, to be used for implementation of a multispecies habitat conservation plan for the Virgin River in Clark County, Nevada, including any associated groundwater monitoring plan. Extends until November 29, 2021, the withdrawal of public land parcels in the fifth and sixth areas of Mesquite and the related purchase authority of the city of Mesquite for the fifth area. Requires: (1) implementation of a plan to provide for local boat access to Lake Mead; and (2) a study of existing, designated routes outside the Conservation Area for designation as an Off-Highway Vehicle Trail. Authorizes the Secretary to designate such a Trail one year after completion of the study. Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) the Virgin Valley Tourism and Economic Advisory Council, and (2) the Gold Butte National Conservation Area Advisory Council. Establishes the Gold Butte National Conservation Area in Nevada. Directs the Secretary to develop a management plan for the long-term protection and management of the Area. Designates specified wilderness areas administered by the National Park Service (NPS) or the BLM in Clark County as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. States that the withdrawal of certain BLM lands for use by the Bureau of Reclamation is terminated. Directs the Secretary to credit specified multiple use lands toward the development of additional non-federal land within Clark County. Requires the Conservation Area and the BLM wilderness areas designated by this Act to be administered as components of the National Landscape Conservation System.</summary>
</bill>
