<bill session="111" type="s" number="1093" updated="2013-07-20T00:33:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oil Independence, Limiting Subsidies, and Accelerating Vehicle Efficiency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">OILSAVE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax incentives for increasing motor vehicle fuel efficiency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5704-5706"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5708-5710" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2009--Introduced.
Oil Independence, Limiting Subsidies, and Accelerating Vehicle Efficiency Act or the OILSAVE Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a new tax credit for the purchase of fuel-efficient motor vehicles; (2) allow a business-related tax credit for the installation of fuel savings components in motor vehicles; and (3) revise the gas guzzler tax for automobiles with fuel economy ratings of less than 24.2 miles per gallon of gasoline (or equivalent amount of other fuel) consumed. Increases civil penalties for violations of manufacturer corporate average fuel economy (CAFE) standards. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to require: (1) the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to implement a program to support deployment of low-greenhouse gas and fuel-saving technologies; and (2) the Secretary of Commerce to define and collect data on characteristics of the U.S. truck fleet, with emphasis on data relating to fuel efficiency and greenhouse gas performance.</summary>
</bill>
