<bill session="110" type="h" number="500" updated="2013-07-19T21:08:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that pay for Members of Congress be reduced following any fiscal year in which there is a Federal deficit.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400099"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400016" joined="2007-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2007-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="2007-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2007-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2007-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="2007-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2007-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2007-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="2007-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2007-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2007-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-16">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/2007--Introduced.
Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2007 - Provides that, if there is a deficit in a fiscal year, then: (1) any pay adjustment (including a cost of living adjustment) for Members of Congress scheduled to take effect in the succeeding calendar year shall be null and void; and (2) rates of pay for Members shall be reduced by a specified percentage, but not below zero. Specifies the mandatory pay rate reduction at: (1) 5%, for the first year; or (2) 10%, for any consecutive subsequent year that expenditures exceed revenues. Specifies conditions for restoration of the original pay rate, together with otherwise scheduled adjustments. Vests authority in the Director of the Congressional Budget Office to make determinations of whether or not a deficit exists in any fiscal year. States that, in making any such determination, the Director shall exclude any budget outlays which directly relate to a military conflict that lasts over 30 days or that is in direct response to a terrorist attack on the United States.</summary>
</bill>
