<bill session="111" type="h" number="4979" updated="2013-07-19T23:57:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapters 83 and 84 of title 5, United States Code, to provide for the indexation of deferred annuities; to provide that a survivor annuity be provided to the widow or widower of a former employee who dies after separating from Government service with title to a deferred annuity under the Civil Service Retirement System but before establishing a valid claim therefor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2010-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E481"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO25" subcommittee="Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/2010--Introduced.
Amends federal civil service law to provide for the indexation of deferred annuities, including survivor annuities, under the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) and the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS) and for individuals becoming subject to FERS by election.Terminates the entitlement of a survivor who remarries before age 55 (currently, who remarries at any age) to an annuity based on the service of a deferred annuitant who dies before establishing a valid claim for a CSRS annuity.</summary>
</bill>
