<bill session="110" type="s" number="1368" updated="2013-07-19T22:32:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Denali Commission Act Amendments Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Denali Commission Act of 1998 to modify the authority of the Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6018"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-05-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/2007--Introduced.
Denali Commission Act Amendments Act of 2007 - Amends the Denali Commission Act of 1998 to provide that no member of the Commission, other than the Federal Co-chairperson, shall be considered to be a federal employee. Authorizes the Commission to accept, use, and dispose of matching funds provided by public and private sources for projects approved by the Commission.Provides that each Commission member who is not a federal employee may elect to waive compensation. Authorizes (current law requires) the Federal Co-chairperson to appoint an Economic Development Committee consisting of specified representatives. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to make direct lump sum payments to the Commission to be used to carry out a training program on careers associated with infrastructure development and long-term stability in rural Alaska. Requires the program to focus on: (1) training for construction, operations, and maintenance of Commission projects; (2) management training relating to the operation of Commission projects; (3) initiatives for Alaskan youths to encourage careers that support Commission projects; and (4) training for construction, operations, and maintenance for public infrastructure projects.Directs the Commission to provide assistance to address the housing needs of teachers in rural Alaska. Authorizes the Commission to assist in housing development activities.Authorizes appropriations through FY2014.</summary>
</bill>
