<bill session="109" type="s" number="3891" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">James Zadroga Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to extend the time for filing certain claims under the September 11th Victim Compensation Fund of 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2006-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2006-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2006-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9366-9367"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-12">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9367" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="565"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="6045"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2006--Introduced.
James Zadroga Act of 2006 - Amends the September 11th Victim Compensation Fund of 2001 (Fund), part of the Air Transportation Safety and System Stabilization Act, to extend the current December 22, 2003, deadline for filing claims under the Fund for five years following enactment of this Act if the Special Master determines that the individual: (1) was unaware that he or she had suffered physical harm as the result of the September 11, 2001, terrorist-related aircraft crashes until after the deadline and before enactment of this Act; (2) was unaware of his or her eligibility to file a claim until after December 22, 2003; (3) suffered psychological harm as a result of the crashes; or (4) in the case of an individual who had previously filed a claim, suffered a significantly greater physical harm than was known to the individual as of the date the claim was filed, but did not know its full extent until after the claim was filed and before enactment of this Act. Allows the filing of a claim also during the five years after the individual first knew that he or she had suffered physical or psychological harm as the result of such crashes, if he or she did not know that until on or after enactment of this Act. Extends the same five-year filing allowance to anyone who did not know the full extent of the harm suffered until on or after the enactment of this Act, even though he or she had previously filed a claim and had suffered a significantly greater physical or psychological harm than was known to the individual as of the date the claim was filed. Waives the single claim requirement in such circumstances. Makes a claimant eligible for compensation based on the psychological harm suffered as a result of the crashes. Defines "immediate aftermath" for compensation eligibility purposes as any period of time after the crashes that was sufficiently close in time to them that there was a demonstrable risk to the claimant of resulting physical or psychological harm, including the period of time during which related rescue, recovery, and cleanup activities were conducted.</summary>
</bill>
