<bill session="109" type="s" number="1056" updated="2013-07-19T20:22:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Southern Nevada Limited Transition Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the City of Henderson, Nevada, certain Federal land located in the City, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="2005-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5328"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5328-5329" label="text as measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-444.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="2425"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/17/2005--Introduced.
Southern Nevada Limited Transition Area Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the city of Henderson, Nevada, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to specified Federal land in Henderson (the Transition Area). Permits the City, after conveyance, to sell any part or parts of the Transition Area for nonresidential development purposes, or to elect to retain parcels in the Transition Area for public recreation or other public purposes consistent with the Recreation and Public Purposes Act. Requires the City to: (1) plan and manage the Transition Area in accordance with Federal law and regulations relating to airport noise compatibility planning; and (2) agree that if any land in the Transition area is sold, leased, or otherwise conveyed by the City, the sale, lease, or conveyance shall contain a limitation to require uses compatible with that airport noise compatibility planning.</summary>
</bill>
