<bill session="109" type="s" number="2126" updated="2013-07-19T20:31:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Family Entertainment Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to limit the exposure of children to violent video games.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2005-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300067" joined="2005-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13789-13791"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1888"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Age"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Video games"/>
    <term name="Violence in mass media"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2005--Introduced.
Family Entertainment Protection Act - Prohibits a business from selling, renting, or permitting the sale or rental of any video game with a Mature, Adults-Only, or Ratings Pending rating from the Entertainment Software Ratings Board to any individual who has not attained the age of 17 years. Subjects violators of this Act to a civil penalty. Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to contract with an expert, independent organization to determine annually whether Board ratings remain consistent and reliable. Authorizes the FTC to conduct: (1) and publicize the results of an annual secret audit of businesses to determine how frequently minors who attempt to purchase video games with a Mature, Adults-Only, or Rating Pending rating are able to do so successfully; and (2) an investigation into embedded content in video games that can be accessed through a keystroke combination, pass-code, or other technological means to estimate certain data about video games with embedded content. Expresses the sense of Congress that whenever the FTC determines that the content of a video game is inconsistent with the rating given to such game, it shall take appropriate action under its authority to regulate unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce. Requires the FTC's Bureau of Consumer Protection to ensure that consumers can file complaints alleging misleading or deceptive content-descriptions or labels on a video game using the same procedure (including an easily accessible online filing system) by which complaints are now accepted concerning other forms of unfair, deceptive, or fraudulent advertising.</summary>
</bill>
