<bill session="109" type="s" number="4051" updated="2013-07-19T20:48:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-11-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Electronic Surveillance bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Oversight and Resource Enhancement Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide sufficient resources to permit electronic surveillance of United States persons for foreign intelligence purposes to be conducted pursuant to individualized court-based orders for calls originating in the United States, to provide additional resources to enhance oversight and streamline the procedures of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, to ensure review of the Terrorist Surveillance Program by the United States Supreme Court, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-11-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10926-10927, S10928"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/4/2006 S11108-11109" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-11-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="665">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 665.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-12-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11160"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3001"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3877"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/14/2006--Introduced.
Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Oversight and Resource Enhancement Act of 2006 - Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) to: (1) authorize the appointment of additional judges to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court (Court); and (2) require FISA judges to act on applications for emergency electronic surveillance within 24 hours. Authorizes the hiring of additional personnel in the Department of Justice (DOJ), Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), National Security Agency (NSA), and the Court to process surveillance applications. Requires the Directors of the FBI and NSA to develop regulations for conducting and seeking approval for emergency electronic surveillance, preparing and submitting applications for such surveillance, and training personnel. Extends from 72 to 168 hours the period during which the Attorney General may authorize emergency electronic surveillance pending judicial authorization of such surveillance. Permits electronic surveillance without a court order of communications between individuals outside the United States for the purpose of collecting foreign intelligence information even if such communications pass through, or the surveillance device is located within, the United States. Requires a court order for the contents of any wire or radio communication sent by a person inside the United States to a person outside the United States. Authorizes enhanced congressional oversight of electronic surveillance activities under FISA. Requires Supreme Court review of any final decision of a U.S. court of appeals concerning the legality of the Terrorist Surveillance Program.</summary>
</bill>
