<bill session="109" type="s" number="2295" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hawaiian Waters Chemical Munitions Safety Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of the Army to conduct a survey and monitoring of off-shore sites in the vicinity of the Hawaiian Islands where chemical munitions were disposed of by the Army Forces, to support research regarding the public and environmental health impacts of chemical munitions disposal in the ocean, and to require the preparation of a report on remediation plans for such disposal sites.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1416"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4778"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2006--Introduced.
Hawaiian Waters Chemical Munitions Safety Act of 2006 - Directs the Secretary of the Army to: (1) conduct a survey of all Hawaiian underwater sites where chemical munitions are known to have been disposed of by the Armed Forces between 1941 and 1972; and (2) identify on Hawaiian coastal nautical charts and other navigational materials navigational hazards to private activities and commercial shipping or fishing operations as identified in the survey. Requires the Secretary to implement appropriate monitoring mechanisms to recognize and track the potential release of hazardous chemical agents into the marine environment from such disposal sites. Directs the Secretary to establish a program to conduct research and provide research grants to study the long-term effects of seawater exposure on chemical munitions, including the potential public health risks associated with, and the environmental impact of, ocean disposal of chemical munitions. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the feasibility and cost of implementing multiple remediation measures at the disposal sites covered by the survey, including an analysis of the public health and environmental safety risks of such sites.</summary>
</bill>
