<bill session="110" type="s" number="2640" updated="2013-07-19T22:44:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans' Benefits Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to enhance and improve insurance, housing, labor and education, and other benefits for veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2008-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="2008-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2008-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-02-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Burns"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Ex-prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Judicial tenure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Life insurance"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Multiple sclerosis"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Osteoporosis"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf War"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Self-help devices for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2008--Introduced.
Veterans' Benefits Enhancement Act of 2008 - Revises veterans' insurance benefits matters to: (1) direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) to grant level-premium term life insurance to certain service-disabled veterans; (2) increase the maximum amount of supplemental service disabled veterans' insurance for totally disabled veterans; (3) provide retroactive traumatic injury coverage under the Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance (SGLI) program for certain members of the Armed Forces who incurred a traumatic injury in the line of duty; (4) provide for the designation of a recipient of funds for traumatic injury coverage when the member is mentally incapacitated or experiencing an extended loss of consciousness; and (5) increase the maximum loan guarantee amount under the veterans' mortgage life insurance program.Revises veterans' housing benefits matters to: (1) allow home improvements and structural alterations for totally disabled members likely to be discharged or released from service; (2) make eligible for specially adapted housing benefits and assistance members with certain severe service-connected disabilities and veterans with such disabilities residing outside the United States; (3) authorize the provision of such assistance for veterans with a severe burn disability and disabled veterans residing temporarily in housing owned by a family member; and (4) increase specially adapted housing benefits for disabled veterans.Revises veterans' employment and education matters to: (1) require coordination of veterans' educational course approval activities with those performed by the Departments of Labor and Education and other appropriate entities; (2) enhance the authority for reimbursing expenses of state approving agencies; (3) waive the residency requirement for a Director for Veterans' Employment and Training; (4) extend through 2009 an increase in benefits for veterans pursuing apprenticeships or on-job training; and (5) increase supplemental educational assistance for members of the Selected Reserve with certain skills or specialties.Deems certain service performed with the military forces of the Philippines and the Philippine Scouts as active U.S. military service for purposes of eligibility for veterans' benefits. Entitles children of such Filipino veterans to the same rate of educational assistance entitlement as children of other veterans.Revises provisions concerning the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims to: (1) eliminate the service limit for retired judges who voluntarily return to the Court; (2) remove the annual limit on Court registration and practice fees; and (3) require reports on Court workloads and expansion of Court facilities.Revises veterans' compensation and pension matters to: (1) add osteoporosis to the disabilities presumed to be service-connected in former prisoners of war with post-traumatic stress disorder; and (2) provide an annual cost-of-living adjustment to temporary dependency and indemnity compensation (DIC) payable to surviving spouses with dependent children under 18 years old.Provides an annual adjustment for veterans' burial benefits.Increases eligibility for, and the amount of, assistance provided to disabled veterans for the purchase of automobiles and adaptive equipment.Allows for the termination or suspension of cellular phone contracts for members undergoing deployments of 90 days or more outside the United States.Provides for the maintenance, management, and availability for research of assets of the Air Force Health Study.Requires: (1) a study on the risk of developing multiple sclerosis as a result of certain military service; and (2) a report on the adequacy of DIC to support survivors of veterans who die from service-connected disabilities.</summary>
</bill>
