<bill session="111" type="s" number="2880" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Rural Broadband Initiative Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to establish an Office of Rural Broadband Initiatives in the Department of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-14">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4545"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/14/2009--Introduced.
Rural Broadband Initiative Act of 2009 - Amends the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to establish in the Department of Agriculture the Office of Rural Broadband Initiatives, to be headed by the Under Secretary for Rural Broadband Initiatives. States that the Under Secretary shall: (1) administer all rural broadband-related grant and loan programs previously administered by the Administrator of the Rural Utilities Service, including the rural broadband access loan and loan guarantee program and the community connect grant program; (2) conduct rural outreach; (3) foster development of a comprehensive rural broadband strategic vision; (4) assess relevant technologies; (5) serve as a single information source for all federal rural broadband programs and services; and (6) provide technical assistance to state, regional, and local governments to develop broadband deployment strategies. Directs the Under Secretary to submit: (1) a comprehensive rural broadband strategy report to the President and to Congress; and (2) a plan for a Rural Broadband Advisory Panel to Congress. Establishes in the Treasury the National Rural Broadband Innovation Fund.</summary>
</bill>
