<bill session="111" type="s" number="3189" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to allow for additional transportation assistance grants.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2010-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2010-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2746"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2010--Introduced.
Expands the urbanized area formula grants program to include public transit projects in urbanized areas with specified population ranges if the state or regional authority that provides public transportation for the area operates less than 100 buses in fixed-route service in the area during peak service hours. Separates population categories by graduated increases of 200,000, starting with between 200,000 and 400,000, and capping at a minimum of 1 million. Establishes certain grant use limits for the operating costs of public transportation equipment and facilities in such projects, beginning with 50% of grant funds for certain activities and declining gradually to 30% for certain other activities. Revises grant eligibility requirements for FY2010-FY2015 for such projects in urbanized areas with a population of at least 200,000. Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation, during FY2010-FY2015, to award an additional grant to a designated recipient for the operating cost of public transportation equipment and facilities under this Act if the recipient: (1) was awarded a grant under the Transit Investments for Greenhouse Gas and Energy Reduction (TIGGER) program; and (2) demonstrates that it has achieved specified energy savings and total greenhouse gas emission reduction as a result of a TIGGER grant project.</summary>
</bill>
