<bill session="109" type="hr" number="577" updated="2013-07-19T18:59:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the conditions for the United States to become a signatory to any multilateral agreement on trade resulting from the World Trade Organization's Doha Development Agenda Round.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400168" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400338" joined="2005-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11270"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="sr" number="459"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2005--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should not be a signatory to any agreement or protocol with respect to the Doha Development Round of the World Trade Organization (WTO) negotiations, or any other bilateral or multilateral trade negotiations that: (1) adopts specified proposals to lessen the effectiveness of domestic and international disciplines on unfair trade or safeguard provisions; or (2) would lessen in any manner the ability of the United States to enforce rigorously its trade laws, including the antidumping, countervailing duty, and safeguard laws. Declares the sense of the House that the federal trade laws and international rules appropriately serve the public interest by offsetting injurious unfair trade, and further "balancing modifications" or other similar provisions are unnecessary and would add to the complexity and difficulty of achieving relief against injurious unfair trade practices. States that the United States should ensure that any new agreement relating to international disciplines on unfair trade or safeguard provisions fully rectifies and corrects decisions by WTO dispute settlement panels or the Appellate Body that have unjustifiably and negatively impacted, or threaten to negatively impact, federal law or practice, including a law or practice with respect to foreign dumping or subsidization.</summary>
</bill>
