<bill session="112" type="s" number="1257" updated="2013-07-20T02:27:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Border Health Security Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish grant programs to improve the health of border area residents and for all hazards preparedness in the border area including bioterrorism and infectious disease, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300054" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2011-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4030-4031"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4031-4032" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2298"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/2011--Introduced.
Border Health Security Act of 2011 - Amends the United States-Mexico Border Health Commission Act to revise the duties of the United States-Mexico Border Health Commission to include serving as an independent and objective body to both recommend and implement initiatives that solve border health issues. Authorizes a member of the Commission to provide advice or recommendations to Congress concerning issues that are considered by the Commission. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Commissioners, to award grants to eligible entities to improve the health of border residents. Requires the Secretary to award grants under the Early Warning Infectious Disease Surveillance project to eligible entities for infection disease surveillance activities in the border area. Requires the Commission to: (1) prepare a binational strategic plan to guide the operations of the Commission, and (2) develop and approve an operational work plan and budget based on the strategic plan. Requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to conduct an evaluation of Commission activitie. Requires the Secretary to enter into a contract with the Institute of Medicine for a study concerning binational health infrastructure (including trauma and emergency care) and health insurance efforts. Authorizes the Secretary to coordinate with the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) in establishing a health alert system that: (1) alerts clinicians and public health officials of emerging disease clusters and syndromes along the border area; and (2) is alerted to signs of health threats, disasters of mass scale, or bioterrorism along the border area.</summary>
</bill>
