<bill session="109" type="s" number="2023" updated="2013-07-19T20:31:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-05-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to improve that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2005-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-272.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-06-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="502">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 502.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2006--Reported to Senate amended.
Amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to require the President to submit to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works, and the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure a biennial audit conducted by the U.S. Comptroller General that includes a detailed accounting of all funds from the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund (Fund) in excess of $100,000 that are disbursed by the National Pollution Funds Center and administered and managed by receiving agencies. Requires the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Transportation, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the heads of any other federal agencies that receive payments from the Fund in excess of $100,000 to provide the President with an annual report accounting of the uses of such funds, including a description of ways in which those uses relate to: (1) oil pollution liability, compensation, prevention, preparedness, and removal; (2) natural resource damage assessment and restoration; (3) oil pollution research and development; and (4) other oil pollution-related activities. Requires such report to be made publicly available on the Internet. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
