<bill session="109" type="s" number="1975" updated="2013-07-19T20:30:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Deceptive Practices and Voter Intimidation Prevention Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit deceptive practices in Federal elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300042" joined="2005-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2005-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2005-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12531"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12531-12532" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4463"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="4069"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Election fraud"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/2005--Introduced.
Deceptive Practices and Voter Intimidation Prevention Act of 2005 - Amends the Revised Statutes and federal criminal law to prohibit any person, whether acting under color of law or otherwise, from knowingly deceiving any other person regarding: (1) the time, place, or manner of conducting any federal election; or (2) the qualifications for or restrictions on voter eligibility for any such election. Creates a private right of action for any person aggrieved by a violation of such prohibition. Prescribes a criminal penalty for such deceptive acts. Authorizes any person to report a deceptive act to the Assistant Attorney General (AAG) of the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice (or a designee). Requires the AAG to investigate such a report within 48 hours after its receipt and provide correct information to the voters if it is determined that an act of deception occurred. Requires an immediate investigation if such a report is received within 72 hours before an election. Directs the AAG, in such an instance, to undertake immediately all effective measures necessary to provide correct information to voters affected by the deception. Directs the Attorney General to study the feasibility of providing such corrective information through public service announcements, the emergency alert system, or other forms of public broadcast.</summary>
</bill>
