<bill session="110" type="s" number="2295" updated="2013-07-19T22:40:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Voter Confidence and Increased Accessibility Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require a voter-verified permanent paper ballot under title III of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13694-13695"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-11-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13695-13701" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="811"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Election Assistance Commission"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Test facilities"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Voting machines"/>
    <term name="Voting of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/2007--Introduced.
Voter Confidence and Increased Accessibility Act of 2007 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (HAVA) with respect to: (1) ballot verification and mandatory paper record audit capacity; and (2) accessibility and ballot verification of results for individuals with disabilities.Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to study, test, and develop best practices to enhance the accessibility of ballot verification mechanisms for individuals with disabilities, voters whose primary language is not English, and voters with difficulties in literacy.Requires laboratories to meet standards prohibiting conflicts of interest as a condition of accreditation for the testing of voting system hardware and software.Outlines additional voting system requirements and prohibitions.Provides for grants for research on development of election-dedicated voting system software. Provides for complaints to the Attorney General by persons aggrieved by violations of HAVA. Directs each state to administer, without advance notice to the precincts selected, audits of the results of elections for federal office held in the state consisting of random hand counts of the voter-verified paper paper ballots required to be produced and preserved for each such election held in the state. Requires the Election Assistance Commission (EAC) to make payments to states to cover the costs incurred in carrying out such mandatory manual audits. Repeals the exemption of the EAC from certain government contracting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
