<bill session="110" type="s" number="635" updated="2013-07-19T22:25:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Methamphetamine Remediation Research Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Methamphetamine Remediation Research Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for a research program for remediation of closed methamphetamine production laboratories, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-02-15">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-06-06">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-10-26">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 110-207.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-10-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="451">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 451.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="365"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="365"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/26/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Methamphetamine Remediation Research Act of 2007 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), not later than one year after the enactment of this Act, to: (1) establish voluntary guidelines, based on the best currently available scientific knowledge, for the remediation of former methampehtamine laboratories, including guidelines regarding preliminary site assessment and the remediation of residual contaminants; (2) consider relevant federal, state, and local requirements in developing the guidelines, the varying types and locations of former methamphetamine laboratories, and the cost of carrying out such guidelines; (3) work with state and local governments and other relevant non-federal agencies in adopting the voluntary guidelines; (4) periodically update such guidelines; and (5) establish a research program to support the development and revision of such guidelines.Directs the Administrator: (1) not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act and every third year thereafter, to convene a conference of appropriate state agencies, individuals, and organizations involved in research and other activities directly relating to the environmental or biological impact of former methamphetamine laboratories; (2) to submit a report to Congress that summarizes the proceedings of the conference, including a summary of recommendations and concerns of non-federal participants; and (3) to make such report widely available to the general public.Directs the Administrator to enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) for a study of the status and quality of research on the residual effects of methamphetanmine laboratories and to report to Congress on the uses of such study.Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to support a research program to develop: (1) new methamphetamine detection technologies, with an emphasis on field test kits and site detection; and (2) appropriate standard reference materials and validation procedures for methamphetamine detection testing. Authorizes appropriations for FY2007-FY2008.</summary>
</bill>
