<bill session="112" type="s" number="464" updated="2013-07-20T02:20:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">End Abuse in Later Life Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a grant program to enhance training and services to prevent abuse in later life.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1144"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-02">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1144-1145" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4979"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/2011--Introduced.
End Abuse in Later Life Act of 2011 - Amends the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 to authorize appropriations for and revise provisions governing the grant program to end abuse of individuals age 50 and over that is authorized to be conducted by the Attorney General through the Director of the Office of Violence Against Women. Makes currently listed activities mandatory for grant recipients and sets forth as additional permissible activities: (1) providing training programs to assist attorneys, health care providers, faith-based leaders, or other community-based organizations in recognizing and addressing instances of such abuse; and (2) conducting outreach activities and public awareness campaigns to ensure that abuse victims receive appropriate assistance. Includes as eligible entities: (1) a population-specific organization with demonstrated experience in assisting individuals over 50 years of age; (2) a victim service provider with demonstrated experience in addressing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking; or (3) a state, tribal, or territorial domestic violence or sexual assault coalition. Requires each eligible entity to demonstrate that it is a part of a multidisciplinary partnership that includes a law enforcement agency, a prosecutor's office, a victim service provider, and a nonprofit program or government agency with demonstrated experience in assisting individuals in later life. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) give priority to proposals providing population-specific services to racial and ethnic minorities and other underserved populations; and (2) conduct research to promote understanding of, prevention of, and response to abuse in later life. Amends the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 to replace the term "elder law" with "abuse in later life."</summary>
</bill>
