<bill session="109" type="h" number="922" updated="2013-07-19T19:12:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Mental Health Services Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve treatment of post-traumatic stress disorder for veterans of service in Afghanistan and Iraq and the war on terrorism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400138"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Group counseling"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="Psychiatrists"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/2005--Introduced.
Veterans Mental Health Services Enhancement Act of 2005 - Authorizes appropriations for the employment of additional psychiatrists and other mental health services specialists at Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers and outpatient facilities specializing in the diagnoses and treatment of post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct a nationwide outreach program at the community level for veterans who participated in Operation Iraqi Freedom or Operation Enduring Freedom who are or may be suffering from PTSD. Directs the Secretary of each military department to conduct a comprehensive review of the mental health care programs of the Armed Forces under the jurisdiction of that Secretary to determine ways to improve the efficacy of such care. Requires the Secretary of each military department to take special care in providing for as seamless a transition as possible from Department of Defense health care services to Department of Veterans Affairs health care services with regard to members of the Armed Forces who were exposed to combat or are otherwise at risk for PTSD. Requires the Secretary of each military department and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) assess the adequacy of privacy and patient confidentiality standards and practices of their respective departments, particularly with regard to patients seeking treatment for PTSD; and (2) identify other factors that may deter members of the Armed Forces from seeking treatment for PTSD.</summary>
</bill>
