<bill session="109" type="s" number="741" updated="2013-07-19T20:19:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Oregon National Forest Administrative Site Disposal Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide for the disposal of certain Forest Service administrative sites in the State of Oregon, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2005-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-04-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-104.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="3013"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/2005--Introduced.
Oregon National Forest Administrative Site Disposal Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to sell or exchange any or all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to specified National Forest System lands, and improvements on those lands, located in the Rogue River, Siskiyou, Siuslaw, Umpqua, and Williamette National Forests in Oregon. Allows the Secretary to convey, without consideration, any or all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to such land to the State of Oregon or a local government for public purposes. Grants the Eugene Mission the first right to acquire certain of such land in a direct sale for market value. Allows the Secretary to accept a cash equalization payment exceeding 25 percent of the value of any such land conveyed by exchange as directed above. Provides for the deposit and treatment of the proceeds from the conveyance of all such land. Describes the authorized uses of deposited funds. Revokes any public land orders applicable to such land. Withdraws such land from location, entry, and patent under the U.S. mining laws. Directs the Secretary to convey, without consideration, certain of such land to the city of Oakridge, Oregon, to facilitate the establishment of a timber museum on such land to be managed by the Upper Williamette Pioneer Association. Adjusts the the Rogue-Umpqua Divide wilderness boundary as identified on the "Rogue-Umpqua Divide Wilderness Boundary Modification" map, dated May 6, 2003. .</summary>
</bill>
