<bill session="111" type="s" number="1574" updated="2013-07-20T00:37:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clean Energy for Homes and Buildings Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish a Clean Energy for Homes and Buildings Program in the Department of Energy to provide financial assistance to promote residential-, commercial-, and industrial-scale energy efficiency and on-site renewable technologies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="2009-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-08-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8769-8771" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/2009--Introduced.
Clean Energy for Homes and Buildings Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to develop and publish for review and comment near-, medium-, and long-term goals for: (1) a minimum number of homes and other buildings to be retrofitted through energy efficiency measures or to have on-site renewable energy systems added; (2) the number of on-site solar energy, wind energy, and geothermal heat pump systems to be installed; (3) the quantities by which use of grid-supplied electricity, natural gas, home heating oil, and other fuels, total fossil fuel dependence in the buildings sector, and greenhouse gas emissions will be reduced; (4) the number of jobs that will be created; and (5) the estimated total energy cost savings for building owners. Establishes in the Department of Energy (DOE) the Clean Energy for Homes and Buildings Program. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish eligibility criteria for applicants for financial assistance (including credit enhancements, debt instruments, or other financial products); and (2) select a portfolio of investments that reaches a diversity of building owners. Authorizes the Secretary to provide financial assistance to eligible applicants to promote the widespread deployment of, and mobilize private sector support of credit and investment institutions for, energy efficiency measures and on-site renewable energy generation systems in buildings.</summary>
</bill>
