<bill session="112" type="sr" number="601" updated="2013-07-20T02:15:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-11-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-11-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-11-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution commending the people of Albania on the 100th anniversary of the declaration of their independence from the Turkish Ottoman Empire on November 28, 1912, and commending Albanians in Albania and Kosovo for protecting and saving the lives of all Jews who either lived in Albania or sought asylum there during the Holocaust.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-11-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6948-6949" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="hr" number="812"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Albania"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Kosovo"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="World history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/27/2012--Introduced.
Commends the people of Albania and Kosova for protecting the lives of all Jews who either lived in Albania or sought asylum there during the Holocaust. Commends Yad Vashem, the Holocaust Martyrs' and Heroes' Remembrance Authority, in Israel for recognizing Albanians who took action at great risk to protect Jews during the Holocaust. Commends the officers, board of directors, and members of the Albanian American Civic League and Albanian American Foundation for their work to bring the plight of the Albanian people and the historic connection between Albanians and Jews to international attention. Reaffirms, on the 100th anniversary of Albania's 1912 declaration of independence, support for close ties between the United States and Albania and between the United States and Kosova, which declared its independence in 2008.</summary>
</bill>
