<bill session="112" type="s" number="1828" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Increasing Small Business Lending Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to increase small business lending, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7193"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-08">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5851"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/8/2011--Introduced.
Increasing Small Business Lending Act of 2011 - Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to extend small business loan fee reductions and eliminations and small business loan guarantees under such Act to one year after the enactment of this Act. Makes uniform between the Small Business Administration (SBA) section 7(a) loan program and the SBA local development business loan program the office space leasing policy, allowing up to 50% of a facility to be leased on either a new or existing building. Allows the SBA Administrator to pool (combine for sale on the secondary market) SBA-guaranteed loans having various interest rates. (Currently, the SBA may pool only SBA-guaranteed loans having the same interest rate.) Requires interest rates on trust certificates representing shares of pooled loans to be the weighted average interest rate of such loans. Requires the SBA to provide to intermediary lenders at least one alternative interest rate other than the Wall Street prime rate.</summary>
</bill>
