<bill session="111" type="s" number="1803" updated="2013-07-20T00:39:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Reserve Accountability Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 31, United States Code, to authorize reviews by the Comptroller General of the United States of emergency credit facilities established by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or any Federal Reserve bank, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2009-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10573"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/2009--Introduced.
Federal Reserve Accountability Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Comptroller General to conduct reviews of (including onsite examinations), and report to Congress on, the accounting, financial reporting, and internal controls of credit facilities established by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, or any Federal Reserve bank, including when such activities are implemented by or on behalf of the Board or any official of a Federal Reserve bank. Defines "credit facilities" as: (1) the Money Market Investor Funding Facility; (2) the Asset-Backed Commercial Paper Money Market Mutual Fund Liquidity Facility; (3) the Term Asset-Backed Securities Loan Facility; (4) the Primary Dealer Credit Facility; (5) the Commercial Paper Funding Facility; and (6) certain other credit facilities approved by the Board, as well as any special purpose vehicle through which any activity of such facilities is conducted. Requires the Board to place on its home Internet website a link entitled "Audit" to a webpage that serves as a repository of public information for not less than six months following the release of the relevant information, including: (1) the reports prepared pursuant to this Act; (2) the annual financial statements prepared by an independent auditor for the Board; and (3) any other information the Board believes is necessary or helpful to the public in understanding its accounting, financial reporting, and internal controls as well as those of the Federal Reserve banks.</summary>
</bill>
