<bill session="110" type="h" number="7028" updated="2013-07-19T22:05:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To limit United States assistance for infrastructure projects in Iraq, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400395"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="2008-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2008--Introduced.
Prohibits U.S. assistance for the acquisition, conversion, rehabilitation, or installation of facilities in Iraq, with exemptions for: (1) amounts made available under the Commanders' Emergency Response Program (CERP) (project amounts in excess of $1 million only to be allowed with the Secretary of Defense's approval and congressional notification); and (2) technical assistance for the government of Iraq. Directs the Secretary of State to conclude an agreement under which the government of Iraq shares with the U.S. government the costs of combined operations of the government of Iraq and the Multi-National Force in Iraq undertaken as part of Operation Iraqi Freedom.</summary>
</bill>
