<bill session="109" type="hc" number="329" updated="2013-07-19T20:05:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress regarding the activities of Islamist terrorist organizations in the Western Hemisphere.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2005-12-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hc" number="338"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Organization of American States (OAS)"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/22/2005--Introduced.
Recognizes the potential threat that sympathizers and financiers of Islamist terrorist organizations that operate in the Western Hemisphere pose to the United States, our allies, and interests. Acknowledges the cooperation of some Western Hemisphere governments to deny the use of their territory to Islamist terrorist organizations and calls on all governments to intensify such efforts. Encourages the President to direct the United States Representative to the Organization of American States (OAS) to: (1) seek OAS support for the creation of a special task force of the Inter-American Committee Against Terrorism (CICTE) to assist in investigating and combating the proliferation of Islamist terrorist organizations in the Western Hemisphere; and (2) urge OAS countries to designate Hezbollah, Hamas, Palestinian Islamic Jihad, al-Qaeda and other such groups as terrorist organizations.</summary>
</bill>
