<bill session="109" type="s" number="2067" updated="2013-07-19T20:31:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">HazCom Simplification and Modernization Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to assist chemical manufacturers and importers in preparing material safety data sheets pursuant to the requirements of the Hazard Communication standard and to establish a Commission to study and make recommendations regarding the implementation of the Globally Harmonized System of Classification and Labeling of Chemicals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2006-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2005-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13370-13371"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13375-13376" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2005--Introduced.
HazCom Simplification and Modernization Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Labor to develop model material safety data sheets for the list of highly hazardous chemicals contained in Appendix A to the Process Safety Management of Highly Hazardous Chemicals standard published in the Code of Federal Regulations. Sets forth requirements for these model material safety data sheets. Establishes a Global Harmonization Commission to: (1) consider the implementation of the United Nations Globally Harmonized System of Classification and Labeling of Chemicals to improve chemical hazard communication; and (2) make recommendations to Congress. Amends requirements for training and employee education under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to direct the Secretary to award demonstration project grants to develop, implement, or evaluate strategies or programs to improve chemical hazard communication in the workplace through the use of technology.</summary>
</bill>
