<bill session="111" type="h" number="1455" updated="2013-07-19T23:24:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Financial Consumer Hotline Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act to require the Council to establish a single telephone number that consumers with complaints or inquiries could call and be routed to the appropriate Federal banking agency or State bank supervisor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="2009-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E651"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2009--Introduced.
Financial Consumer Hotline Act of 2009 - Amends the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 to require federal financial institution regulatory agencies, coordinating through the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council, to establish: (1) a single, toll-free telephone number for consumer complaints and inquiries concerning institutions under their jurisdiction; and (2) a system for routing such calls to the federal financial institution regulatory agency that primarily supervises the financial institution, or that is otherwise the appropriate agency to address the subject of the complaint or inquiry.Cites circumstances under which state agencies may receive appropriate call transfers from such federal systems.</summary>
</bill>
