<bill session="111" type="s" number="3937" updated="2013-07-20T01:00:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Suburban Core Opportunity, Restoration, and Enhancement (SCORE) Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to revitalize suburban communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Introduced.
Suburban Core Opportunity, Restoration, and Enhancement (SCORE) Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to designate one or more SCORE project areas. Conditions such a designation on whether: (1) the area is nominated by one or more local governments, including municipal and county authorities; and (2) the local government provides written assurances that it convened a SCORE advisory committee to enter into a collaborative community planning process to determine the SCORE project area to be nominated, and meets other related criteria. Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive grants to local governments to: (1) create strategic plans for SCORE project areas; and (2) fund activities to revitalize such areas. Requires a local government receiving a revitalization grant to establish a separate SCORE Reinvestment Fund. Requires such a grant to be used to: (1) acquire real, commercial, or industrial property and existing structures within a SCORE project area; (2) pay for engineers to develop or redevelop the property and structures; and (3) pay for property and structure construction, reconstruction, alteration, or rehabilitation, or to make substantial improvements to them. Deems a business located within a SCORE project area and receiving community block grant funds under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (HCDA) to have met specified requirements for any job creation or job retention effort undertaken with such funds, including the one that assisted activities benefit persons of low and moderate income. Exempts any economic development project located within a SCORE project area receiving HCDA funds from HCDA public benefit standards. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) a three-year work opportunity tax credit for the hiring of employees who perform services for a trade or business located in a SCORE project area; and (2) an additional depreciation allowance for business or investment property located in such an area.</summary>
</bill>
