<bill session="112" type="h" number="2124" updated="2013-07-20T01:28:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Southwest Cross-border Violence Recognition Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve the safety, security, and operational control of the international border by providing the Department of Homeland Security with an accurate definition of the term "cross-border violence", to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to develop measures to quantify cross-border violence data for reporting to Congress and other entities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412481"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412395" joined="2011-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2011-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2012-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2011-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2011-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration Policy and Enforcement" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2011--Introduced.
Southwest Cross-border Violence Recognition Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS): (1) within 180 days, to report on metrics to be used to gauge the incidents or occurrences of cross-border violence and on how the resulting findings shall be quantified for periodic reporting; and (2) every 90 days after submitting such report, to report on incidents or occurrences of cross-border violence, incorporating such metrics and including information and crime statistics from federal, state, local, and tribal sources. Requires such metrics to include: (1) border sheriff and state law enforcement reports on crime, vandalism, theft, burglary, apprehensions, accidents, and capital crimes; (2) reports from local hospitals in border states regarding the number of individuals treated for wounds obtained during acts of cross-border violence; (3) the impact to property values and businesses along the border as a result of factors such as acts of vandalism, theft, burglary, destruction of property, and intimidation; and (4) accounts of cross-border violence reported by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP), and other federal agencies.</summary>
</bill>
