<bill session="109" type="s" number="3877" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Electronic Surveillance bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill entitled the "Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Improvement and Enhancement Act of 2006".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2006-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2006-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2006-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2006-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400619" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="2006-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2006-09-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="600">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 600.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="109" type="h" number="6056"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3001"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="3001"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="4051"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Management information systems"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2006--Introduced.
States that specified chapters of the federal criminal code relating to electronic surveillance and the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) shall provide the exclusive means by which domestic electronic surveillance may be conducted. Prohibits any modification or repeal of any provisions of title I (Electronic Surveillance) of FISA without an express legislative directive. Directs the President to brief each member of the congressional intelligence committees on the Terrorist Surveillance Program of the National Security Agency (NSA) and certain other surveillance programs. Amends FISA to extend the period allowed for emergency electronic surveillance without a court order. Authorizes the Attorney General to delegate the authority to approve an application for electronic surveillance and to appoint certain personnel in the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) and the NSA to authorize emergency surveillance in the United States. Authorizes the appointment of additional judges to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court. Directs the Attorney General to develop and implement a classified document management system to process electronic surveillance applications.Expands the authority of the President to authorize wartime electronic surveillance without a court order. Permits electronic surveillance without a court order of communications between individuals outside of the United States under certain circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
