<bill session="110" type="s" number="100" updated="2013-07-19T22:21:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Healthy Students Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to encourage the health of children in schools by promoting better nutrition and increased physical activity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S109-110"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Diet"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Organic farming"/>
    <term name="Physical education and training"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports facilities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/2007--Introduced.
Healthy Students Act of 2007 - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to require the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to establish a Commission to Improve School Meals composed of nutrition and children's health experts tasked with developing new nutritional standards for the School Lunch, Summer Food Service, Child and Adult Care Food, and School Breakfast programs. Requires such standards to ban foods of minimal nutritional value. Provides for the adjustment of program payment rates to compensate for compliance with such standards. Repeals the current requirement that the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary) issue guidance to states and school food authorities to increase the consumption of foods and food ingredients recommended in the most recent Dietary Guidelines for Americans. Requires the Secretary to establish a pilot program providing grants to school districts or nonprofit organizations for use in promoting healthy food alternatives under the School Lunch and School Breakfast programs. Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to elementary and secondary schools for Healthy Hour pilot programs which increase each school day by an hour that is exclusively devoted to physical activity. Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish a student loan forgiveness program for nurses who agree to employment as full-time nurses in elementary or secondary schools for three complete school years. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow corporations a tax deduction for the charitable contribution to a private foundation of exercise or gymnasium equipment for use by elementary and secondary school students.</summary>
</bill>
