<bill session="110" type="h" number="2938" updated="2013-07-19T21:29:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Land Grant Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize grants to upgrade agriculture and food sciences facilities at the District of Columbia Land Grant University, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1453"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural colleges"/>
    <term name="Agricultural experiment stations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2007--Introduced.
District of Columbia Land Grant Enhancement Act of 2007 - Amends the Smith-Lever Act and the Hatch Act of 1887 to apply to the District of Columbia the reduced matching funds requirements for federal formula funds for agricultural extension work and experiment stations, respectively. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to waive such matching funds requirements when the District of Columbia is unlikely to meet them. Amends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to authorize funding to assist the University of the District of Columbia (UDC), a land-grant university, to construct, acquire, rent, alter, or repair buildings or facilities or relevant equipment necessary for conducting agricultural research. Makes UDC eligible for competitive grants under such Act for food and agricultural sciences education at schools having significant minority enrollments.</summary>
</bill>
