<bill session="112" type="h" number="662" updated="2013-07-20T01:16:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-04">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide an extension of Federal-aid highway, highway safety, motor carrier safety, transit, and other programs funded out of the Highway Trust Fund pending enactment of a multiyear law reauthorizing such programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2011-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2011-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2011-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2011-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-11">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-11">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-02-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-02-28T18:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 112-18, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-28">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on the Budget for a period ending not later than Feb. 28, 2011 for consideration of such provisions of the bill as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(d), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-28T18:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Ways and Means discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-28T18:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Natural Resources discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-28T18:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on The Budget discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-02-28T18:47:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="9">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 9.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-03-01T16:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 128 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 662 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, if offered by Representative Mica of Florida or his designee, which shall be in order without intervention of any point of order, shall be considered as read, shall be separately debatable for 10 minutes equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent and shall not be subject to a demand for a division of the question.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02T14:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 128 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02T14:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 128.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1482-1494" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1482-1484" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02T14:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 662 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, if offered by Representative Mica of Florida or his designee, which shall be in order without intervention of any point of order, shall be considered as read, shall be separately debatable for 10 minutes equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent and shall not be subject to a demand for a division of the question.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02T14:53:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 662.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02T15:41:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 128, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mica amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02T16:09:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1491-1493" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02T16:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Polis moved to recommit with instructions to Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1491-1493" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1491" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02T16:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Polis (CO) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the Committee on Transportation to report the bill back to the House forthwith with an amendment which inserts a section rescinding all unobligated balances of contract authority provided or reserved for planning, design, or construction of the Gravina Island bridge, Alaska, or the Knik Arm bridge, Alaska.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02T16:19:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1493" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02T16:36:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 181 - 246, 2 Present (Roll no. 159).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2011-03-02T16:42:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="160" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 421 - 4 (Roll no. 160).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02T16:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1202-1204" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2011-03-03" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2011-03-04">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2011-03-04" type="public" number="112-5">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 112-5.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="128"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4239"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4239"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4276"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4281"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="4348"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Denali Commission"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h173"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/4/2011--Public Law.
Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2011 - (Sec. 1) Directs the Secretary of Transportation to reduce the amount apportioned for a surface transportation program, project, or activity for FY2011 by amounts apportioned or allocated under the Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2010 and the Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2010, Part II for the period October 1, 2010-March 4, 2011. Title I: Federal-Aid Highways - (Sec. 101) Amends the Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2010 to extend through FY2011 the authorization of appropriations out of the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) (other than the Mass Transit Account) for the federal-aid highway, surface transportation research, and transportation planning programs under the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU). Extends through FY2011 the authorization of appropriations, at increased amounts, for federal-aid highway program administrative expenses. Title II: Extension of Highway Safety Programs - (Sec. 201) Amends SAFETEA-LU to extend through FY2011 the authorization of appropriations for National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) safety programs, but only at authorized FY2009 levels, including: (1) highway safety research and development, (2) the occupant protection incentive grant program, (3) the safety belt performance grant program, (4) state traffic safety information system improvements, (5) the alcohol-impaired driving countermeasures incentive grant program, (6) the National Driver Register, (7) the high visibility enforcement program, (8) motorcyclist safety, (9) the child safety and child booster seat safety incentive grant program, and (10) NHTSA administrative expenses. (Sec. 202) Extends through FY2011 the authorization of appropriations for Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) programs, but only at authorized FY2009 levels, including: (1) motor carrier safety grants, (2) FMCSA administrative expenses, (3) commercial driver's license program improvement grants, (4) border enforcement grants, (5) performance and registration information system management grants, (6) commercial vehicle information systems and networks deployment grants, (7) safety data improvement grants, (8) a set-aside for high priority activities that improve commercial motor vehicle safety and compliance with commercial motor vehicle safety regulations, (9) a set-aside for new entrant motor carrier audit grants, (10) commercial driver's license information system modernization, (11) FMCSA and NHTSA outreach and education, (12) the commercial motor vehicle operators grant program, (13) the FMCSA's Motor Carrier Safety Advisory Committee, and (14) the working group for development of practices and procedures to enhance federal-state relations. (Sec. 203) Extends through FY2011 the funding for hazardous materials (hazmat) research projects. Amends the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act to extend through FY2011 the authorization of appropriations, and the current requirements for their distribution, for fish restoration and management projects. Extends the set-aside for administrative expenses for carrying out such projects. Title III: Public Transportation Programs - (Sec. 301) Extends through FY2011 the allocation of capital investment grant funds for federal transit programs, including the metropolitan planning program and the state planning and research program. (Sec. 302) Extends the special rule authority of the Secretary to award urbanized area formula grants to finance the operating cost of equipment and facilities for use in public transportation in an urbanized area with a population of at least 200,000. (Sec. 303) Allocates through FY2011 certain amounts for formula and bus grants and capital investment grants, but only at authorized FY2009 levels, for: (1) certain new fixed guideway capital projects of under $75 million; (2) new fixed guideway ferry systems and extension projects in Alaska and Hawaii; (3) payments to the Denali Commission for docks, waterfront development projects, and related transportation infrastructure; (4) ferry boats or ferry terminal facilities; (5) a set-aside for the national fuel cell bus technology development program; (6) projects in nonurbanized areas; (7) intermodal terminal projects; and (8) bus testing. (Sec. 304) Extends through FY2011 the apportionments of: (1) nonurbanized area formula grants for public transportation on Indian reservations, and (2) capital investment grant funds for certain fixed guideway modernization projects. (Sec. 306) Extends through FY2011 the authorization appropriations from the HTF Mass Transit Account, but only at authorized FY2009 levels, for: (1) formula and bus grant projects, including allocations for specified projects; (2) capital investment grants; (3) transit research, including allocations for transit cooperative research programs, the National Transit Institute, the university centers program, transportation projects to comply with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, the National Technical Assistance Center for senior transportation, and national research programs; and (4) administrative expenses. (Sec. 307) Extends through FY2011 certain SAFETEA-LU programs, but only at authorized FY2009 levels, including: (1) the contracted paratransit pilot program, (2) the public-private partnership pilot program, (3) project authorizations for final design and construction and preliminary engineering of specified fixed guideway projects, and (4) the elderly individuals and individuals with disabilities pilot program. Extends through FY2011 certain allocations for national research and technology programs. (Sec. 308) Extends obligation authority of the Highway Category and the Mass Transit Category through FY2011, but limited to the FY2009 amount. Title IV: Extension of Expenditure Authority - (Sec. 401) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend through FY2011 authorities for expenditures from: (1) the HTF Highway and Mass Transit accounts, and (2) the Sport Fish Restoration and Boating Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
