<bill session="109" type="s" number="2442" updated="2013-07-19T20:34:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Safe Foreign Investments Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the President or the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States to submit to Congress draft investigation reports on national security related investigations, to address mandatory investigations by such committee, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2335"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Dubai Ports World aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government ownership"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2006--Introduced.
Safe Foreign Investments Act of 2006 - Amends the Defense Production Act of 1950 to direct the President or his designee, no later than seven days before the completion of an investigation of a proposed or pending merger, acquisition, or takeover (transaction) that could affect persons engaged in commerce in the United States or the national security, and before any such determination becomes effective, to submit to the congressional homeland security committees a draft report of its findings. Requires mandatory investigations of a transaction involving an entity controlled by or acting on behalf of a foreign person other than a foreign government only in the case in which the transaction involves critical infrastructure and could affect U.S. national security. States that the President's designee, for purposes of such investigations, shall be the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS).</summary>
</bill>
