<bill session="111" type="s" number="193" updated="2013-07-20T00:24:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Temporary Judgeships and Bankruptcy Judgeships Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" partial="1" type="short">Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to create and extend certain temporary district court judgeships.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2009-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300013" joined="2009-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2009-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300077" joined="2009-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2009-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300098" joined="2009-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S257"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-01-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S257" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-07-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="471">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 471.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/21/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Temporary Judgeships and Bankruptcy Judgeships Act of 2010 - Title I: Temporary Judgeships For District Courts - (Sec. 101) Requires the President to appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, one additional district judge for the eastern district of California and one additional district judge for the district of Nebraska. Prohibits filling of the first vacancy in the office of district judge in each of the offices of district judge authorized by this Act occurring 10 years or more after the confirmation of the judge named to fill the temporary district judgeship created by this Act. Amends the Judicial Improvements Act of 1990 to extend the temporary judgeships in the district of Hawaii, the district of Kansas, and the northern district of Ohio. Amends the 21st Century Department of Justice Appropriations Authorization Act to declare that the first vacancy in the office of district judge in the district of Arizona, the central district of California, and the eastern district of Texas authorized by this Act, occurring 20 years or more after the confirmation date of the judge named to fill the temporary district judgeship created in the applicable district by this Act, shall not be filled. Title II: Bankruptcy Judgeships - Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2010 - (Sec. 202) Amends the federal judicial code to authorize the appointment of additional permanent bankruptcy judges in various states. (Sec. 203) Converts certain temporary offices of bankruptcy judges to permanent offices in specified states. (Sec. 204) Extends certain temporary offices of bankruptcy judges previously authorized for Pennsylvania and North Carolina. (Sec. 205) Increases bankruptcy filing fees. Reduces the amount of bankruptcy fees to be deposited as offsetting collections to the United States Trustee System Fund.</summary>
</bill>
