<bill session="109" type="h" number="4920" updated="2013-07-19T19:47:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Accountability and Transparency in Ethics Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Rules of the House of Representatives to reform the ethics process, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="2006-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on House Administration, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="hr" number="772"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4948"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2128"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee membership"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional publicity"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional travel"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2006--Introduced.
Accountability and Transparency in Ethics Act - Establishes as an independent ethics commission within the legislative branch the Investigations Commission to: (1) investigate and report to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct (Committee) on any alleged violation of law, rule, regulation, or other applicable standard of conduct by a Member, officer, or employee of the House of Representatives; (2) report to appropriate federal or state authorities, with the approval of the House, any substantial evidence of a violation of any applicable law; and (3) adopt rules affording protections to respondents comparable to those that were provided by rule XI (Procedures of Committees and Unfinished Business) of the Rules of the House in effect immediately before the amendments to such rule made by this Act. Establishes mandatory annual ethics training for Members and House employees. Amends rule XXV (Limitations on Outside Earned Income and Acceptance of Gifts) to require the Committee's advance authorization of a privately-funded trip by any Member, officer, or employee of the House. Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (LDA) to transfer certain functions of the Clerk of the House to the Committee with respect to filing of lobbyist registrations. Authorizes the Committee to charge a registration fee. Requires registered lobbyists to file quarterly instead of semiannual disclosure reports with the Committee in an electronic form. Requires the Committee to maintain certain lobbying disclosure information in an electronic database, available to the public free of charge over the Internet. Subjects registered lobbyists, lobbyists employed by an organization registered under the LDA, or the client of such lobbyist or organization to penalties for offering gifts to a Representative in Congress, or any officer or employee of the House, knowing that such gift violates the rules of the House. Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit former Members, officers, or employees of either chamber of Congress, and any employee of any other legislative office of Congress from making lobbying contacts (within one year after such individuals leave office) with any former Member, officer, or employee of either chamber of Congress, and any former employee of any other legislative office of Congress.</summary>
</bill>
