<bill session="113" type="s" number="808" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Office of the Inspector General of the Senate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/24/2013--Introduced.
Establishes the Office of the Inspector General (IG) of the Senate. Requires the Majority and Minority Leaders of the Senate to appoint the first IG. Limits the IG to an initial five-year term and two additional terms if reappointed. Requires the IG to: (1) audit and investigate Senate programs and operations; (2) review legislation and regulations relating to Senate programs and operations, and make recommendations concerning their impact on the economy and efficiency in the administration of such programs and operations or the prevention and detection of fraud and abuse in them; and (3) keep the Committee on Rules and Administration and the Committee on Appropriations informed concerning fraud and other serious problems, abuses, and deficiencies relating to such administration and recommend corrective action. Requires the Office to establish a publicly available website for posting its reports and audits, including a direct homepage link for individuals to report fraud, waste, and abuse without being required to disclose personally identifying information.</summary>
</bill>
