<bill session="113" type="h" number="2248" updated="2013-11-02T06:37:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ban Poisonous Additives Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ban the use of bisphenol A in food containers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412560" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2013-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/2013--Introduced.
Ban Poisonous Additives Act of 2013 - Deems a food to be adulterated if its container: (1) is composed, in whole or in part, of bisphenol A (BPA); or (2) can release BPA into food.&#160; Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to grant one-year renewable waivers to a facility for a particular container if such facility: (1) demonstrates that it is not technologically feasible to replace BPA in the container or to use an alternative container that does not contain BPA, and (2) submits to the Secretary a plan and timeline for removing BPA from such container. Sets forth labeling requirements for a product granted a waiver. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (FDA), to review substances in order determine whether there is a reasonable certainty that no harm will result from aggregate exposure to such substance, taking into consideration potential adverse effects from low dose exposure and the effects on vulnerable populations and populations with high exposure. Sets forth remedial actions based on the Secretary's determination. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require a manufacturer or supplier of a food contact substance to notify the Secretary of the identity and intended use of any such substance prior to its introduction into interstate commerce and of its determination that: (1) no adverse health effects result from low-dose exposures to such substance; and (2) such substance has not been shown, after tests which are appropriate for the evaluation of the safety of food contact substances, to cause reproductive or developmental toxicity in humans or animals.</summary>
</bill>
