<bill session="109" type="s" number="3948" updated="2013-07-19T20:47:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhanced Border Tunnel Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend chapter 27 of title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the unauthorized construction, financing, or, with reckless disregard, permitting the construction or use on one's land, of a tunnel or subterranean passageway between the United States and another country.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300045"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10289-10290"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10291" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4816"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="h" number="4830"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2355"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="109" type="s" number="2652"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tunnels"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2006--Introduced.
Enhanced Border Tunnel Prevention Act - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit the construction or financing of an unauthorized tunnel or subterranean passage that crosses the international border between the United States and another country. Imposes a 25-year prison term for such offense. Doubles penalties for persons who use such a tunnel or passage to smuggle an alien, illegal goods, controlled substances, weapons of mass destruction, or members of a terrorist organization Imposes a 15-year prison term on any person who knows of or recklessly disregards the construction or use of an unauthorized tunnel or passage on land that such person owns or controls. Subjects to forfeiture any property involved in, or traceable to, the construction or financing of an unauthorized tunnel or passage. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to promulgate or amend sentencing guidelines to provide for increased penalties for persons convicted of criminal offenses related to the construction or financing of an unauthorized tunnel or passage.</summary>
</bill>
