<bill session="111" type="hr" number="456" updated="2013-07-19T22:59:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20T12:30:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-20T12:30:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 627) to amend the Truth in Lending Act to establish fair and transparent practices relating to the extension of credit under an open end consumer credit plan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412307"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19T18:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-120, by Ms. Pingree (ME).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19T18:47:00-04:00">
      <text>It shall be in order to take from the Speaker's table H.R. 627, with the Senate amendment thereto, and to consider in the House, a motion that the House concur in the Senate amendment. The Senate amendment shall be considered as read; shall be debatable for one hour; the previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The question of adoption of the motion shall be divided. If either portion of the divided question fails, no House disposition shall have occurred. H.Res. 450 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-05-19T18:48:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="55">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 55.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T10:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5808-5815" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T10:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 456.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T11:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5815" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T11:10:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 456, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the resolution and by voice vote announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Sessions demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T12:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5822" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2009-05-20T12:30:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="273" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 247 - 180 (Roll no. 273).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5808" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T12:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="450"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="627"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2009--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendment to H.R. 627 (Credit Card Accountability Responsibility and Disclosure Act of 2009).</summary>
</bill>
