<bill session="112" type="h" number="1901" updated="2013-07-20T01:26:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Saving America's Youth: the Youth Employment Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">SAY YEA</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create and encourage the creation of jobs for youth, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400350"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2011-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400152" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2011-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2012-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2011-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2011-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2011-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Natural Resources, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform     .</text>
      <committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO30" subcommittee="Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2011--Introduced.
Saving America's Youth: the Youth Employment Act of 2011 or SAY YEA - Amends the Workforce Act of 1998 regarding the work opportunity tax credit with respect to disconnected youth (who are not regularly attending school, not regularly employed, nor readily employable) hired in 2009 or 2010 under the youth opportunity grants program to lower the maximum eligibility age of such youth from 24 to 21. Directs the Secretary of Labor (Secretary) to make certain allotments to states for summer jobs programs for disconnected youth. Requires the Secretary to award grants to states to carry out employment programs for the partial reimbursement of wages paid by employers of small or medium-sized business concerns for new hires or rehires of former employees. Requires states to give priority for payments to eligible employers who hire or rehire a disconnected youth. Requires the Secretary to make allotments and grants to states to carry out eligible on-the-job training programs for disconnected youth. Directs the President to establish a public service employment program to employ individuals to carry out works of a public nature in connection with parks, roads, schools, and after-school programs. Requires priority for such jobs to be given to individuals who are disconnected, low-income, and long-term unemployed youth. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) extend the work opportunity tax credit through calendar 2016, (2) include as a member of a targeted group for purposes of such credit a qualified Title 1-B youth services recipient and rename a "qualified ex-felon" as a "qualified ex-offender" for purposes of the credit, (3) double the amount of allowable wages that may be considered in calculating such credit, (4) extend the designation period for tax-preferred empowerment zones, and (5) allow an employer tax credit through 2013 for the employment of disconnected youth. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to give preference to the hiring of individuals age 16 to 21 for federal park and forestry jobs. Authorizes contracting officers of executive agencies to give preference in the award of federal contracts for the procurement of goods and services to employers: (1) that employ, in a youth apprenticeship and in the performance of the contract, disconnected youth who reside in high unemployment areas; and (2) whose contracts are funded for FY2012 under a law enacted to create infrastructure, transportation, or green energy jobs.</summary>
</bill>
