<bill session="112" type="s" number="3462" updated="2013-07-20T02:46:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Criminal Antitrust Anti-Retaliation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to provide anti-retaliation protections for antitrust whistleblowers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2012-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5736"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-07-31">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5736" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2012--Introduced.
Criminal Antitrust Anti-Retaliation Act - Prohibits discharging or in any other manner discriminating against a whistleblower in terms and conditions of employment because: (1) the whistleblower provided information to the employer or the federal government concerning a violation of antitrust law or another criminal law committed in conjunction with a potential violation of antitrust law; or (2) the whistleblower participated in, or otherwise assisted, an investigation relating to such a violation. Allows a whistleblower who alleges discharge or other discrimination to seek relief: (1) by filing a complaint with the Secretary of Labor; or (2) if the Secretary has not issued a final decision within 180 days of filing such complaint, to bring an action at law or equity. Entitles a whistleblower who prevails in any such action to all relief necessary to make such whistleblower whole.</summary>
</bill>
