<bill session="111" type="h" number="2767" updated="2013-07-19T23:36:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Investing in Tomorrow's Technology Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to extend and improve the Small Business Innovation Research Program and the Small Business Technology Transfer Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Contracting and Technology .</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
      <committee name="House Science and Technology"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
      <committee name="House Small Business"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSM23" subcommittee="Contracting and Technology" name="House Small Business"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY19" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation" name="House Science and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2009--Introduced.
Investing in Tomorrow's Technology Act - Amends the Small Business Act to extend through FY2011 the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Program and the Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) Program. Provides that, with respect to participation in an SBIR or STTR program: (1) a business that has more than 500 employees shall not qualify as a small business; and (2) in determining whether a small business is independently owned and operated, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) shall not consider the business as affiliated with a venture capital operating company if such company does not own 50% or more of the business and the company's employees do not constitute a majority of the business's board of directors. Provides limited conditions under which a small business shall still be considered eligible for SBIR/STTR participation when a venture capital operating company controlled by a business with more than 500 employees has an ownership interest in a small business owned in majority part by venture capital operating companies.</summary>
</bill>
