<bill session="110" type="s" number="980" updated="2013-07-19T22:28:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-04-01">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Ryan Haight Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act of 2007</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Ryan Haight Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act of 2008</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to address online pharmacies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2008-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2007-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3712-3713"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-03-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3713-3715" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-16">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 110-472.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2007-09-27">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-03-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="617">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 617.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-04-01">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2307-2310" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2307-2309" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-01">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:SENATE" datetime="2008-04-01" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02T10:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-11-17">
      <text>By Senator Leahy from Committee on the Judiciary filed written report. Report No. 110-521.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6353"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="6353"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4383"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/1/2008--Passed Senate amended.
Ryan Haight Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act of 2008 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to prohibit the delivery, distribution, or dispensing of controlled substances over the Internet without a valid prescription. Exempts telemedicine practitioners. Defines "valid prescription" as a prescription that is issued for a legitimate purpose by a practitioner who has conducted at least one in-person medical evaluation of the patient. Adds definitions to the Controlled Substances Act relating to online pharmacies and the issuance of prescriptions over the Internet.Imposes registration and reporting requirements on online pharmacies.Requires an online pharmacy to: (1) display on its Internet homepage a statement that it complies with the requirements of this Act; (2) comply with state laws for the licensure of pharmacies in each state in which it operates or sells controlled substances; (3) post on its Internet homepage specified information, including the name, address, and telephone number of the pharmacy, the qualifications of its pharmacist-in-charge, and a certification of its registration under this Act; and (4) notify the Attorney General and applicable state boards of pharmacy at least 30 days prior to offering to sell, deliver, distribute, or dispense controlled substances over the Internet.Authorizes the Attorney General to issue a special registration under this Act for telemedicine practitioners.Increases criminal penalties involving controlled substances in Schedules III, IV, and V of the Controlled Substances Act. Authorizes states to apply for injunctions or obtain damages and other civil remedies against online pharmacies that are deemed a threat to state residents.Requires the U.S. Sentencing Commission, in determining whether to amend or establish new sentencing guidelines to conform the guidelines and policy statements to this Act, to consult with the Department of Justice (DOJ), experts, and other affected parties concerning which penalties for scheduled substances should be reflected.Requires the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) to report to Congress after the enactment of this Act and annually for two years after such initial report on: (1) the foreign supply chains and sources of controlled substances offered for sale without a valid prescription on the Internet; (2) DEA efforts and strategy to decrease such foreign supply chains; and (3) DEA efforts to work with domestic and multinational pharmaceutical companies and others in combating the sale of controlled substances over the Internet without a valid prescription.</summary>
</bill>
