<bill session="111" type="s" number="2804" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Employ America Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require employers to certify that they have not and will not lay off a large number of employees before they are allowed to employ foreign workers in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2009-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-19">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2009--Introduced.
Employ America Act - Prohibits the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) from approving an employer petition for any visa authorizing employment in the United States unless the employer has certified to the Secretary of Labor that the employer: (1) has not provided a notice of a mass layoff during the 12-month period immediately preceding the alien's scheduled hiring date; and (2) does not intend to provide a notice of a mass layoff. States that if an employer provides a notice of a mass layoff after the approval of a visa any visas approved during the most recent 12-month period for such employer shall expire 60 days after the date on which such notice is provided and shall not be subject to judicial review. Exempts an employer from such requirements if the employer certifies to the Secretary of Labor that the total number of the employer's workers who are U.S. citizens working in the United States will not be reduced by a mass layoff.</summary>
</bill>
