<bill session="112" type="s" number="191" updated="2013-07-20T02:18:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Amateur Radio Emergency Communications Enhancement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Amateur Radio Emergency Communications Enhancement Act of 2011</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to direct the Department of Homeland Security to undertake a study on emergency communications.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-01-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-06-13">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment. With written report No. 112-22.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-06-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="74">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 74.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="81"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/13/2011--Reported to Senate amended.
Amateur Radio Emergency Communications Enhancement Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS): (1) to study and report to Congress on the uses and capabilities of Amateur Radio Service communications in emergencies and disaster relief; and (2) in conducting the study, to utilize the expertise of stakeholder entities and organizations, including the amateur radio, emergency response, and disaster communications communities. Directs the DHS Inspector General to report on Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) grant programs, including: (1) to what degree the programs provide duplicative or overlapping assistance, (2) the cost of each program, and (3) recommendations for consolidation and elimination of programs to reduce duplication.</summary>
</bill>
