<bill session="109" type="h" number="4436" updated="2013-07-19T19:43:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-12-22">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide certain authorities for the Department of State, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-12-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-06">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T21:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T21:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11607-11609" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T21:02:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4436.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2005-12-14T21:08:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11607-11608" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T21:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2005-12-15" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13687" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2005-12-17">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2005-12-22">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2005-12-22" type="public" number="109-140">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-140.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Epidemics"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in science"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Singapore"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Student transportation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/22/2005--Public Law.
(Sec. 1) Authorizes the Secretary of State to provide for U.S. participation in the Regional Emerging Diseases Intervention Center ("REDI Center") in Singapore. Requires the Secretary to: (1) consult with the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate (Committees); and (2) report on REDI Center efforts respecting bioterrorism concerns. (Sec. 2) Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to credit Department of State medical reimbursements to the currently available appropriation account, which shall be available for expenditure during the fiscal year received or longer as may be provided by law. (Sec. 3) Amends the Diplomatic Security Act to authorize the Secretary to not convene an Accountability Review Board to conduct an inquiry for incidents that involve serious injury, loss of life, or significant property destruction at a U.S. mission in Iraq or Afghanistan during the period of October 1, 2005, through September 30, 2009. Requires the Secretary, in the case of such an incident, to: (1) notify the Committees; and (2) investigate the incident and submit a report to such Committees. (Sec. 4) Amends the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2004 to repeal the provision making United States Agency for International Development (USAID) post differential and danger pay increases for employees not in Iraq or Afghanistan subject to the provision of similar pay allowances for Department employees. Increases the maximum post-differential and danger pay allowance for a Foreign Service employee to 35% of base pay. Directs the Secretary to report to the Committees and to the Committee on Government Reform of the House and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate respecting such increases' effect on "hard-to-fill" positions. (Sec. 5) Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to authorize the Foreign Service Grievance Board to retain an employee on the payroll while a grievance is being reviewed. (Sec. 6) Amends the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2003 to extend the International Broadcasting Bureau personal services contracting pilot program through December 31, 2006. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the Department to provide in advance funds available for official residence expenses to those persons currently eligible to receive such reimbursement. (Sec. 8) Amends the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994 to authorize the Broadcasting Board of Governors to pay the primary and secondary education costs of dependents of personnel stationed in the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, including certain transportation costs, if the Board determines that the schools available in the Commonwealth are unable to provide an adequate education. Limits such payments to amounts similarly permitted to Department of Defense (DOD) dependents' educational expenses in the Commonwealth.</summary>
</bill>
