<bill session="113" type="s" number="859" updated="2013-11-02T06:59:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Animal and Public Health Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to provide for the conducts of activities to detect, and respond in a timely manner to, threats to animal health.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="954"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2013--Introduced.
Animal and Public Health Protection Act - Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to offer to enter into contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements with eligible laboratories to: (1) detect emerging or existing threats to animal health and support the protection of public health, the environment, and the agricultural economy; (2) provide the capability for standardized test procedures, laboratory biosafety and biosecurity, interconnected electronic data reporting, and emergency preparedness evaluation; and (3) coordinate the development and implementation of national veterinary diagnostic laboratory capabilities. Directs the Secretary to give priority to eligible laboratories at existing federal and state facilities and those at institutions of higher education.</summary>
</bill>
