<bill session="112" type="h" number="1630" updated="2013-07-20T01:24:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security and Medicare Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a procedure to safeguard the surpluses of the Social Security and Medicare hospital insurance trust funds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412265" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412446" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412287" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2011-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2011--Introduced.
Social Security and Medicare Protection Act - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to make it out of order in the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any concurrent resolution on the budget (or related measure) that would set forth a surplus for any fiscal year less than the combined surpluses of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund for that fiscal year. Makes it out of order in the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any (spending or tax) measure if its enactment would cause the surplus for any fiscal year covered by the most recently agreed to budget resolution to be less than such combined Fund surpluses.</summary>
</bill>
