<bill session="111" type="h" number="2984" updated="2013-07-19T23:38:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">United States Mariner and Vessel Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 46, United States Code, to assist in the defense of United States mariners and vessels against piracy, to ensure the traditional right of self-defense of those vessels against piracy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2009-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2009--Introduced.
United States Mariner and Vessel Protection Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Coast Guard's Commandant to deploy a maritime safety and security team for up to six months to deter, protect against, and rapidly respond to acts of piracy against vessels in international waters. Directs the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to issue regulations establishing standards and circumstances under which an individual is authorized to use force (including lethal force) against an individual in the defense of a vessel against piracy. Limits the liability of the individuals, the federal government, and owners, operators, and masters of vessels in actions arising out of a use of force authorized under the regulations. Directs the Secretary to work through the International Maritime Organization (IMO) to establish agreements to promote coordinated action among flag and port states to deter, protect against, and rapidly respond to acts of piracy against the vessels of, and in the waters under the jurisdiction of, those nations, and to ensure limitations on liability similar to those under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
