<bill session="111" type="s" number="3154" updated="2013-07-20T00:54:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Advancing FASD Research, Prevention, and Services Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize and extend the Fetal Alcohol Syndrome prevention and services program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2010-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2010-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-03-23">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/2010--Introduced.
Advancing FASD Research, Prevention, and Services Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend the Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorders (FASD) programs (as renamed under this Act, previously the Fetal Alcohol Syndrome and Fetal Alcohol Effect programs). Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) establish and carry out a research agenda for FASD; (2) facilitate surveillance, public health research, and prevention of FASD; and (3) continue the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Fetal Alcohol Syndrome. Requires the Secretary to provide financial assistance to: (1) establish or expand state FASD programs; (2) implement best practices to educate children with FASD, educate members of the criminal justice system on FASD, and educate adoption or foster care agency officials about services for children with FASD; (3) provide transitional services for those affected by prenatal alcohol exposure; (4) develop public service announcements to raise awareness of the risks associated with alcohol consumption during pregnancy; (5) increase awareness and identification of FASD in federally qualified health centers; and (6) provide respite care for caretakers, recruit mentors, and provide educational and supportive services to families of individuals with FASD. Directs the Comptroller General to make recommendations regarding the appropriate roles and responsibilities of federal entities with respect to programs and activities related to FASD. Requires the Secretary of Education to direct the Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services to conduct training on FASD surveillance and disseminate best practices in the education and support of children with FASD. Requires the Attorney General to direct the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to: (1) implement FASD screening procedures; (2) conduct training on surveillance and on identification and support of individuals with FASD; and (3) study the inadequacies of the current system.</summary>
</bill>
