<bill session="113" type="s" number="517" updated="2013-11-02T06:56:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote consumer choice and wireless competition by permitting consumers to unlock mobile wireless devices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1594-1595"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1595" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="1123"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2013--Introduced.
Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act - Repeals a Library of Congress (LOC) rulemaking determination, made upon the recommendation of the Register of Copyrights, regarding the circumvention of technological measures controlling access to copyrighted software on wireless telephone handsets (mobile telephones) for the purpose of connecting to different wireless telecommunications networks (a practice commonly referred to as "unlocking" such devices). Reestablishes, as an exemption to provisions of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) prohibiting such circumvention, a previous LOC rule permitting the use of computer programs, in the form of firmware or software, that enable used wireless telephone handsets to connect to a wireless telecommunications network, when circumvention is initiated by the owner of the copy of such computer program solely to connect to such a network and access to the network is authorized by the network operator, thus permitting unlocked phones. Directs the Librarian of Congress, upon the recommendation of the Register, to determine whether to extend such exemption to include any other category of wireless devices in addition to wireless telephone handsets (e.g., tablets and other mobile broadband-enabled devices).</summary>
</bill>
