<bill session="109" type="s" number="400" updated="2013-07-19T20:16:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Prevention of Illegally Imported Controlled Substances Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Todd Rode Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prevent the illegal importation of controlled substances.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1531-1532"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1534" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2005--Introduced.
Prevention of Illegally Imported Controlled Substances Act of 2005 or the Todd Rode Act - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to require a shipment of controlled substances that is imported into the United States in violation of the Act that has a value of less than $10,000 to be seized, summarily forfeited to the United States, and destroyed. Declares that: (1) provisions of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act regarding the disposition of refused articles do not authorize the delivery of the substances pursuant to the execution of a bond; and (2) the substances may not be exported. Authorizes the seizure and destruction of such controlled substances without notice to the importer, owner, or consignee of the substances involved. Requires appraisal of such substances only to the extent sufficient to document that the substances are subject to this Act. Requires that procedures promulgated under this Act be designed toward the goal of ensuring that a substantial majority of shipments of such substances are identified, seized, and destroyed. Prohibits controlled substances from being destroyed to the extent that the Attorney General determines that the substances should be preserved as evidence.</summary>
</bill>
