<bill session="111" type="s" number="1117" updated="2013-07-20T00:33:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Upper Connecticut River Partnership Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Upper Connecticut River Partnership Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide assistance in implementing cultural heritage, conservation, and recreational activities in the Connecticut River watershed of the States of New Hampshire and Vermont.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5822-5823"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5823" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-92.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-306.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="592">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 592.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2643"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
Upper Connecticut River Partnership Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a Connecticut River Grants and Technical Assistance Program to provide financial and technical assistance to the states of New Hampshire and Vermont, through the Connecticut River Joint Commissions of New Hampshire and Vermont, to improve the management of the upper Connecticut River watershed. Authorizes the Secretary to provide the Commissions with financial and technical assistance to further the purposes of this Act. . Requires the Commissions to develop criteria to prioritize and determine the eligibility of applicants for assistance under the Program and to review and prioritize applications for such assistance. Requires such criteria to be submitted by the Commissions for review by the Secretary. Sets forth procedures for the approval or disapproval of the criteria. Allows the Commissions to use funds under this Act to provide financial and technical assistance to state and local governments, nonprofit organizations, and other public and private entities for the protection of the watershed. Authorizes appropriations. Limits the federal share of the total cost of any activity funded by assistance under this Act to half of that activity's total cost. Permits the non-federal contribution towards such an activity to be in the form of in-kind contributions of fairly valued goods or services. Terminates the authority of the Secretary to provide financial assistance under this Act 10 years after enactment.</summary>
</bill>
