<bill session="111" type="s" number="916" updated="2013-07-20T00:31:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ed Walker Memorial Act for Improvements to the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to include certain former nuclear weapons program workers in the Special Exposure Cohort under the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-04-28">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="2114"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2009--Introduced.
Ed Walker Memorial Act for Improvements to the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program - Amends the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to include certain former nuclear weapons program workers in the Special Exposure Cohort under the energy employees occupational illness compensation program. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) issue regulations for designating additional classes of employees, including those employed during a period of residual contamination, as members of the Special Exposure Cohort; and (2) determine whether workers employed at the Bethlehem Steel site in Lackawanna, New York, meet the requirements of this Act for membership in the Special Exposure Cohort. Requires the Secretary to provide a report to Congress identifying facilities at which classes of employees were employed that meet the requirements for membership in the Special Exposure Cohort, as well as the number of classes and the number of employees in each class.</summary>
</bill>
