<bill session="112" type="s" number="1894" updated="2013-07-20T02:32:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-09-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Justice Against Sponsors of Terrorism Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to deter terrorism, provide justice for victims, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2012-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7710-7711"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="5904"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="3534"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2011--Introduced.
Justice Against Sponsors of Terrorism Act - Amends the federal judicial code to include among the exceptions to U.S. jurisdictional immunity of foreign states any statutory or common law tort claim arising out of an act of extrajudicial killing, aircraft sabotage, hostage taking, terrorism, or the provision of material support or resources for such an act, or any claim for contribution or indemnity relating to a claim arising out of such an act. Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) impose liability on, and grant U.S. district courts personal jurisdiction over, any person who aids, abets, provides material support or resources to, or conspires with a person who commits an act of international terrorism that injures a U.S. national; (2) repeal provisions prohibiting civil actions against foreign states or foreign officials for damages related to acts of terrorism; and (3) extend from 4 to 15 years the limitation period for bringing an action for civil damages resulting from an act of international terrorism and allow previously time-barred cases that would have been timely filed under such extended limitation period to be refiled within 90 days of the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
