<bill session="110" type="sr" number="697" updated="2013-07-19T22:19:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-09-30">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A resolution supporting the goals and ideals of National Cyber Security Awareness Month and raising awareness and enhancing the state of computer security in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300007" joined="2008-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10178-10179"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-09-30" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote" where="s">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10127-10129" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10127-10128" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10178-10179" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="hr" number="1456"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Special months"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/2008--Passed Senate without amendment.
Supports the goals and ideals of National Cyber Security Awareness Month (October 2008). Congratulates the National Cyber Security Division of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), the National Cyber Security Alliance, and the Multi-State Information Sharing and Analysis Center, and other organizations working to improve cyber security in the United States on the fifth anniversary of the National Cyber Security Month. Declares that the House of Representatives continues to work with federal agencies, national organizations, businesses, and educational institutions to encourage the development and implementation of voluntary standards, practices, and technologies in order to enhance the state of computer security in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
