<bill session="111" type="h" number="3233" updated="2013-07-19T23:41:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Predictable, Equitable, and Transparent (PET) Project Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to limit the annual cost of appropriation earmarks and to make them more predictable, equitable, and transparent.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412294"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2009-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412299" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2009-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2009--Introduced.
Predictable, Equitable, and Transparent (PET) Project Act of 2009 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to limit to 1/2 of 1% the allocation solely to appropriation earmarks of the amount allocated to the Senate and House appropriations committees for the first fiscal year of a budget resolution. Entitles each Senator to 1/100th of the Senate earmark allocation and each Member of the House to 1/441 of the House earmark allocation. Makes it out of order in either chamber to consider any measure that would cause the level of total new budget authority or total outlays for appropriation earmarks, as adjusted, set forth in the applicable budget resolution to exceed or breach such limitations. Requires a Member or Senator requesting an appropriation earmark, within five legislative days after making such request, to: (1) submit the amount requested, the project name, and a project description of its subject matter to the appropriate Clerk for posting on the Clerk's website; and (2) insert in the Congressional Record a written statement that includes such information and certifies that neither the Member, Senator, or any family member has any financial interest in the earmark. Requires each Clerk's website to include an up-to-date, comprehensive, and searchable database comprising all such requests for the current fiscal year and the budget year. Makes a conforming amendment to Rule XXI (Restrictions on Certain Bills) of the Rules of the House</summary>
</bill>
