<bill session="112" type="s" number="481" updated="2013-07-20T02:20:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Response to Eliminate Eating Disorders Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to enhance and further research into the prevention and treatment of eating disorders, to improve access to treatment of eating disorders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300061" joined="2011-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1228"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1228-1232" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/2011--Introduced.
Federal Response to Eliminate Eating Disorders Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to expand, intensify, and coordinate eating disorder research. Authorizes the Director to award grants for consortia in eating disorder research. Establishes the Interagency Eating Disorders Coordinating Council within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) improve the collection, analysis and reporting of state epidemiological data on eating disorders; (2) study the economic costs of eating disorders; and (3) award grants for programs to prevent eating disorders and obesity and to promote health body image and appropriate eating behaviors. Directs the National Center for Health Statistics and the National Center for Education Statistics to study jointly the impact eating disorders have on educational advancement and achievement. Requires the Director of CDC to study mandatory reporting of body mass index. Requires the Secretary to provide for public service announcements on eating disorders. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to award grants for training and education programs to provide health professions students or residents with an understanding of, and clinical skills pertinent to identifying and treating, eating disorders. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to permit funds made available to local education agencies for innovative assistance programs to be used for eating disorder programs. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to expand coverage for eating disorders. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, to award grants for patient advocacy to help individuals with eating disorders obtain adequate health care services and insurance coverage.</summary>
</bill>
