<bill session="111" type="h" number="2617" updated="2013-07-19T23:35:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mercury-Free Vaccines Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to reduce human exposure to mercury through vaccines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1243"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2009--Introduced.
Mercury-Free Vaccines Act of 2009 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to deem a banned mercury-containing vaccine to be adulterated. Amends the Public Health Service Act to provide that a vaccine is a banned mercury-containing vaccine if one dose of the vaccine contains one or more micrograms of mercury in any form. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to declare that an actual or potential bioterrorist incident or other public health emergency makes the administration of such vaccines advisable for a specified period. Requires the Secretary to prohibit the distribution of banned mercury-containing influenza vaccines that are approved as biological products to: (1) any child under the age of three years old (effective July 1, 2009); (2) pregnant women if the vaccine contains thimerosal (effective July 1, 2009); and (3) any child under the age of six (effective July 1, 2010). Requires the Secretary to revise the vaccine information included with mercury-containing vaccines to include: (1) a statement that indicates the presence of mercury in the vaccine; (2) information on the availability of any mercury-free or mercury-reduced alternative vaccine and instructions on how to obtain such an alternative vaccine; and (3) a recommendation against administration of any mercury-containing vaccine to a pregnant woman. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) should disseminate, with any vaccine-related information, a recommendation against administration of any thimerosal-containing vaccine to a pregnant woman.</summary>
</bill>
