<bill session="112" type="hr" number="347" updated="2013-07-20T01:05:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-07-13T14:28:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-13T14:28:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2018) to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to preserve the authority of each State to make determinations relating to the State's water quality standards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-12T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-144, by Mr. Bishop (UT).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-12T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2011-07-12T18:55:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="52">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 52.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4957-4963" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13T12:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 347.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13T13:05:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4962" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13T13:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 347, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Polis (CO) demanded a vote by the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13T14:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4963" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2011-07-13T14:28:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="564" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 250 - 171 (Roll no. 564).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4958" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="112" type="h" number="2018"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/12/2011--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2018) to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to preserve the authority of each State to make determinations relating to the State's water quality standards.</summary>
</bill>
