<bill session="109" type="h" number="2690" updated="2013-07-19T19:27:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Voter Choice Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that a State may use a proportional voting system for multiseat congressional districts, to require the use of instant runoff voting in certain elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400513"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Proportional representation"/>
    <term name="Runoff elections"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Voting machines"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/2005--Introduced.
Voter Choice Act of 2005 - Authorizes a state entitled to more than one Representative in Congress to establish a number of districts for election of Representatives that is less than the number of Representatives to which the state is entitled, as long as the Representatives are elected: (1) under a system meeting the constitutional standard of majority rule and of individuals having equal voting power; (2) the system ensures the election of any candidate in a multiseat district who receives a share of votes cast that is at least one vote greater than one-third of the total number of votes cast in the district; and (3) the number of residents per Representative is equal for all Representatives elected in the state. Requires each state to conduct general elections for federal office held in the state during 2008 and each succeeding year using an instant runoff voting system, and ensure that the voting equipment and technology used to conduct the elections is compatible with such a system. Establishes a program under which the Election Assistance Commission shall make grants to eligible states to defray the costs of administering an instant runoff voting system or a proportional voting system.</summary>
</bill>
