<bill session="111" type="h" number="4072" updated="2013-07-19T23:48:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29T18:18:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-09-29T18:18:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">AMERICA Works Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Manufacturing Efficiency and Retraining Investment Collaboration Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">AMERICA Works Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">American Manufacturing Efficiency and Retraining Investment Collaboration Achievement Works Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require that certain Federal job training and career education programs give priority to programs that provide a national industry-recognized and portable credential.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To require that certain Federal job training and career education programs give priority to programs that provide an industry-recognized and nationally portable credential.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412300"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2009-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412267" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412273" joined="2010-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412279" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400177" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412289" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412291" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2009-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and Labor"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T18:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Hirono moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T18:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7088-7090" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T18:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4072.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28T18:51:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29T18:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7273-7274" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2010-09-29T18:18:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="556" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 412 - 10 (Roll no. 556).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/28/2010 H7088-7089" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29T18:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29T18:18:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="3529"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2010--Passed House amended.
American Manufacturing Efficiency and Retraining Investment Collaboration Achievement Works Act or AMERICA Works Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998, with respect to statewide and local adult and youth workforce investment employment and training programs, to require a one-stop delivery system, in selecting and approving training services, or programs of training services, to give priority consideration to state- and local board-approved services and programs that lead to an industry-recognized and nationally portable credential that is in high demand in the local area served and listed in the skill credential registry created under this Act. Requires that funds allocated for local area youth activities be used, in part, for training programs, giving priority consideration to those that lead to a registry-listed credential in high demand in the local area served. Amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to require the same priority consideration in the state and local plans for career and technical education programs as well as in tech prep programs. Requires the Secretary of Labor to: (1) create a registry of skill credentials; and (2) list in the registry credentials that are required by federal or state law for an occupation, are from the Manufacturing Institute-Endorsed Manufacturing Skills Certification System, and are industry-recognized and nationally portable credentials consistent with established industry competency models as well as consistently updated through third party validation to reflect changing industry competencies.</summary>
</bill>
