<bill session="111" type="s" number="3732" updated="2013-07-20T00:59:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to establish within the Department of Education the Innovation Inspiration school grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412329" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="2010-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6894"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/2010--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive matching grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to: (1) promote science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) in secondary schools; (2) support the participation of secondary school students in nonprofit robotics or STEM competitions; and (3) broaden secondary school students' access to STEM careers. Allows secondary schools to apply for such grants if their LEA does not. Gives priority to grant applications that address the needs of: (1) rural or urban schools; (2) low-performing schools or school districts; or (3) LEAs or schools that serve at least 10,000 poor children or a student population at least 20% of which is poor. Authorizes the Secretary to waive all or part of the matching requirement for financially-strapped LEAs or schools. Directs the Secretary to: (1) publicize the grant program and nontraditional STEM teaching methods; and (2) evaluate the efficacy of the grant program.</summary>
</bill>
