<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1276" updated="2013-07-19T21:01:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-06-20T10:46:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-06-20T10:46:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 5876) to require certain standards and enforcement provisions to prevent child abuse and neglect in residential programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400065"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-17T18:39:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-717, by Mr. Cardoza.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-17T18:39:00-04:00">
      <text>The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except clauses 9 and 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and Labor now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment. The rule waives all points of order against the amendment in the nature of a substitute except for clause 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2008-06-17T18:39:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="236">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 236.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-06-20T09:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5734-5739" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-20T09:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1276.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-20T09:49:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1276, the Chair put the question of ordering the previous question on H.Res. 1276 and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lincoln Diaz-Dalart demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of ordering the previous question on H.Res. 1276 until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-20T10:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5742-5743" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-20T10:37:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 179 (Roll no. 435).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5738-5739, H5742" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5738-5739" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2008-06-20T10:46:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="436" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 223 - 185 (Roll no. 436).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5734-5735" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-06-20T10:46:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="110" type="h" number="5876"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2008--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 5876 (Stop Child Abuse in Residential Programs for Teens Act of 2008).</summary>
</bill>
