<bill session="109" type="s" number="2308" updated="2013-07-19T20:33:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Coal Mine Safety bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mine Safety and Health Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 to improve mine safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2006-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2006-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300085" joined="2006-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1429-1430"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Oxygen"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/16/2006--Introduced.
Mine Safety and Health Act of 2006 - Amends the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 to impose additional health and safety requirements for all coal or other mines, including regarding: (1) the strategic location of an oxygen station; (2) wireless emergency tracking devices; (3) wireless communication devices; (4) restricting communications relating to a rescue operation only to individuals participating in the rescue; and (5) secondary telephone service. Requires interviews of miners regarding an accident or occurrence without the presence of the mine operator. Directs the Secretary of Labor to: (1) establish rules for conducting investigations of mine accidents; and (2) report to specified congressional committees within 30 days of completing an investigation. Requires the Secretary to: (1) conduct a quarterly review of a mine operator's ventilation system, methane and dust control plan, and roof control plan; and (2) contact an operator who has received a citation within 24 hours to ensure that steps are being taken to correct the safety violation. Requires the Secretary to establish a central communications emergency call center for all coal and other mine operations. Imposes increased penalties for flagrant violations of mine safety standards, for failure to promptly report mine disasters, and for habitual violators of mine safety standards. Imposes additional user fees on mine operators who incur such penalties and dedicates such fees for equipment, training, and other expenses relating to mine safety. Requires all miners to receive training in the proper usage of wireless communications devices. Requires rescue workers to participate in unannounced emergency rescue drills at an operating mine at least twice a year.</summary>
</bill>
