<bill session="109" type="s" number="3833" updated="2013-07-19T20:46:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Armed Forces Employment Support Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to authorize support for the Armed Forces Support Foundation in assisting members of the National Guard and Reserve and former members of the Armed Forces in securing employment in the private sector, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8847-8848"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aerospace industries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy industries"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/2006--Introduced.
Armed Forces Employment Support Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that the federal government should support private sector employment initiatives for military personnel. Authorizes the Chief of the National Guard Bureau to make grants to the Armed Forces Support Foundation to support Foundation activities in assisting members of the National Guard and reserves and former members of the Armed Forces in securing employment in the private sector. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Foundation should enter into agreements with entities involved in energy, transportation, aerospace, domestic security, and other areas in which the employment of individuals with past military experience would be of particular utility.</summary>
</bill>
