<bill session="112" type="h" number="2209" updated="2013-07-20T01:29:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Forest Service Administrative Review Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To replace the current Forest Service administrative appeals process with a pre-decisional administrative review process modeled after the successful approach used in the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412436"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/2011--Introduced.
Forest Service Administrative Review Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), through the Forest Service, to establish a pre-decisional administrative review process that will serve as the sole means by which persons can seek an administrative review regarding proposed actions of the Forest Service concerning projects and activities that implement land and resource management plans developed under the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974. Sets forth requirements for the pre-decisional administrative review process concerning the occurrence of the review period, eligibility of a participant in the process, and notice of the proposed decision. Exempts from such process an emergency situation that exists for which immediate implementation of a proposed action is necessary. Applies certain judicial review provisions of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 with respect to: (1) the judicial review of an action challenging a proposed action under this Act, and (2) any request for an injunction regarding such an action. Makes this Act non-applicable to: (1) an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project under such Act that has its own special administrative review process, and (2) a proposed action under this Act for which a categorical exclusion is provided.</summary>
</bill>
