<bill session="113" type="h" number="128" updated="2013-11-02T06:20:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Political Advertising Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require radio and television broadcasters to provide free broadcasting time for political advertising, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400211"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/3/2013--Introduced.
Fairness in Political Advertising Act of 2013 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require each licensee for a television broadcasting station to make available free broadcast time in each even-numbered year for political advertising. Provides standards for time allotment, including total time to be allotted, the length of each unit of such free time, the hours of the day and the time of the year in which such free time must be allowed, a limitation on such free time, and the use of such free time. Requires candidates meeting certain minimum qualifying standards to be treated equally for purposes of such allotment. Provides that nothing in this Act shall restrict a candidate's right to purchase other broadcast time on such station. Requires a cable operator to make available annually free cable time for political advertising under similar requirements. Prohibits the renewal of the license of any television broadcast station licensee, or the franchise of any cable operator, that fails to comply with such requirements.</summary>
</bill>
