<bill session="111" type="h" number="6528" updated="2013-07-20T00:11:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Field EMS Quality, Innovation, and Cost Effectiveness Improvements Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for improvement of field emergency medical services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412214"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="2010-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2010--Introduced.
Field EMS Quality, Innovation, and Cost Effectiveness Improvements Act of 2010 - Designates the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) as the primary federal agency for field emergency medical services (field EMS). Defines "field EMS" as emergency medical services provided to patients prior to or outside a medical facility or other clinical setting.&#160; Requires the Administrator of NHTSA to develop and implement a cohesive national strategy to strengthen the development of field EMS at the federal, state, and local levels. Directs the Administrator to establish: (1)&#160;the EQUIP grant program to promote excellence, quality, universal access, innovation, and preparedness&#160;in field EMS;&#160; (2)&#160;the SPIA grant program to improve field EMS system performance, integration, and accountability; and (3) national guidelines for medical oversight of field EMS.&#160; Authorizes the Administrator to maintain, improve, and expand the National EMS Information System, including the National EMS Database, to insure that database information&#160;is available to federal and state policymakers, EMS stakeholders, and researchers. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to make grants for the development, availability, and dissemination of field EMS education programs and courses for field EMS personnel.&#160;Directs the Secretary to: (1) complete an evaluation of alternative delivery models for medical care through field EMS and the integration of field EMS patients with other medical providers and facilities; and (2)&#160;conduct or support up to five demonstration projects to evaluate alternative dispositions of&#160;field EMS patients (e.g., transporting such patients by ambulance&#160;to alternative medical facilities). Amends title XI (General Provisions) of the Social Security Act to include field EMS as a model for testing by the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require: (1)&#160; the Director of the Center for Quality Improvement and Patient Safety of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality&#160;to establish a Field EMS Evidence-Based Practice Center to support research to promote the highest quality of emergency medical care in&#160;field EMS and the most effective delivery system for such care; and (2) the HHS Secretary to establish an Emergency Care Coordination Center to promote and fund research, collaboration, and preparedness in emergency medicine and trauma health care. Requires the Administrator to establish and administer a National Emergency Medical Services Advisory Council to provide advice and recommendations to federal agencies and a national forum to&#160;deliberate on field EMS. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) establish the Emergency Medical Services Trust Fund; and (2) allow taxpayers to designate a portion of any income tax overpayment and make additional contributions to finance such Fund.</summary>
</bill>
