<bill session="111" type="s" number="1773" updated="2013-07-20T00:39:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Cancer Care Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of comprehensive cancer care planning under the Medicare Program and to improve the care furnished to individuals diagnosed with cancer by establishing a Medicare hospice care demonstration program and grant programs for cancer palliative care and symptom management programs, provider education, and related research.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10363-10364"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10364-10366" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="111" type="h" number="1844"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/2009--Introduced.
Comprehensive Cancer Care Improvement Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of comprehensive cancer care planning services. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to conduct a two-year demonstration project for Medicare payment for comprehensive cancer care symptom management services furnished by an eligible entity in accordance with a described plan. Directs the Secretary to make grants to eligible entities for establishing a new, or expanding an existing, palliative care and symptom management program for cancer patients. Directs the Secretary to make grants to eligible entities to improve the quality of graduate and postgraduate training of physicians, nurses, and other health care providers, as well as continuing professional education, in palliative care and symptom management for such patients. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to establish a program of grants for research on palliative care, symptom management, communication skills, and other end-of-life topics for such patients.</summary>
</bill>
