<bill session="109" type="s" number="278" updated="2013-07-19T20:15:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Summer Operations and Seasonal Equity Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to revise certain requirements for H-2B employers and require submission of information regarding H-2B non-immigrants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S982-983"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-02-03">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Seasonal labor"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/2005--Introduced.
Summer Operations and Seasonal Equity Act of 2005 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require that no less than 12,000 of the total H-2B visas (temporary nonagricultural workers) available for any fiscal year (currently, up to 66,000) must be made available in each quarter of such year. States that an alien counted toward the numerical limitations applicable to such visas within the three years prior to the approval of a petition for an H-2B temporary worker shall not be counted again toward such limitations. Makes this provision effective as if enacted on October 1, 2004. Provides for its expiration on October 1, 2007. Amends the American Competitiveness and Workforce Improvement Act of 1998 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate information regarding: (1) the numbers of aliens granted H-2B status or terminated from H-2B status, on a quarterly basis; and (2) the countries of origin, occupations of, and compensation paid to aliens granted H-2B status, the number of aliens terminated from such status, and the number of aliens provided such status during both the fiscal year reported and the preceding fiscal year, on an annual basis.</summary>
</bill>
