<bill session="113" type="h" number="2546" updated="2013-11-02T06:40:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect American Investments Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect financial transactions in the United States from enforcement of certain excise taxes imposed by any foreign government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400626"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412528" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1257"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Protect American Investments Act of 2013 - Prohibits a U.S.-based company, entity, or person from paying a financial transaction tax imposed by a foreign country on any covered financial transaction. Defines "covered financial transaction" as a financial transaction occurring on a U.S. exchange or over-the-counter within the United States, notwithstanding the nationality of the issuer of such security or the residence of any party to the transaction. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) promulgate regulations or other guidance to carry out this Act; (2) not assist any foreign government in collecting any excise tax, related penalty, or related judgment on any covered financial transaction; and (3) apply provisions of the Convention Between the United States of America and the Government of the French Republic for the Avoidance of Double Taxation and the Prevention of Fiscal Evasion With Respect to Taxes on Income and Capital to exempt covered financial transactions.</summary>
</bill>
