<bill session="110" type="h" number="2646" updated="2013-07-19T21:26:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2007-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mental Health Services in Public Health Emergencies Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish grant programs to provide funding for mental health services in response to public health emergencies, for statewide plans for providing such services in response to such emergencies, and for the training of mental health professional with respect to the treatment of victims of such emergencies, and to establish the National Mental Health Crisis Response Technical Assistance Center.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400201"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2007-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2007--Introduced.
Mental Health Services in Public Health Emergencies Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to allow the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Center for Mental Health Services, to make grants to: (1) states and political subdivisions to provide mental health services in response to public health emergencies; and (2) states to develop statewide plans for providing such services and to train personnel to implement such plan effectively.Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to establish the National Mental Health Crisis Response Technical Assistance Center to: (1) provide consultation and technical assistance to the Director and state and local governments on developing and implementing plans for providing mental health services in response to public health emergencies; (2) develop policy guidelines on mental health concerns related to crisis incidents and develop recommendations for proposed regulations and legislative proposals; (3) develop and conduct training events and conferences on mental health needs of disaster victims and witnesses; (4) serve as the principal clearinghouse for information concerning the mental health aspects of public health emergencies; and (5) provide onsite technical expertise during public health emergencies.Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to award grants for the training of health professionals with respect to the treatment of individuals who are victims of disaster.</summary>
</bill>
