<bill session="111" type="h" number="4207" updated="2013-07-19T23:50:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">2009 District of Columbia Omnibus Authorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize improvements in the operation of the government of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2886-2887"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Natural Resources, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Competition Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Competition Policy" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="5103"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2009--Introduced.
2009 District of Columbia Omnibus Authorization Act - Amends the District of Columbia Appropriation Act, 1982, as amended by the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1990, to repeal the prohibition against, and so permit, the promotion or operation of revenue-raising games of chance on the federal enclave, its adjacent public buildings, and land controlled by the Shipstead-Luce Act. Amends the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to make permanent the authority to: (1) increase the amount appropriated to the District of Columbia (District) as local funds during a fiscal year attributable to unanticipated growth of revenue collections; and (2) allocate funds from the District emergency and contingency reserve funds, respectively, and use them for cash flow management purposes. Revises certain specifications for the authorized transfer by the District Council, on behalf of the United States, to the District Redevelopment Land Agency of all federal right, title, and interest in the Southwest Waterfront Project Site. Authorizes such transfer by one or more quitclaim deeds. Authorizes the Agency to lease or sell the Site to a redevelopment company or other lessee or purchaser. Repeals the U.S. reversionary interest in such property. Permits construction of buildings or facilities on the following federal lands in the District without congressional approval: (1) Fort Dupont Park (U.S. Reservation 405); (2) Benning Stoddert Park, including the Benning Recreation Center (U.S. Reservation 706); and (3) Walter Reed Army Medical Center (Parcel 319). Requires the Director of the National Park Service and the Secretary of the Interior each to transfer specified lands to the District. Exempts income earned on District government notes and obligations from state and local taxation. Amends the District of Columbia Official Code to revise the authorities of the chief judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals to: (1) provide biennial and, as under current law, annual judicial conferences; and (2) require active magistrate judges at such conferences. Authorizes the chief judges of the District Superior Court and of the District Court of Appeals to toll or delay judicial proceedings in certain natural disaster or other emergency situations. Amends the Code to authorize the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration to establish a voluntary separation incentive payments program for nonjudicial employees of the District courts substantially similar to that for certain federal employees and members of the uniformed services. Amends the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to reduce from 114 to 70 days after a vacancy occurs the timing for special elections for ward council members in the District. Revises the annual salary of the Chief Financial Officer of the District to a rate which is not less than (currently, an annual rate equal to) level I of the Executive Schedule. Modifies the project for flood control, Potomac River, Washington, DC, to authorize the Secretary of the Army to construct the project at a specified federal cost. Authorizes the use of a specified portion of such funds to reimburse the District for its incurred costs in designing and constructing a permanent closure at 17th Street Northwest. Deauthorizes a specified portion of the project for navigation, Potomac River, Washington Channel, District of Columbia.</summary>
</bill>
