<bill session="109" type="s" number="3701" updated="2013-07-19T20:45:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Catastrophic Health Coverage Promotion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to determine successful methods to provide protection from catastrophic health expenses for individuals who have exceeded health insurance coverage for uninsured individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2006-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8060"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Catastrophic health insurance"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mortality"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/2006--Introduced.
Catastrophic Health Coverage Promotion Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish demonstration projects to provide health care coverage to individuals who: (1) are not eligible for Medicaid or Medicare benefits and have exceeded $10,500 in out-of-pocket health care costs in a year or an adjusted amount based on the average out-of-pocket costs of individuals with catastrophic illnesses in a state for the year; or (2) were receiving Medicare or Medicaid benefits but who have exhausted their eligibility and any additional private health insurance coverage. Directs the Secretary, in designing such demonstration projects, to use: (1) state risk pools; (2) reinsurance mechanisms for small businesses; (3) public or private arrangements for the provision of affordable health insurance coverage to cover catastrophic health care expenses; and (4) any combination of such arrangements. Requires the Secretary to establish demonstration projects to provide health insurance coverage for catastrophic health benefits to individuals who do not have health insurance coverage. Directs the Secretary, in designing such demonstration projects, to: (1) use a catastrophic health insurance product administered by private health insurance plans with a deductible indexed to income level or an adjusted deductible amount based on average out-of-pocket costs; and (2) subsidize such catastrophic coverage and allow subsidies on a sliding scale to offer an affordable product for individuals earning below 200% of the federal poverty level. Establishes evaluation requirements for the projects.</summary>
</bill>
