<bill session="113" type="s" number="366" updated="2013-11-02T06:55:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993 to require the Bureau of Land Management to provide a claimant of a small miner waiver from claim maintenance fees with a period of 60 days after written receipt of 1 or more defects is provided to the claimant by registered mail to cure the 1 or more defects or pay the claim maintenance fee, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S785"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-28.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="1307"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993 regarding waivers of small miner claim maintenance fees to extend the allowance of a certain period to cure a defect in the waiver application to a failure to timely file either a waiver application or an affidavit of annual labor associated with the application and the required application fees. Considers specified claimholder claims as: (1) having received a first half final certificate for application before September 30, 1994; and (2) qualifying for specified relief under the Act, including opportunity to cure.</summary>
</bill>
