<bill session="109" type="h" number="4929" updated="2013-07-19T19:47:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2006-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Investment National Security Review Act of 2006</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend section 721 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 to enhance the effectiveness of the investigations of certain mergers, acquisitions, and takeovers for national security implications, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400354"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, International Relations, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA19" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business intelligence"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Corporate divestiture"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dubai Ports World aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government ownership"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/2006--Introduced.
Foreign Investment National Security Review Act of 2006 - Amends the Defense Production Act of 1950 to revise provisions concerning presidential authority to review pending or proposed mergers, acquisitions, or takeovers (transactions) which could result in foreign control of any person engaged in interstate commerce in the United States. Directs the President, after receiving written notification of a transaction, and acting through the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS), to conduct an investigation to determine the effects, if any, of the transaction on U.S. national security. Requires investigations to be completed within 75 days. Reestablishes CFIUS as a multi-agency committee (currently, a committee within the Department of the Treasury). Prohibits a transaction unless the President finds that it will not threaten to impair U.S. national security. Provides for enforcement of presidential findings. Prohibits judicial review of such determinations. Outlines factors to be considered during an investigation, including domestic production and national defense requirements. Requires the President, after a determination to approve or disapprove a transaction, to immediately notify (by written report) both Houses of Congress. Allows Congress 30 days after notification of an approved transaction to pass a joint resolution disapproving the transaction. Directs the President and designated agencies to submit biennial reports to Congress on: (1) evidence of coordinated strategies by one or more countries to acquire U.S. companies involved in research, development, or production of critical technologies for which the United States is a leading producer; and (2) U.S. critical infrastructure owned, controlled, or dominated by an alien, foreign corporation, or foreign government.</summary>
</bill>
