<bill session="110" type="h" number="6823" updated="2013-07-19T22:03:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2008-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">PRO Energy Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Promoting Real Opportunities for Energy Security Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the acquisition of advanced biofuels for the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400660"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2008--Introduced.
Promoting Real Opportunities for Energy Security Act or the PRO Energy Security Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Energy to acquire advanced biofuels for the purpose of filling the Strategic Petroleum Reserve if the average weighted price of oil exceeds $75 per barrel for three consecutive days. Defines "advanced biofuel" to mean renewable fuel, other than ethanol derived from corn starch, that has lifecycle greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions that are at least 50% less than baseline lifecycle GHG emissions. Authorizes the following types of fuels to be eligible for consideration as "advanced biofuel": (1) ethanol derived from cellulose, hemicellulose, or lignin; (2) ethanol derived from sugar or starch (other than corn starch); (3) ethanol derived from waste material; (4) biomass-based diesel; (5) biogas (including landfill gas and sewage waste treatment gas) produced through the conversion of organic matter from renewable biomass; (6) butanol or other alcohols produced through the conversion of organic matter from renewable biomass; and (7) other fuel derived from cellulosic biomass.Requires the Secretary of Energy to submit to specified congressional committees a report containing: (1) a description of how the Secretary will acquire advanced biofuels for such purpose; and (2) recommendations for criteria and procedures for making advanced biofuels available from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve to appropriate federal and nonfederal entities.</summary>
</bill>
