<bill session="112" type="s" number="1770" updated="2013-07-20T02:31:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2011-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Every Child Deserves a Family Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to prohibit discrimination in adoption or foster case placements based on the sexual orientation, gender identity, or marital status of any prospective adoptive or foster parent, or the sexual orientation or gender identity of the child involved.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2012-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2012-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2012-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2012-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2011-11-01">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="1681"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/2011--Introduced.
Every Child Deserves a Family Act - Prohibits an entity that receives federal assistance and is involved in adoption or foster care placements from discriminating against prospective adoptive or foster parents solely on the basis of their sexual orientation, gender identification, or marital status or on the basis of the sexual orientation or gender identity of the child involved. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), in order to ensure compliance with, and ensure understanding of the legal, practice, and culture changes required by this Act in making foster care and adoption placement decisions, to provide specified technical assistance to all entities covered by this Act. Requires a Government Accountability Office (GAO) study of whether states have substantially complied with this Act in eliminating policies, practices, or statutes that deny adoption rights on the basis of these criteria.</summary>
</bill>
