<bill session="112" type="h" number="5941" updated="2013-07-20T02:01:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2012-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">DART Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">DHS Audit Requirement Target Act of 2012</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To obtain an unqualified audit opinion, and improve financial accountability and management at the Department of Homeland Security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2012-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2012-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2012-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight, Investigations, and Management.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM09" subcommittee="Oversight, Investigations, and Management" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/2012--Introduced.
DHS Audit Requirement Target Act of 2012 or the DART Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to take steps to ensure that the full set of consolidated financial statements of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for FY2013 and each fiscal year thereafter are ready in a timely manner and in preparation for an audit as part of preparing the required performance and accountability reports, in order to obtain an unqualified opinion. Requires each annual report submitted by DHS's Chief Financial Officer to include a plan: (1) to obtain such unqualified opinion; (2) that addresses how DHS will eliminate material weaknesses and significant deficiencies in internal controls over financial reporting; and (3) to modernize the financial management systems of DHS, including consideration of alternative approaches that include modernizing existing, and establishing new, financial management systems and associated financial controls.</summary>
</bill>
