<bill session="111" type="h" number="2495" updated="2013-07-19T23:34:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-09-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Real Property Disposal Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 40, United States Code, to enhance authorities with regard to real property that has yet to be reported excess, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400282"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400177" joined="2009-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-10">
      <text>Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-09-10">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSGO24" subcommittee="Government Management, Organization, and Procurement" name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2009--Introduced.
Federal Real Property Disposal Enhancement Act of 2009 - Requires the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) to: (1) issue guidance for federal agency real property plans, including recommendations on how to identify and dispose of excess properties, evaluate disposal costs and benefits, and prioritize disposal decisions based on agency missions and anticipated future need for holdings; (2) report to specified congressional committees annually for five years on agency efforts to reduce their real property assets; and (3) assist agencies in the identification and disposal of excess real property. Includes among the amounts the Administrator is authorized to obligate from proceeds from the disposition of excess real property: (1) amounts to pay the costs related to identifying and preparing properties to be reported excess by another agency; and (2) amounts to pay the costs associated with the reversion, custody, and disposal of reverted real property. Revises requirements for federal agency retention of proceeds from the transfer or sale of excess real property. Provides that requirements under the McKinney Vento Homeless Assistance Act for the use of public buildings and real property to assist the homeless shall not apply to certain non-excess federal buildings or real property selected for demolition.</summary>
</bill>
