<bill session="111" type="s" number="2856" updated="2013-07-20T00:51:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-12-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Fisheries Agreement Clarification Act</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">International Fisheries Agreement Clarification Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to allow the United States-Canada Transboundary Resource Sharing Understanding to be considered an international agreement for the purposes of section 304(e)(4) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412381" joined="2009-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-12-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2009-12-17">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-194.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-05-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="402">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 402.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="4369"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/24/2010--Reported to Senate amended.
International Fisheries Agreement Clarification Act - Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to recognize the United States-Canada Transboundary Resource Sharing Understanding (and other related fishery management Understandings and decisions made under such Understandings) as an international agreement under such Act. States that: (1) annual fishing level recommendations for fishery stocks in any given year under such Understandings may be exceeded as long as the fishing mortality level allows for progress toward rebuilding affected fish stocks; (2) the 10-year fishery rebuilding requirement shall not apply to stocks covered by such Understandings; and (3) this Act shall apply to fishing years beginning after April 30, 2010.</summary>
</bill>
