<bill session="109" type="s" number="679" updated="2013-07-19T20:19:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Central Contractor Registry Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to require the registration of contractors' taxpayer identification numbers in the Central Contractor Registry database of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2005-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2005-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3058-3059"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3059" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/2005--Introduced.
Central Contractor Registry Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Defense to maintain a centralized, electronic database, to be known as the Central Contractor Registry, for the registration of sources of property and services (contractors) who seek to participate in contracts and other procurements entered into by various Federal procurement officials. Requires the Registry to include certain tax-related information for each contractor, including their taxpayer identification numbers and authorization for the Secretary of Defense to obtain verification of such numbers from the Commissioner of Internal Revenue. Makes contractors who do not register such information, or who register invalid information, ineligible for contracts entered into under the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949.</summary>
</bill>
