<bill session="109" type="s" number="572" updated="2013-07-19T20:18:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-09-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeland Security Food and Agriculture Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Homeland Security Food and Agriculture Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to give additional biosecurity responsibilities to the Department of Homeland Security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300001"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2005-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-03-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2388-2389" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9433-9434"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Collins with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="224">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 224.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>By Senator Collins from Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs filed written report. Report No. 109-209.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Food supply"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Plant diseases"/>
    <term name="Plant protection"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/2005--Reported to Senate amended.
Homeland Security Food and Agriculture Act of 2005 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to carry out a program to protect the U.S. agriculture and food supply from agroterrorist acts. States that such program shall provide for: (1) advising and coordinating with federal, state, local, regional, and tribal homeland security officials regarding prevention and preparedness for, and the response to, an agroterrorist act; and (2) executing the Secretary's agriculture security responsibilities described in specified Homeland Security Presidential Directives. Sets forth the Secretary's responsibilities, including: (1) increasing biosecurity communication and coordination among federal, state, local, regional, and tribal emergency response providers and animal health and plant disease specialists; (2) ensuring that such entities execute their respective emergency roles; (3) ensuring that state, local, and tribal officials have adequate access to federal biosecurity information and resources; (4) coordinating with the Secretary of Transportation to develop guidelines on agricultural transportation restrictions in response to an agricultural disease; (5) coordinating with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) in considering the potential environmental impact of an agricultural disease response by federal, regional, state, local, and tribal emergency response providers and animal health and plant disease specialists; (6) working with federal agencies (including other elements of the intelligence community and the Department of Agriculture) to improve the ability of employees to identify a biological commodity or product, livestock, or any other good imported from a suspect location; (7) coordinating with the Department of State to provide the President and federal agencies with guidelines for mutual assistance agreements with other countries to provide training for U.S. veterinarians, public health workers, and agriculture specialists in the identification and control of foreign diseases, to provide resources and technical assistance personnel to foreign governments with limited resources, and to participate in a bilateral or multilateral biosecurity training program; (8) cooperating with state, local, and tribal homeland security officials to establish state and regional response plans; and (9) establishing a state and local homeland security task force to identify the best practices for carrying out a regional or state biosecurity program, and to design training for emergency response providers and animal health and plant disease specialists. Directs the Office of State and Local Coordination and Preparedness to establish a state and local grant program to facilitate the participation of state and local agriculture security experts in community emergency planning efforts. Authorizes FY2006 appropriations for such program.</summary>
</bill>
