<bill session="109" type="s" number="1602" updated="2013-07-19T20:27:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Improving Long-Term Care Choices Act of 2005</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to require States to disregard benefits paid under long-term care insurance for purposes of determining medicaid eligibility, to expand long-term care insurance partnerships between States and insurers, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow individuals a deduction for qualified long-term care insurance premiums, the use of such insurance under cafeteria plans and flexible spending arrangements, and a credit for individuals with long-term care needs, to establish home and communitybased services as an optional medicaid benefit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300006" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300022" joined="2005-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9520-9523"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health insurance portability"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Welfare waivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2005--Introduced.
Improving Long-Term Care Choices Act of 2005 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to disregard benefits paid under long-term care insurance for purposes of determining Medicaid eligibility. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish specified additional consumer protections with respect to long-term care insurance policies, based on the October 2000 National Association of Insurance Commissioners model regulations. Amends SSA title XIX to permit the expansion of long-term care partnership insurance policies to all states. Requires all new partnership policies to be Qualified Long-Term Care Insurance Policies. Directs the Secretary to set standards for reciprocity to provide for the portability of long-term care partnership policies from one partnership state to another partnership state. Directs the Secretary to establish a National Clearinghouse for Long-Term Care Information. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) a deduction from gross income for eligible long-term care premiums paid during the taxable year; and (2) a tax credit to help cover long-term care expenses. Provides that no gain or loss shall be recognized on the exchange of a qualified long-term care insurance contract for another qualified long-term care insurance contract. Amends SSA title XIX to provide states with a new option to offer home and community-based services to Medicaid-eligible individuals without obtaining a federal waiver. Directs the Secretary to issue regulations removing administrative barriers under Medicare (SSA title XVIII) and Medicaid that impede the offering of integrated acute and long-term care services, which combine acute, home and community-based, nursing facility and mental health services, and coverage of prescription drugs, into a single model of care for individuals who are dually eligible for such programs. Directs the Secretary to make recommendations to Congress for removal of statutory barriers to the offering of such integrated services.</summary>
</bill>
