<bill session="111" type="hc" number="147" updated="2013-07-20T00:14:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2009-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of Congress regarding people in the United States with bleeding disorders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412299" joined="2009-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412253" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412232" joined="2010-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Blood and blood diseases"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2009--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress regarding the federal government's responsibility with respect to research, funding, access to treatment, public education and awareness, and support for screening for bleeding disorders. Calls for: (1) the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to provide Congress with a five-year research plan for people with bleeding disorders; (2) the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to continue to improve outreach, treatment, and prevention for such disorders by facilitating an educational relationship between treatment centers, university health clinics, and undergraduate student populations; and (3) referrals of people with bleeding disorders to federally sponsored hemophilia treatment centers as critical to comprehensive treatment of such disorders. Urges: (1) physicians to screen all women presenting with menorrhagia for von Willebrand's disease; (2) patient advocate organizations and medical specialty societies to continue to collaborate on public education campaigns about bleeding disorders; and (3) physicians to screen all adolescents attending institutions of higher education for von Willebrand's disease.</summary>
</bill>
