<bill session="111" type="h" number="5602" updated="2013-07-20T00:03:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2010-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gulf Coast Access to Savings Act of 2010</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for distributions from retirement plans for losses as a result of the explosion on and sinking of the mobile offshore drilling unit Deepwater Horizon, the discharge of oil in the Gulf of Mexico caused by such explosion and sinking, or the effects of such discharge on the economy in the areas affected by such discharge.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400328"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2010-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2010--Introduced.
Gulf Coast Access to Savings Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow tax-free distributions, up to $50,000 in any taxable year, from retirement plans on or after April 20, 2010, and before January 1, 2011, for individuals whose principal place of abode is in Florida, Alabama, Mississippi, Louisiana, or Texas and who sustained an economic loss caused by the explosion on and sinking of the Deepwater Horizon offshore drilling unit, the resulting discharge of oil in the Gulf of Mexico, or the effects of such discharge on the economy in the affected areas. Provides tax incentives for the use of distributions by individuals in affected states to make home purchases. Increases to $100,000 the amount which may be borrowed without penalty from an employer benefit plan by individuals in affected states.</summary>
</bill>
